<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>California Permits Turning Wastewater to Drinking Water  (2023/12/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/california-permits-turning-wastewater-to-drinking-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>California officials recently approved new rules to let water agencies <strong>recycle</strong> wastewater and put it right back into the pipes that carry drinking water to homes, schools, and businesses.</p>
<p>It is a big step for California. The state has struggled for many years to secure drinking water for more than 39 million people. It shows a change in public opinion on a subject that as recently as twenty years ago was met with criticism and ended similar projects.</p>
<p>Since then, California has been through several extreme <strong>droughts</strong>. That includes the most recent one that scientists say was the driest three-year period on record. And it left the state's water supply at dangerously low levels.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Lakeisha Bryant, public information representative at the Santa Clara Valley Water District, holds flasks of water before and after it is purified at the Silicon Valley Advance Purification Center on December 13, 2023, in San Jose, California. (AP Photo/Terry Chea)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cdb74d74-c5e7-4549-9ca4-00b7a3588a0f_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Lakeisha Bryant, public information representative at the Santa Clara Valley Water District, holds flasks of water before and after it is purified at the Silicon Valley Advance Purification Center on December 13, 2023, in San Jose, California. (AP Photo/Terry Chea)</span></div>
<p>"Water is so <strong>precious</strong> in California. It is important that we use it more than once," said Jennifer West. She is director of WateReuse California, a group that supports recycled water.</p>
<p>California has been using recycled wastewater for many years. A team has used it to make ice surfaces for the game of hockey. It has been used to make snow for the sport of skiing. And farmers use it to water their crops.</p>
<p>But it has not been used directly for drinking water. Orange County, a suburban area of Los Angeles, operates a water cleaning system that recycles wastewater and then uses it to refill underground <strong>aquifers</strong>. That water then mixes with the groundwater for months before being pumped up and used for drinking water again.</p>
<p>California's new rules would let – but not require – water agencies to take wastewater, treat it, and then put it right back into the drinking water system. California would be just the second U.S. state to permit this, following Colorado.</p>
<p>It has taken officials more than 10 years to develop these rules, a process that included several studies by independent groups of scientists. A state law required the California Water Resources Control Board to approve these rules by December 31. It was met with just a few days left.</p>
<p>The vote was met with approval by some of the state's biggest water agencies. All of which have plans to build huge water recycling plants in the coming years.</p>
<p>A project in San Diego is aiming to produce nearly half of the city's water through recycling water by 2035. And the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California aims to produce up to nearly 570 million liters a day for its 19 million people. Adel Hagekhalil is with Metropolitan Water. He said the new rules will permit new projects that have not yet been considered.</p>
<p>Water agencies will need public support to complete these projects. That means proving to people that recycled water is not only safe to drink but also not dirty.</p>
<p>California's new rules require the wastewater be treated for all bacteria and viruses, even if they are not present in the wastewater. That is different from regular water treatment rules, which only require treatment for known diseases, said Darrin Polhemus. He is a director of the drinking water group for the California Water Resources Control Board.</p>
<p>In fact, the treatment is so intense it removes all of the minerals that make fresh drinking water taste good. That means the minerals need to be added back at the end of the process.</p>
<p>"It's at the same drinking water quality, and probably better in many <strong>instances</strong>," Polhemus said.</p>
<p>Polhemus added that it takes time and money to build these treatment centers. So, they will only be available for bigger cities at first.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recycle </strong>– <em>v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
<p><strong>drought </strong>– <em>n</em>. a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p><strong>precious </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very valuable or important: too valuable or important to be wasted or used carelessly</p>
<p><strong>aquifer </strong>– <em>n</em>. a layer of rock or sand that can absorb and hold water</p>
<p><strong>instances </strong><em>– n.</em> an example of a particular type of action or situation: an occasion of something happening</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Years after Pandemic, Students Still Far Behind  (2023/12/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/three-years-after-pandemic-students-still-far-behind.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>In the third full school year since the COVID-19 pandemic began, students continued to feel the effects of school closures. Some leading experts and education officials worry that the learning loss caused by the pandemic may be long-term.</p>
<p>Making matters worse, many students are missing school. <strong>Chronic</strong> <strong>absenteeism</strong> is becoming more common at school <strong>districts</strong> around the country. Some students went missing from the attendance rolls during the pandemic and have never been accounted for.</p>
<p>And in a year of growing artificial intelligence technology, AI has also entered the classroom. Some schools have banned the use of chatbots like ChatGPT. Other teachers are using the new technology to help students, hoping they use the technology in <strong>appropriate</strong> ways.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Jenes Ochoa Rojas goes over the lines of a three-scene play written by ChatGPT in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c5aa-08db135b1214_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Jenes Ochoa Rojas goes over the lines of a three-scene play written by ChatGPT in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.<i>&amp;#</i>160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)</span></div>
<p>Here is a look at the big issues that shaped education in 2023 and will shape education in the year to come.</p>
<p><strong>Continued learning loss </strong></p>
<p>In June, the U.S. Department of Education released the scores from a national math and reading test that is given to 13-year-olds. About 8,700 students took the test in both math and reading in late 2022.</p>
<p>The results showed a drop of nine points in math and four points in reading compared to 2020, the last year the test was administered. The department's information shows that those are the largest point decreases between tests recorded since 1973.</p>
<p>The test asks students to read short <strong>passages</strong> and identify the main idea or some facts. In math, students had to answer simple multiplication and geometry questions.</p>
<p>The latest test scores show that American 13-year-old students are back to their lowest level in math since 1990 and lowest reading level since 2004.</p>
<p>Math and Reading scores were no better outside the U.S. Students around the world suffered historic setbacks in reading and math. That information comes from results of the latest Program for International Student Assessment (PISA).</p>
<p>The PISA is an international comparative study of the scores of 15-year-old students on tests in reading, math and science. It is administered by OECD. Nearly 700,000 students worldwide took part in the study.</p>
<p>PISA is given every three years. The latest results showed an "<strong>unprecedented</strong> drop in performance" since 2018. The 2022 results were released on December 5. It is the first extensive study with data on how the pandemic has affected student performance around the world.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic was a major reason for the worldwide score drops. But science and reading scores were dropping even before the pandemic. This suggests there are other reasons for the decrease.</p>
<p>Factors such as the level of investment in education, the social value and pay levels of teachers, and educational beliefs of students have all influenced educational results, OECD found.</p>
<p><strong>Absent, missing students</strong></p>
<p>Students are not going to make gains in learning if they miss school. Education officials and activists are concerned about an increase in the number of students who are absent for many days during the school year.</p>
<p>Education policy experts call the problem "chronic absenteeism." Chronic absenteeism is defined as missing more than 10 percent out of the days in a school year.</p>
<p>There are many reasons why students miss a lot of school. Certain physical problems and mental health problems, which have increased since the pandemic, are possible causes.</p>
<p>Certain community conditions also can affect attendance, says Joshua Childs, a professor of education policy at the University of Texas at Austin. These include whether a student has safe transportation to and from school and whether the school itself is a safe environment. Childs added that if families do not feel connected with the school community or do not value education that can add to absenteeism.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of American students have also dropped out of public schools since the start of the COVID-19 pandemic. They have essentially gone missing from schools.</p>
<p>A recent examination found an estimated 240,000 students in 21 states whose absences from school could not be explained. These students did not move out of state. They also did not sign up for private school or home-school.</p>
<p>The issue of missing students received a lot of attention in 2020 after the pandemic closed schools around the country. In the years since, however, the issue has largely become a budgeting problem.</p>
<p>There is no longer urgency to find the students who disappeared from school. Early in the pandemic, school workers would go to the students' homes to try and help them return to the classroom. Most of those efforts have ended.</p>
<p><strong>Changing technology</strong></p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic showed how useful digital technology could be for schools. But it also showed the limitations of technology in the educational setting. Millions of students were able to attend classes online and avoid spreading the virus. But many students failed to learn by such methods.</p>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization ( or UNESCO) argues against unsupervised wide use of digital tools and AI in education. A recent UNESCO report says there is little evidence that wide technology use improves learning.</p>
<p>The organization says digital educational tools can never replace the human connection of teacher and student. There is a very large divide, or gap, between rich and poor countries when it comes to digital resources</p>
<p>"Even if connectivity was <strong>universal</strong>, it would still be necessary to demonstrate ...that digital technology offers real added value in terms of effective learning," the UNESCO report says.</p>
<p>Many educators fear students will use the AI tool ChatGPT to write their reports or <strong>cheat</strong> on homework. New York City school officials started blocking the writing tool on school devices and networks in January. But other teachers are including it in the classroom.</p>
<p>Donnie Piercey is a teacher in Lexington, Kentucky. He told his fifth-grade students to try and outsmart the tool that was creating writing <strong>assignments</strong>. Piercey says his job is to prepare students for a world where knowledge of AI will be required.</p>
<p>He describes ChatGPT as just the latest technology in his 17 years of teaching that raised concerns about the possibility of cheating. Other tools include Google, Wikipedia and YouTube.</p>
<p>"As educators, we haven't <strong>figured</strong> out the best way to use artificial intelligence yet," he added. "But it's coming, whether we want it to or not."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>chronic </strong><em>— adj. </em>continuing or occurring again and again for a long time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>absent</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— adj. </em>not present at a usual or expected place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>district</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— n. </em>an area established by a government for official government business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>appropriate </strong><em>— adj. </em>right or suited for some purpose or situation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>passage </strong><em>— adj. </em>a usually short section of a book, poem, speech, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>— adj. </em>not done or experienced before</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em> a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>universal </strong><em>— adj. </em>done or experienced by everyone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cheat </strong><em>— v. </em>to break a rule or law usually to gain an advantage at something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>assignment </strong><em>— n. </em>a job or duty that is given to someone : a task someone is required to do</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>figure </strong><em>— v. </em>to understand or find by thinking</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia's Involvement in Sports Likely to Grow in 2024  (2023/12/27) | 沙特金元体育2024年可能继续大杀四方</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/saudi-arabia-s-involvement-in-sports-likely-to-grow-in-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>At the beginning of 2023, Saudi Arabia's growing influence on professional golf, and sports in general, was a concern for players and their fans.<br/>
2023年初，沙特阿拉伯对职业高尔夫和整个体育运动的影响力越来越大，这引起了球员及其球迷的忧虑。</p>
<p>Twelve months later, discussions are very different. Worries about the supposed threat of "sportswashing" - using sports to improve a country's reputation – have declined. Concerns about moral issues - the line between "right" and "wrong" - have also gone down. Attention now is fixed on just how rich the Saudis might make the athletes.<br/>
12个月后，议论情况大不相同。人们对所谓的“体育洗白”（利用体育运动来提高国家声誉）威胁的担忧有所减少。对道德问题，即“对”和“错”之间界限的担忧也有所下降。现在，人们的注意力集中在沙特人可能会让运动员变得多么富有上。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What has changed?<br/>
发生了什么变化？</span></p>
<p>Two major events caused the change. On June 6, the PGA Tour announced it was looking to go into business with the Saudi group that was paying for the kingdom's LIV Golf, which the tour had labeled as a threat.<br/>
两件大事导致了这一变化。6月6日，美国职业高尔夫球巡回赛宣布，它正寻求与赞助LIV Golf的沙特组织开展业务，该巡回赛曾称其为威胁。</p>
<p>Then, six months later, Jon Rahm, the world's third-ranked professional golfer and an early resister of LIV, decided to join LIV for a deal reported to be worth about $500 million.<br/>
六个月后，世界排名第三的职业高尔夫球手、LIV的早期抵制者琼·拉姆决定加入LIV，据报道这笔交易价值约5亿美元。</p>
<p>Other important events included the continuing talks between the Saudis and leaders of professional tennis organizations. In addition, the push into soccer will bring the world's biggest sporting event, the World Cup, to Saudi Arabia in 2034.<br/>
其他重要活动包括沙特人与职业网球组织领导人之间的持续会谈。此外，进军足球将在2034年为沙特阿拉伯带来世界上最大的体育赛事世界杯。</p>
<p>
Dan Durbin is director of the Institute of Sports, Media and Society at the University of Southern California (USC). Durbin said of the Saudi plans: "You're investing in sports, which is one of the few growth industries in the world....It is, as far as we can see, an almost endless growth industry."<br/>
丹·德宾是南加州大学体育、媒体和社会研究所所长。德宾在谈到沙特的计划时说：“投资体育是世界上为数不多的增长型行业之一……就我们所见，这是一个几乎增长无止境的产业。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Saudi's investments<br/>
沙特的投资</span></p>
<p>In early 2022, the discussion about golf centered on Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund, or PIF, in LIV Golf. At the time, six-time major winner Phil Mickelson made a critical comment about Saudi Arabia related to the murder of the Washington Post writer Jamal Khashoggi.<br/>
2022年初，关于高尔夫的讨论集中在沙特阿拉伯公共投资基金对LIV golf的投资上。当时，六届大满贯得主菲尔·米克尔森就沙特卷入《华盛顿邮报》作家贾迈勒·卡舒吉的谋杀案发表了批评性评论。</p>
<p>Mickelson's comment set the dividing line in what was viewed as a moral question. And the discussion ignored how important Saudi Arabia is in the world economy. The Saudis gain much of their importance by supplying around 15 percent of the world's petroleum.<br/>
米克尔森的评论划下了一个道德问题的分界线。这些讨论忽略了沙特阿拉伯在世界经济中的重要性。沙特通过供应全球约15%的石油而获得了很大的重要性。</p>
<p>Besides golf, the fund offered one of soccer's biggest stars, Cristiano Ronaldo, $200 million to join a Saudi team. And it also owns the Premier League's Newcastle soccer club.<br/>
除了高尔夫，该基金还出资2亿美元邀请足球巨星克里斯蒂亚诺·罗纳尔多加盟了沙特球队。它还拥有英超联赛的纽卡斯尔足球俱乐部。</p>
<p>As the calendar turns to 2024, there is no sign of Saudi involvement in sports slowing. The Saudis are hosting a Formula One auto race. They are also looking to invest some $5 billion into cricket's Indian Premier League with an eye on making it bigger in other countries.<br/>
随着日历转到2024年，沙特对体育运动的参与没有放缓的迹象。沙特正在举办一场一级方程式赛车比赛。他们还希望向印度板球超级联赛投资约50亿美元，为的是扩大该项运动在其它国家的规模。</p>
<p>The ATP, which runs men's professional tennis, has a five-year deal to hold one of its biggest events in the Saudi port city of Jeddah. Talks between the Saudis and the women's tour are reportedly ongoing.<br/>
经营男子职业网球的职业网球联合会签订了一份为期五年的协议，它将在沙特港口城市吉达举办其最大的赛事之一。据报道，沙特和女子职业网球巡回赛之间的谈判正在进行中。</p>
<p>In a sign of how public discussions have changed, Billie Jean King, who fought for equal pay for women in sports, has said bringing women's tennis to the kingdom might not be all bad despite its poor record on women's rights.<br/>
比莉·让·金曾为女性在体育运动中的同工同酬而奋斗，她表示，尽管沙特在女权方面的记录不佳，但将女子网球带到沙特可能并不完全是坏事，这表明公众讨论已经发生了变化。</p>
<p>"I don't think you really change unless you engage," she said earlier this year.<br/>
她今年早些时候说：“我不认为你真的会改变，除非你参与进来。”</p>
<p>Durbin says sports is a way for the kingdom to be seen as more than an oil-producer with a bad human-rights record.<br/>
德宾说，体育运动是沙特被视为不仅仅是一个人权记录不佳的石油生产国的途径。</p>
<p>"For decades, sports has been the center of soft diplomacy," he said. "You try to create a positive response and feeling about your ethics because you're holding to the rules of sports."<br/>
他说：“几十年来，体育一直是软外交的中心。各国试图对自己的道德标准做出积极的回应和感受，因为你坚持体育规则。”</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我叫约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Millions Infected with Dengue as Temperature Rises  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/millions-infected-with-dengue-as-temperature-rises.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The disease dengue is spreading across the Western Hemisphere in numbers not seen since record-keeping began in 1980. Experts are warning that rising temperatures and growing cities are increasing the rate of infection.</p>
<p>More than 4 million cases have been reported throughout the Americas and the Caribbean so far this year, breaking a record set in 2019. Officials from the Bahamas to Brazil are warning of crowded health centers and new infections daily. Reports say there have been more than 2,000 deaths across the wide area.</p>
<p>Thais dos Santos is with the Pan American Health Organization, the area office of the World Health Organization (WHO) in the Americas. She said diseases like dengue, "provide us a really good <strong>sentinel</strong> of what is happening with climate change."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Children with dengue wait to be seen by doctors at the Mario Ortiz Children's Hospital in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, Feb. 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Ipa Ibanez,File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c907-08dbffd9834e_cx7_cy0_cw86_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Children with dengue wait to be seen by doctors at the Mario Ortiz Children's Hospital in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, Feb. 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Ipa Ibanez,File)</span></div>
<p>A lack of good <strong>sanitation</strong> and strong health systems have added to the rise in cases. But experts say <strong>droughts</strong> and floods linked to climate change are causing greater spread of the virus. That is because stored water and heavy rains appeal to mosquitoes.</p>
<p>Dr. Gabriela Paz-Bailey is chief of the dengue branch for the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Puerto Rico. She noted that higher temperatures also are expanding the mosquito's habitat and helping the virus develop faster inside the mosquito. That leads to higher viral loads and a higher chance of transmission.</p>
<p>This year's Northern Hemisphere summer was the hottest ever, with August about 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer than pre-industrial period averages. And Copernicus, the European climate service, reported that 2023 is the second hottest year on record.</p>
<p>Worldwide, more than 4.5 million cases of dengue had been reported as of early November. There have been more than 4,000 deaths reported in 80 countries.</p>
<p>Countries like Bangladesh are seeing a record number of cases and deaths. The government in the South Asian country has reported more than 313,700 cases and more than 1,600 deaths. Most of the deaths happened within three days of hospitalization.</p>
<p>The mosquito that carries dengue also has been identified in 22 European countries, with local spread of the disease seen in France, Italy and Spain. In August, the central African country of Chad reported its first dengue outbreak in history.</p>
<p>Dengue affects some 129 countries, with roughly half the world's population at risk, says the WHO. Infected female mosquitoes pass the virus when they feed on animals. The sickness can cause severe headaches, fever, vomiting, rash and other signs. While most infected people do not get symptoms, severe cases can lead to <strong>plasma</strong> leakage and death.</p>
<p>What is worse, experts say, repeated infections means a higher risk of developing severe dengue.</p>
<p>The Caribbean also is battling an increase in cases. The area had reported a 15 percent increase in confirmed cases by early October compared with the same period last year, says the Caribbean Public Health Agency.</p>
<p>Officials on the French Caribbean islands of Guadeloupe and Martinique declared an epidemic in August that is still ongoing. Martinique is reporting an average of 800 cases a week on the island of some 394,000 people.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Jamaica and the Bahamas declared an outbreak in September followed by Barbados in October.</p>
<p>Poor countries struggle the most with dengue. Bad sanitation creates a good reproduction environment for infected mosquitoes. Poor housing conditions leave people at greater risk of exposure to mosquitoes. Dengue outbreaks can crush already poor and overworked health systems.</p>
<p>Jeremy Farra is chief scientist for the WHO. He said dengue is very difficult to treat partly because patients often delay in seeking medical care. The virus can progress so quickly, he said. Treating those with the disease requires very close patient supervision and a lot of time.</p>
<p>Farra said, "Imagine that you have a thousand people like that requiring all that <strong>delicate</strong> clinical care. It can very quickly <strong>overwhelm</strong> a system."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sentinel </strong><em>— n. </em>sometimes used figuratively</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>drought</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— n. </em>a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pre-industrial </strong><em>— adj. </em>relating to a time before industrialization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>plasma </strong><em>— n. </em>the watery part of blood that contains blood cells</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>delicate </strong><em>— adj. </em>easily broken or damaged</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What White House Gardens Say about America  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-white-house-gardens-say-about-america.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The earliest presidents who lived in the White House did not want the large outdoor areas that the <strong>monarchs</strong> of Europe might enjoy.</p>
<p>Marta McDowell is writer of <em>All the Presidents' Gardens. </em>She said, "You can understand that, given our democratic form of government." But she said she thinks that a visit to the home of the British royal family, Buckingham Palace, caused President John Kennedy to expand the White House <strong>gardens</strong>.</p>
<p>From the start, presidents and their families influenced the 7.2 hectares of open space in the front and back of the White House differently. Their choices often showed their values and traditions of their day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A view of the restored Rose Garden at the White House in Washington, Saturday, Aug. 22, 2020. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-637d-08dbfcd82e88_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A view of the restored Rose Garden at the White House in Washington, Saturday, Aug. 22, 2020. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)</span></div>
<p>McDowell said that the White House is "really their home" while they are in office. She added that as long as they work with the historic plan of the gardens the National Park Service tries to meet the desires of the administration. The National Park Service oversees the gardens.</p>
<p>John Quincy Adams, America's sixth president, worked in the garden. Theodore Roosevelt, the 26th president, took down glass structures called greenhouses that were first built by James Buchanan, the 15th president, in the 1850s.</p>
<p>John Kennedy, the 35th president, redesigned one garden called the Rose Garden in the 1960s. First lady Michelle Obama, wife of the 44th president, built a food garden using plants and seeds from the home of Thomas Jefferson, the third president. Today, the garden has more than 50 kinds of vegetables.</p>
<p>Pierre L'Enfant was the city planner and <strong>architect</strong> for America's first president, George Washington. At first, he planned for a 30-hectare presidential garden. However, as a believer in small government, Jefferson reduced the White House grounds to just 2 hectares. The gardens were expanded to the current 7.2 hectares</p>
<p>Jefferson, like many Americans who had just freed themselves from a British monarch, was concerned about creating a new <strong>king</strong>.</p>
<p>"Avoid <strong>palaces</strong> and gardens of palaces," William Thornton, a Washington city representative warned. "If you build a palace with gardens, I will find you a king."</p>
<p>Over time, several different plants and flowers were planted at the White House. They include roses which have been around since at least Jefferson's time. They also include peonies, wanted by first lady first lady Nancy Reagan of the 40th president, and Texas bluebells, asked for by first lady Laura Bush of the 43rd president.</p>
<p>Oak and elm trees have also been on the White House grounds almost since the beginning. One tree, a chestnut oak southeast of the White House, might be the oldest tree on the grounds. The White House says it has been around since 1800.</p>
<p>McDowell says the White House gardens represent gardening tradition over time. First it followed designs in Europe, and then it was shaped by local traditions, the area, and the climate.</p>
<p>But she said, "It's not that they are always the leader. In fact, sometimes they're following."</p>
<p>The White house grounds were open to the public up until 1923. That was when Calvin Coolidge, the 30th president, permanently closed them to unapproved visitors.</p>
<p>These days, the White House Garden planned visits for the public are usually available for the public twice a year, one weekend in the spring and again in autumn.</p>
<p>McDowell said, "They are full of tradition. They're full of beauty."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>monarch </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person (such as a king or queen) who rules a kingdom or empire</p>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n</em>. an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>architect </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who designs buildings</p>
<p><strong>king </strong>– <em>n</em>. a male ruler of a country who usually inherits his position and rules for life</p>
<p><strong>palace </strong>– <em>n</em>. the official home of a king, queen, or president</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rohingya Girls Forced into Dangerous Marriages in Malaysia  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/rohingya-girls-forced-into-dangerous-marriages-in-malaysia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Rohingya girl from Myanmar wanted to do anything she could to provide some money for her parents and three younger siblings. They needed food.</p>
<p>The 14-year-old and her family are members of the Muslim minority in Myanmar. The group is always in danger of attack by government forces and others there.</p>
<p>Last year, the girl, M, agreed to marry a man in Malaysia who promised to send about $4,000 to her family.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rohingya refugee, S, age 16, stands in the hallway of a friend's home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, on Oct. 6, 2023. S traveled to Malaysia from Myanmar in 2023 to marry an older man who paid for her passage. (AP Photo/Victoria Milko)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f1ec8071-da5b-441c-90f4-671ed68f3b86_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rohingya refugee, S, age 16, stands in the hallway of a friend's home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, on Oct. 6, 2023. S traveled to Malaysia from Myanmar in 2023 to marry an older man who paid for her passage. (AP Photo/Victoria Milko)</span></div>
<p>She and all the girls in this report are identified by only the first letter of their names for their safety.</p>
<p>M told the <em>Associated Press</em> she was not ready for marriage. But she had an urgent need to help her family.</p>
<p>Now, a year later in Kuala Lumpur, her 35-year-old husband rapes her almost every night.</p>
<p>M's experience is not unusual, the <em>AP</em> reports.</p>
<p>Many underage girls are now in Malaysia living in forced marriages to older men.</p>
<p>The girls say conditions for Rohingya in Myanmar and refugee camps in Bangladesh were very bad. Soldiers and others were raping and killing people. Others had their homes burned and property stolen. Malaysia seemed like a possibility for a safer life.</p>
<p><strong>Difficult journey</strong></p>
<p>The AP interviewed 13 Rohingya for the report. All had arrived in Malaysia since 2022. The youngest girl was 13. They all say they feel like hostages. They are rarely permitted outside their homes. They say they are not prepared to be mothers. About half are pregnant and some have children already.</p>
<p>The path to flee the refugee camps or Myanmar is dangerous. Some try crossing the Andaman Sea by boat although many die on the long trip. The United Nations said most Rohingya who survived the crossing this year were women and children.</p>
<p>The people who take the girls on dangerous trips to Malaysia are called traffickers. The girls are crowded onto boats and vehicles for the trip. There is little food. The traffickers also rape and beat the girls.</p>
<p>When M arrived in Malaysia, the man she was to marry called for the ceremony to take place at once. M was still bleeding from the rapes she suffered on her journey. A person who helps the Rohingya girls took her to a hospital for care.</p>
<p>When M got home, she found out the man who was now her husband already had a wife and two children. M does not tell her parents what happened to her. She thinks it might cause her husband to stop sending monthly payments to her family.</p>
<p><strong>Pain and unwanted pregnancy</strong></p>
<p>Another girl, D, is in the same situation. She is 13. She plays with a little toy whale as she talks. She wants to play outside or visit a market nearby. But, her husband does not permit her to leave the home. She is forced to have sex every day. She does not want a baby, but she knows there is a good chance she will get pregnant.</p>
<p>"I want to run," D said.</p>
<p>R is 16. She has a newborn. She is one of several girls in a building filled with child <strong>brides</strong> who now have their own children. You can hear the babies crying.</p>
<p>She said life as a refugee in Bangladesh was difficult. But, as one of 11 children in her family, she was never lonely there. She had no one in Malaysia except her husband. She would be alone all day while he was at work.</p>
<p>R gave birth recently. "When I saw my baby's face, I was happy, because now I have a friend," she told the <em>AP</em>.</p>
<p>However, being a mother is not easy. She said she does not know how to be a mother.</p>
<p>"I miss my mom," she said. "I want my parents."</p>
<p>S is pregnant and homeless. Her Malaysian husband forced her to leave when he found out she was pregnant. Without a job, S walks the streets of Kuala Lumpur asking strangers for money.</p>
<p>"I once dreamed of having a happy family," S says. "I don't dream much anymore."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bride </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for the female in a traditional marriage</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Finds Material that Could Support Possible Life on Saturn’s Moon  (2023/12/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/nasa-finds-material-that-could-support-possible-life-on-saturn-s-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>NASA has discovered new evidence that Saturn's moon Enceladus holds material that is important to the early development of life.</p>
<p>The American space agency said the new evidence came from observations made by its Cassini spacecraft. Cassini spent seven years observing seasonal changes around Saturn. During that time, the spacecraft also collected data on Saturn's moons.</p>
<p>Two of Cassini's discoveries involved Saturn's moons Titan and Enceladus. In its observations of Titan, the spacecraft studied the moon's climate activity and recorded data on rivers, lakes and oceans. Cassini also found evidence of several Earth-like qualities of Titan that could support life.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Water from the subsurface ocean of Saturn's moon Enceladus sprays from huge fissures out into space. (Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5839-08dc024b6fe1_cx6_cy8_cw87_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Water from the subsurface ocean of Saturn's moon Enceladus sprays from huge fissures out into space. (Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute)</span></div>
<p>Another Cassini discovery involved the observation of hydrogen molecules in ice particles and <strong>vapor</strong> shooting upward from the moon's surface. Researchers announced that finding in 2017, the same year Cassini officially ended its <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>In announcing that discovery, NASA scientists said the presence of hydrogen molecules could signal deep-sea chemical reactions between water and rock that could create microbial life.</p>
<p>Now, the space agency is sharing a new finding that supports the earlier discoveries. Scientists examining Cassini data said they identified "strong confirmation" of the presence of another molecule seen as important for enabling life.</p>
<p>Evidence of the molecule – hydrogen cyanide – was found in data relating to the same shooting flows of ice and water vapor observed by Cassini on Enceladus.</p>
<p>The team used data collected by an instrument aboard Cassini designed to measure the activity of gas, ions and ice particles around Saturn. The discovery process involved a lot of mathematics aiming to understand the newly examined data.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>The new evidence is described <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-023-02160-0.epdf?sharing_token=9f1fFhF9x9DTwwV3Z4KYPtRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0O62obxNW8k7GDHtvLUshnFEHPyLmkRC9CrS4VWCC4iWzGprsnt-SNu6EBvPgXNhKu_g09avF1rQpc6EgUqbrTYGqv1r68pzsZqFESsPMU6Dvgyq4KlXUNeNP_gtWiJyoM%3D">in a study</a> in <em>Nature Astronomy</em> by scientists from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in California.</p>
<p>The lead writer of the study, Jonah Peter, is currently a doctoral student at Harvard University. He called the discovery of hydrogen cyanide "particularly exciting," saying the molecule is "the starting point for most theories on the <strong>origin</strong> of life."</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-study-finds-life-sparking-energy-source-and-molecule-at-enceladus">said in a statement</a> that for life to exist in space, there must be collections of the right building blocks. One of the most important of these is amino acids. "Hydrogen cyanide is one of the most important and <strong>versatile</strong> molecules needed to form amino acids," NASA noted.</p>
<p>The researchers said hydrogen cyanide molecules can join together in many different combinations. They can also serve as a "<strong>precursor</strong>" for different kinds of amino acids.</p>
<p>In addition, the latest examination of Cassini data suggested the underground ocean on Enceladus "holds a powerful source of chemical energy." The ocean sits beneath the moon's icy surface.</p>
<p>"Unidentified until now, the energy source is in the form of several organic compounds, some of which, on Earth, serve as fuel for organisms," NASA said.</p>
<p>Astronomers involved in the research said that the discovery provides fresh evidence that there may be more chemical energy inside Enceladus than previously thought. The more energy that is available, the team said, the more likely it is that life can form and survive.</p>
<p>"Not only does Enceladus seem to meet the basic requirements for <strong>habitability</strong>," said JPL's Jonah Peter, "we now have an idea about how complex biomolecules could form there, and what sort of chemical pathways might be involved."</p>
<p>The search for possible life on Titan will continue when NASA launches its Dragonfly exploratory mission in 2026. Dragonfly is a drone, or pilotless aircraft. The vehicle is designed to capture images and also land on Titan to collect data.</p>
<p>Tom Nordheim is a planetary scientist at JPL who helped lead the research. He noted that although NASA purposely sent the spacecraft crashing into Saturn's atmosphere to end its service, Cassini is still proving to be a valuable research tool.</p>
<p>"Our study demonstrates that while Cassini's mission has ended, its observations continue to provide us with new <strong>insights</strong> about Saturn and its moons..." Nordheim said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and Nature. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vapor </strong><em>– n. </em>many small drops of liquid that form in the air</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>an important job or task, often involving travel to somewhere</p>
<p><strong>ion </strong><em>– n. </em>an atom or small group of atoms that has an electrical charge because it has added or lost electrons</p>
<p><strong>origin </strong><em>– n. </em>where something begins or comes from</p>
<p><strong>versatile </strong><em>– adj. </em>using for doing a lot of different things</p>
<p><strong>precursor </strong><em>– n. </em>something that happens or exists before something else and influences its development</p>
<p><strong>insight </strong><em>– n. </em>a thing that helps someone gain a deeper understanding of something</p>
<p><strong>habitability </strong>–n. able to support living in or on</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Suggests Obesity Increasing Among US Children  (2023/12/25) | 研究表明美国儿童肥胖率增长</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/study-suggests-obesity-increasing-among-us-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A new study adds to evidence that obesity is becoming more common in young children in America.<br/>
一项新的研究进一步证明，肥胖在美国幼儿中变得越来越普遍。</p>
<p>The study appeared in the medical publication Pediatrics.<br/>
这项研究发表在医学期刊《儿科学》上。</p>
<p>The findings are similar to other national data, which suggests around 2.5 percent of all preschool-aged children were severely obese during the same period.<br/>
这一发现与其他国家数据相似，这些数据表明，在同一时期，约2.5%的学龄前儿童严重肥胖。</p>
<p>One of the study's writers, Heidi Blanck of the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, said "We were doing well and now we see this upward trend....We are dismayed at seeing these findings."<br/>
该研究的作者之一，美国疾病控制和预防中心的海蒂·布兰克说：“我们做得很好，现在我们看到了这种上升趋势……我们对这些发现感到沮丧。”</p>
<p>Dismayed is a term that means very worried or disappointed.<br/>
Dismayed是一个术语，意思是非常担心或失望。</p>
<p>The study looked at children ages 2 to 4 who took part in the Women, Infants and Children (WIC) program. The program gives healthy foods and other services to preschool-aged children in low-income families. The children were weighed and measured.<br/>
这项研究观察了2至4岁参加妇女、婴儿和儿童（WIC）项目的儿童。该计划为低收入家庭的学龄前儿童提供健康食品和其他服务。孩子们测量了体重和身高。</p>
<p>The researchers found that 2.1 percent of kids in the program were severely obese in 2010. Six years later, the rate had dropped to 1.8 percent. But by 2020, it was 2 percent. That amounts to about 33,000 of more than 1.6 million kids in the WIC program.<br/>
研究人员发现，2010年，该项目中有2.1%的儿童严重肥胖。六年后，这一比例降至1.8%。但到2020年，这一比例为2%。这相当于参与WIC项目的160多万儿童中的约3.3万人。</p>
<p>The study showed major increases in 20 states. California's was the highest at 2.8 percent. There also were large increases in some racial and ethnic groups. The highest rate, about 2.8 percent, was among Hispanic children.<br/>
这项研究显示，有20个州的严重肥胖比例大幅增加。加利福尼亚州的比例最高，为2.8%。一些种族和族裔群体的严重肥胖比例也大幅增加。西班牙裔儿童的比例最高，约为2.8%。</p>
<p>Experts say severe obesity at a very early age is nearly irreversible – meaning the damage is nearly impossible to undo.<br/>
专家表示，年幼时期的严重肥胖几乎是不可逆转的，这意味着这种损害几乎不可能消除。</p>
<p>Severe obesity is strongly linked with health problems and an early death.<br/>
严重肥胖与健康问题和过早死亡密切相关。</p>
<p>It is not clear why the increase occurred, Blanck said.<br/>
布兰克说，目前还不清楚为什么会出现这种增长。</p>
<p>When WIC obesity rates dropped, some experts suggested 2009 policy changes might be responsible. Those changes took out juice from infant food packages, provided less saturated fat, and tried to make it easier for people to buy fruits and vegetables.<br/>
当WIC肥胖率下降时，一些专家认为原因可能是2009年的政策改革。这些改革消除了婴儿食品包中的果汁，减少了饱和脂肪，并试图让人们更容易购买水果和蔬菜。</p>
<p>The package has not changed. But "the daily hardships that families living in poverty are facing may be harder today than they were 10 years ago, and the slight increases in the WIC package just weren't enough," said Dr. Sarah Armstrong, a Duke University childhood obesity researcher.<br/>
这些食品包没有改变。但是，杜克大学儿童肥胖研究人员萨拉·阿姆斯特朗博士说：“如今生活在贫困中的家庭每天面临的困苦可能比10年前更严重，而WIC项目食品包的小幅增加还不够。”</p>
<p>The researchers faced difficulties. The number of kids in WIC declined in the past ten years. And the study included 2020, the year the COVID-19 pandemic hit. At the time, fewer parents brought their children in to see doctors. That reduced the amount of complete information available.<br/>
研究人员面临困难。在过去的十年里，WIC项目的孩子数量有所下降。这项研究包括新冠肺炎大流行的2020年。当时，带孩子来看病的父母越来越少。这减少了可用的完整信息量。</p>
<p>Despite its limitations, it was a "very well done study," said Deanna Hoelscher, a childhood obesity researcher at the UTHealth Houston School of Public Health. She added, "It gives you a hint of what's going on."<br/>
休斯顿公共卫生学院健康科学中心的儿童肥胖研究员迪安娜·霍尔舍说，尽管有局限性，但这是一项“做得很好的研究”。她补充道，“这提示了现状。”</p>
<p>What has happened since 2020 is not yet known. Some small studies have suggested an increase in childhood obesity — especially during the pandemic. During the pandemic, kids were kept home from schools. Their eating and bedtime schedules were changed and physical activity decreased.<br/>
自2020年以来发生了什么还不得而知。一些小型研究表明，儿童肥胖率有所上升，尤其是在疫情期间。疫情期间孩子们被关在家里不上学。他们的饮食和就寝时间发生了改变，体育锻炼也有所减少。</p>
<p>"We are thinking it's going to get worse," Hoelscher said.<br/>
“我们认为情况会变得更糟，”霍尔舍说。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我叫约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ukraine's Army Struggles with Mental Effects of Combat  (2023/12/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/ukraine-s-army-struggles-with-mental-effects-of-combat.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mental health expert Oleh Hukovskyi recently stood in a temporary classroom in eastern Ukraine speaking to a group of soldiers. They were attending a class on how to deal with the <strong>stress </strong>of war.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi is one of hundreds of professionals and volunteers across Ukraine treating soldiers for mental health problems. It is a growing issue for an army facing <strong>fatigue</strong> as soldiers fight a larger enemy.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency spoke to 13 people involved in supporting troops and four soldiers undergoing treatment. The treatment can last for a few days to several weeks in more serious cases. It also includes soldiers who have lost arms or legs and who are learning to live with their injuries.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Serhii Rostikov, (R) head of a unit for combat stress control of the 21st Separate Mechanized Brigade, speaks with a soldier, Nov. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Sofiia Gatilova)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-98da-08dc01aad0f0_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Serhii Rostikov, (R) head of a unit for combat stress control of the 21st Separate Mechanized Brigade, speaks with a soldier, Nov. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Sofiia Gatilova)</span></div>
<p>Soldiers spoke of stress, <strong>anxiety</strong>, fear, guilt and being extremely tired. But they also spoke of friendship, a sense of <strong>obligation</strong> to hurry back to their units and a strong desire to repel the enemy.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi is one of the soldiers Reuters spoke to. He is a former <strong>psychiatrist</strong>. He joined the armed forces about six months after Russia launched an invasion in February 2022.</p>
<p>Now, he runs a mental health support group attached to the 67th Separate Mechanized Brigade. The brigade is in the area of Lyman, a town heavily damaged by the war.</p>
<p>"They have obligations and have to return to the front line," Hukovskyi said of the troops.</p>
<p>Some of the soldiers are being treated for light wounds and battle stress at a medical aid center.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi said Ukrainian soldiers were not given enough breaks from fighting.</p>
<p>"Forty-five days is a <strong>critical</strong> period when soldiers can stay and...have a chance to stay mentally healthy," he said. He added that in some situations they might remain in battle longer. When that happens, they experience more head injuries and more battle fatigue.</p>
<p><strong>Citizen soldiers</strong></p>
<p>Many of those fighting joined as volunteers. They had little, if any, preparation for sometimes fierce combat conditions.</p>
<p>The soldiers attending the class answer questions and suggestions. However, Hukovskyi knows there are limitations. Soon, the soldiers will have to return to fighting.</p>
<p>"Ukraine has an army of <strong>mobilized</strong> citizens who just yesterday were teachers, artists, poets, IT specialists, or workers," said Dana Vynohradova. He is deputy brigade commander for mental health support.</p>
<p><strong>Nightmares and fear</strong></p>
<p>"DJ" attended Hukovskyi's class last month. Before the war, he was a factory worker from central Ukraine. Like most other soldiers, he goes by his <strong>call sign</strong>, DJ.</p>
<p>"I have <strong>nightmares</strong> and they <strong>exhaust</strong> me. When I get some time to rest, I don't sleep at all," DJ told the group. Later, the 50-year-old explained that he was not prepared for the fierce combat.</p>
<p>DJ said his position near the front line was under continuous attack by Russian forces. Like others, he said he suffers from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and a <strong>concussion</strong>.</p>
<p>On a rainy November day in a nearby village, Dmytro, a 24-year-old soldier, talks with his unit's stress control group leader. He is a man named Serhii Rostikov. The Russians occupied the village in 2022. The two men walk and talk among damaged houses.</p>
<p>Rostikov said soldiers decide for themselves whether to seek mental health support. However, other specialists said unit commanders could make recommendations if they see signs for concern.</p>
<p>"After the artillery shelling, I developed a fear of going back to (combat) positions," said Dmytro. He is with the 21<sup>st</sup> Separate Mechanized Brigade.</p>
<p>He told Reuters that he reached out to his former group leader Rostikov for help. After working together, Rostikov sent Dmytro to <strong>rehabilitation</strong>. Dmytro said, "...I have no fear now and can easily go back to a combat position. I think we need <strong>psychologists</strong>, because soldiers suffer from a lot of stress."</p>
<p>Many soldiers who seek psychological support return to battle after short breaks. Some more serious cases are sent away from the front for more treatment.</p>
<p>DJ later said he had been kept away from combat for further treatment. Dmytro has rejoined his unit.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian military has tried to recruit more people for psychological support.</p>
<p>Ukraine's armed forces declined to answer questions about efforts to get support workers. It also did not release how many soldiers had been treated for psychological conditions since the start of the invasion. Such details are often treated as military secrets.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Mario Ritter.</p>
<p><em>Charlotte Bruneau reported this story for Reuters with additional reporting by Sofiia Gatilova and Stefaniia. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stress </strong>–n. a state of mental tension</p>
<p><strong>fatigue </strong>–n. a condition of being very tired</p>
<p><strong>anxiety </strong>–n. fear or worry about something</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong>–n. the feeling of having a responsibility to do something</p>
<p><strong>psychiatrist</strong> –n. a medical doctor who deals with mental health</p>
<p><strong>critical </strong>–adj. very important</p>
<p><strong>mobilize </strong>–v. (military) to organize and use people and resources for war</p>
<p><strong>call sign </strong>–n. a set of letters or numbers that is used to identify a person on radio or for special purposes</p>
<p><strong>nightmare </strong>–n. a frightening dream</p>
<p><strong>concussion </strong>–n. an injury that results from a blow to the head</p>
<p><strong>rehabilitation </strong>–n. treatment for an injury that is physical or mental that aims to return the patient back to normal life</p>
<p><strong>psychologist </strong>–n. a health worker who deals with mental health but is not a doctor and cannot order the use of medication</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit from St. Nicholas'  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-visit-from-st-nicholas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>
In 1822, an American professor named Clement Clarke Moore wrote a poem that redefined the image of Saint Nicholas. It was called "Account of a Visit from Saint Nicholas." He did not expect it to be published. He wrote it as a Christmas present for his young children. In recent years, experts have questioned whether Moore actually wrote the poem.</p>
<p>Some believe it was written by Henry Livingston, a map maker in New York who wrote and published funny poems in his spare time.</p>
<p>But whoever wrote this classic poem, it has since become a favorite around the world. This poem combines the traditions of Santa Claus, seasonal decorations and gift-giving that have come to define Christmas in America.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit From St. Nicholas'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9BC4B48F-8C2D-4097-B73E-B411786E115D_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit From St. Nicholas'</span></div>
<p>We give you the staff of Learning English reading Clement Clarke Moore's poem, popularly known as "'Twas the Night Before Christmas."</p>
<p>
<em>‘Twas the night before Christmas, when all through the house<br/>
Not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.<br/>
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care,<br/>
In hopes that Saint Nicholas soon would be there.</em></p>
<p><em>The children were nestled all snug in their beds,<br/>
While visions of sugar plums danced in their heads.<br/>
And mamma in her ‘kerchief, and I in my cap,<br/>
Had just settled our brains for a long winter's nap.</em></p>
<p><em>When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter,<br/>
I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.<br/>
Away to the window I flew like a flash,<br/>
Tore open the shutters and threw up the sash.</em></p>
<p><em>The moon on the breast of the new-fallen snow<br/>
Gave lustre of mid-day to objects below.<br/>
When, what to my wondering eyes did appear,<br/>
But a miniature sleigh, and eight tiny reindeer.</em></p>
<p><em>With a little old driver, so lively and quick,<br/>
I knew in a moment it must be Saint Nick.<br/>
More rapid than eagles his coursers they came,<br/>
And he whistled, and shouted, and called them by name!</em></p>
<p><em>"Now Dasher! Now, Dancer! Now, Prancer and Vixen!<br/>
On, Comet! On, Cupid! On Donder and Blitzen!<br/>
To the top of the porch! To the top of the wall!<br/>
Now dash away! Dash away! Dash away all!"</em></p>
<p><em>As dry leaves that before the wild hurricane fly,<br/>
When they meet with an obstacle, mount to the sky.<br/>
So up to the house-top the coursers they flew,<br/>
With the sleigh full of toys, and Saint Nicholas, too.</em></p>
<p><em>And then, in a twinkling, I heard on the roof<br/>
The prancing and pawing of each little hoof.<br/>
As I drew in my head, and was turning around,<br/>
Down the chimney Saint Nicholas came with a bound.</em></p>
<p><em>He was dressed all in fur, from his head to his foot,<br/>
And his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and soot.<br/>
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back,<br/>
And he looked like a peddler, just opening his pack.</em></p>
<p><em>His eyes -- how they twinkled! His dimples how merry!<br/>
His cheeks were like roses, his nose like a cherry!<br/>
His droll little mouth was drawn up like a bow,<br/>
And the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.</em></p>
<p><em>The stump of a pipe he held tight in his teeth,<br/>
And the smoke it encircled his head like a wreath.<br/>
He had a broad face and a little round belly,<br/>
That shook when he laughed, like a bowlful of jelly!<br/>
He was chubby and plump, a right jolly old elf,<br/>
And I laughed when I saw him, in spite of myself!<br/>
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head,<br/>
Soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.</em></p>
<p><em>He spoke not a word, and went straight to his work,<br/>
Filled all the stockings, then turned with a jerk.<br/>
And laying his finger aside of his nose,<br/>
And giving a nod, up the chimney he rose!</em></p>
<p><em>He sprang to his sleigh, to his team gave a whistle,<br/>
And away they all flew like the down of a thistle.<br/>
But I heard him exclaim, ‘ere he drove out of sight,<br/>
"Happy Christmas to all, and to all a good-night!"</em></p>
<p><em>Dorothy Gundy produced the video.</em></p>
<p><em>Do you have a favorite holiday poem? Tell us about it in the comments section.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Tis the Season!  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/tis-the-season.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about the word "season." We use this word in many different ways.</p>
<p>"Season" can <strong>refer to </strong>one of the four parts of the year. For example, Washington, D.C. is in a part of the United States that has four seasons: winter, spring, summer, and autumn. Some parts of the U.S. do not have four seasons.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A diver dressed as Santa Claus performs amongst fish during a Christmas-themed underwater show at an aquarium in Seoul, South Korea on December 4, 2019. (Photo by Jung Yeon-je / AFP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/A98A677E-54CF-4C5F-867A-156CD807A4D4_cx6_cy0_cw91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A diver dressed as Santa Claus performs amongst fish during a Christmas-themed underwater show at an aquarium in Seoul, South Korea on December 4, 2019. (Photo by Jung Yeon-je / AFP)
</span></div>
<p>"Season" can also describe the periods marked by warmth and growth or cold weather and falling leaves. For example, when the weather becomes warmer and days are lighter longer, the growing season begins for some plants. When the weather gets colder and the days darker, the <strong>hibernation</strong> season begins for some animals.</p>
<p>We also use "season" to describe periods that are only related to the weather. For example, some areas of the world have <u>rainy seasons</u> and <u>dry seasons</u>. Some parts of the U.S. have <u>tornado season</u>. And in other parts of the world there are <u>monsoon seasons</u>.</p>
<p>"Season" can also refer to the time before and during a major holiday. December is a busy <u>holiday season</u> in many parts of the world. Holidays include Christmas, Hanukkah, Kwanzaa, the Feast of Our Lady of Guadalupe and the Winter Solstice. December is often a time to take a break from work and spend time with loved ones.</p>
<p>Speaking of Christmas, when we say <u>‘tis the season</u> we are talking about something dealing with this holiday – its good side and its not-so-good side. For example, let's say I give a co-worker a big box of homemade cookies. They might say to me, "Thanks! But why are you giving me so many cookies?" I can answer, "'Tis the season!"</p>
<p>Here is another example. If I go out to a store and it is packed with holiday shoppers, I could <strong>complain</strong> to a friend. And they could respond, "Well, ‘tis the season!" What they <em>really </em>mean is this: At this time of the year, stores are usually very busy with Christmas shoppers.</p>
<p>In fact, Christmas is like <u>open season</u> on shopping deals. "Open season on" something means that it is being hunted, targeted, or in this case ... bought.</p>
<p>"Open season" also describes a period of time when a particular activity or opportunity is unrestricted. It is widely available. This term probably comes from hunting. Hunting traditionally has many restrictions. People can hunt only at certain times of the year and even then, there are restrictions on which animals and how many you can hunt. Fishing too has similar restrictions. But if it is open season, there are few restrictions.</p>
<p>As in our earlier shopping example, we can use this term for just about anything that is targeted with few restrictions. When talking about the best times to travel, for example, it is a good idea to travel <u>off-season</u>. If few people are traveling, it is a good time to find <strong>cheap</strong> air travel, hotels, and <strong>rental</strong> cars. It is open season on travel deals.</p>
<p>And like <u>hunting season</u>, we can have other "seasons" too. For example, beach areas are popular during <u>tourist season</u>. And people with <strong>allergies</strong> probably do not like <u>hay fever season</u> or <u>allergy season</u>.</p>
<p>So, "season" can simply mean a time of the year marked by a special activity. Sports seasons, for example, are popular with fans of sports.</p>
<p>We also have different seasons in our lives: Our time as children, going off to college, becoming parents, helping our aging parents, starting new careers or starting retirement. These are all different seasons of life. And they all have different <strong>aspects</strong> to enjoy and to be thankful for.</p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>refer </strong><strong>to </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to talks about or describe</p>
<p><strong>hibernate </strong><em>–v. </em>to pass winter in a resting state : <strong>hibernation</strong><strong> </strong>–n.</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong><em>–v.</em> to say that you are unhappy with something</p>
<p><strong>cheap </strong><em>–adj.</em> not costly; low cost</p>
<p><strong>rental </strong><em>–adj.</em> something you have paid for the temporary use of</p>
<p><strong>allergy </strong>–n. a condition of being especially sensitive to things like pollen, mold or foods which can make a person suffering from it feel sick</p>
<p><strong>career </strong>–n. the period of working and doing a job in one's life, especially within one field or profession</p>
<p><strong>aspect </strong>–n. a part of something</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you have similar expressions in your language? Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>George W. Bush: Wartime President  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-george-w-bush.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about George Walker Bush. He took office in 2001 as the 43rd president.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - George W. Bush" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/39fec087-a03f-4396-8a32-cdca08f06a08_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - George W. Bush</span></div>
<p>He has a similar name to another president -- his father, George Herbert Walker Bush.</p>
<p>To simplify things, Americans sometimes call the younger Bush "43," or simply "W." Here we will just call him Bush.</p>
<p>Because Bush is a recent president, historians have not reached a broad agreement on his time as a leader.</p>
<p>But he will surely be remembered for facing one of the biggest challenges to any president: the attacks against the U.S. on September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>George Bush was born in the northeast state of Connecticut. But his parents soon moved to the southwest state of Texas. George grew up there and considered Texas home.</p>
<p>The Bush family had a long background in politics. Bush's grandfather was a senator. His father held many public offices. In some ways, George was prepared for a career in politics, too.</p>
<p>He went to the same private <strong>boarding school</strong> as his father. Then, like his father and grandfather, George went to Yale for college. He also worked on several political campaigns. But he said he did not consider pursuing politics.</p>
<p>Instead, he earned a degree in business at Harvard and took a job in an oil company in Texas. In time, he founded his own oil business.</p>
<p>And he married <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/about-the-white-house/first-ladies/laura-welch-bush/">Laura Welch</a>, who was a teacher and librarian in their hometown. They had <strong>twin </strong>daughters named Barbara and Jenna.</p>
<p>In these years as a young adult, Bush began to make some changes. He began attending a Christian church regularly. He decided to stop drinking alcohol because it was creating problems in his personal life. And he turned his attention to politics.</p>
<p>Bush lost the first election in which he competed, a race to become a member of Congress. So, for a while, he focused on business investments and helping his father's political career.</p>
<p>But in 1992, his father lost re-election to the presidency. And the younger Bush saw a chance to enter politics himself again. In 1994, Bush ran for governor of Texas. To many people's surprise, he won.</p>
<p>Four years later, he was overwhelmingly re-elected. Many voters liked his image as, what he called, a "<strong>compassionate</strong> conservative." In other words, he wanted to use traditional Republican ideas about government to help society.</p>
<p>Following two successful terms as governor, Bush turned his attention to the presidency. In 2000, he competed against the vice president at the time, Al Gore. The winner was not announced until more than a month following the election – usually, the winner is announced within hours.</p>
<p>Both sides disputed the process of counting votes in the state of Florida. Finally, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled on the process. The Court ordered state officials to stop re-counting votes. Bush's lead stood.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>Bush entered office expecting to bring many of the ideas he pursued in Texas to the entire nation. For example, as president he permitted religious groups to receive government funding, and set national standards for public schools.</p>
<p>These moves were popular with many voters. But they also challenged some American traditions: the separation of church and state, and the ability of public schools to govern themselves.</p>
<p>For many presidents, these policies might have created a <strong>legacy</strong>. But early in Bush's term, he faced a crisis that defined much of his time in office.</p>
<p>Hijackers linked to the al-Qaeda group seized four airplanes on September 11, 2001. They purposely crashed two planes into the twin towers of the World Trade Center in New York City, eventually killing more than 2,700 people.</p>
<p>Another plane was flown into the Pentagon, the country's military headquarters outside of Washington, DC. About 200 people died there.</p>
<p>The fourth plane was aimed at another important target. But passengers fought the hijackers. The plane lost control and crashed in a field in Pennsylvania. All 44 people on board died there.</p>
<p>President Bush was visiting an elementary school in Florida that morning. He learned about the attacks while he was reading with the children.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, Bush spoke to the nation. He said the U.S. would answer both the terrorist groups and the countries that permitted terrorist groups to <strong>thrive</strong>.</p>
<p>Over the next years, Bush took a number of actions to create a new national security strategy. They included creating a Department of Homeland Security, making changes to the country's intelligence operations, and reforming the U.S. military.</p>
<p>He also sent U.S. forces into Afghanistan to destroy terrorist networks there. Bush was especially targeting the person who had designed the September 11 terrorist attacks, Osama bin Laden.</p>
<p>The struggle in Afghanistan was successful at first, but continued throughout Bush's time in office. And bin Laden was not captured while Bush was president.</p>
<p>In 2003, Bush opened another front on what some called the "war on terror." He and other government officials said the leader of Iraq, Saddam Hussein, was developing weapons that could kill many people. They said Hussein – and his connections to terrorist groups – threatened Americans and people in other countries.</p>
<p>Hussein did not agree to leave Iraq. So U.S. and British forces launched bombs at targets in the country's capital. Additional troops destroyed what was left of the targets. Hussein was quickly overthrown.</p>
<p>But the weapons of mass destruction were not found.</p>
<p>For the rest of Bush's presidency, U.S. forces remained in Iraq. Bush promised that Americans would stabilize the country and help Iraqis create a democratic government.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>The presidency of George W. Bush is too recent to understand its impact. But there is some evidence of the public's reaction at the time.</p>
<p>Bush received some of the highest ratings of any president. In the weeks following the September 11 attacks, 90 percent approved of his leadership.</p>
<p>He was re-elected in 2004. But his popularity steadily decreased .</p>
<p>At the end of his second term, he had one of the lowest public approval ratings of any president: 33 percent.</p>
<p>The U.S. economy had entered a recession. More Americans disagreed especially with his decision to invade Iraq. And some criticized his government for responding too slowly after Hurricane Katrina struck New Orleans and the country's Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>Since Bush left the White House in 2009, his approval ratings have – like those of many presidents – risen again. He has mostly avoided public appearances. Instead, he has enjoyed playing sports, helping charities, and reading U.S. history.</p>
<p>He also began a new hobby: painting. He has created <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/president-george-bush-portraits-of-courage/3748579.html">portraits</a> of dozens of veterans to honor their service in the military.</p>
<p>
I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this report for Learning English. Hai Do was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>boarding school </strong>- <em>n. </em>a school where students can live during the school term</p>
<p><strong>twin</strong> - <em>adj. </em>used to describe two children who are born to the same mother at the same time<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>compassionate </strong>- <em>adj. </em>feeling or showing concern for someone who is sick, hurt or poor</p>
<p><strong>legacy</strong> - <em>n. </em>something that happened in the past or that comes from someone in the past</p>
<p><strong>thrive</strong> - <em>v. </em>to grow or develop successfully</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South African Company to Make Rings that Protect Against HIV  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/south-african-company-to-make-rings-that-protect-against-hiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A South African company will make <strong>vaginal</strong> devices that protect against HIV. Medical experts say that should at some point make them less costly and more easily available.</p>
<p>HIV is a virus that causes AIDS, a serious disease that affects the body's natural defense system, or immune system.</p>
<p>The Population Council is an international nonprofit that does medical research. It announced recently that the South African healthcare company Kiara Health will start making the devices, or rings, from the medical product silicone in the next few years. It estimates that 1 million could be produced each year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman dances as she listens to music while attending a World AIDS Day commemoration at Nkosi's Haven in Johannesburg on Nov. 30, 2019 on the eve of World AIDS Day. (AP Photo/Denis Farrell, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/435ab65d-af4d-48f0-97c8-061c7a637024_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman dances as she listens to music while attending a World AIDS Day commemoration at Nkosi's Haven in Johannesburg on Nov. 30, 2019 on the eve of World AIDS Day. (AP Photo/Denis Farrell, File)</span></div>
<p>The devices release a drug that helps prevent HIV infections. They are approved by nearly 12 countries and the World Health Organization (WHO).</p>
<p>The nonprofit group owns the rights to the ring, which are now made by a Swedish company. About 500,000 rings are currently available to women in Africa at no cost, bought by donors.</p>
<p>Ben Phillips is a spokesman at the U.N. AIDS agency. He said the ring gives women the freedom to use it without anyone else's knowledge or agreement.</p>
<p>"For women whose partners won't use a condom or <strong>allow</strong> them to take <strong>oral</strong> (preventative HIV) medicines, this gives them another option," he said. A condom is a device worn by a male partner to prevent pregnancy and the spread of sexual diseases.</p>
<p>HIV remains the leading cause of death among women of <strong>reproductive</strong> age in Africa. And 60 percent of new infections are in women, information from WHO shows.</p>
<p>The ring releases the drug dapivirine in small amounts over a month. It currently costs $12 to $16, but experts expect the price to drop once it is widely produced in Africa. Developers are also working on a version that will last up to three months, which should also lower the yearly cost.</p>
<p>WHO has suggested the ring be used as an additional tool for women at high risk of HIV. Officials in more than 12 African countries, including South Africa, Botswana, Malawi, Uganda and Zimbabwe have also approved it.</p>
<p>WHO pointed to two studies in its approval, saying the ring reduced women's chances of getting HIV by about a third. While other research has suggested the risk could be dropped by more than 50 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Cheng reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vagina </strong>– <em>n</em>. the passage in a woman's or female animal's body that leads from the uterus to the outside of the body</p>
<p><strong>allow </strong>– <em>v</em>. to permit (something)</p>
<p><strong>oral </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used to describe a medicine that you eat or swallow</p>
<p><strong>substantial </strong>– <em>adj</em>. large in amount, size, or number</p>
<p><strong>reproductive </strong>– <em>adj</em>. relating to or involved in the production of babies, young animals, or new plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>A History of Christmas in America  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-history-of-chrismas-in-america.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>Today, Steve Ember and Shirley Griffith present a special program on Christmas traditions in the United States during the first half of the 19th century.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Santa Claus drives his reindeer and sleigh float along Central Park West during the Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade, Thursday, Nov. 23, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Jeenah Moon)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d7b8-08dbef5b9edb_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Santa Claus drives his reindeer and sleigh float along Central Park West during the Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade, Thursday, Nov. 23, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Jeenah Moon)
</span></div>
<p>During this period, there was no set way of celebrating the day, which was not yet an official holiday. Communities around the country honored the day in different ways. Some observed Christmas as an important Christian religious day honoring the birth of Jesus. Others celebrated the day with parties, music, drinking and eating. And, some communities did not celebrate the day at all.</p>
<p>But, it was during this period that Americans began to reinvent the holiday. They combined ancient Christmas traditions from different cultures with modern American influences.</p>
<p>Here are Steve Ember and Shirley Griffith.</p>
<p>In 1819, the popular American writer Washington Irving wrote a series of five essays<strong> </strong>published in a book called <em>The Sketchbook of Geoffrey Crayon, Gent</em>.</p>
<p>The essays describe a wealthy British landowner who invites his farm workers into his home to celebrate Christmas. The landowner recreates a traditional Christmas as it would have been celebrated in the distant past. Irving praised this looking back to ancient traditions. He liked the idea of different levels of <strong>society</strong> coming together to enjoy a<strong> festive</strong> and peaceful holiday. Washington Irving seemed to express concern about the lack of such <strong>unifying </strong>Christmas traditions in modern America.</p>
<p><strong>Immigrants shape Christmas traditions</strong></p>
<p>Penne Restad wrote a book <em>Christmas in America: A History</em>. It shows how Americans began to slowly shape Christmas into a unifying national holiday during the first half of the 19th century. She describes how Christmas had different meanings for Americans who came from different cultural and religious backgrounds. Many immigrants brought Christmas traditions from their own countries.</p>
<p>Religion played a big role in how an American might celebrate the holiday. Calvinist Christians banned the celebration of Christmas. But groups such as Episcopalians and Moravians honored the day with religious services and seasonal <strong>decorations</strong>.</p>
<p>By mid-century, Christian groups began to ignore their religious differences over the meaning of Christmas and honored the day in special ways.</p>
<p>Christmas became an important time for families to celebrate at home. More and more Christian Americans also began to follow the European traditions of Christmas trees and giving gifts. Christians believed that the tree represented Jesus and was also a sign of new beginnings. German immigrants brought their tradition of putting lights, sweets and toys on the branches of evergreen trees placed in their homes.</p>
<p>This tradition of setting up a Christmas tree soon spread to many American homes. So did the <strong>practice</strong> of giving people presents. As these traditions increased in popularity, the modern trade and business linked to Christmas also grew.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas as a holiday</strong></p>
<p>As Christmas became more popular, some states declared the day a state holiday. Louisiana was the first state to make the move in 1837. By 1860, 14 other states had followed. It was not until 1870 that President Ulysses Grant made Christmas a federal holiday.</p>
<p>Americans already knew old Christmas songs that came from England and other areas of Europe. But many new American Christmas songs started to become popular. For example, in eighteen forty-nine, a religious leader from Massachusetts wrote the words to <em>It Came Upon a Midnight Clear</em>.The song <em>J</em><em>ingle Bells </em>appeared seven years later. And, a year later, a religious leader in Williamsport, Pennsylvania wrote the song <em>We Three Kings of Orient Are</em>.</p>
<p>And of course, no discussion of Christmas would be complete without talking about of one of the holiday's most famous representations, Santa Claus.</p>
<p>This character is based on the story of Saint Nicholas, a Christian holy person believed to have lived in the third century. Saint Nicholas became known as a protector of children. Different cultures have given him different names. These include Sinterklaas, Kris Kringle and Father Christmas. But for most Americans his most popular name would become Santa Claus.</p>
<p>In the 19th century, many Dutch immigrants living in the United States celebrated the feast of Saint Nicholas on December 6. Saint Nicholas was especially important to New Yorkers because of their history as a Dutch colony. In 1809, Washington Irving published his <em>History of New York</em>. It lists Saint Nicholas as the patron saint of New Yorkers. He describes the saint wearing a low hat, large pants, and smoking a pipe. Does this description sound familiar?</p>
<p><em>Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>society </strong>- <em>n. </em>people in general thought of as living together in organized communities with shared laws, traditions, and values</p>
<p><strong>festive</strong> - <em>adj. </em>cheerful and exciting: suited to a celebration or holiday</p>
<p><strong>unifying</strong> - <em>v. </em> to cause (people or things) to be joined or brought together</p>
<p><strong>decoration </strong>- <em>n. </em>something that is added to something else to make it more attractive</p>
<p><strong>practice </strong>- <em>n. </em>something that is done often or regularly</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Assessment and Evaluation  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/assessment-and-evaluation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the words "assessment" and "evaluation."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>What is difference between Assessment and evaluation?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Assessment &amp; Evaluation" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f32e-08dc0101902a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Assessment &amp; Evaluation</span></div>
<p>Noor</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Noor. This is a good question.</p>
<p>Many people use the terms assessment and evaluation interchangeably. That means they see little or no difference between them in most cases. The terms are related. They both involve performance and education, but they are not the same thing. It is a mistake to use them interchangeably.</p>
<p>Assessment <strong>focuses on</strong> student learning, documenting what students know and what they can do. Assessment has many purposes. They include finding out a student's overall ability, measuring to what <strong>degree</strong> a student has gained control of an identified set of <strong>criteria</strong>, and providing students with information about their strengths and weaknesses. Assessment is a continual process. Its goal is to help students improve.</p>
<p>Here are some sentences using assessment.</p>
<p><em>Teachers should use classroom assessments to inform instruction.</em></p>
<p><em>The students completed a weekly assessment.</em></p>
<p><em>The school uses a variety of assessment tools.</em></p>
<p>Evaluation often focuses on the performance of an organization. Evaluation involves using criteria and evidence to find out if an organization is meeting its goals. Evaluation only happens at set times, and its goal is to judge the quality of an organization. Assessment can be a part of the evaluation process. That is because assessment results are often used to make judgements.</p>
<p>Here are some sentences using evaluation.</p>
<p><em>The class was canceled due to results from the curriculum evaluation.</em></p>
<p><em>The school district completed its special education program evaluation last month.</em></p>
<p><em>The governor focused on the lack of school counseling evaluations.</em></p>
<p>Although assessment and evaluation are both used in education and relate to measuring performance, they have different focuses, purposes, timing, and <strong>outcomes</strong>. The terms are also used a lot in other fields such as finance, medicine and engineering.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Noor.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>focus on</strong>–<em>v</em>. pay attention to</p>
<p><strong>degree</strong> –<em>n</em>. a level which can be measured in some way and compared to other levels</p>
<p><strong>criteria</strong>—<em>n</em>. conditions which must be met</p>
<p><strong>outcome</strong>–<em>n</em>. final product or end result</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Those Who Fear Illness Die Earlier  (2023/12/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/those-who-fear-illness-die-earlier.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A large Swedish study has found an unexpected finding about people diagnosed with extreme fear of serious illness. It found they are more likely to die earlier than people who are not as concerned about their health.</p>
<p>Hypochondriasis, now called illness anxiety disorder, is a rare condition with <strong>symptoms</strong> that go beyond average health concerns. People with the disorder are unable to lose their fears despite normal doctor visits and lab tests. Some may change doctors repeatedly. Others may avoid medical care.</p>
<p>Dr. Jonathan E. Alpert of Montefiore Medical Center in New York said, "Many of us are mild hypochondriacs." But he added there are also people on the extreme side of it who are always worrying and thinking about whether they have a serious illness.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A hospital exam room is seen in Alabama on Thursday, July 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Brynn Anderson, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/889255c8-cb5a-4351-9fb4-3f42b57d27d5_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A hospital exam room is seen in Alabama on Thursday, July 30, 2015. (AP Photo/Brynn Anderson, File)</span></div>
<p>People with the disorder are suffering and "it's important to take it seriously and to treat it," said Alpert, who was not involved in the new study. Treatment can include behavioral <strong>therapy</strong>, calming methods, education, and sometimes mental health medication.</p>
<p>The researchers have found that people with the condition have an increased risk of death from both natural and unnatural causes, including suicide. Continuing<strong> stress</strong> and its effects on the body could explain some of the differences, the writers said. The study was published recently in <em>JAMA Psychiatry</em>.</p>
<p>David Mataix-Cols of the Karolinska Institute in Sweden led the research. "We got lucky," he said, because the Swedish system for organizing disease has a separate entry for hypochondriasis. That permitted research on thousands of people over 24 years, from 1997 to 2020.</p>
<p>Older research had suggested the risk of suicide might be lower for people with the condition. Mataix-Cols said their research found that statement was incorrect. In the study, the risk of suicide death was four times higher for people with the condition.</p>
<p>They looked at 4,100 people with hypochondriasis and <strong>matched</strong> them with 41,000 people similar in age, sex, and where they lived. They used a measurement called person years, which measures the number of people and how long they were followed.</p>
<p>Overall death rates were higher in the people with hypochondriasis, 8.5 instead of 5.5 per 1,000 person years. People with the condition died younger than the others, with a <strong>mean</strong> age of 70 instead of 75. The risk of death from diseases related to body systems, such as breathing and eating, was higher. The risk of death from cancer, however, was about the same.</p>
<p>Alpert leads the American Psychiatric Association's group on research. He said more care is needed when suggesting a patient to mental health professionals. Patients can become angry because they feel they are being accused of imagining symptoms.</p>
<p>Alpert added, "... <strong>fortunately</strong>, there are good treatments."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>symptom </strong>– <em>n</em>. a change in the body or mind which indicates that a disease is present</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong>– <em>n</em>. the treatment of physical or mental illnesses</p>
<p><strong>stress </strong>– <em>n</em>. a state of mental tension and worry caused by problems in your life or work</p>
<p><strong>match </strong>– <em>v</em>. to compare (something) with something else</p>
<p><strong>mean </strong>– <em>n</em>. average</p>
<p><strong>fortunately </strong>– <em>adv</em>. used to say that something good or lucky has happened</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thailand Pushes ‘Land Bridge’ to Speed Trade  (2023/12/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/thailand-pushes-land-bridge-to-speed-trade.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thailand is looking for investment to build a "land bridge" across the narrow southern part of the country. The Southeast Asian nation hopes to provide a shorter path for <strong>cargo</strong> between the Pacific and Indian oceans without having to go through the Malacca Strait and Singapore.</p>
<p>Under the plan, cargo would travel by highway and railroad from the area of Chumpon on the Gulf of Thailand to Ranong on the Indian Ocean to be loaded onto waiting ships.</p>
<p>Thai Prime Minister Srettha Thavisin has been seeking support for the $28-billion project from investors around the world. At the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) gathering in San Francisco, Srettha said the land bridge would connect the oceans "without requiring ships to sail down along the tip of Singapore, known to experience <strong>congestion</strong> and would cut transport <strong>duration</strong>." He called it a "very important project, not just for Thailand, but also for the world."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Thailand is looking for investment to build a land bridge across its southern neck, which would cut cargo transit times. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-63c8-08dc0140a04d_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Thailand is looking for investment to build a "land bridge" across its southern neck, which would cut cargo transit times. </span></div>
<p>Thailand says it is open to interest from all investors. After a meeting with Japanese businesses and leaders, Srettha said there was interest in the project without providing additional information. Thai transport minister Suriya Juangroongruangkit said more than 10 American companies expressed interest without naming them.</p>
<p><strong>China's interest in the area</strong></p>
<p>China, an important trade nation in the area, has not commented on the plan for the land bridge.</p>
<p>For many years, Chinese businesses have been pushing for a deepwater project called the Kra Canal. The canal would cross the Kra Isthmus and would permit large ships to pass. The proposed project would cut at least one day of sailing time from passing through the Malacca Strait.</p>
<p>Former Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha set up a Chinese-supported center to study the canal idea. But it has never started because of the cost and possible environmental damage.</p>
<p>Sompong Putivisutisak, a professor at Chulalongkorn University, has studied the land bridge proposal. Sompong said, "(China) won't give away its position that easily until it sees the other investors."</p>
<p>He told VOA there are two reasons that China would invest in the land bridge project: "First, financial <strong>benefits</strong>, secondly geopolitics. Financially, this project is not worth the investment, but geopolitically it could be interesting as China would have control over both seas."</p>
<p>At a Belt and Road Initiative meeting in Beijing last October, Thai officials said the land bridge could be connected to another high-speed railway under construction from Thailand to Singapore. Srettha even drew a map of the route during a meeting, which he posted online.</p>
<p>But critics say the plan is unlikely to win China's full backing. They say a land bridge would require loading and unloading cargo from ships and would not save any time.</p>
<p>Somboon Kamhang, chairman of the Coordinating Committee on Development, called it "another dreamy project." He told VOA, "China isn't interested in the land bridge project. Building a land bridge is just way too costly and <strong>time-consuming</strong>, but China can get behind the canal idea which could give it more control over the region."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Vijitra Duangdee reported this story for VOA News. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cargo</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>goods that are transported by a vehicle</p>
<p><strong>congestion</strong> <em>–n.</em> the state of being too full or crowed with something</p>
<p><strong>duration </strong><em>–n.</em> the amount of time something lasts</p>
<p><strong>benefits </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> good results from some choice or action</p>
<p><strong>time-consuming </strong><em>–adj.</em> taking a lot of time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>EU Reaches Major Migration Agreement  (2023/12/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/eu-reaches-major-migration-agreement.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The European Union has reached an agreement that sets new rules for controlling migration.</p>
<p>The deal, announced Wednesday, will become part of an EU agreement called the New Pact on Migration and Asylum. <em>The Associated Press </em>reported the document will need to get final EU approval by February and is expected to enter into force by June.</p>
<p>The main purpose of the agreement is to set new rules to ease difficulties facing EU nations as they seek to deal with migrant arrivals. The deal also aims to establish a process for EU nations to more fairly share the duties and costs related to migration.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Federal Police attempt to find a group of migrants who illegally crossed the border from Poland into Germany, while on patrol in a forest near Forst south east of Berlin, Germany, on Oct. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Markus Schreiber, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ad88-08dc02573e69_cx10_cy16_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Federal Police attempt to find a group of migrants who illegally crossed the border from Poland into Germany, while on patrol in a forest near Forst south east of Berlin, Germany, on Oct. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Markus Schreiber, File)</span></div>
<p>The laws cover <strong>screening</strong> policies for when migrants first arrive in the EU. They also provide rules relating to migrants seeking asylum and set guidelines for processing <strong>applications</strong> and dealing with possible migration crises.</p>
<p>"It's truly a historic day," European Parliament President Roberta Metsola told reporters in Brussels after the negotiations. She added that reaching an agreement was important because migration is likely to be a major campaign issue ahead of EU elections in June.</p>
<p>"Let's not underestimate the risk if we had not reached such a deal," Metsola said. She added that she hopes the agreement will persuade EU members not to establish individual borders because the migration flows can now be more effectively dealt with.</p>
<p>Migrant arrivals in the EU are down from a high in 2015 of more than 1 million. Most of those migrants entering Europe were fleeing war in Syria and Iraq. But the flows started to increase in recent years and reached 255,000 so far this year through November, Reuters news agency reported. More than half of these crossed the Mediterranean from Africa, mainly to Italy.</p>
<p>Italian Interior Minister Matteo Piantedosi called the deal a "great success" for Europe and Italy. He said it should help EU border countries most involved with migration feel less alone.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said finding agreement on migration disputes was very important and can help lighten the load for the most affected EU states, including Germany.</p>
<p>Outgoing Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte said he sees the deal improving "control over migration" and providing a better asylum process for migrants to the EU. Far-right lawmaker Geert Wilders aims to replace Rutte after winning the country's elections last month on a campaign that included anti-migration policies.</p>
<p>Under the new system, countries not at the EU border will have to choose between accepting their share of 30,000 asylum applicants or paying nearly 22,000 euros per person to the EU.</p>
<p>The screening system seeks to separate those in need of international protection from others who are not.</p>
<p>People whose asylum applications have a low chance of approval – such as those from India, Tunisia or Turkey – can be prevented from entering the EU and detained at the border. People seen as representing a threat to security can also be held at the border. The agreement also sets policies for speeding up the processing of applications.</p>
<p>While praised by many European leaders, the agreement also received criticism from groups seeking to assist migrants.</p>
<p>The European Council on Refugees and Exiles – a migrant rights organization – condemned the proposed rules on X, formerly Twitter. The group said the policies were "Byzantine in their complexity and Orban-esque in their cruelty." The message was commenting on Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, who ordered the building of security fences to keep migrants out of the country.</p>
<p>Rights group Amnesty International said it sees the deal setting EU asylum law back many years and leading to greater suffering for people seeking asylum. It also said the agreement is likely to cause more people "to be put into <strong>de facto</strong> detention" at the EU's borders, including families with children and other "<strong>vulnerable</strong>" individuals.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>screen </strong><em>– v. </em>to find out information about someone in order to decide whether they are suitable for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>– n. </em>an official and usually written request for something</p>
<p><strong>de facto </strong><em>– adj. </em>existing in fact, although perhaps not intended or officially accepted<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>– adj. </em>easy to hurt or attack physically or emotionally</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar, Language in 'Take Me Home, Country Roads'  (2023/12/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/grammar-and-figurative-language-in-take-me-home-country-roads.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many Americans will travel over the winter holidays, often to return to the homes and towns of their childhood. For people from the state of West Virginia, and wider <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/discover-americas-appalachian-trial/2766408.html">Appalachia</a>, one song comes to mind on the trip home: <em>Take Me Home, Country Roads</em>.<em> </em>Singer John Denver co-wrote and performed the 1971 song. It became a major hit.</p>
<p>Recently, my favorite singer, Lana Del Rey, recorded her version of the song after performing in West Virginia in October.</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will look at parts of the song performed by Del Rey and connect it to grammar and <strong>figurative</strong> language.<strong> </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Grammar and Figurative Language in " country="" home="" me="" roads="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d776-08dc01aef575_w268_r1.png" take=""/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Grammar and Figurative Language in "Take Me Home, Country Roads" </span></div>
<p>Let's look at the first <strong>verse</strong> of the song.</p>
<p><strong>Metaphors, appositives, and comparative adjectives</strong></p>
<p><em>Almost Heaven, West Virginia</em></p>
<p><em>Blue Ridge Mountains, Shenandoah River</em></p>
<p><em>Life is old there, older than the trees</em></p>
<p><em>Younger than the mountains, growing like a <strong>breeze</strong></em></p>
<p>In the first verse we have a couple of comparisons. One comparison uses an appositive as <strong>metaphor</strong>. The others use comparative adjectives and even a <strong>simile</strong>.</p>
<p>Appositives are nouns or noun phrases that go beside another noun to describe it. Sometimes we can use the appositive structure to create a metaphor.</p>
<p>"Almost Heaven, West Virginia" is a metaphor using an appositive. Here, our subject is "West Virginia" and the appositive is "Almost Heaven." The appositive is giving more information about "West Virginia." The comma takes the place of the typical verb used to make metaphors, "be."</p>
<p><em>West Virginia is almost Heaven.</em></p>
<p><em>Almost Heaven, West Virginia</em></p>
<p>"Heaven" is a perfect place. Many cultures and traditions uphold it as a beautiful, holy place people go when they die.</p>
<p>So, if West Virginia is "almost heaven," its natural landscape of mountains and rivers and trees must be a holy place of beauty.</p>
<p>Next, we have a comparison of "life" in West Virginia. It is "older than the trees" and "younger than the mountains." "Older" and "younger" are comparative adjectives.</p>
<p>Comparative adjectives compare one thing to another. They help express whether something has more or less of a <strong>particular </strong>quality.</p>
<p>The song suggests the ancient history of the land. Scientists say the mountains began to develop about a billion years ago. Life began sometime after that but before the growth of trees, the song goes.</p>
<p>And the mountains and life continue into the future, the song then suggests. The writers used the simile, "growing like a breeze," to express this idea.</p>
<p>A simile is a figure of speech in which unlike things are compared with the use of the words "like" or "as."</p>
<p>Breezes come and go and sometimes grow into a stronger wind. This verse could mean that life and land grow with ease in West Virginia.</p>
<p>Let's move onto the <strong>chorus</strong> of the song.</p>
<p><strong>Imperatives and personification </strong></p>
<p><em>Country roads, take me home</em></p>
<p><em>To the place I belong</em></p>
<p><em>West Virginia, mountain mama</em></p>
<p><em>Take me home, country roads</em></p>
<p>In the chorus of the song, we have an interesting grammatical feature and some figurative language.</p>
<p>We have an imperative structure that is repeated in the beginning and end of the chorus:</p>
<p><em>Country roads, take me home</em></p>
<p><em>Take me home, country roads</em></p>
<p>Imperatives are predicate-only clauses used to give instruction, direction or command. Imperative sentences use the base form of the verb and may have other information.</p>
<p>We know that this song was written about a road trip through the mountains and rural communities. The singer seeks direction from the "country roads," themselves, to find the way home.</p>
<p>We also have more figurative language. The writers refer to West Virginia as "mountain mama." This is an example of personification or the human representation of a non-living thing.</p>
<p>The reference humanizes West Virginia and suggests that it is the mother of mountains. But, it uses the more childlike term, "mama" for mother. The word expresses hominess, warmth and <strong>nostalgia</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today we looked at the beloved song <em>Country Roads</em>. We found figurative language like metaphors using appositives and personification, which is the humanizing of non-living things.</p>
<p>We even found some interesting grammar with the use of comparative adjectives like "younger" and "older" to describe life in West Virginia and imperatives or commands to give direction through the "country roads."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Mateo. And we're both from West Virginia.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>figurative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used with a meaning that is different from the basic meaning</p>
<p><strong>verse</strong> - <em>n. </em>writing in which words are arranged in a rhythmic pattern: poetry or song</p>
<p><strong>breeze </strong><em>– n. </em>a gentle wind</p>
<p><strong>metaphor </strong>– <em>n.</em> a way of describing something by comparing it with something else that has some of the same qualities using the verb "be"</p>
<p><strong>simile</strong> – <em>n</em>. an indirect comparison using "like" or "as"</p>
<p><strong>particular</strong> – <em>adj</em>. used when you want to talk about one thing or a certain kind of thing rather than ones that are similar</p>
<p><strong>chorus </strong><em>– n.</em> part of a song that is repeated; a large organized group of singers</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cat Steals the Show in Video Sent by Laser from Space  (2023/12/21) | 橘猫成为太空激光发送视频主角</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/cat-steals-the-show-in-video-sent-by-laser-from-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>The U.S. space agency says an orange cat named Taters is the star of the first video sent by laser from deep space.<br/>
美国航天局表示，第一段由激光从外太空发送的视频的主角是一只名叫“土豆”的橘猫。</p>
<p>NASA's Psyche spacecraft sent the 15-second video to Earth from 30 million kilometers in space. The video shows Taters as he chases a red laser light.<br/>
美国宇航局的普赛克飞船从3000万公里外的太空向地球发送了这段15秒的视频。视频显示“土豆”在追逐红色激光灯。</p>
<p>It took less than two minutes for the video to reach Caltech's Palomar Observatory. The video quality is called ultra high-definition. It was sent at the test system's maximum rate of 267 megabits per second.<br/>
这段视频传输到加州理工学院的帕洛玛天文台花了不到两分钟时间。这种视频质量被称为超高清。它是以该测试系统每秒267兆的最大速率发送的。</p>
<p>NASA loaded the video into Psyche's laser communication experiment before launching the spacecraft to visit a rare metal asteroid in October. The mission team at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in Pasadena, California, decided to use an employee's three-year-old cat.<br/>
美国宇航局在10月发射普赛克飞船前往一颗稀有金属小行星，在此之前，它将视频加载到了飞船的激光通信实验中。位于加利福尼亚州帕萨迪纳的美国宇航局喷气推进实验室的任务团队决定使用一名员工的三岁猫。</p>
<p>The video was sent to Earth on December 11 and was released by NASA this week. The test sent the video faster than most internet connections here on Earth, said project leader Ryan Rogalin.<br/>
该视频于12月11日发送到地球，并于本周由美国宇航局发布。项目负责人瑞恩·罗加林说，这次实验发送视频的速度比地球上大多数互联网连接的速度都快。</p>
<p>NASA wants to improve communications from deep space as it prepares efforts to send astronauts to the moon and possibly to the planet Mars. The laser test is meant to send data at rates up to 100 times greater than the radio systems currently used by spacecraft far from Earth.<br/>
美国宇航局希望改善深空通信，为将宇航员送上月球和火星做准备。这次激光实验旨在以比目前远离地球的航天器使用的无线电系统高出100倍的速率发送数据。</p>
<p>More tests are planned as Psyche heads towards the main area of asteroids between the planets Mars and Jupiter. But Taters will not be making anymore appearances, JPL said.<br/>
喷气推进实验室表示，随着普赛克飞船前往火星和木星之间小行星的主要区域，计划进行更多实验。但是“土豆”不会再出现了。</p>
<p>Joby Harris is an art director in JPL's DesignLab. He could not be any happier, but he does not want his cat's new public attention to go to his head.<br/>
乔比·哈里斯是喷气推进实验室设计实验室的艺术总监。他再高兴不过了，但他不想让他的猫再次受到公众关注。</p>
<p>"I'm celebrating his spotlight with him but making sure he keeps his paws on the carpet," Harris said in an email Tuesday.<br/>
哈里斯在周二的一封电子邮件中说：“我和它一起庆祝它的露脸时刻，但要确保它把爪子放在地毯上。”</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>2023: A Big Year for Artificial Intelligence  (2023/12/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-big-year-for-artificial-intelligence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) became a popular subject in 2023. Still, the technology has a long way to go to meet people's futuristic expectations of human-like machines.</p>
<p>ChatGPT was central to this year's attention on AI. The <strong>chatbot </strong>showed the world recent developments in computer science, although not everyone understood quite how it works or what to do with it.</p>
<p>AI scientist Fei-Fei Li suggested that 2023 would be remembered for the great changes in technology as well as the public awakening. It was a year for people to figure out "what this is, how to use it, what's the <strong>impact </strong>— all the good, the bad and the ugly," she added.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The OpenAI logo is seen displayed on a cell phone with an image on a computer screen generated by ChatGPT's Dall-E text-to-image model, Friday, Dec. 8, 2023, in Boston. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f72a0d88-4574-457d-9070-4c9e3539ba9b_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The OpenAI logo is seen displayed on a cell phone with an image on a computer screen generated by ChatGPT's Dall-E text-to-image model, Friday, Dec. 8, 2023, in Boston. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer)</span></div>
<p><strong>Concerns over AI</strong></p>
<p>The first AI concerns of 2023 began soon after New Year's Day. That is when classrooms reopened and schools from Seattle to Paris started blocking ChatGPT. Students were already asking the chatbot — released in late 2022 — to write papers and answer take-home tests.</p>
<p>AI large language models behind technology such as ChatGPT work by predicting the next word in a sentence. The models make such predictions after having "learned" the structure of a huge number of human-written works. The large language models often get facts wrong. But the results appeared so natural that it created interest in the next AI developments and possible uses for trickery and <strong>deception</strong>.</p>
<p>Worries grew as this new group of generative AI tools produced not just words but also images, music and voices. They seemed to threaten the jobs of anyone who writes, draws, and creates music and computer languages. Concerns about AI tools fueled strikes by Hollywood writers and actors and legal disputes from artists to writers.</p>
<p>Some of the most respected AI scientists warned that the technology's progress was marching toward outsmarting humans and possibly threatening their existence. Yet other scientists called the warnings overblown and brought attention to more immediate risks.</p>
<p>By spring, AI-created videos known as deepfakes had appeared in U.S. election campaigns. Deepfakes are videos that contain realistic images but with digital changes to people's actions and speech. One deepfake falsely showed Donald Trump <strong>embracing</strong> the nation's former top infectious disease expert. The technology made it increasingly difficult to tell the difference between real and fake videos of the wars in Ukraine and Gaza.</p>
<p>By the end of the year, the AI crisis affected ChatGPT's maker, OpenAI. The San Francisco-based company led by chief executive Sam Altman was nearly destroyed by disagreements over its mission.</p>
<p>AI debates also led to new laws from the European Union and consideration from others, including the United States Congress.</p>
<p><strong>Too much excitement?</strong></p>
<p>AI products released in 2023 have brought technology achievements not possible in earlier times. But the market research company Gartner says they arrive with "inflated expectations" and "massive claims" about its abilities.</p>
<p>Gartner analyst Dave Micko said leading AI developers are pushing the latest technology with their current line of products, including search engines and workplace productivity software.</p>
<p>He said, "As much as Google and Microsoft and Amazon and Apple would love us to adopt the way that they think about their technology and that they deliver that technology, I think adoption actually comes from the bottom up."</p>
<p>It is easy to forget that this is not the first appearance of AI in business. The technology has been used to help guide self-driving cars, compare objects and individual faces, and recognize speech in software like Siri and Alexa.</p>
<p>In 2011, Tom Gruber launched Siri, which was bought and used by Apple in the iPhone. At that time, it was the only major use of AI that people had ever experienced.</p>
<p>But Gruber believes what's happening now is the "biggest wave ever" in AI, launching new possibilities as well as dangers.</p>
<p>The dangers could come fast in 2024. Major national elections in the U.S., India and elsewhere could get flooded with AI-created deepfakes.</p>
<p>In the longer term, AI technology's rapidly improving language, visual sensing and step-by-step planning abilities could create a kind of digital assistant — but only if given access to the "inner loop of our digital life stream," Gruber said.</p>
<p>"They can <strong>manage </strong>your attention as in, ‘You should watch this video. You should read this book. You should <strong>respond</strong> to this person's communication,'" Gruber said. He added, "That is what a real executive assistant does. And we could have that, but with a really big risk of personal information and privacy."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell. And I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Matt O'Brien reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>chatbot</strong> <em>-- n. </em>a computer program designed to converse with people</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>-- n.</em> a powerful or major influence or effect</p>
<p><strong>deception</strong> -<em>- n.</em> the act of making someone believe something that is not true</p>
<p><strong>embrace</strong> <em>-- v.</em> to hold someone in your arms as a way of expressing love or friendship</p>
<p><strong>manage</strong> <em>-- v.</em> to take care of and make decisions about something</p>
<p><strong>respond</strong> <em>- v.</em> to say or write something as an answer to a question or request</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: Myanmar Overtakes Afghanistan as World’s Top Opium Producer  (2023/12/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/un-myanmar-overtakes-afghanistan-as-world-s-top-opium-producer.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A United Nations report finds that Myanmar has <strong>overtaken</strong> Afghanistan as the world's top opium producer.</p>
<p>The change came after Myanmar expanded its opium production for a third year, the U.N. reported. In Afghanistan, production fell sharply in 2023 after the Taliban placed a ban on poppy farming.</p>
<p>The latest data on worldwide opium production was recently released in the U.N.'s report, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.unodc.org/roseap/uploads/documents/Publications/2023/Southeast_Asia_Opium_Survey_2023.pdf">Southeast Asia Opium Survey 2023</a>. The report was released by the U.N.'s Office of Drugs and Crime (UNODC).</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man walks through a flowering opium poppy field in Shan state, Myanmar, 2023. (UNODC)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a70b-08dbfadebb96_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man walks through a flowering opium poppy field in Shan state, Myanmar, 2023. (UNODC)</span></div>
<p>The report estimates opium crops in Afghanistan dropped an estimated 95 percent in 2023 after the Taliban's ban and enforcement efforts.</p>
<p>During the same period, an increasing number of farmers in Myanmar turned to opium as a new crop. The increase in production follows a military takeover of the government in 2021 that pushed the country into a civil war. The situation has severely hurt Myanmar's economy.</p>
<p>The U.N. report estimates poppy growth and processing in Myanmar grew 33 percent in 2022 and another 18 percent this year. That amounts to a total of 47,000 hectares. That is the most land Myanmar has used for opium production since 2013.</p>
<p>Jeremy Douglas is the area representative for the UNODC. He told VOA the country's economic and security situation have severely limited business possibilities and led more people to turn to opium farming to make money.</p>
<p>Most families in Myanmar make their living off the land. But a World Bank report released in May found that nearly half of farming families said they worry about having enough food. That number was up from 26 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>The UNODC estimates Myanmar's farmers grew enough poppy this year to produce up to 1,080 metric tons of dry opium. This amounted to total earnings of up to $2.5 billion. Most of this money is believed to have gone to traffickers shipping the product across Asia and as far as Australia, often as heroin.</p>
<p>Most of that heroin flows through neighboring Thailand on its way to other places. In September, Thai police seized over 440 packs of heroin, along with some 15 million methamphetamine pills. A top Thai law enforcement official told VOA the $8.2 million drug seizure was the largest in the country's history.</p>
<p>The UNODC report notes Afghanistan's reduced opium production is expected to create a worldwide heroin shortage and drive prices higher. This is likely to lead even more farmers in Myanmar to start growing poppies.</p>
<p>Douglas said such a shortage could also result in more heroin processed in the Golden Triangle area making its way beyond the Asia-Pacific to Europe and North America. The Golden Triangle is a heavily criminalized area near the borders of Myanmar, Laos and Thailand. It is known for growing and producing large amounts of drugs.</p>
<p>Afghan heroin started taking over the European and North American markets from the Golden Triangle more than 10 years ago. That change came as drug controllers in Southeast Asia started dealing mostly in methamphetamine.</p>
<p>Douglas told VOA that even as Afghan production falls sharply, there is still large demand for opium on the world market. He said, "It's highly likely that we're going to start seeing Golden Triangle heroin returning to markets that it hasn't been in for quite some years."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Voice of America's Zsombor Peter and the United Nations reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>overtake </strong><em>– v. </em>to catch up with and then pass by someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lacking Counselors, US Schools Turn to Online Therapy  (2023/12/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/lacking-counselors-us-schools-turn-to-online-therapy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Public schools in the United States are increasingly employing online mental health services, or teletherapy, for students.</p>
<p>At least 16 of the 20 largest American public school systems are offering online therapy to reach millions of students, reports the Associated Press. In those systems alone, schools have signed provider contracts worth more than $70 million.</p>
<p>The business model is making so much money that <strong>venture capitalists </strong>are investing in new companies as the market grows. However, some experts have raised concerns about the quality of care offered by fast-growing tech companies.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An employee of Hazel Health displays the opening page of the company's app, Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023 (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fa9b-08dbfb5fa7e5_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An employee of Hazel Health displays the opening page of the company's app, Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023 (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)</span></div>
<p>But educators say teletherapy works for many kids and is meeting a large need. Schools are also experiencing shortages in on-site therapists. Online help has made therapy more easily available to children, especially poorer students and those in rural areas. Schools let students connect with online <strong>counselors</strong> during the school day or after hours from home.</p>
<p>Ishoo is a mother of two in Lancaster, California. She struggled to help her second-grade daughter deal with severe <strong>anxiety</strong>.</p>
<p>Last spring, her school district started a teletherapy program and Ishoo signed up her daughter. During a month of weekly video sessions at her home, the girl opened up to a therapist. The therapist gave the student tools and techniques to reduce anxiety.</p>
<p>"She learned that it's OK to ask for help, and sometimes everyone needs some extra help," Ishoo said.</p>
<p>The 13,000-student school system, like many others, has counselors and psychologists on staff. But it is not enough to meet the need, said Trish Wilson, the Lancaster <strong>supervisor</strong> of counseling.</p>
<p>Therapists in the area have full caseloads, making it impossible to offer students immediate care, she said. Students rarely have to wait long for an online session.</p>
<p>Students and their parents said in interviews they turned to teletherapy after struggling with feelings of sadness, loneliness, stress and anxiety. For many, returning to in-person school after distance learning was very difficult.</p>
<p>Schools are using federal pandemic relief money to pay for help as experts have warned of worrying rates of youth depression, anxiety and suicide. Many school districts are signing contracts with private companies. Others are working with local health care providers, nonprofits or state programs.</p>
<p>Mental health experts welcome the extra support but warn about possible risks. For one, it is getting harder to employ on-site school counselors and psychologists. Competition with telehealth providers is not helping.</p>
<p>"We have 44 counselor <strong>vacancies</strong>, and telehealth definitely <strong>impacts</strong> our ability to fill them," said Doreen Hogans. She is supervisor of school counseling in Prince George's County, Maryland. Hogans estimates 20 percent of school counselors who left have taken teletherapy jobs. The jobs often provide more favorable working hours than the schools.</p>
<p>The quick growth of the companies raises questions about the quality of the therapists, and their experience with children and privacy, said Kevin Dahill-Fuchel. He is executive director of Counseling in Schools, a nonprofit that helps schools improve traditional, in-person mental health services.</p>
<p>One of the biggest providers is San Francisco-based Hazel Health. It started with telemedicine health services in schools in 2016 and expanded to mental health in May 2021, CEO Josh Golomb said. It now employs more than 300 therapists providing teletherapy in over 150 school districts in 15 states.</p>
<p>Other providers are getting into the space. In November, New York City started a free telehealth therapy service for teens to help end barriers to <strong>access</strong>, said Ashwin Vasan, the city's health commissioner. New York is paying the company TalkSpace $26 million over three years for a service permitting teenagers to download an app and connect with therapists.</p>
<p>Unlike other cities, New York is offering the service to all teens, whether attending private, public or home schools, or not in school at all.</p>
<p>"I truly hope this normalizes and democratizes access to mental health care for our young people," Vasan said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>venture capital</strong><em>— n. </em>money that is used to start a new business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>counselor </strong><em>— n. </em> a person who provides advice as a job : a person who counsels people</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>anxiety </strong><em>— n. </em>fear or nervousness about what might happen</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>supervise</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— v. </em>to be in charge of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vacancy </strong><em>— n. </em> a job or position that is available to be taken</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>impact </strong><em>— n. </em>the act or force of one thing hitting another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— n. </em>a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pope Approves Blessings for Same-sex Couples  (2023/12/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/pope-approves-blessings-for-same-sex-couples.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Pope Francis officially approved letting Catholic clergy <strong>bless</strong> same-sex <strong>couples</strong>, the Vatican announced Monday.</p>
<p>The move is a complete change in church policy that aims to make the church more welcoming while continuing its ban on <strong>gay</strong> marriage.</p>
<p>Some have cheered the Vatican statement as a step to break down discrimination in the Catholic Church. But LGBTQ+ supporters say the policy means that the church still considers gay couples as less than heterosexual partners.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Pope Francis leads the Angelus prayer from his window, at the Vatican, Dec. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Guglielmo Mangiapane/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-fce2-08dbffdc46d7_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Pope Francis leads the Angelus prayer from his window, at the Vatican, Dec. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Guglielmo Mangiapane/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>The Vatican document expands on a letter that Francis sent to two conservative cardinals last October. In that letter, Francis suggested such blessings could be offered if they were not seen or mistaken as marriage ceremonies.</p>
<p>The new document repeats that condition and reaffirms that marriage is a lifelong union between a man and a woman. It stresses that the blessings must not be tied to any Catholic celebration or religious service and should not be performed at the same time as a marriage ceremony. Also, the blessings cannot use ceremonial acts, clothing or movements that belong in a wedding.</p>
<p>But it says requests for such blessings for same-sex couples should not be denied. "For, those seeking a blessing should not be required to have <strong>prior</strong> moral perfection," it said.</p>
<p>The document added, "There is no <strong>intention</strong> to <strong>legitimize</strong> anything, but rather to open one's life to God, to ask for his help to live better..."</p>
<p>The Vatican holds that marriage is a union between man and woman. As a result, it has long opposed same-sex marriage and considers homosexual acts to be "disordered." Nothing in the new document changes that teaching.</p>
<p>In the new document, the church says a blessing is about helping people increase their trust in God. "It is a seed of the Holy Spirit that must be nurtured, not hindered," it said.</p>
<p>It stresses that people in "irregular" unions of extramarital sex — gay or straight — are in a state of sin. But that should not keep them from God's love or <strong>mercy</strong>. "Even when a person's relationship with God is clouded by sin, he can always ask for a blessing, stretching out his hand to God," the document said.</p>
<p>The document is the latest attempt by the Pope to welcome gay Catholics. In 2013, he said, "Who am I to judge?" when asked about a gay clergy. Earlier this year, he told The Associated Press that "being homosexual is not a crime."</p>
<p><strong>Reactions to the announcement</strong></p>
<p>Ramón Gómez oversees human rights for the Movement for Homosexual Integration and Liberation in Chile. He said the statement was a step toward breaking down discrimination in the church and could help LGBTQ+ people in countries where even civil unions are not legal. But he said the document "gives the signal that same-sex couples are <strong>inferior</strong> to heterosexual couples."</p>
<p>The Reverand James Martin supports welcoming LGBTQ+ Catholics. He praised the new document as a "huge step forward" and a change from the Vatican's 2021 policy.</p>
<p>"Along with many Catholic priests, I will now be delighted to bless my friends in same-sex marriages," he said in an email.</p>
<p>In Germany, clergy have been blessing same-sex couples for years. And the head of the German Bishops Conference welcomed the document.</p>
<p>Bishop Georg Baetzing said, "This means that a blessing can be given to couples who do not have the opportunity to marry in church, for example due to divorce, and to same-sex couples."</p>
<p>In the United States, the Reverand John Oesterle, a Catholic priest in Pittsburgh, said many priests would probably not be open to offering such a blessing, but he welcomed Francis' action.</p>
<p>He said, "When I was growing up, the <strong>assumption</strong> was that God made everyone straight. What we have learned is that is not true. In accepting people as God made them, and if Jesus' primary teaching is we should love and serve one another in the community, I think that's what gives Pope Francis the openness to God's presence in those relationships."</p>
<p>Traditionalists, however, expressed shock and anger. Luigi Casalini of Messa in Latino (Latin Mass) blog wrote that the document did not follow the church's teachings. "The church is crumbling," he wrote.</p>
<p>University of Notre Dame theologian Ulrich Lehner was also concerned. Lehner called it: "The most unfortunate public announcement in decades." He said it could lead to division in the church.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Nicole Winfield and David Crary reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bless </strong><em>–v.</em> to ask God to care for and protect someone</p>
<p><strong>couple </strong><em>–n.</em> two people who are married or have an intimate relationship</p>
<p><strong>gay (homosexual) </strong><em>–adj.</em> sexually interested in the same sex</p>
<p><strong>prior </strong><em>–adj.</em> taking place earlier</p>
<p><strong>intention </strong><em>–n</em>. a plan or aim</p>
<p><strong>legitimize </strong><em>–v.</em> to make acceptable and normal</p>
<p><strong>mercy </strong><em>–n.</em> kind treatment where it is not expected or deserved</p>
<p><strong>inferior </strong><em>–adj.</em> not as good as something else</p>
<p><strong>assumption </strong><em>–n. </em>an opinion that is not based on direct knowledge but is thought to be the case</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Yemeni Rebel Attacks Affect International Shipping  (2023/12/20) | 也门胡塞武装袭击影响国际航运</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/yemeni-rebels-attacks-affect-international-shipping.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The recent attacks on ships in and near the Red Sea by Yemen's Houthi rebels have affected some of the world's top shipping and oil companies. The threat has moved trade away from an important route for global trade. The change will likely cause delays and increase the prices of goods and energy.<br/>
也门胡塞叛军最近在红海及其附近袭击船只，影响了一些世界顶级航运和石油公司。该威胁使贸易偏离了全球贸易的一条重要航道。这一变化可能会造成延误，并提高商品和能源的价格。</p>
<p>Both oil and European natural gas prices rose a little over market concerns about Houthi attacks. The group, which is supported by Iran, confirmed two new attacks Monday. They were the latest in a series of attacks targeting container ships and oil tankers passing through the narrow waterway that separates Yemen from East Africa. The waterway then leads north to the Red Sea and the Suez Canal. It is estimated that 10 percent of the world's trade passes through the canal.<br/>
由于市场对胡塞袭击事件的担忧，石油和欧洲天然气价格都略有上涨。由伊朗支持的该组织星期一证实了两起新的袭击事件。这是针对通过也门与东非之间狭窄水道的集装箱船和油轮的一系列袭击中的最新一起。然后，这条水道向北通向红海和苏伊士运河。据估计，世界贸易的10%通过该航道。</p>
<p>Energy supplies reach Europe and beyond on tankers. And food products like palm oil and grain are carried by container ships through the Suez Canal.<br/>
能源供应通过油轮到达欧洲及其他地区。棕榈油和谷物等食品由集装箱船通过苏伊士运河运输。</p>
<p>"This is a problem for Europe. It's a problem for Asia," said John Stawpert. He is with the International Chamber of Shipping. The industry group represents 80 percent of the world's commercial shipping fleet. Stawpert noted that 40 percent of Asia-Europe trade normally takes the route through the Red Sea.<br/>
“这是欧洲的麻烦，也是亚洲的麻烦，”约翰·斯塔珀特表示。他在国际航运协会工作。该行业机构代表了全球80%的商业航运船队。斯塔珀特指出，40%的亚欧贸易通常通过红海航道。</p>
<p>Almost all goods that stores need for Christmas will have already arrived. But online orders could be delayed, experts said. That is because four of the world's five largest container shipping companies have suspended or rerouted movements from the Red Sea in recent days.<br/>
商店圣诞节所需的几乎所有商品都已到货。但专家表示，网上订单可能会延迟。这是因为最近几天，世界五大集装箱运输公司中的四家已经暂停或改变了从红海的运输路线。</p>
<p>MSC, Maersk, CMA CGM Group, and Hapag-Lloyd are shipping companies that move all consumer goods between Asia and Europe. Almost "all services will have to make this rerouting," said Simon Heaney, who is with Drewry, a shipping research group.<br/>
地中海航运公司、马士基、达飞集团和赫伯罗特是在亚洲和欧洲之间运输所有消费品的航运公司。航运研究组织德鲁里航运咨询公司的西蒙·希尼说，几乎“所有公司都必须重新安排路线”。</p>
<p>Ships will have to go around South Africa's Cape of Good Hope instead. That will add at least a week of travel time, experts say.<br/>
船只将不得不绕行南非的好望角。专家表示，这将增加至少一周的航行时间。</p>
<p>Depending on what companies decide to do, they could add more ships to make up for the longer trip. They could also travel faster, but that would use more fuel.<br/>
根据公司的决定，他们可以增加更多的船只来弥补更长的行程。它们也可以行驶得更快，但这会消耗更多的燃料。</p>
<p>Stawpert of the Shipping Chamber said he expects some price increases in the short term. But that depends on how long the security threat lasts.<br/>
航运商会的斯塔珀特表示，他预计短期内价格会有所上涨。但这取决于该安全威胁持续的时间。</p>
<p>The Houthi military spokesman said Monday his group launched what he described as "naval aircraft" at the Cayman Islands-flagged ship Swan Atlantic. The boat is a chemical and oil products carrier. The group also attacked the Panama-flagged cargo ship MSC CLARA. He did not offer more details.<br/>
胡塞军方发言人周一表示，胡塞武装向悬挂开曼群岛国旗的“大西洋天鹅”号发射了他所说的“海上无人机”。这艘船是一艘化学品和石油产品运输船。该团伙还袭击了悬挂巴拿马国旗的“地中海航运克拉拉号”货轮。他没有提供更多细节。</p>
<p>Denmark-based ship operator Uni-Tankers said the Swan Atlantic was hit by an unknown object that started a small fire. Crew members put it out and all were reported to be safe, the company said. It received military aid and continued on its way.<br/>
总部位于丹麦的船舶运营商Uni Tankers表示，大西洋天鹅号被一个不明物体击中，引发了一场小火灾。该公司表示，船员将火扑灭，所有人员都安然无恙。它得到了军事援助并继续前进。</p>
<p>U.S., French, British and other warships already patrol the area, keeping the waterway open. Stawpert said countries' naval presence has increased and that should improve confidence in the shipping industry and somewhat ease the threat.<br/>
美国、法国、英国等国军舰已经在该地区巡逻，保持航道畅通。斯塔珀特说，各国海军的存在已经加大，这应该会提高对航运业的信心，并在一定程度上缓解威胁。</p>
<p>Problems in Red Sea shipping could have far-reaching effects because they are happening at the same time ships are being restricted through the Panama Canal. The canal is a major trade route between Asia and the United States.<br/>
红海航运问题可能会产生深远影响，因为这些问题发生的同时，船只正被限制通过巴拿马运河。这条运河是亚洲和美国之间的一条主要贸易路线。</p>
<p>Some companies had planned to reroute to the Red Sea to avoid delays at the Panama Canal caused by a lack of rainfall, experts said.<br/>
专家表示，一些公司曾计划改道前往红海，以避免巴拿马运河因降雨量不足而导致的延误。</p>
<p>With the Houthi attacks, companies taking measures to avoid risk will have to take the longer route around Africa.<br/>
随着胡塞袭击事件的发生，各公司采取措施规避风险将不得不绕非洲走更长的路线。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: More Americans Affected by Long-term Tiredness  (2023/12/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/study-more-americans-affected-by-long-term-tiredness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health &amp; Lifestyle Report.</p>
<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has released its most recent estimate for adults with chronic fatigue syndrome.</p>
<p>People with chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) suffer from at least six months of severe tiredness that is not helped by rest. They can also report pain and mental <strong>confusion</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Nancy Rose, who contracted COVID-19 in 2021 and exhibits long-haul symptoms including brain fog and memory difficulties, pauses while organizing her desk space, Jan. 25, 2022, in Port Jefferson, New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/618f989b-6beb-4183-ad00-2a260240349e_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Nancy Rose, who contracted COVID-19 in 2021 and exhibits long-haul symptoms including brain fog and memory difficulties, pauses while organizing her desk space, Jan. 25, 2022, in Port Jefferson, New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo, File)</span></div>
<p>Health officials said the study was the first nationally representative estimate of how many U.S. adults have chronic fatigue syndrome. The study gathered information from 2021 to 2022. It found that 1.3 percent of American adults reported having CFS or something like it.</p>
<p>These numbers from the CDC are larger than earlier studies have suggested. They likely include people with long COVID, a condition of long-lasting sickness after a COVID-19 infection.</p>
<p>The findings led CDC's Dr. Elizabeth Unger to say that CFS "is not a rare illness." She was one of the writers of the report.</p>
<p>The tiredness and other symptoms of CFS can get worse after exercise, work, or other activity. There is no cure, and no testing leads to a quick <strong>diagnosis</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>No known cause</strong></p>
<p>Doctors do not know the cause. However, research suggests it is the body's overreaction to an infection or other shock to the immune system.</p>
<p>The condition gained attention nearly 40 years ago, when many cases were reported in Incline Village, Nevada, and Lyndonville, New York. Some doctors dismissed it, calling it psychosomatic. Psychosomatic means a problem is mental or emotional rather than physical.</p>
<p>Some doctors also called it "yuppie flu." "Yuppie" stands for "young, urban professional," people who have good jobs and medical coverage.</p>
<p>Some doctors still think CFS is a mental condition, experts and patients say.</p>
<p>Doctors "called me a <strong>hypochondriac</strong> and said it was just <strong>anxiety</strong> and depression," said Hannah Powell. She is a 26-year-old woman from Utah who was diagnosed after five years.</p>
<p><strong>New findings from the report</strong></p>
<p>The new CDC report is based on a <strong>survey</strong> of more than 57,000 U.S. adults. They were asked if a doctor or other health-care professional had ever told them they had myalgic encephalomyelitis, or CFS, and whether they still have it. About 1.3 percent said yes to both questions.</p>
<p>CDC officials said that results in an estimate of 3.3 million U.S. adults.</p>
<p>The study also reported other findings. It said that CFS was more common in women than men. White people reported the condition more than other racial and ethnic groups. Earlier, smaller studies reported similar findings.</p>
<p>The findings showed there was less of a difference between women and men than some earlier studies suggested. And there was little difference between Black and white people.</p>
<p>However, the study also found that a higher percentage of poor people reported the condition than wealthy people.</p>
<p><strong>CFS is not a popular diagnosis</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Brayden Yellman is a specialist at the Bateman Horne Center in Salt Lake City, Utah. He said patients who report the condition usually have health care coverage. He said doctors might believe them more when they say they "continue to be <strong>fatigued </strong>and can't go to work."</p>
<p>The CDC study is based on patients' memories. It did not use medical records. That could lead to overcounting. However, it is possible that only a percentage of people with CFS are diagnosed, said Dr. Daniel Clauw. He is director of the University of Michigan's Chronic Pain and Fatigue Research Center.</p>
<p>He added that is not a "popular diagnosis to give because there (are) no drugs approved for it. There (are) no treatment guidelines for it."</p>
<p>The total number likely includes some patients with long COVID who were suffering from long-term tiredness, CDC officials said.</p>
<p>"We think it's the same illness," Yellman said. But long COVID is more widely accepted by doctors and is being diagnosed much more quickly, he said.</p>
<p>Powell, one of Yellman's patients, was a high school athlete who came down with an illness during a trip to Belize before her final year. Doctors thought she had malaria, and she seemed to recover. But she developed chronic tiredness, had trouble sleeping, and had frequent <strong>vomiting</strong>. She said she slowly stopped playing sports and had trouble doing schoolwork.</p>
<p>After five years, a doctor said she had chronic fatigue. She began to regain normal life through regular treatments of fluids and medications. She graduated from the University of Utah and now works for an organization that helps domestic violence victims.</p>
<p>Getting care is still a struggle, she said.</p>
<p>"When I go to the (emergency room) or to another doctor's visit, instead of saying I have chronic fatigue syndrome, I usually say I have long COVID," Powell said. "And I am believed almost immediately."</p>
<p>And that's the Health &amp; Lifestyle Report. I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Mike Stobbe reported this story for the Associated Press. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p><p><strong style="font-size: 9pt;">_______________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>confusion </strong><em>–n.</em> an inability to think clearly</p>
<p><strong>diagnosis </strong><em>–n.</em> when a doctor says or confirms that a person has a medical condition</p>
<p><strong>hypochondriac </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who is worried about sickness and death more than normal</p>
<p><strong>anxiety </strong><em>–n.</em> a feeling of worry and high tension</p>
<p><strong>survey </strong><em>–n.</em> a study in which researchers ask people questions about what they think and report the results</p>
<p><strong>fatigued </strong><em>–adj.</em> feeling tired or worn out</p>
<p><strong>vomit </strong><em>–v</em>. to be sick in the stomach and to expel its contents out of one's mouth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Story of Santa Claus  (2023/12/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-story-of-santa-claus.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Santa Claus is someone who will remain in the hearts of children forever. He is the make-believe person who brings toys and other gifts to children at Christmas. To grown-ups, he is a special symbol of good will and selfless giving.<br/>
<br/>
Santa Claus also has some other names, like Saint Nicholas, Kris Kringle and Pelznickel.</p>
<p>The Santa Claus we talk about in the United States flies from his home at the North Pole on Christmas Eve to bring toys and gifts to children. The happy, white-bearded man is dressed in red. He usually flies on a <strong>sleigh</strong> led by his reindeer. Santa enters each home through the <strong>chimney</strong> and fills children's stockings with toys and gifts.</p>
<p>This modern image of Santa Claus largely comes from Clement Clark Moore's famous poem, <em>A Visit from St. Nicholas.</em></p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man dressed as Santa Claus waves during the 97th Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade in Manhattan, New York City, U.S., November 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Mike Segar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/85ad8313-4d64-40d1-a70d-404bc29466ed_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">A man dressed as Santa Claus waves during the 97th Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade in Manhattan, New York City, U.S., November 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Mike Segar)</span></div>
<p><em>‘Twas the night before Christmas, when all through the house<br/>
Not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse;<br/>
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care,<br/>
In hopes that St. Nicholas soon would be there;...</em></p>
<p><em>He spoke not a word, but went straight to his work,<br/>
And filled all the stockings; then turned with a jerk,<br/>
And laying his finger aside of his nose,<br/>
And giving a nod, up the chimney he rose;</em></p>
<p>Santa Claus is believed to have come from the story of St. Nicholas. He was a 4th-century clergy in the Mediterranean port city of Myra, part of modern-day Turkey. It is said that St. Nicholas gave away all his wealth to help the poor and the sick. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.history.com/topics/christmas/santa-claus#santa-claus-around-the-world">History.com</a><em> </em>says St. Nicholas became known as the protector of children and sailors. It adds that he was the most popular saint in Europe.</p>
<p>In the 18th century, Dutch immigrants brought the story of Saint Nikolaas and the tradition of gift-giving to New York City. The Dutch said his name very quickly. It sounded like "Sinterklaas." When English speakers said this word, it sounded like Santa Claus.</p>
<p>German immigrants working as farmers in the American state of Pennsylvania also knew of Saint Nikolaas. But they called him Pelznickel. This word came from "pelz," meaning fur in German, and "nickel" for Nicholas. Saint Nikolaasor became a man dressed in fur who came once a year with gifts for good children.</p>
<p>Pelznickel became part of a celebration honoring the Christkindl, as the Germans called the child of Christ. After some time, Christkindl became "Kris Kringle." That is another name you will hear for Santa Claus.</p>
<p>A Santa-liked <strong>figure</strong> is known as Father Christmas in Britain and Père Noel in France. In Scandinavia, an elf named Jultomten was thought to deliver gifts in a sleigh drawn by goats. In Italy, a woman called La Befana rides a broomstick down the chimneys of homes to bring toys for lucky children.</p>
<p>The image of Santa Claus as we now see him came from Thomas Nast. He was an American painter born in Bavaria, Germany.</p>
<p>Nast remembered that, when he was a little boy, a kind old man would give toys and cakes to the children on Christmas. So, when Nast painted Santa Claus, he looked like the old man from his childhood.</p>
<p>Nast painted Santa as a short, fat, <strong>jolly</strong> old man with a long beard. He wore a red suit with white fur. He also gave Santa a North Pole workshop, elves, and a wife, Mrs. Claus. Through the years, Nast's painting has remained the most popular picture of Santa Claus.</p>
<p>American children write letters to Santa hoping to be on his "nice list" for Christmas gifts. On Christmas Eve, they leave cookies and milk for Santa and carrots for his reindeer: Dasher, Dancer, Prancer, Vixen, Comet, Cupid, Donner, Blitzen and "the most famous reindeer of all," Rudolph.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story with additional material from VOA Learning English and History.com.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sleigh</strong> - n. a large, open vehicle that is usually pulled by a horse (or reindeer) over snow or ice.</p>
<p><strong>chimney</strong> - n. a part of a building through which smoke rises into the air</p>
<p><strong>figure</strong> - n. a person</p>
<p><strong>jolly</strong> - adj. happy and cheerful</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russian Volunteers Joining Ukraine to Fight Russia  (2023/12/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/russian-volunteers-joining-ukraine-to-fight-russia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>In Ukraine, a man who goes by his military name Karabas is training to fight against the Russian army. But Karabas is not from Ukraine. He is from Russia.</p>
<p>Karabas was living in Moscow when Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022. He was shocked and very upset, and he decided to act.</p>
<p>He decided to find a way to get to Ukraine. There, he hoped to join troops fighting Russian forces.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Members of the pro-Ukrainian Russian ethnic Siberian Battalion practice at a military training close to Kyiv, Ukraine, Wednesday, Dec. 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Efrem Lukatsky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-49b1-08dbfd928291_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Members of the pro-Ukrainian Russian ethnic Siberian Battalion practice at a military training close to Kyiv, Ukraine, Wednesday, Dec. 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Efrem Lukatsky)</span></div>
<p>It took him almost a year to make it happen.</p>
<p>Today, he is part of the Siberian Battalion, a group of Russians who have joined the Ukrainian military to fight against their own country. Its members come mostly from ethnic minorities from Russia's far east.</p>
<p>They hope to someday help remove Russian President Vladimir Putin from power.</p>
<p>Karabas told The Associated Press that he was <strong>disappointed</strong> in the Russian people. He said he was upset that people were supporting Putin without thinking. And he was upset that they did not seem to care about the war.</p>
<p>"That is why I wanted to come here...and fight for a free Ukraine," he added.</p>
<p>Unlike other volunteer units in Ukraine with Russian nationals, the Siberian Battalion is officially part of the Ukrainian army. To enter the unit, fighters must pass strict security checks. This process can take up to a year.</p>
<p>Karabas went to Armenia first. There, he met Ukrainians and learned to speak the Ukrainian language. Now, he refuses to speak Russian.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian army is training the Siberian Battalion and sending them to the front lines in eastern Ukraine. That area has seen some of the deadliest fighting of the war. Russian and Ukrainian forces continue to fight for control of it.</p>
<p>Fighters in the battalion from eastern Siberia hope a Ukrainian victory will weaken or change Russia's control over their <strong>region</strong>. The area is among the poorest in Russia. People from the area's Yakut and Buryat ethnic communities complain of racism and unfair use of power against them in Russia. This has made some activists call for independence.</p>
<p>Another Russian fighter, who goes by the name Holod, openly said he wants Putin's administration removed from power.</p>
<p>"When this happens, we can talk about victory," he said.</p>
<p>Karabas and other Russians left their entire lives behind, including families and friends.</p>
<p>Some from the battalion have already been sent near Avdiivka, a Ukraine-controlled city in the Donetsk region. The Russian military has been fighting to take control of the area.</p>
<p>The battalion was created six months ago. It has fewer than 100 members, but Ukrainian military leaders hope more will join. Based on <strong>applications</strong> they have received, they are aiming to have up to 300 members in the unit.</p>
<p>Karabas said there may be tens or hundreds of thousands of other Russians like him, willing to fight with Ukraine.</p>
<p>"I think we should have a lot more (Russian fighters)," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Vasilisa Stepanenko wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>disappointed </strong><em>-adj. </em>unhappy with a result or situation</p>
<p><strong>region </strong><em>-n. </em>an area of a country</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>-n. </em>a formal, written request to enter a program or organization or get permission to do something.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Create ‘Biocomputer’ with Lab-Grown Brain Tissue  (2023/12/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/scientists-create-biocomputer-with-lab-grown-brain-tissue.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>American researchers have combined lab-grown human brain tissue with computer hardware to create a working biocomputer.</p>
<p>The scientists say brain cells used in the experiment were able to recognize speech and complete simple math problems.</p>
<p>The team made brain-like tissue that took the form of what they called a "brain organoid." Harvard University's Stem Cell Institute <a class="wsw__a" href="https://hsci.harvard.edu/organoids">explains</a> that an organoid is a collection of individualized, complex cells that can be grown from stem cells in a lab.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this July 29, 2013 photo, a researcher holds a human brain in a laboratory at Northwestern University's cognitive neurology and Alzheimer's disease center in Chicago. (AP Photo/Scott Eisen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-00ec-08dbfd8e8539_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this July 29, 2013 photo, a researcher holds a human brain in a laboratory at Northwestern University's cognitive neurology and Alzheimer's disease center in Chicago. (AP Photo/Scott Eisen)</span></div>
<p>Under the right laboratory conditions, organoids can be made to look and even work similarly to real human tissue and organs. In this process, stem cells "can follow their own genetic <strong>instructions</strong> to self-organize," the Stem Cell Institute says.</p>
<p>So far, scientists have been able to produce organoids that look like, or resemble, some organs. These organs include the brain, kidney, lung, stomach and liver. Such lab-created organoids are generally used to study how organs work without needing to experiment on actual organs.</p>
<p>In the biocomputer experiment, the team said stem cells were able to form neurons similar to those found in the human brain. Neurons are electrically charged cells that transport signals to the brain and other parts of the body.</p>
<p>Feng Guo led the experiment. He is a bioengineer and professor of Intelligent System Engineering at Indiana University Bloomington. His team recently published their research results <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-023-01069-w.epdf?sharing_token=NYPf_32wRs_t6U-N_UVaLtRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0M8M4oYFZwXw3ADmbAHb74edPY2vKOF1O-GEmUziwBdM4S_Qm6LsNScxuBszwcCh3Rk4pthEc9aDrLpsaqe7-4YKhK3HWl1E_kodyNXdLfYE8tDAEEOwYPeyB57nYaTS37RGi7ufFW6oTEw56CoODMlO5EDr-JQRXB5mXPmLNcJ7z0bta70aD4yJ4RBCmGphCY%3D&amp;tracking_referrer=www.technologyreview.com">in a study</a> in <em>Nature Electronics</em>.</p>
<p>The researchers attached the brain organoid to a set of traditional electronic computing <strong>circuits</strong>. The researchers call this system Brainoware. The system was used to establish communication between the organoid and electronic circuits. An artificial intelligence (AI) tool was used to help read the neural activity of the organoid.</p>
<p>The scientists aim to build "a bridge between AI and organoids," Guo <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-03975-7">explained</a> to <em>Nature</em>. Guo believes that combining organoids and computer circuits could provide additional speed and energy to improve the performance of AI computing systems.</p>
<p>The study notes that adding human brain power might be able to help machines with the things they do not do as well as people. For example, the researchers said humans generally have a faster learning ability and use less energy thinking than computers do.</p>
<p>During one part of the experiment, the team tested the Brainoware system's voice recognition ability. The team trained the system on 240 recordings of eight different voices. The researchers said the organoid produced different neural signals in reaction to the different voices. The <strong>accuracy</strong> level of the system reached 78 percent, Guo said.</p>
<p>"This is the first demonstration of using brain organoids [for computing]," Guo <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/12/11/1084926/human-brain-cells-chip-organoid-speech-recognition/">told</a> <em>MIT Technology Review</em>. He added, "It's exciting to see the possibilities of organoids for biocomputing in the future."</p>
<p>Guo said these results persuaded his team that a brain-computer system can work to improve computing performance, especially for some AI jobs. But he noted the best accuracy rates recorded by the Brainoware system were still below the accuracy rates of traditional AI networks. Guo said this is one of the things his team plans to try to improve.</p>
<p>Lena Smirnova is a developmental neuroscientist at Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore, Maryland. She told <em>Nature</em> that more research will be needed to improve such systems. But she said, "The study confirms some key <strong>theoretical</strong> ideas that could eventually make a biological computer possible."</p>
<p>Smirnova noted that in earlier experiments, researchers have used other kinds of neuron cells to perform similar computational activities. But the latest study, she said, was the first to demonstrate this kind of performance in a brain organoid.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Nature Electronics, The Associated Press, Harvard's </em><em>Stem Cell Institute and MIT Technology Review. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>instruction </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of steps for how to do something</p>
<p><strong>circuit </strong><em>– v. </em>a complete circle an electric current travels around</p>
<p><strong>accurate </strong><em>– adj. </em>correct or exact</p>
<p><strong>theoretical </strong><em>– adj. </em>based on the ideas that relate to a subject, not the practical uses of that subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>A Short History of UN Climate Deal Promises  (2023/12/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-short-history-of-un-climate-deal-promises.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>United Nations delegates from nearly 200 countries recently held a climate meeting in Dubai, United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>The delegates agreed that the world must move away from fossil fuels like oil, gas, and coal.</p>
<p>The U.N. meeting on climate change is called COP28 this year. Recently, <em>The Associated Press</em> gave details about some of the main results of notable climate talks over almost 30 years:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Activists demonstrate for climate justice and a ceasefire at the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, Dec. 9, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Peter Dejong, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/55a437db-880e-45ed-8ff6-4b4ba8c5a31e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Activists demonstrate for climate justice and a ceasefire at the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, Dec. 9, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Peter Dejong, File)</span></div>
<p><strong>The Kyoto Protocol</strong></p>
<p>The Kyoto Protocol was the third high-level U.N. climate meeting. It took place in Kyoto, Japan in 1997.</p>
<p>The agreement asked 41 countries that produced a lot of carbon gases to cut their <strong>emissions</strong> by about five percent compared to their emission levels in 1990.</p>
<p>Countries agreed to some of the terms in the Kyoto Protocol by 2005. The United States and China, however, did not approve the agreement. Those countries have the world's two largest economies and produce the largest amount of carbon gases.</p>
<p>The Kyoto Protocol was not successful by some measures. Emissions have greatly increased since then. But it is the first time so many U.N. members agreed that carbon gases were a problem.</p>
<p><strong>Copenhagen's money for the climate</strong></p>
<p>The 2009 climate meeting in Copenhagen, Denmark is widely seen as a failure. Developing and developed countries disagreed on cutting emissions and whether poor nations could use oil, natural gas, and coal to grow their economies.</p>
<p>However, wealthy countries promised to send $100 billion a year to developing countries. The money was to be used for green technology by 2020. Green technology often describes energy technology that does not produce pollution when it is used.</p>
<p>But wealthy nations did not reach their goal of $100 billion by the start of the 2020s. That led to criticism from developing countries and environmentalists.</p>
<p>In 2022, the Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development, an international economic group, said wealthy countries probably reached their $100-billion goal.</p>
<p>But the British nonprofit group Oxfam said 70 percent of the money was in the form of loans. It said the loans increased debt problems in developing countries.</p>
<p>Also, an increasing number of weather-related disasters are blamed on climate change. Experts say the money promised is not enough. British economist Nicholas Stern said that developing countries likely need $2 trillion every year by 2030 for climate projects and recovery.</p>
<p><strong>The Paris agreement</strong></p>
<p>The Paris Agreement is widely considered the single biggest U.N. agreement on climate change. In 2015, about 196 nations agreed to keep atmospheric warming "well below" 2 degrees Celsius since, what the agreement calls, "pre-industrial times." Later, the goal became limiting warming no higher than 1.5 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>The U.N. says the Paris agreement is a "legally binding international treaty," meaning that it has the force of law in countries that approve it. But there do not appear to be punishments for countries that do not follow its rules.</p>
<p>Today, the goal of limiting the rise of the atmosphere's temperature to 1.5 degrees is still central to climate discussions. U.N. experts say the world's temperature has not passed the limit set in the Paris agreement. The U.N. says it has warmed from 1.1 to 1.2 degrees Celsius since the early 1800s. But it says the atmosphere will reach the 1.5-degree limit soon unless large cuts in emissions are made quickly.</p>
<p><strong>Glasgow and coal</strong></p>
<p>Six years after the Paris agreement, climate officials wanted another agreement to strengthen the levels agreed upon in 2015.</p>
<p>The meeting in Glasgow, Scotland was put off until 2021. It was delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic. The meeting included protests led by teenaged climate activist Greta Thunberg. She helped lead a worldwide movement of youth activists demanding more action from leaders.</p>
<p>In Glasgow, countries agreed to "<strong>phase</strong>-down" coal use. That is different from saying "phase-out." India and China, two of the world's biggest coal users, pressed for the change.</p>
<p>So far, most countries have failed to meet the promises they made at the Glasgow deal. Emissions from coal have increased and most major coal-using countries have yet to slow use of the fuel.</p>
<p><strong>Loss and damage in Sharm el-Sheikh</strong></p>
<p>Last year, climate talks took place in the Egyptian vacation town of Sharm el-Sheikh. There, countries agreed to create a <strong>fund</strong> for poor nations for the first time.</p>
<p>Delegates agreed to a loss and damage fund. Its aim was to provide money to countries that suffered damage from severe weather events.</p>
<p>Delegates at the COP27 meeting called for the fund to be created after a flood in Pakistan killed an estimated 2,000 people and caused billions of dollars in losses.</p>
<p>The fund was officially created on the first day of this year's talks in Dubai. Over $700 million has been promised. Giving to the fund is voluntary.</p>
<p>U.N. climate experts say billions of dollars are needed because of weather-related events like cyclones, rising sea levels, floods and droughts. The experts blame the extreme events on increasing temperatures in Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Guaurav Saini And Sibi Arasu reported this story for The Associated Press with Press Trust of India. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>emission </strong>– <em>n</em>. the act of producing or sending out something (such as energy or gas) from a source</p>
<p><strong>phase out </strong>– <em>phr. v</em>. to stop using, making, or doing (something) gradually over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>fund </strong>– <em>n</em>. an amount of money that is used for a special purpose</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mickey Mouse Will Soon Belong to You, Me, Everyone  (2023/12/18) | 早期版本米老鼠即将版权到期进入共有领域</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/mickey-mouse-will-soon-belong-to-you-me-everyone.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>An early version of Mickey Mouse, the famous Disney character, will soon belong to you, me and everybody else.<br/>
迪士尼著名角色米老鼠的早期版本很快就会属于大众。</p>
<p>The mouse that started a Hollywood empire, along with several other characters, movies, and books will enter the public domain on January 1st.<br/>
这只开创了好莱坞帝国的老鼠，以及其他几个角色、电影和书籍将于1月1日进入公有领域。</p>
<p>Public domain is the term to describe creative works that are no longer protected by U.S. copyright law. Once a work enters the public domain, it can legally be shared, performed, reused, or repurposed without permission or cost.<br/>
公有领域是一个专业术语，用于描述不再受美国版权法保护的创意作品。一旦作品进入公有领域，就可以合法地共享、表演、重利用或重新调整用途，而无需获得许可或支付费用。</p>
<p>Mickey Mouse, and Minnie Mouse, first appeared publicly in the 1928 film Steamboat Willie. Copyright law at the time provided protection for 75 years. But in 1998, U.S. law extended copyright protection for another 20 years.<br/>
米老鼠和米妮老鼠首次公开出现在1928年的电影《汽船威利》中。当时的版权法提供了75年的保护。但在1998年，美国法律将版权保护期又延长了20年。</p>
<p>Jennifer Jenkins is head of Duke University's Center for the Study of Public Domain. Jenkins says copyright law is sometimes called the Mickey Mouse Protection Act. As the character is about to enter the public domain, she says "This is it. This is Mickey Mouse. This is exciting because it's kind of symbolic."<br/>
詹妮弗·詹金斯是杜克大学公有领域研究中心的负责人。詹金斯说，版权法有时被称为《米老鼠保护法》。随着这个角色即将进入公有领域，她说：“就是这样。这是米老鼠。这很令人兴奋，因为它有点象征意义。”</p>
<p>In a statement, the Disney Company told The Associated Press, "Ever since Mickey Mouse's first appearance in the 1928 short film Steamboat Willie, people have associated the character with Disney's stories, experiences, and authentic products." The company added, "More modern versions of Mickey will remain unaffected by the expiration of the Steamboat Willie copyright..."<br/>
迪士尼公司在一份声明中告诉美联社，“自从米老鼠第一次出现在1928年的短片《汽船威利》中以来，人们已经把这个角色与迪士尼的故事、经历和正牌产品联系在一起。”该公司补充道，“现代版本的米奇将不受《汽船威利》版权到期的影响……”</p>
<p>People will only be able to use the version of the mouse in Steamboat Willie that has become public. However, observers expect the courts to be busy in the coming years judging what is inside and outside Disney's ownership.<br/>
人们将只能使用已经开放版权的《汽船威利》中使用米老鼠版本。然而观察人士预计，未来几年，法院将忙于判断属于和不属于迪士尼所有权的情况。</p>
<p>Disney also holds a trademark on Mickey to represent the company and its brand. That law bars the use of the character as a Disney product identifier for anyone except Disney.<br/>
迪士尼还持有米奇的商标，以代表公司及其品牌。该法律禁止除迪士尼以外的任何人使用该角色作为迪士尼产品的标识符。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Others in the public domain<br/>
公有领域的其他</span></p>
<p>Another famous animal character, Tigger, will also join his friend Winnie the Pooh in the public domain. The bouncing tiger first appeared in the book The House at Pooh Corner by British writer A.A. Milne. It turns 96 in January.<br/>
另一个著名的动物角色跳跳虎，也将加入他的朋友小熊维尼的行列进入公有领域。这只蹦蹦跳跳的老虎首次出现在英国作家A.A.米尔恩的《维尼角的小屋》一书中。今年一月份它就满96岁了。</p>
<p>The silly old bear Pooh, himself, became public property two years ago when Milne's book Winnie the Pooh came of age. The soft-spoken bear, no longer protected by copyright, is seen terrorizing women in this year's horror film Winnie the Pooh: Blood and Honey.<br/>
两年前，当米尔恩的书《小熊维尼》到了法定年头时，这只傻里傻气的老熊维尼就成了公共财产。这只说话轻声细语的熊不再受版权保护，在今年的恐怖电影《小熊维尼：血与蜜》中，可以看到它吓唬女性。</p>
<p>Other creative works entering the U.S. public domain are Charlie Chaplin's film Circus, Virginia Woolf's book Orlando, and Eugene O'Neill's play Long Day's Journey into Night.<br/>
其他进入美国公有领域的创意作品包括查理·卓别林的电影《马戏团》、弗吉尼亚·伍尔夫的书《奥兰多》和尤金·奥尼尔的戏剧《漫漫长夜》。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Young Indonesians Clean up Waterways, Better Solution Needed  (2023/12/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/young-indonesians-clean-up-waterways-better-solution-needed.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Children in the Indonesian city of Bogor are cleaning up a local lake on their own.</p>
<p>The young people take small boats, called kayaks, out on the water. They direct the kayaks toward floating trash. They remove the trash from the water and place it in their boats. Later, on land, all the trash is examined and dealt with.</p>
<p>About 20 children take part in the effort to fight pollution but it began with one boy. Ten years ago, Giri Marhara decided to start cleaning up the lake. He was just 16 years old at the time and had a <strong>habit</strong> of cleaning up his environment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Environmental activist members of the Situ Gede Cleanliness Warrior pick up trash while paddling kayaks at Setu Gede lake in Bogor, West Java, Indonesia, Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1582-08dbfcc51fee_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Environmental activist members of the Situ Gede Cleanliness Warrior pick up trash while paddling kayaks at Setu Gede lake in Bogor, West Java, Indonesia, Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)</span></div>
<p>Young people like Marhara have been at the front of environmental and climate change movements in recent years. Movements like school strikes for climate action, protests at United Nations climate talks, and local clean ups have often been youth-led.</p>
<p>The <strong>small-scale</strong> campaigns in Indonesia have been popular with younger people, gaining support and attention.</p>
<p>"For me, cleaning up is <strong>catharsis</strong>, cleaning up is <strong>refreshing</strong>," said Marhara. He said children playing nearby would often ask if they could help him with lake clean up.</p>
<p>They formed a group last year, called the Situ Gede Cleanliness Warrior, named after the lake. They boat across the lake, pick up trash, and identify what can be recycled.</p>
<p>Marhara and his friends have collected more than 2,700 kilograms of trash in and around the Situ Gede lake.</p>
<p>The trash problem in Indonesia is widespread. Its Environmental and Forestry Ministry says the country produced more than 35 million tons of waste last year. It estimates that 35 percent of waste in the country is <strong>unmanaged</strong>. Garbage along roadways, waterways and natural environments is a common sight.</p>
<p>Waste is also responsible for around 3 percent of global greenhouse gas emissions, says the World Resources Institute. Much of that comes from food waste. If left to <strong>decompose</strong> in landfills, food waste can release methane. The gas warms the planet and is around 80 times stronger than carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>The trash problem has raised health concerns: Plastic waste, for example, gets broken down into tiny pieces called microplastics, which can enter the human body. Studies suggest it can damage the <strong>endocrine</strong>, nervous and immune systems, and can carry an increased risk of cancers.</p>
<p>There are alternatives to landfill or littering for some waste products: food waste can be <strong>composted</strong>, for example. Some other types of waste, like certain types of plastic, can be reused or recycled. But environmentalists also say the world needs to make less waste in the first place, as much of it ends up in landfills or in the world's oceans.</p>
<p>But as waste continues, youth-led clean ups can still make an impact, even if it is just for small areas or communities.</p>
<p>Marhara believes that lasting change will require ending "behavior that is causing trash to be out there in the environment," he said, saying the country has a "<strong>littering</strong> culture."</p>
<p>"I think that the only way to counter that culture is by developing a <strong>counterculture</strong>," a clean up culture, he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story<strong> </strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>habit </strong><em>— n. </em>a usual way of behaving</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>catharsis </strong><em>— n. </em>the act or process of releasing a strong emotion</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>refreshing</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— adj. </em>pleasantly new, different, or interesting</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>manage</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— v. </em>to have control of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>decompose</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— adj. </em>to cause something to be slowly destroyed and broken down by natural processes, chemicals, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>endocrine </strong><em>— n. </em>relating to glands which release hormones or other products directly into the blood</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>compost </strong><em>— n. </em>a decayed mixture of plants (such as leaves and grass) that is used to improve the soil in a garden</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>landfill </strong><em>— n. </em>a system in which waste materials are buried under the ground</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>counterculture </strong><em>— n</em>. a culture with values and customs that are very different from and usually opposed to those accepted by most of society</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Led to the Resignation of an Ivy League President?  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-led-to-the-resignation-of-an-ivy-league-president.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The presidents of three well-known American universities recently spoke to members of the U.S. Congress about antisemitism on college <strong>campuses</strong>.</p>
<p>Antisemitism is the word used to describe a hatred of Jewish people.</p>
<p>The House's Committee on Education called Liz Magill of the University of Pennsylvania, Claudine Gay of Harvard and Sally Kornbluth of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) for a five-hour hearing in Washington, D.C.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - University of Pennsylvania President Liz Magill testifies before a House Education and The Workforce Committee hearing titled Holding Campus Leaders Accountable and Confronting Antisemitism on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Ken Cedeno)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/803e2aa7-6c8a-4cf3-93a4-430d15d63ba2_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - University of Pennsylvania President Liz Magill testifies before a House Education and The Workforce Committee hearing titled "Holding Campus Leaders Accountable and Confronting Antisemitism" on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Ken Cedeno)</span></div>
<p>The Republican-led committee chose the three leaders because their schools "have been at the center of the rise in antisemitic protests," a committee spokesperson said in a statement.</p>
<p>The protests are related to the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas. On October 7, Hamas fighters launched a surprise attack in Israel and killed over 1,200 Jewish people. Since then, the conflict has led to the deaths of more than 18,000 people in the Palestinian territory of Gaza.</p>
<p>Protesters who supported Palestine used the word "intifada," an Arabic word for resistance, and the phrase "from the river to the sea." Some people believe the phrase is a call for the death of all Jews.</p>
<p><strong>"Yes or no?"</strong></p>
<p>Representative Elise Stefanik is a Republican lawmaker from New York state. Stefanik, who went to Harvard, asked each university leader about how their school would react to calls to kill a large number of Jews, something described as <strong>genocide</strong>.</p>
<p>Stefanik asked Magill: "Does calling for the genocide of Jews violate Penn's rules or <strong>code of conduct</strong>? Yes or no?"</p>
<p>Magill did not answer "yes" or "no." Instead, she said the university only considers if "speech turns into conduct." By that, she meant the university respects an individual's right to free speech. But if the speech became "directed and severe, <strong>pervasive,</strong>" as the president said, it would then be considered more serious. In response to a question about whether a student would be punished for their speech, Magill said it depended on "<strong>context</strong>."</p>
<p>When faced with the same questions from Stefanik, Gay of Harvard and Kornbluth of MIT also did not say "yes" or "no."</p>
<p>Gay answered that it depended on the context. She added that when "speech crosses into conduct, that violates our policies." And Kornbluth answered that she had not "heard calling for the genocide of Jews on our campus."</p>
<p><strong>Criticism and questions of free speech</strong></p>
<p>The answers brought serious criticism from national and state political leaders, students, and members of the college community.</p>
<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, a Democrat, said Magill's answer was "unacceptable." He said talk of genocide against any group of people "is all in the wrong... She needed to give a one-word answer."</p>
<p>A spokesman for President Joe Biden criticized the three college presidents' answers. In a statement, he said they did not go far enough to condemn antisemitism on campuses. And calls for genocide go against "everything we represent as a country."</p>
<p>All three university presidents later apologized for not speaking out against Jewish genocide. Magill called for a review of Penn's policies which she said have long been guided by the U.S. Constitution. Gay wrote that "calls for violence or genocide against the Jewish community, or any religious or ethnic group are <strong>vile</strong>, they have no place at Harvard."</p>
<p>Free speech experts say the college presidents' answers at the hearing did follow the current understanding of the Constitution's right to free speech.</p>
<p>Suzanne Nossell is the leader of the nonprofit PEN America, a free-expression organization. She said the First Amendment of the U.S. Constitution protects "even deeply hateful speech."</p>
<p><strong>The outcome</strong></p>
<p>The congressional hearing took place on December 5.</p>
<p>By December 9, Magill resigned under pressure from wealthy donors and <strong>alumni</strong>. The pressure had started earlier this autumn when the university permitted a meeting on campus despite charges that some speakers had shown antisemitic views in other comments.</p>
<p>At MIT, the school's leadership group, called the MIT Corporation, announced its support for Kornbluth, who is Jewish, two days after the hearing. It said in a statement, "She has done excellent work in leading our community, including in addressing antisemitism, Islamophobia, and other forms of hate ..."</p>
<p>Gay faced pressure from Harvard's donors and alumni to step down. But more than 600 Harvard professors voiced their support for her leadership. They say that the school should not be influenced by political pressure.</p>
<p>Laurence Tribe is a well-known law professor at Harvard. He was critical of Gay's answer at the hearing. But he supported her continued leadership. Tribe said that "it is dangerous for universities to be... <strong>bullied</strong> into <strong>micromanaging</strong> their policies."</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Harvard leadership group announced that it would stand behind Gay and she would continue as the university's president.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>campus </strong><em>–n. </em>the physical location of a college or university's buildings</p>
<p><strong>genocide </strong><em>–n.</em> the deliberate killing of people who belong to a particular racial, political, or cultural group</p>
<p><strong>code of conduct </strong><em>–n.</em> rules on how to participate in a group, such as how to be a student at a university</p>
<p><strong>pervasive </strong><em>–adj.</em> spreading to all parts of something</p>
<p><strong>context </strong><em>–n.</em> the words that are used with a certain word or phrase and that help to explain its meaning</p>
<p><strong>vile </strong><em>–adj.</em> evil, immoral, unpleasant</p>
<p><strong>alumni </strong><em>–n.</em> the people who graduated from a school or university</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>–v.</em> to frighten, hurt, or threaten (a smaller or weaker person) : to act like a bully toward (someone)</p>
<p><strong>micromanage </strong><em>–v.</em> to try to control all parts of something usually in a way that is not wanted</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you think the universities dealt properly with their presidents?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>When Does a Problem 'Snowball'?  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/when-does-a-problem-snowball.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>If you live in a part of the world that is experiencing winter right now, it might be snowing.</p>
<p>But even if you do not live in a snowy <strong>climate</strong>, try to image cold, snowy weather. Imagine having a snowball fight with your friends. A snowball is, of course, a ball of snow. But not all snow makes good snowballs. If the snow is too light and dry, it will not hold together. It is <strong>powdery</strong>. Wetter snow makes for great snowballs. You can pack it into a tight ball, which is great for throwing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Snowballs fly during a snowball fight organized by the DC Snowball Fight Association, on the National Mall in the snow, Monday, Jan. 3, 2022, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/E81E4789-5EA7-4E37-9AAE-5573AD054F7B_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Snowballs fly during a snowball fight organized by the DC Snowball Fight Association, on the National Mall in the snow, Monday, Jan. 3, 2022, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)</span></div>
<p>A snowball might hurt a bit, but it would not cause a lot of damage. But imagine that snowball rolling down a hill. As it rolls, it picks up more and more snow. It gets bigger and bigger until it crashes into something and causes damage!</p>
<p>And that gives us "snowball" as a verb.</p>
<p>Dictionary.com defines the verb "snowball" as becoming "larger, greater, more <strong>intense</strong>..." very quickly.</p>
<p>If something like a project, campaign, or business snowballs, its progress rapidly increases and grows. For example, after a photographer posted a picture on Instagram of a m<i><i>onkey</i></i> protecting a human baby, her followers snowballed to over 1 million within a week!</p>
<p>However, when we use this expression the ending results are usually not good. Something that snowballs in a bad way <u>goes downhill</u> quickly. For example, when we do not take care of small problems, they can snowball into bigger ones.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear an example using the verb "snowball."</p>
<p><em>A: I have a friend who lied about knowing sign language on her <strong>r</strong></em><strong><em>e</em></strong><strong><em>sum</em></strong><strong><em>e</em></strong><em>. She thought no one would ask her to actually prove she knew sign language. But her boss asked her to. In fact, he set up a big meeting with the deaf community and assigned her to act as <strong>translator</strong>. She lied about why she could not attend the event. But her boss surprised her with an unplanned meeting. That is when he found out that she did not know how to sign. Her lie on her r</em><em>e</em><em>sum</em><em>e</em><em> quickly snowballed into a workplace drama that got her fired from her job. </em></p>
<p>Next, let's talk about the expression <u>snowball effect</u>.</p>
<p>A <u>snowball effect</u> is a situation where one action or event causes many other similar actions or events. And these actions or events grow and grow bigger and more problematic – just like a snowball rolling down a hill.</p>
<p>A snowball effect is similar to a <u>chain of events</u>. However, with a chain of events, one thing leads to another. But these events do not necessarily intensify or grow bigger.</p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Hopefully, using resources on VOA Learning English is having a snowball effect on your English studies ... in a good way!</p>
<p>Until next time, I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>climate </strong><em>– n. </em>a region with specified weather conditions<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>powdery </strong><em>– adj. </em>resembling or consisting of matter in a finely divided state</p>
<p><strong>intense </strong><em>– adj. </em>existing in an extreme degree</p>
<p><strong>r</strong><strong>e</strong><strong>sum</strong><strong>e </strong><em>– n. </em>a short account of one's career and qualifications</p>
<p><strong>translator </strong><em>– n. </em>to turn into one's own or another language</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you have a similar expressions in your language? Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html" target="_blank" title="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Bill Clinton: Survivor  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-bill-clinton.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>
VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about William Jefferson Clinton – better known as Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Clinton took office in 1993, and was re-elected in 1996. In many ways, historians consider his time in office a success. The economy expanded, and the country was largely at peace.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Bill Clinton" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7493e0cb-7da8-4433-85f3-39609c1945f0_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Bill Clinton</span></div>
<p>But Clinton had some notable failures, too. He could not persuade Congress to accept a plan to reform the nation's health care system.</p>
<p>And, in his second term, the House of Representatives took steps to remove him from office. But the Senate decided not to act.</p>
<p>Clinton finished his second term with high approval ratings. Yet he is also remembered for being only the second U.S. president to be <strong>impeached</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Bill Clinton came from a town with a memorable name: Hope. He grew up there, and in another nearby town in the Southern state of Arkansas.</p>
<p>For most of his early life, Bill was raised by his grandmother and his mother, both nurses. His father had died in a car accident before he was born.</p>
<p>People who knew Bill as a young man remember him as very intelligent, charming with people, and talented in music. His mother told him he would be president one day.</p>
<p>Sure enough, Clinton pursued activities that would lead to a political career. He attended college at Georgetown University in Washington, DC, where he studied international affairs; led student government groups; and took a position as a <strong>clerk</strong> in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>He went on to study at Oxford University in England on a prestigious Rhodes Scholarship.</p>
<p>Then he graduated from law school at Yale University. There, he met another student who would be his wife, Hillary Rodham. The two went on to have one child together, a daughter named Chelsea.</p>
<p>After finishing his studies, Clinton returned to his home state of Arkansas and pursued political office. At 32, he became one of the youngest governors ever in the country.</p>
<p>Two years later, he was voted out of office, and -- as historian Russell Riley notes -- he became the youngest <em>former</em> governor.</p>
<p>And that is how a good deal of Clinton's political career continued: in a pattern of successes and failures.</p>
<p>His successes often came as a result of his <strong>centrist</strong> policies, which appealed to people of different political beliefs. He also was an effective public speaker and, to many, a likable, charismatic person who seemed to care deeply about others.</p>
<p>But, his critics pointed out, Clinton also appeared to make many decisions simply for political advantage. And he sometimes tried to please so many people that he pleased no one.</p>
<p>Following a series of increasingly national roles – as well as a series of setbacks – Clinton campaigned for president in 1992. At first, he did not do well in the campaign. He was young and not well-known. He also suffered from reports that he had relationships with women who were not his wife.</p>
<p>But in time, Clinton began winning primary contests. Reporters called him the "Comeback Kid." He earned a public image as a politician who could survive problems.</p>
<p>In the general election, Clinton competed against the sitting president, Republican George H.W. Bush. The two men also faced an unusually strong third-party candidate named Ross Perot.</p>
<p>On Election Night, Clinton prevailed. Because Americans had split their votes among three major candidates, Clinton earned less than 50% of the popular vote. But he won enough electoral votes to become the next U.S. president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>The people who worked on Bill Clinton's presidential campaign adopted an informal motto. They said, "It's the economy, stupid." In other words, campaign officials believed that most Americans cared primarily about how a president's policies would affect their financial concerns.</p>
<p>So, President Clinton quickly set about making a series of economic changes. They included raising taxes on wealthier Americans and cutting spending to help poorer Americans.</p>
<p>In a few years, the U.S. budget deficit was gone, the federal government had a surplus, and the country's financial situation was strong and healthy – although not everyone approved of the steps Clinton took to get there, or believed he should get all the credit.</p>
<p>Early in his first term, Clinton sought an additional reform he believed would help voters' financial concerns: affordable health insurance for all Americans. Most people in the U.S. either bought private health insurance or did not have any insurance to help pay for medical costs. Clinton wanted to find a way for the U.S. government to support Americans' health-related expenses.</p>
<p>He appointed his wife, first lady Hillary Clinton, to lead a healthcare reform effort. Hillary Clinton, a lawyer, had led a similar effort to reform education in Arkansas when her husband was governor there.</p>
<p>But some lawmakers in Congress – as well as some voters – rejected her efforts. The reform effort failed.</p>
<p>Clinton also struggled in some early foreign policy moves. He withdrew American troops from Somalia after their humanitarian efforts there turned into a bloody military struggle.</p>
<p>He was also criticized for failing to intervene quickly in the genocide in Rwanda, where hundreds of thousands of people were killed.</p>
<p>Later, Clinton won praise for some of his foreign policy. His government helped restore the elected president in Haiti after a coup. It also helped negotiate peace agreements in Bosnia and Ireland. And it cooperated with NATO to intervene in the Kosovo area and stop attacks on Albanians there.</p>
<p>In general, Clinton believed the U.S. had an important role to play in maintaining peace and protecting human life around the world. At the same time, he did not want to use too many American resources to do so. He aimed to cooperate with other nations, and to set moderate goals.</p>
<p>As usual, Clinton adopted an approach that was not too extreme on one side or another.</p>
<p><strong>Impeachment</strong></p>
<p>During most of his time as president, Clinton had been under investigation. Federal judges had appointed a special counsel, named Kenneth Starr, to find out if the president had committed any crimes related to financial investments before he took office.</p>
<p>During the investigation, Starr learned that the president had been having a sexual relationship with a young woman who worked in the White House. Starr asked Clinton about the affair under oath.</p>
<p>Later, Starr accused Clinton of lying about his relationship with the woman. Starr said that Clinton had also tried to prevent others from telling the truth about some of his activities.</p>
<p>In time, the president publicly admitted the relationship, and he apologized to voters and his family. But he said he had not lied or told anyone else to lie for him.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the House of Representatives did not accept Clinton's defense. They advanced two articles of impeachment.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the U.S. Senate then considered the case. It is their job to examine the evidence and decide whether to remove a president from office. A majority did not believe the actions Clinton was accused of were serious violations against the country. They voted to acquit Clinton of the charges and permit him to continue as president.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>In the U.S., a president can serve only two full terms. After his second, Bill Clinton and his wife settled in a town outside New York City. In time, Hillary Clinton became the U.S. senator from New York, as well as a secretary of state and the Democratic Party's candidate for president.</p>
<p>Bill Clinton, like many other U.S. presidents, wrote about his experiences and helped develop his presidential library. He also worked on humanitarian, health, and economic issues with his family's organization, the Clinton Foundation.</p>
<p>For many, Clinton's time in office is remembered as a mixed experience. The economy was at one of its strongest in U.S. history. Most people could find jobs, and many Americans bought homes for the first time. In the mid-1990s especially, the Internet and other new developments created a technology boom.</p>
<p>In addition, Clinton was an effective public speaker, and he inspired new groups of people to support his Democratic Party. Many voters approved of his appointments of women and minorities to positions of power in his government. They also liked the steps he took to reduce the use of handguns, protect the environment, and provide paid time off work for some people to care for themselves or their families.</p>
<p>But both Democrats and Republicans found fault with some of Clinton's efforts. And even his supporters note that the president had to spend much of his time in office answering charges of wrongdoing.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impeach</strong> - <em>v. </em>to charge (a public official) with a crime done while in office</p>
<p><strong>clerk</strong> - <em>n. </em>a person whose job is to keep track of records and documents for a business or office</p>
<p><strong>centrist </strong>- <em>adj.</em> having political opinions that are not extreme; having beliefs fall between those of liberals and conservatives</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Did People Search for in 2023?  (2023/12/16) | 谷歌发布2023年度热搜榜</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-did-people-search-for-in-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Google, the most popular internet search engine, releases its "Year in Search 2023" this week.<br/>
互联网最热门搜索引擎谷歌本周公布了“2023年热搜榜”。</p>
<p>Around the world, Google says the "war in Israel and Gaza" was the top search for news. The ongoing war topped searches for "Titanic submarine," which imploded in June, and February's "Turkey earthquake," which killed at least 50,000 in Turkey and Syria.<br/>
谷歌表示，在世界各地，“以色列和加沙战争”是新闻热搜榜首。这场正在进行的战争超过了对今年6月内爆的“泰坦尼克号潜艇”和2月在土耳其和叙利亚造成至少5万人死亡的“土耳其地震”的搜索。</p>
<p>Damar Hamlin was Google's top trending person on search this year. He is an American football player who collapsed as his heart stopped suddenly during a game in January. People also searched for Travis Kelce. In case you have not heard, Kelce is another American football player who is dating singer Taylor Swift.<br/>
达马尔·哈姆林是谷歌今年搜索量最高的人物。他是一名美式橄榄球运动员，在一月份的一场比赛中因心脏骤停而倒下。人们也在搜索特拉维斯·凯尔斯。为了防止你没有听过，凯尔斯是正在与歌手泰勒·斯威夫特约会的另一位美式橄榄球运动员。</p>
<p>Among those who passed away, people want to know about Matthew Perry, a well-known actor in the American television show Friends. Singers Tina Turner of the United States and Sinéad O'Connor from Ireland rounded out the top three.<br/>
在逝者当中，人们想要了解美国电视节目《老友记》中的著名演员马修·佩里。美国歌手蒂娜·特纳和爱尔兰歌手希妮德·奥康娜跻身前三。</p>
<p>In the world of movies, Barbie and Oppenheimer were not only the top Hollywood money-makers but also the top searches for the year. The two films topped Jawan, an Indian movie seen by millions on the streaming service Netflix.<br/>
在电影界，《芭比》和《奥本海默》不仅是好莱坞的赚钱机器，也是今年的热门搜索对象。这两部电影超过了在流媒体服务Netflix上有数百万观众观看的印度电影《战士》。</p>
<p>Yoasobi's "アイドル (Idol)" was the most searched song on Google this year. The Japanese musical group is made up of producer Ayase and singer Ikura. Inter Miami CF, the new home of Argentine soccer player Lionel Messi, led Google's sports teams search. And Bibimbap, a Korean meal of rice, vegetables, egg and protein, was the top search for a recipe.<br/>
夜游乐队的《偶像》是今年谷歌搜索量最高的歌曲。这个日本乐队由制作人Ayase和歌手几田莉拉组成。阿根廷足球运动员莱昂内尔·梅西的新东家迈阿密国际足球俱乐部在谷歌的运动队搜索中排名第一。由大米、蔬菜、鸡蛋和蛋白质组成的韩国餐石锅拌饭在搜索食谱时排名第一。</p>
<p>Google says information on the top search results came from January 1 through November 27 of this year. Search results are presented worldwide as well as individually for nearly 50 countries.<br/>
谷歌表示，排名第一的搜索结果信息来自今年1月1日至11月27日。搜索结果显示在全球范围内以及近50个国家/地区。</p>
<p>In India, the top news search was for Chandrayaan-3, the spacecraft that touched down on the moon in August. The successful landing made India only the fourth country to land on the moon.<br/>
在印度，最热门的新闻搜索是“月船3号”，这是今年8月登陆月球的航天器。这次成功着陆使印度成为第四个登上月球的国家。</p>
<p>Typhoon Kanun and Jeon Cheongjo were the top news searches in South Korea. And Ashura and Güllac, national dishes often made during religious celebrations, were the top recipes in Turkey.<br/>
台风卡努和全清道是韩国最热门的新闻搜索。在土耳其，经常在宗教庆祝活动中制作的民族菜肴阿舒拉和古拉克是最受欢迎的食谱。</p>
<p>To mark the search engine's 25th birthday, Google also released top search data "of all time" across several areas. Since 2004 (when the company's search data first became available worldwide), the most-Googled Grammy winner of all time has been Beyoncé. Portuguese soccer great Cristiano Ronaldo is the highest-searched athlete, and the most-searched movie or television program is Harry Potter.<br/>
为了纪念该搜索引擎25周年，谷歌还发布了几个领域“有史以来”的热门搜索数据。自2004年（该公司的搜索数据首次在全球范围内公布）以来，有史以来谷歌搜索次数最多的格莱美奖得主是碧昂斯。葡萄牙足球巨星克里斯蒂亚诺·罗纳尔多是搜索量最高的运动员，而搜索量最高的电影或电视节目是《哈利·波特》。</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'The Gift of the Magi,' by O. Henry  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-gift-of-the-magi-o-henry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Karen Leggett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p><em>Editor's Note: We are pleased to share a traditional holiday story with you, 'The Gift of the Magi' by O. Henry. </em><em>Karen Leggett adapted this story for VOA Learning English. Your storyteller was Shep O'Neal. The producer was Lawan Davis.</em></p>
<p>One dollar and eighty-seven cents. That was all. And sixty cents of it in the smallest pieces of money - pennies. Pennies saved one and two at a time by <strong>negotiating</strong> with the men at the market who sold vegetables and meat. Negotiating until one's face burned with the silent knowledge of being poor. Three times Della counted it. One dollar and eighty-seven cents. And the next day would be Christmas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Gift of the Magi" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/36fb8ef4-a6ec-4ed7-a573-0924aaa83d0d_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Gift of the Magi</span></div>
<p>There was clearly nothing to do but sit down and cry. So Della cried. Which led to the thought that life is made up of little cries and smiles, with more little cries than smiles.</p>
<p>Della finished her crying and dried her face. She stood by the window and looked out unhappily at a gray cat walking along a gray fence in a gray back yard. Tomorrow would be Christmas Day, and she had only one dollar and eighty-seven cents to buy her husband Jim a gift. She had been saving every penny she could for months, with this result.</p>
<p>Jim earned twenty dollars a week, which does not go far. Expenses had been greater than she had expected. They always are. Many a happy hour she had spent planning to buy something nice for him. Something fine and rare -- something close to being worthy of the honor of belonging to Jim.</p>
<p>There was a tall glass mirror between the windows of the room. Suddenly Della turned from the window and stood before the glass mirror and looked at herself. Her eyes were shining, but her face had lost its color within twenty seconds. Quickly she pulled down her hair and let it fall to its full length.</p>
<p>Now, Mr. and Mrs. James Dillingham Young had two possessions which they valued. One was Jim's gold time piece, the watch that had been his father's and his grandfather's. The other was Della's hair.</p>
<p>Had the Queen of Sheba lived in their building, Della would have let her hair hang out the window to dry just to reduce the value of the queen's jewels.</p>
<p>So now Della's beautiful hair fell about her, shining like a brown waterfall. It reached below her knees and made itself almost like a covering for her. And then quickly she put it up again. She stood still while a few tears fell on the floor.</p>
<p>She put on her coat and her old brown hat. With a quick motion and brightness still in her eyes, she danced out the door and down the street.</p>
<p>Where she stopped the sign read: "Madame Sofronie. Hair Goods of All Kinds." Della ran up the steps to the shop, out of breath.</p>
<p>"Will you buy my hair?" asked Della.</p>
<p>"I buy hair," said Madame. "Take your hat off and let us have a look at it."</p>
<p>Down came the beautiful brown waterfall of hair.</p>
<p>"Twenty dollars," said Madame, lifting the hair with an experienced hand.</p>
<p>"Give it to me quick," said Della.</p>
<p>The next two hours went by as if they had wings. Della looked in all the stores to choose a gift for Jim.</p>
<p>She found it at last. It surely had been made for Jim and no one else. It was a chain -- simple round rings of silver. It was perfect for Jim's gold watch. As soon as she saw it she knew that it must be for him. It was like him. Quiet and with great value. She gave the shopkeeper twenty-one dollars and she hurried home with the eighty-seven cents that was left.</p>
<p>When Della arrived home she began to repair what was left of her hair. The hair had been ruined by her love and her desire to give a special gift. Repairing the damage was a very big job.</p>
<p>Within forty minutes her head was covered with tiny round curls of hair that made her look wonderfully like a schoolboy. She looked at herself in the glass mirror long and carefully.</p>
<p>"If Jim does not kill me before he takes a second look at me," she said to herself, "he'll say I look like a song girl. But what could I do--oh! what could I do with a dollar and eighty-seven cents?"</p>
<p>At seven o'clock that night the coffee was made and the pan on the back of the stove was hot and ready to cook the meat.</p>
<p>Jim was never late coming home from work. Della held the silver chain in her hand and sat near the door. Then she heard his step and she turned white for just a minute. She had a way of saying a little silent prayer about the simplest everyday things, and now she whispered: "Please God, make him think I am still pretty."</p>
<p>The door opened and Jim stepped in. He looked thin and very serious. Poor man, he was only twenty-two and he had to care for a wife. He needed a new coat and gloves to keep his hands warm.</p>
<p>Jim stopped inside the door, as <strong>immovable</strong> as a dog smelling a bird. His eyes were fixed upon Della. There was an <strong>expression</strong> in them that she could not read, and it frightened her. It was not anger, nor surprise, nor fear, nor any of the feelings that she had been prepared for. He simply looked at her with a strange expression on his face. Della went to him.</p>
<p>"Jim, my love," she cried, "do not look at me that way. I had my hair cut and sold because I could not have lived through Christmas without giving you a gift. My hair will grow out again. I just had to do it. My hair grows very fast. Say 'Merry Christmas!' Jim, and let us be happy. You do not know what a nice-- what a beautiful, nice gift I have for you."</p>
<p>"You have cut off your hair?" asked Jim, slowly, as if he had not accepted the information even after his mind worked very hard.</p>
<p>"Cut it off and sold it," said Della. "Do you not like me just as well? I am the same person without my hair, right?</p>
<p>Jim looked about the room as if he were looking for something.</p>
<p>"You say your hair is gone?" he asked.</p>
<p>"You need not look for it," said Della. "It is sold, I tell you--sold and gone, too. It is Christmas Eve, boy. Be good to me, for it was cut for you. Maybe the hairs of my head were numbered," she went on with sudden serious sweetness, "but nobody could ever count my love for you. Shall I put the meat on, Jim?"</p>
<p>Jim seemed to awaken quickly and put his arms around Della. Then he took a package from his coat and threw it on the table.</p>
<p>"Do not make any mistake about me, Dell," he said. "I do not think there is any haircut that could make me like my girl any less. But if you will open that package you may see why you had me frightened at first."</p>
<p>White fingers quickly tore at the string and paper. There was a scream of joy; and then, alas! a change to tears and cries, requiring the man of the house to use all his skill to calm his wife.</p>
<p>For there were the combs -- the special set of objects to hold her hair that Della had wanted ever since she saw them in a shop window. Beautiful combs, made of shells, with jewels at the edge --just the color to wear in the beautiful hair that was no longer hers. They cost a lot of money, she knew, and her heart had wanted them without ever hoping to have them. And now, the beautiful combs were hers, but the hair that should have touched them was gone.</p>
<p>But she held the combs to herself, and soon she was able to look up with a smile and say, "My hair grows so fast, Jim!"</p>
<p>Then Della jumped up like a little burned cat and cried, "Oh, oh!"</p>
<p>Jim had not yet seen his beautiful gift. She happily held it out to him in her open hands. The silver chain seemed so bright.</p>
<p>"Isn't it wonderful, Jim? I looked all over town to find it. You will have to look at the time a hundred times a day now. Give me your watch. I want to see how it looks on it."</p>
<p>Instead of obeying, Jim fell on the couch and put his hands under the back of his head and smiled.</p>
<p>"Dell," said he, "let us put our Christmas gifts away and keep them a while. They are too nice to use just right now. I sold my gold watch to get the money to buy the set of combs for your hair. And now, why not put the meat on."</p>
<p>The <strong>magi</strong> were wise men--wonderfully wise men--who brought gifts to the Baby Jesus. They invented the art of giving Christmas gifts. Being wise, their gifts were wise ones. And here I have told you the story of two young people who most unwisely gave for each other the greatest treasures of their house. But in a last word to the wise of these days, let it be said that of all who give gifts, these two were the wisest. Everywhere they are wisest. They are the magi.</p>
<p><em>Download activities to help you understand this story <a class="wsw__a" href="https://docs.voanews.eu/en-US-LEARN/2014/12/23/802e047a-0721-4918-b463-4bf5926937b0.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.</em></p>
<p><em>Now it's your turn. Write to us in the Comments section or on <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com" target="_blank">51VOA.COM</a> about a very special gift you received</em></p>
<p></p><p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><small><big>Words in This Story</big></small></h2>
<p><strong>negotiate</strong> - <em>v.</em> to discuss something formally in order to make an agreement</p>
<p><strong>immovable</strong> - <em>adj. </em>not able to be moved <strong>:</strong> firmly fixed in place</p>
<p><strong>expression</strong> - <em>n. </em> the way someone's face looks that shows emotions and feelings</p>
<p><strong>magi </strong>- <em>n.</em> the wise men, generally assumed to be three in number, who paid homage to the infant Jesus. Matt. 2:1–12.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indigenous Women Bring Amazon Tribe Back from Near Extinction  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/indigenous-women-bring-amazon-tribe-back-from-near-extinction.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Juma are native people of the Amazon rain forest area in Brazil. In the 1990s, there were only four people remaining in the tribe.</p>
<p>They were Aruká, the father, and his three daughters – Boreá, Mandeí and Maytá.</p>
<p>In 2021, Aruká died from COVID-19. The news appeared around the world. The <em>New York Times</em> newspaper wrote the "last man of his tribe" was gone and many people believed the tribe would go <strong>extinct</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Juma Indigenous sisters Mandei Juma, from left, Mayta Juma and Borea Juma pose for a picture at their community, near Canutama, Amazonas state, Brazil, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Andre Penner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1acf682b-c57a-41bf-88fa-e863222f2c27_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Juma Indigenous sisters Mandei Juma, from left, Mayta Juma and Borea Juma pose for a picture at their community, near Canutama, Amazonas state, Brazil, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Andre Penner)</span></div>
<p>The tribe, in the past, was built upon the idea that men had to be in charge. Once the last man died, the tribe would no longer exist.</p>
<p>But the daughters had a different idea. Before Aruká died, he and his daughters started thinking about a way to keep the tribe alive by choosing a female leader.</p>
<p>Mandeí said her sisters and father wanted her to take the position. So, Mandeí became the first woman chief in the area.</p>
<p>Earlier in their lives, the Juma sisters married men from other tribes to make sure their family line could continue.</p>
<p>Over many years, the number of Juma people has grown. In the area that is now Juma territory, there is a lot of activity. Children play in the river. People catch fish. Women work to make flour from the cassava root. Others hunt in the forest.</p>
<p>They also gather at a community building called a maloca, to eat, take care of animals, rest, and use their phones. The building has mobile phone signal equipment.</p>
<p>Aruká, the last Juma male leader, is buried under the maloca.</p>
<p>Mandeí recently retired as leader. Her older sister, Boreá, is chief now.</p>
<p>Mandeí said she found leadership difficult, at first. She said other people did not treat the Juma with respect because the tribe was so small. People also opposed her leadership because she is female, she said.</p>
<p>It hurt her but did not stop her. "I <strong>adapted</strong> to seek solutions for our people," she said.</p>
<p>The Juma territory needs a strong leader. It is about the size of a large city, similar to Las Vegas, Nevada. Old-growth forest covers the land. A Juma leader's main job is to protect the territory and its natural wealth from outsiders.</p>
<p>People come and cut down the trees. They then use the cleared land to plant grasses that are used to raise animals.</p>
<p>The changes are damaging to the traditional life of native people. Developers plan to build a road nearby. The Juma say that will bring more people and industry to the area. Mandeí says the environment is already changing.</p>
<p>"The river doesn't fill with water as it used to ... The water shouldn't dry up so much like this. It's much hotter, it wasn't like this before. Our concern is: Why is this happening? Because of deforestation," she said.</p>
<p>The Juma people work to protect their land – they move around the territory by boat and even use <strong>drones</strong> to view their land from above.</p>
<p>Mandeí's nephew, Puré, is one of the guards. He said he is proud to be a Juma and protect the land.</p>
<p>He said he broke the rules and followed his mother's lineage. "If I don't identify myself as Juma, who else will?"</p>
<p>Puré's mother married a man from another tribe. When he was born, he was registered as a member of his father's tribe. But at 15, he decided to add the Juma name, his mother's name, to his name. He had to visit Brazil's indigenous people's office to make the change.</p>
<p>Two of his cousins also added Juma to their names.</p>
<p>There were not many Juma people to begin with. Experts on Brazil's native people say before non-indigenous people made contact with the Juma, there were probably a few thousand. The Juma fought the invaders and suffered major losses in battle. A book by a German Christian clergyman<strong> </strong>says the last attack on the Juma came in 1964. Over 30 people were killed, including Aruká's father.</p>
<p>Later, when Mandeí became the leader, she asked for help in saving the Juma language. In 2019, she invited a language expert to visit and help create a dictionary for use with mobile phones. They also created digital records of the language with stories, speeches, and songs in the Juma language.</p>
<p>Wesley dos Santos went to Brazil to work on the project. He is a graduate student at the University of California – Berkeley. He said the language, Kawahiva, is endangered. It is only used by 560 people. One of its variations is Juma, and there are seven others.</p>
<p>Mandeí said she is concerned that the language and the people who speak it will disappear one day. There are only 24 people living in the Juma village. The three sisters are still trying to decide how to pass down the Juma traditions to the people who come after them.</p>
<p>"The largest responsibility I share with my sisters is not to lose Juma culture as taught by our father," Mandeí said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>–n.</em> no longer existing</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong><em>–v.</em> to change based on new information</p>
<p><strong>drone</strong><em>–n.</em> a small flying robot that often has a camera</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wondering About Wonder?  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/wondering-about-wonder.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the word "wonder" as a noun and a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-36f1-08dbfc22883a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am one of your followers from Iran.</p>
<p>I have question about the word "wonder."</p>
<p>How can I use it as a noun and a verb in a sentence in various ways?</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>Ali</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, especially for the month of December, Ali. We sometimes describe Christmas as "the most wonderful time of the year." The expression comes from a song by Andy Williams.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>"Wonderful" mean full of wonder. But what exactly is "wonder?"</p>
<p>In today's Ask a Teacher will we answer your question by looking at "wonder" as a noun and a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Wonder as a noun</strong></p>
<p>"Wonder" is the feeling of surprise and <strong>amazement</strong> usually caused by something that is new, strange, unexpected or different. It can also be something that people can <strong>admire</strong> or love and want to protect.</p>
<p><em>The <strong>roaming</strong> cats of Old San Juan are one of the wonders of Puerto Rico.</em></p>
<p>You may have heard people say, "no wonder." This is another way of saying "it is not surprising." For example:</p>
<p><em>It is no wonder that the meeting started late. Everyone was stuck in traffic!</em></p>
<p>Now let's look at "wonder" as a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Wonder as verb</strong></p>
<p>"Wonder" can mean to be in a state of surprise.</p>
<p><em>I always wonder at Amaury Guichon's life-size chocolate <strong>sculptures</strong> of things like dragons and giraffes!</em></p>
<p>It can also mean to think about something because it interests you.</p>
<p><em>I wonder what the economy will be like after inflation.</em></p>
<p><em>Jessica wondered where her next vacation would be: Scotland or Thailand?</em></p>
<p>We can also use "wonder" to make <strong>formal</strong> and polite requests.</p>
<p><em>I wonder if you could pick me up at the train station next week.</em></p>
<p>"Wonder" can also be used as an adjective. We use "wonder" to describe something that is extraordinary.</p>
<p><em>Wonder Woman has superhuman strength and the ability to fly!</em></p>
<p><em>There were many wonder drugs developed in the 20<sup>th</sup> century, including penicillin and insulin.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Ali.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>amazement </strong>– n. a feeling of being very surprised or shocked</p>
<p><strong>admire</strong> – <em>v</em>. to feel respect or approval of someone</p>
<p><strong>roam</strong><em> </em>— <em>v. </em>to go to different places without having a particular purpose or plan</p>
<p><strong>sculpture</strong> – n. a form of art in which hard materials are worked into object that has width, height, and depth</p>
<p><strong>formal </strong>–<em> adj. </em>serious and official</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mobile App Helps People Seeking Money from Strangers  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/mobile-app-helps-people-seeking-money-from-strangers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Do you still leave home with money in your <strong>pocket</strong>?</p>
<p>Now that many stores have gone "cashless" and most people do not have money in their pocket, those who once depended on <strong>handouts</strong> from strangers often end the day empty-handed.</p>
<p>Many people without homes or jobs say they are not able to get much money from strangers anymore.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A vendor selling Street Sense holds up her sign saying she can accept donations from cashless apps like Venmo and CashApp, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d2b79979-0c18-45d9-b926-870c16882d31_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A vendor selling Street Sense holds up her sign saying she can accept donations from cashless apps like Venmo and CashApp, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)</span></div>
<p>John Littlejohn is 62 years old and lives in Washington, D.C. He said he has been homeless for 13 years. In recent years, he said, people would tell him they left home without any money.</p>
<p>"I would be out here for six or seven hours and wouldn't get more than $12 to $15," he said.</p>
<p>People can use <strong>apps</strong> on their mobile phones to pay for most things, so they do not leave home with bills or coins. For a while, those without homes and <strong>charities</strong> that depended on <strong>spare</strong> change suffered.</p>
<p>But they are using technology, too.</p>
<p>Littlejohn sells copies of a newspaper called <em>Street Sense</em>. It is published by a nonprofit organization that says it helps homeless people. Now people who want to buy the newspaper can use an app. The money goes directly to the seller. Littlejohn is able to pay for an apartment with the money he gets from selling <em>Street Sense</em> and also other jobs he does.</p>
<p>Some people who stand outside public places such as subway stations and ask for money are called panhandlers. Sylvester Harris is one of them. He talked to a reporter near a subway station close to a large sports center in Washington, D.C. He said people often look like they want to give him money, but they do not have coins or bills.</p>
<p>"Everybody just has (credit cards) or their phones now," he said.</p>
<p>Homeless people often do not have bank accounts, credit cards or real identification that would permit them to use a mobile phone app to get money.</p>
<p>The cashless society also used to be a problem for a charity organization called the Salvation Army. The group is known for sending people to stand in busy places with a big red cooking pot, known as a kettle. People walk past the kettle and drop a dollar or a few coins inside.</p>
<p>However, as more people started using their phones and credit cards to make payments, the Salvation Army was receiving less money.</p>
<p>Now, the organization permits people to make donations by <strong>tapping</strong> their phones on the red kettle.</p>
<p>Michelle Wolf is with the Salvation Army in Washington. She said the technology is only available in a few places around the city, but it already has brought in more money.</p>
<p>Most people give $5 and often people give $20, she said.</p>
<p>The head of <em>Street Sense</em> said he started to see a problem about 10 years ago. Those who sold his newspapers said people did not have money to buy them.</p>
<p>"We were losing sales," said Brian Canmore. "Times were changing, and we had to change with them."</p>
<p>He heard that a similar newspaper in Vancouver, Canada created a payment app. Now the newspaper in Washington uses the same technology.</p>
<p>Thomas Ratliff also works for <em>Street Sense</em>. He is in charge of the 100 sellers around Washington. He said a big problem started in 2020 when many workers stayed home because of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>He said people who came to Washington for work were the main buyers of the newspaper. Many of those people are still not coming into the city. Now the sellers take the subway to busier areas outside of Washington, D.C. in Maryland and Virginia to sell the papers.</p>
<p>Ratliff noted that some payment apps that do not require a bank account -- Venmo and Cash App – still require a steady mobile phone number. But the sellers often change their number and then they have trouble getting paid.</p>
<p>There is a way for homeless people without jobs to get money in the cashless society. They can use the Samaritan app. It permits people to give money to someone just by <strong>scanning</strong> a special <strong>code </strong>– a QR code – with their phone. People who scan the code can read a story about the person and donate money that is meant to be used for buying food or clothing.</p>
<p>Jon Kumar started the Samaritan app. Charities pay him to use his technology for their work. He said it is hard to walk past a person when you know their story. His app, he said, "personalizes the person in need."</p>
<p>The people who use the app to ask for money must meet with a case manager to claim their money. The manager can also help the person with services, such as directing them to counseling or drug <strong>rehabilitation</strong>.</p>
<p>None of the apps or new technology will solve every problem for homeless people. Many people do not have the ability to sell newspapers, for example. Others are too old to work so they depend on asking people for money. Not everyone has a mobile phone.</p>
<p>Kumar said some people are "not a great fit" for this kind of intervention. He said some people need more support than a phone app can offer.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pocket <i></i>173;</strong>–n. a small cloth container sewed into some clothing</p>
<p><strong>app (application) </strong>–n. a computer application.</p>
<p><strong>charity</strong>—n. a not-for-profit organization that aims to do some good in society</p>
<p><strong>spare </strong>–adj. something that is extra</p>
<p><strong>tap </strong>–v. to lightly touch</p>
<p><strong>scan </strong>–v. to use a machine to take a picture to record an image of something like a document or other media</p>
<p><strong>code (QR) </strong>–n. a special sign that can be scanned and which directs the scanning device to a website that provides additional information</p>
<p><strong>rehabilitation </strong>–n. the process of trying to bring someone back to normal or health after an illness, drug problem or similar difficulty</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indonesian Bird Could Face New Threat from Capital City Development  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/indonesian-bird-could-face-new-threat-from-capital-city-development.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>An endangered bird in Indonesia could face new threats from development linked to the country's new capital city.</p>
<p>The bird is the maleo, a tall animal with black feathers and a pink chest. It is native to Indonesia's Sulawesi island and a few neighboring ones.</p>
<p>The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) considers the maleo to be "critically endangered." The environmental group's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/">Red List</a> identifies wildlife across the world currently facing threats. The IUCN estimates only 8,000 to 14,000 adult maleos remain in the wild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A pair of maleos look for a spot to lay an egg in Mamuju, West Sulawesi, Indonesia, Friday, Oct. 27, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a648-08dbfa7eeb88_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A pair of maleos look for a spot to lay an egg in Mamuju, West Sulawesi, Indonesia, Friday, Oct. 27, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)</span></div>
<p>West Sulawesi has been set up as a "support" area for building activities. The Indonesian government plans to move the nation's capital from Jakarta to a new city on Borneo island. West Sulawesi and Borneo are separated by an ocean passageway called the Makassar Strait and are just a six-hour boat trip apart.</p>
<p>Support work will take place in areas around West Sulawesi's capital, Mamuju. The development is expected to include the building of new roads and seaports to be used to transport materials to the new capital, named Nusantara, on Borneo.</p>
<p>Activities include tree clearing, digging, and removing stones. The process already has changed the forest environment on West Sulawesi and is harming maleo <strong>nesting</strong> areas near the beach.</p>
<p>These latest changes follow others to the birds' general environment, or habitat, linked to human activities in the area. These changes have made the trip for maleos to lay their eggs increasingly more difficult.</p>
<p>The maleo is considered "critically endangered because the next step is <strong>extinction</strong>," said biologist Marcy Summers. She directs the Alliance for Tompotika Conservation, a non-governmental organization working to support maleo <strong>conservation</strong> in the area. Summers noted that maleo populations had decreased by more than 80 percent since 1980.</p>
<p>Experts do not know how many maleos still live around Mamuju or across West Sulawesi island. The West Sulawesi Forestry Agency was only able to record the presence of nesting grounds in 23 villages based on reports from locals in the area. But of those, only 18 are considered active nesting areas.</p>
<p>"As far as I know, maleo birds are in <strong>decline</strong>," said Andi Aco Takdir, chief of the West Sulawesi Forestry Agency. He pointed to several reasons for the decline, including destruction of beach areas, and expanding human development activities.</p>
<p>Takdir said the government has been warning people in the area to stop establishing palm oil operations and to halt all other development around maleo nesting grounds.</p>
<p>Officials said the government is committed to keeping the birds even with massive development to support the new capital city.</p>
<p>Another problem has been thieves, also called poachers. The Associated Press reports that poachers steal maleo eggs from the sand where their parents have hidden them.</p>
<p>Poachers sell the eggs for about $1 to people as food. The eggs are a traditional gift for many people in Mamuju and other parts of Sulawesi.</p>
<p>Muhammad Idris is a local official in West Sulawesi. He told the AP that government officials there are prepared to take steps to protect the maleos even with the new capital development.</p>
<p>Idris said, "Nature conservation must be used as an <strong>achievement </strong>and (projects) must not be built leaving behind problems."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nest </strong><em>– v. </em>a home built by birds for their eggs and by some other creatures to live in</p>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>no longer existing on Earth</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>decline </strong><em>– v. </em>to go down in amount, importance, quality, etc.</p>
<p><strong>achievement </strong><em>– n. </em>something good that you achieve: to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boston Common: America’s First Public Park  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/boston-common-america-s-first-public-park.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Almost 400 years ago, America's early European colonists voted to tax each household in Boston about $70 in today's money. The money was used to buy a local farm. The plan was to use it as a common area for the public.</p>
<p>That is how Boston Common, in the state of Massachusetts, became America's first public <strong>park.</strong></p>
<p>Liz Vizza is president of the Friends of the Public Garden, an organization that supports Boston Common. She noted that Bostonians did not have backyards – private outdoor spaces behind their homes. Boston Common, she said, became "their front yard and backyard and common ground. It was a place that everybody owned."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Oldest Public Park" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d371-08dbf4d37028_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Oldest Public Park</span></div>
<p>On any given day, colonists walking though Boston Common would see soldiers setting up camp or their neighbors taking walks. They may also have seen public punishments. Presidents George Washington and John Adams also visited the park.</p>
<p>Visitors would have seen cows, because everyone had the right to keep one cow per household in the area.</p>
<p>Today, visitors will find dogs instead of cows in the 20-hectare park. The cows became outlawed in 1830 as Boston Common became more of a place for <strong>recreation</strong>.</p>
<p>Friends of the Public Garden estimates that Boston Common sees 7 million visitors each year.</p>
<p>"Boston Common is a central stage of <strong>civic</strong> life in Boston and it's been that center stage of civic life for hundreds of years, ever since it began as a park in 1634," Vizza said. "America's oldest park is a place where we come to celebrate, we come to protest, we come to find a place alone," she added.</p>
<p>Boston Common is home to several large pieces of art. They include "The Embrace," a <strong>sculpture </strong>that shows civil rights leader Martin Luther King, Jr. holding his wife, Coretta Scott King. The Brewer Fountain was the park's first public piece of art. It won the top award at the 1855 World's Fair in Paris, France.</p>
<p>The pieces of art found on the Common may soon change to include a wider selection of subjects.</p>
<p>Vizza said, "We want people to look at it with new eyes and just have a deeper understanding and respect and <strong>awareness</strong> of the history."</p>
<p>That history includes the native Massachusett tribe, the first people to live where the Common is now. The state of Massachusetts is named after the Massachusett people.</p>
<p>Vizza said, "People have lived on this land for 12,000 years. So, we do want to think about colonial America because that's a <strong>fascinating</strong> story for us. But what's an even more fascinating story is to <strong>peel</strong> those layers open to think about the Native Americans living here."</p>
<p>Vizza's team is working with tribal members to develop a piece to recognize the Massachusett tribe. They hope to have something in place by 2026, when America will celebrate its 250th birthday.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>park </strong>– <em>n</em>. a piece of public land in or near a city that is kept free of houses and other buildings and can be used for pleasure and exercise</p>
<p><strong>recreation </strong>– <em>n</em>. something people do to relax or have fun: activities done for enjoyment</p>
<p><strong>civic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to a city or town or the people who live there</p>
<p><strong>sculpture </strong>– <em>n</em>. a piece of art that is made by carving or molding clay, stone, or metal</p>
<p><strong>landscape </strong>– <em>n</em>. a picture that shows a natural scene of land or the countryside</p>
<p><strong>awareness </strong>– <em>adj</em>. knowing that something (such as a situation, condition, or problem) exists</p>
<p><strong>fascinating </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very interesting or appealing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar for a Gift-giving Season  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/grammar-for-a-gift-giving-season.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>We are entering a major gift-giving season in the United States. People purchase goods and services for their loved ones, friends, coworkers, and others.</p>
<p>But how do we talk about giving gifts? How do we use subjects, verbs, and objects to describe gift giving?</p>
<p>Those questions will be the subject of today's Everyday Grammar.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0d3b-08dbfcbb1c81_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start with some important terms and ideas.</p>
<p><strong>Elements </strong></p>
<p>In <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-for-giving-gifts/7377191.html" target="_blank">a recent Everyday Grammar lesson</a>, we explored questions about gifts – asking what others might want in terms of a gift.</p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will talk about statements we might make after we purchase the gift.</p>
<p>Before we continue with the lesson, we need to identify the key elements of a sentence.</p>
<p>The simplest way to divide a sentence is into two parts: the subject and the <strong>predicate</strong>.</p>
<p>The subject is generally a noun, noun phrase, or pronoun.</p>
<p>The predicate, on the other hand, says something about the subject. The predicate contains a verb, objects, indirect objects, and so on.</p>
<p>Now that we have our basic building blocks of language, we should explore how to put them together.</p>
<p><strong>Putting elements together </strong></p>
<p>We will start with the predicate. Why? Because the predicate is central to today's lesson.</p>
<p>The language we use in the predicate to describe a gift purchase often falls into a simple <strong>pattern</strong>: transitive verb + noun <strong>phrase</strong> 1+noun phrase 2.</p>
<p>A transitive verb is one that takes a direct object. A direct object is the receiver of the verb's action.</p>
<p>So, in the pattern we just learned about, we can say that the transitive verb takes a noun phrase that acts like the direct object.</p>
<p>Finally, we might have a second noun phrase that acts like the indirect object – the person who receives the direct object.</p>
<p>Please note that the direct object does not always appear directly next to the verb, as we will see.</p>
<p>Some examples will clarify this explanation.</p>
<p><strong>Examples </strong></p>
<p>When we talk about gift giving, we often use three transitive verbs: get, buy, and give.</p>
<p>The direct object is the gift. The indirect object is the person receiving the gift.</p>
<p>So, let's imagine we have a friend named Mary. We might say the following about Mary's gift-giving decision:</p>
<p><em>Mary got her son a book.</em></p>
<p>In our example, the subject is Mary. The predicate is "got her son a book."</p>
<p>The direct object is "a book." What did Mary get? She got a book. Who is going to receive the book? Her son. In this case, "her son" is the indirect object.</p>
<p>So, in the sentence "Mary got her son a book," we can say that the structure is subject + transitive verb + noun phrase 1 + noun phrase 2.</p>
<p>Here are two other examples. Let's use the transitive verbs "buy" and "give":</p>
<p><em>Jonathan bought his mother a sweater.</em></p>
<p><em>Felicia gave her friend a painting.</em></p>
<p>All of these examples are in their past forms. But we can also use these verbs in other forms as well.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Create a sentence using the following elements:</p>
<p>The subject is "My father."</p>
<p>The predicate consists of the verb "get," the noun phrase "a <strong>vase</strong>," and the noun phrase "my mother."</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here is one possible answer:</p>
<p><em>My father got my mother a vase.</em></p>
<p>The order of the sentence is subject + transitive verb + indirect object + direct object.</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>Today we explored one pattern we often use to describe gift giving. To be clear: we use other patterns as well.</p>
<p>One of these makes use of the prepositions "to" and "for." But that will have to be the subject of a future lesson.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>predicate</strong><em> – n. grammar:</em> the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
<p><strong>pattern</strong><em> – n.</em> the regular and repeated way in which something happens</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
<p><strong>vase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a container that is used for holding flowers or for decoration</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>At COP28, Nations Agree to Move away from Fossil Fuels  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/at-cop28-nations-agree-to-move-away-from-fossil-fuels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Nearly 200 countries agreed on Wednesday to move away from using planet-warming fossil fuels. The deal came after two weeks of intense negotiations at the 2023 United Nations Climate Change Conference, also known as COP28.</p>
<p>World leaders gathered in Dubai for the meeting. The agreement was meant to send a powerful message that the world is united in its desire to break with fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Scientists say the agreement is the last best hope to prevent climate <strong>catastrophe</strong>. But nations have not always followed climate agreements made in the past.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="U.N. Climate Chief Simon Stiell, from left, COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber and Hana Al-Hashimi, chief COP28 negotiator for the United Arab Emirates, pose at the end of the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, on Dec. 13, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e0edc700-fd42-4143-8e3b-fb56d1f79cb9_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">U.N. Climate Chief Simon Stiell, from left, COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber and Hana Al-Hashimi, chief COP28 negotiator for the United Arab Emirates, pose at the end of the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, on Dec. 13, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)</span></div>
<p>COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber called the deal "historic." He added that its true success would be in taking action. "We are what we do, not what we say," he said. "We must take the steps necessary to turn this agreement into... actions."</p>
<p>Norway's Minister of Foreign Affairs Espen Barth Eide said, "It is the first time that the world unites around such a clear <strong>text</strong> on the need to <strong>transition</strong> away from fossil fuels."</p>
<p>More than 100 countries had pushed for strong language in the COP28 agreement to "<strong>phase out</strong>" oil, gas, and coal use. However, they faced powerful opposition from the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC). The organization controls nearly 80 percent of the world's proven oil reserves as well as about one-third of worldwide oil output. The group, led by Saudi Arabia, said the world can cut emissions without rejecting <strong>specific</strong> fuels.</p>
<p>That dispute had some observers worried that an agreement would not come together.</p>
<p>The lead negotiator for the Alliance of Small Island States, Anne Rasmussen, criticized the deal as not strong enough. But she did not officially object to the agreement. Her speech in Dubai drew a standing <strong>applause</strong> that lasted nearly two minutes.</p>
<p>Danish Minister for Climate and Energy Dan Jorgensen noted one reason the deal was impressive. "We're standing here in an oil country, surrounded by oil countries, and we made the decision saying let's move away from oil and gas," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Transitioning away from fossil fuels</strong></p>
<p>The deal does not call for "phasing out" fossil fuels. It calls for "transitioning away" from fossil fuels to reach "net zero by 2050 in keeping with the science."</p>
<p>In some ways, that language describes what is already happening. Some governments have enacted policies in recent years to move to a greener economy.</p>
<p>Europe and the United States have retired some coal-fired power plants. And many countries have policies meant to increase sales of electric vehicles.</p>
<p>The deal calls on governments to move even faster in several areas. They include increasing renewable energy by three times by 2030, speeding up efforts to reduce coal use, and developing technologies such as carbon capture.</p>
<p>German climate diplomat Jennifer Morgan said there was not much difference between "phasing out" and "transitioning away." She said, "I think the ‘phase-out' was about sending a clear signal. And I think the ‘just transition away from' is a way of phrasing the phase-out" for poorer nations who cannot act as quickly as richer ones.</p>
<p>Li Shuo of the Asia Society told the Associated Press that when the two phrases are <strong>translated</strong> into Mandarin or Japanese, there is almost no difference.</p>
<p>The Reuters news agency reported that a source familiar with Saudi Arabia's position described the deal as "a menu where every country can follow its own pathway."</p>
<p>China, the world's biggest carbon polluter today, suggested that industrialized countries should take the lead.</p>
<p>Zhao Yingmin is China's vice environment minister. He said after the deal was approved, "Developed countries have...historical responsibilities for climate change."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>catastrophe</strong> - n. a terrible disaster</p>
<p><strong>text</strong> - n. words on a writing or document</p>
<p><strong>transition</strong> - n. change from one state to another</p>
<p><strong>phase out</strong> - v. to stop something gradually over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>specific</strong> - adj. special or particular</p>
<p><strong>applause</strong> - n. cheer</p>
<p><strong>translate</strong> - v. to change words from one language to another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Jury Rules Google App Store Operates as Monopoly  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/jury-rules-google-app-store-operates-as-monopoly.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American jury has found that Google's app store operates as an illegal <strong>monopoly</strong>.</p>
<p>The decision came in a lawsuit brought by video game company Epic Games. The jury reached the decision this week in California after a four-week trial.</p>
<p>Epic had argued Google uses business methods that block competition against its Google Play Store. That is where users can download <strong>apps</strong> for smartphones and other devices using the Android operating system (OS). Google owns the Android OS. Epic uses Google Play and other app stores to sell its popular game Fortnite and others.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This March 23, 2010, file photo shows the Google logo at the Google headquarters in Brussels, Belgium. (AP Photo/Virginia Mayo, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/03190000-0aff-0242-5ad4-08da3e6b9459_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This March 23, 2010, file photo shows the Google logo at the Google headquarters in Brussels, Belgium. (AP Photo/Virginia Mayo, File)</span></div>
<p>Experts predict that if the ruling stands, it could cost Google billions of dollars in business. It could also change the way all app stores do business in the future. Google condemned the court's decision and said it will appeal the ruling.</p>
<p>Android holds by far the largest share of the mobile OS market worldwide. Online data researcher Statista <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272698/global-market-share-held-by-mobile-operating-systems-since-2009/">estimated</a> in October that Android had a market share of 70.5 percent. The next closest competitor, Apple, held a market share of 28.8 percent.</p>
<p>Other companies, such as Apple, also operate app stores. Epic brought a similar lawsuit against Apple in 2021. In it, Epic argued Apple used methods in its app store that created a monopoly that blocked competition. A federal judge ruled mostly in Apple's favor in that case. Epic has appealed that ruling.</p>
<p>One of the biggest issues in both cases was whether Google and Apple have the right to require developers to use the app store's payment systems. Such systems can take up to 30 percent of a sale in <strong>commissions</strong> from app developers.</p>
<p>In the case of Epic vs. Apple, the judge mostly sided with Apple. But the judge did find that Apple had used some unfair business methods which violated California law. The judge ordered Apple to permit developers across the United States to add their own links to process payments within iPhone apps.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency reported that Google's appeal will take place in the same court in San Francisco that decided Epic's case against Apple. Epic's appeal of the Apple decision is currently before the U.S. Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The jury in the Epic vs. Google legal case debated for about three hours before giving its decision on Monday. It decided that Google's control of its Play Store amounted to an illegal monopoly. The monopoly covered both Google's app selling system and its payment processing method within the app, the jury found. Epic did not ask the court for financial damages.</p>
<p>Epic chief Tim Sweeney praised the court's decision on X, formerly known as Twitter. "Victory over Google!" Sweeney <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1734370774830797210">wrote</a>. In a company statement, Epic called the <strong>verdict</strong> "a win for all app developers and <strong>consumers</strong> around the world."</p>
<p>Google's vice president of government affairs and public policy, Wilson White, confirmed the company's plan to appeal the ruling. In a statement, he said, "We will continue to defend the Android business model and remain deeply committed to our users, partners, and the broader Android <strong>ecosystem</strong>."</p>
<p>White added his opinion that the Google Play Store currently offers "more choice and openness" than any other major mobile provider.</p>
<p>Depending on how the court's ruling is enforced, Google could lose billions of dollars yearly in commissions on sales through the Play Store. But the company's main source of earnings, online advertising, would not be directly affected by the court's decision.</p>
<p>The case now goes back to the judge in the trial, U.S. District Judge James Donato. He will hear arguments on both sides about how Google should change its business operations to improve fair competition. The judge has suggested this process could begin in the second week of January.</p>
<p>During those hearings, Google will be able to argue against the changes proposed by Epic. In addition, any orders established by the judge at the end could be appealed. These processes, technology experts say, could result in the case extending for many months, or possibly years.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this report for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse.</em></p>
<p><span>___________________________________________________</span></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>monopoly </strong><em>– n. </em>complete control of the entire supply of goods or of a service in a certain area or market</p>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device</p>
<p><strong>commission </strong><em>– n. </em>a payment made to someone who sells goods that is directly related to the amount sold</p>
<p><strong>verdict </strong><em>–n. </em>the decision of a jury in a trial in a court of law</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who buys goods or services<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong><em>– n. </em>all the things that are part of a particular environment or situation</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do You Say That Name Again?  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-do-you-say-that-name-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>News reporters, politicians and public <strong>figures</strong> have had trouble saying some of the words that relate to the top stories of the year year. Last week, the online language learning company Babbel released its lists of the most <strong>mispronounced</strong> words in the United States and Britain.</p>
<p>The two lists are a reminder of the year's news on everything from scientific discoveries to politics.</p>
<p>Babbel teacher Malcolm Massey noted the <strong>diversity</strong> of the words. This year's words come from several different languages.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - SZA arrives at the 64th annual Grammy Awards, April 3, 2022, in Las Vegas. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c42f-08dbfa9cb107_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - SZA arrives at the 64th annual Grammy Awards, April 3, 2022, in Las Vegas. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)
</span></div>
<p>"I think a lot of it is due to how close our cultures have become because of how <strong>globalized</strong> things are," Massey said.</p>
<p><strong>Singers, actors and politicians</strong></p>
<p>A popular singer who spells her name S-Z-A is on the U.S. list. Babbel notes her name is pronounced SIZ-uh,[short I sound].</p>
<p>The first name of another entertainer is also on the list. Cillian Murphy is an Irish actor who starred in this summer's hit as physicist J. Robert Oppenheimer. His first name is pronounced KI-lee-uhn.</p>
<p>Other pronunciations on the U.S. list include the name of biotech businessman Vivek Ramaswamy, who is a Republican presidential candidate. The correct way to say his name is Vih-VAKE Rah-mah-SWAH-me.</p>
<p>Two volcanoes were also on the list — Mexico's Popocatepetl, (Poh-poh-kah-TEH-peh-til), and Hawaii's Kilauea, (Kee-lou-EY-uh).</p>
<p>The winning word at this year's Scripps National Spelling Bee also made the U.S. list. That word was psammophile (SAM-uh-file.) It means any animal or plant that prefers sandy soils or areas.</p>
<p>The <strong>coronation</strong> of King Charles in May helped put the Stone of Scone, (Stown uhv Skoon), on Britain's list. The holy stone rests beneath the Coronation Chair where a new king first receives his crown.</p>
<p>Kristie Denlinger teaches <strong>linguistics</strong> at the University of Texas in Austin. She said hearing an unfamiliar word often enough can help someone master it.</p>
<p>"Anything that is kind of different from what a speaker is used to, they can learn how to pronounce things in different ways than what they're used to, it just takes more <strong>exposure</strong>," Denlinger said.</p>
<p><strong>A personal choice</strong></p>
<p>Massey said that as one learns a new pronunciation, it is important to "not stress perfection but progress over time, so practicing these words again and again."</p>
<p>In some cases, the correct pronunciation is just a matter of personal choice. Earning a place on the U.S. list was the last name of Travis Kelce, the Kansas City Chiefs' American football player. Whether Kelce should be pronounced with one or two syllables, Kels or KEL-See, has been a subject even his own family talks about.</p>
<p>Both Travis and his brother, Philadelphia Eagles center Jason Kelce, say their last name as KEL-see. On a <strong>podcast</strong>, they discussed with their father, Ed Kelce, how that pronunciation came to be.</p>
<p>"I got tired of correcting people," said Ed Kelce, who said that his co-workers always called him KEL-see.</p>
<p>Jason Kelce then asks: "Should we go by Kels or KEL-see?" His father answers: "Do whatever you want. I did."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jamie Stengle reported on this story for the Associated Press. Jill Robbins adapted this story for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>figure – </strong><em>n</em>. a person who is well-known and important in some way.</p>
<p><strong>mispronounced</strong> – <em>adj.</em> not said in a correct way</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong>– <em>n.</em> containing many very different elements</p>
<p><strong>globalized </strong>– <em>adj.</em> when people from one country link with people</p>
<p>from another country in order to work or communicate with them</p>
<p><strong>coronation</strong> – <em>n.</em> the ceremony at which a king or queen is crowned</p>
<p><strong>linguistics</strong> – <em>n.</em> the science of language</p>
<p><strong>exposure</strong> – <em>n.</em> publicity, being seen or heard</p>
<p><strong>podcast</strong> – <em>n. </em>an audio file similar to a radio broadcast, that can be listened to on a website or app on your phone or computer</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gates Foundation Takes on Poverty in US  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/gates-foundation-takes-on-poverty-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>In recent years, city leaders in Grand Island, Nebraska, observed that many workers and students were walking or riding long distances to their jobs or schools. So when city administrator, Laura McAloon, learned of a chance to study the development of a bus system to meet those transportation needs, she took it.</p>
<p>The study received support from the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation along with the International City/County Management Association.</p>
<p>It sent McAloon to Washington, D.C. along with other local leaders to learn about policies to lift people in their community out of poverty.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Laura McAloon, Grand Island City Administrator, poses for a photo on Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Grand Island, Nebraska. (AP Photo/John Peterson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6817-08dbfa6e13bc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Laura McAloon, Grand Island City Administrator, poses for a photo on Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Grand Island, Nebraska. (AP Photo/John Peterson)</span></div>
<p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation announced last week that it will donate $100 million to expand its work on reducing poverty in the U.S. The commitment is part of the $460 million the foundation said in 2022 it would donate over four years to this area of need. The foundation says it is looking to quicken the speed at which its gifts have an <strong>impact</strong>.</p>
<p>Ryan Rippel is a founding director for economic strategy at the Gates Foundation. He said the large donations represent an important change in its strategy and give <strong>grantees</strong> more power in directing their own work.</p>
<p><strong>Goal to help 50 million Americans</strong></p>
<p>The investment is a small part of the foundation's overall budget, which was $7 billion last year. But it has quickly grown. The expansion of their work, Rippel said, depends on whether they meet their goal of improving economic <strong>mobility</strong> for 50 million people in the U.S. who are just above the poverty level with a yearly <strong>income</strong> of $29,160.</p>
<p>The foundation will give money to organizations working to expand support for local government using evidence -based policies that improve economic mobility. That includes policies that connect people with skills without college degrees to jobs, helping people receive government <strong>benefits</strong> and pushing businesses to change working conditions to improve work-life balance.</p>
<p>The grantees include Opportunity@Work, Families and Workers Fund, Prosperity Now, Pacific Community Ventures, Results for America and the Urban Institute.</p>
<p>At a meeting in Washington, D.C., in May, the Urban Institute introduced the tools and research they have developed to help cities and counties understand barriers to economic mobility. There, McAloon from Grand Island realized that her city of 53,000 needed to collect more information.</p>
<p>By the end of the meeting, they had changed their objectives and launched a data collective and analysis project. That included <strong>surveying</strong> local citizens and working with the human resources departments of major local employers.</p>
<p>What the city learned is that transportation had been a problem for workers. But when the meatpacking plant and other manufacturers raised wages after the pandemic, many households were able to pay for cars. Now the problem, the employers said, was housing.</p>
<p>At the close of Grand Island's research study this fall, McAloon said they found it would not be possible to set up a bus system under federal rules. Instead, they are exploring a transportation <strong>pool</strong> that is partially paid for by employers and the state.</p>
<p>The study led to new communication and cooperation across agencies, schools and local organizations. And McAloon's office learned that a lack of plumbers and electricians was holding up new housing developments. So, she reached out to the community college, which is now setting up a technical training program in high schools.</p>
<p>"It was a matter of a couple of emails," she said. "And they're already working on ... making an impact on that issue that's keeping us from building more houses."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>impact </strong><em>— n. </em>a powerful or major influence or effect</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grant </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that is given to someone by a government, a company, etc., to be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mobility </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability or tendency to move from one position or situation to another usually better one</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>income </strong><em>— n. </em>money that is earned from work, investments, business, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>benefit </strong><em>— n. </em>a good or helpful result or effect</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>survey </strong><em>— n. </em>an activity in which many people are asked a question or a series of questions in order to gather information about what most people do or think about something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pool </strong><em>— n. </em>a group of people who do the same job or activity together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Will Europe’s New Artificial Intelligence Rules Affect the World?  (2023/12/13) | 欧盟新版人工智能规定将如何影响全球？</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-will-europe-s-new-artificial-intelligence-rules-affect-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>European nations reached an agreement on rules for artificial intelligence (AI) last week. Some experts say the regulations will affect people around the world.<br/>
欧洲国家上周就人工智能规定达成协议。一些专家表示，这些规定将影响到世界各地人们。</p>
<p>Here are some of the details of the agreement reported by the Associated Press:<br/>
以下是美联社报道的一些协议细节：</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">The AI Act and how it works:<br/>
《人工智能法案》及其运作方式：</span></p>
<p>The AI Act aims to regulate or establish guidelines for AI technology that has the potential to cause problems if misused.<br/>
《人工智能法案》旨在规范或制定人工智能技术的指导方针，如果滥用，人工智能技术可能会引发问题。</p>
<p>AI systems that recommend online material, or those that check email messages, would be less regulated. But technology that concerns healthcare or medical decisions would have higher requirements.<br/>
推荐在线材料或检查电子邮件的人工智能系统将受到较少的监管。但涉及医疗保健或医疗决策的技术将有更高的要求。</p>
<p>Some AI systems will be banned except in some cases. They include systems that scan people's faces in public and systems that make predictions about future behavior such as whether a person will commit a crime.<br/>
除某些情况外，一些人工智能系统将被禁止。它们包括在公共场合扫描人们面部的系统，以及预测未来行为（如一个人是否会犯罪）的系统。</p>
<p>The new AI Act will not take effect until two years after a vote from European lawmakers. The vote is planned for the first part of next year. The soonest it would be in place is sometime early in 2026.<br/>
新的《人工智能法案》要到欧洲立法者投票两年后才能生效。投票计划在明年上半年进行。它最快将在2026年初生效。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">How will the Act affect the world?<br/>
该法案将如何影响世界？</span></p>
<p>Some experts say the guidelines could become a global standard. That has happened before. One recent European decision caused U.S. company Apple to stop using its lightning data cable in favor of a more widely used cable.<br/>
一些专家表示，这些指导方针可能会成为一项全球标准。这种情况以前也发生过。欧洲最近的一项决定导致美国苹果公司停止使用其闪电接口数据线，转而使用一种更广泛使用的数据线。</p>
<p>Experts say Europe's rules might be used as a blueprint in other parts of the world. Anu Bradford is a professor at Columbia University in New York City. She called Europe's act "comprehensive" and "a game-changer." Bradford noted the European rules will "show the world AI can be governed."<br/>
专家表示，欧洲的规定可能会被用作世界其他地区的蓝图。阿努·布拉德福德是纽约哥伦比亚大学的教授。她称欧洲的法案是“全面的”和“游戏规则的改变者”。布拉德福德指出，欧洲的规定将“向世界表明人工智能是可以治理的”。</p>
<p>Rights groups complained that Europe's decision to not completely ban the use of facial recognition "is a missed opportunity." Amnesty International noted that Europe did not ban exports of AI technology that covers social scoring. Social scoring systems permit governments to record how well citizens follow rules.<br/>
人权组织抱怨说，欧洲没有完全禁止使用面部识别的决定是“错过了一个机会”。大赦国际指出，欧洲没有禁止出口涵盖社会评分的人工智能技术。社会评分系统允许政府记录公民遵守规则的程度。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are the U.S. and China doing?<br/>
美国和中国在做什么？</span></p>
<p>In the United States, President Joe Biden signed an executive order in October on AI. Biden required AI technology companies to share test results and other information with the government. Government organizations will create requirements for AI tools that must be followed before systems are released for public use.<br/>
在美国，乔·拜登总统于10月签署了一项关于人工智能的行政命令。拜登要求人工智能技术公司与政府共享测试结果和其他信息。政府组织将对人工智能工具提出要求，在系统发布供公众使用之前必须遵守这些要求。</p>
<p>China released rules for AI tools that create material such as photos, text and videos. The rules are only short-term guidelines. President Xi Jinping also called for an open and fair environment for AI development around the world.<br/>
中国发布了创建照片、文本和视频等材料的人工智能工具的规定。这些规定只是短期的指导方针。习主席还呼吁为世界各地人工智能技术发展创造公开、公正的环境。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Will Europe's rules change ChatGPT?<br/>
欧洲的规定会改变ChatGPT吗？</span></p>
<p>The rise of ChatGPT, an AI tool based in the U.S., is one of the reasons for Europe's new set of rules. Europe's rules include guidelines for chatbots and other AI systems that can do jobs such as writing, creating video and writing computer code.<br/>
总部位于美国的人工智能工具ChatGPT的兴起是欧洲制定新规则的原因之一。欧洲的规则包括针对聊天机器人和其他人工智能系统的指导方针，这些系统可以完成写作、创建视频和编写计算机代码等工作。</p>
<p>Systems must clearly show where the material that went into training the bots came from. They also must show how much energy was used to train the systems, or models. They should be open about how they control the data that comes from their tool's users. And they need to observe the EU's copyright property protection laws.<br/>
系统必须清楚地显示用于训练机器人的材料来自哪里。他们还必须显示有多少能源用于训练系统或模型。他们应该公开如何控制来自工具用户的数据。他们还需要遵守欧盟的版权保护法。</p>
<p>High technology systems or risky uses of AI are required to follow stricter rules. Those include systems that create basic pieces of information, such as computer code, that others will then use to create other AI systems.<br/>
高科技系统或人工智能的高风险使用需要遵守更严格的规则。其中包括创建基本信息的系统，如计算机代码，然后其他人将使用这些信息创建其他人工智能系统。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
