<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Forest Service Moving Trees to Save Them  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/forest-service-moving-trees-to-save-them.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Some important tree species native to the northwestern states in the U.S. are no longer growing well because of climate change.</p>
<p>As conditions change in states such as Washington, Oregon and California, trees such as the Douglas fir, Western red cedar, giant sequoia and redwood may need to move -- with the help of humans.</p>
<p>Some of the trees do not do well when temperatures rise. Others suffer during times of <strong>drought</strong>. The goal is to move the trees to areas where the climate might more <strong>suitable</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - City of Bellevue Forest Management Program Supervisor Rick Bailey holds a juvenile giant sequoia in his hands on Oct. 11, 2022, in Bellevue, Wash. (AP Photo/Manuel Valdes, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6951398f-6af4-4e04-b34b-83543276db37_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - City of Bellevue Forest Management Program Supervisor Rick Bailey holds a juvenile giant sequoia in his hands on Oct. 11, 2022, in Bellevue, Wash. (AP Photo/Manuel Valdes, File)</span></div>
<p>Forest scientists are generally in favor of moving the trees so they do not die out. However, not all of the scientists agree on the best way to do it.</p>
<p>There are three ways to move trees: assisted population <strong>migration</strong>, assisted species migration and <strong>range</strong> expansion.</p>
<p>Assisted population migration involves scientists moving a tree's seeds within its current growing range. Assisted species migration involves scientists moving a species far from its existing area. In this case, that would include moving redwoods and sequoias from California to Washington.</p>
<p>The third way, range expansion, moves trees just outside their current growing range. Each way has different results for the trees and other animals and insects that depend on the trees.</p>
<p>Michael Case is a forest <strong>ecologist</strong> at the Nature Conservancy in Virginia. He said "there is a huge difference" among the different migration methods.</p>
<p>He said the risk of failure increases "whenever you plant something in an area where it is not <strong>locally</strong> found." He said the risk is not only to the trees. There is also the risk of causing problems in the ecosystem.</p>
<p>Case is working on an assisted population migration program with Douglas fir and Western hemlock trees. He is testing whether the trees, originally from drier parts of the northwest, can do well in western Washington where there is a drought. His organization believes that assisted population migration has fewer risks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Forest Service also takes part in assisted population migration programs. Dr. David Lytle is the agency's deputy chief for research and development. He said the agency is "very very <strong>cautious</strong>" about moving plants outside of their "historic range."</p>
<p>Douglas Tallamy is a professor of entomology and wildlife ecology at the University of Delaware. He said one worry about species migration is that local caterpillars might not eat the leaves of trees that are new to the area. The caterpillars serve as food for birds and other animals, so they must have a good food source.</p>
<p>Although the concerns are documented, the city of Portland, Oregon, is working on a species migration project for 11 tree species. The project includes three oak trees: California black oak, canyon live oak and interior live oak. Tallamy said oak trees are among the most important in North America. "When you move them out of range," he said, "the things that are <strong>adapted</strong> to eating them no longer have access to them."</p>
<p>The city <strong>responded</strong> to questions from the Associated Press, and said it is using guidelines "from universities, state and federal sources" and more, in its project.</p>
<p>Another group working on species migration projects in the northwest is called PropagationNation. To propagate means to produce a new plant through the use of seeds or parts of another plant.</p>
<p>That organization is planting non-local trees around the Seattle, Washington area in hopes that they will start growing in places where Western red cedar, Western hemlock and big leaf maple are having trouble.</p>
<p>David Milarch is the leader of a group in Michigan that supports keeping old trees alive. It is called Archangel Ancient Tree Archive. Milarch said the hope is to permit redwoods and sequoias to grow in areas to the north. The hope is not to <strong>replace</strong> native trees.</p>
<p>He said his group hopes the trees "will still be here in 100 to 200 years and not join the list of trees that are going <strong>extinct</strong>."</p>
<p>The organizations that are not practicing widely accepted methods for moving species feel like the risks are worth it.</p>
<p>But Robert Slesak is not sure about either practice. He oversees population migration sites run by the U.S. Forest Service in California, Oregon and Washington.</p>
<p>He said he has concerns about assisted species migrations and assisted population migrations that lack experimental <strong>rigor</strong>. Rigor describes an activity that has been tested with high standards.</p>
<p>He said all of the ideas about how to move trees should follow experiments that have already produced strong results.</p>
<p>"Everyone knows we need to do some kind of action related to climate, but there's a real risk of making it worse."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a dry weather period</p>
<p><strong>suitable </strong><em>–adj.</em> comfortable or correct</p>
<p><strong>migration </strong><em>–n.</em> the movement of something to a new place</p>
<p><strong>range </strong><em>–n.</em> the usual area of land covered by a plant or tree (in this case)</p>
<p><strong>ecologist </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who studies living things and their environment</p>
<p><strong>locally </strong><em>–adj.</em> a small area where something is originally found</p>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>–adj.</em> careful or concerned</p>
<p><strong>adapted </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that has changed and now functions in a new place</p>
<p><strong>respond </strong><em>–v.</em> to answer</p>
<p><strong>replace </strong><em>–v.</em> to put something new in place of something</p>
<p><strong>to go extinct </strong><em>–v.</em> to die out</p>
<p><strong>rigor </strong><em>–n.</em> the quality of being exact, careful or strict</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Plane Crash in Tokyo Raises Design Concerns  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/plane-crash-in-tokyo-raises-design-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Investigators are studying what went wrong when a Japanese coast guard aircraft and a passenger jet crashed into each other on Tuesday at Haneda Airport in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Officials want to find out what caused the crash. But there are also many questions about the fire that broke out when the planes <strong>collided</strong> on the runway.</p>
<p>The body of the passenger jet, an Airbus 350, was made of carbon-<strong>composite fibers</strong>. Passenger aircraft bodies have traditionally been made of aluminum.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Japan Airlines plane is on fire on the runway of Haneda airport on Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024 in Tokyo, Japan. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e8c0-08dc0d51417e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Japan Airlines plane is on fire on the runway of Haneda airport on Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024 in Tokyo, Japan. </span></div>
<p>The crash may become an important test of the safety of composite materials for some uses in aircraft.</p>
<p><strong>The crash</strong></p>
<p>Communications from air traffic control at the airport describe some of the events leading to the crash. The larger Japan Airlines (JAL) passenger jet was given permission to use the runway where the coast guard plane, a Bombardier Dash-8, was preparing for takeoff.</p>
<p>When they struck each other, an orange fireball exploded from the aircraft and the passenger jet continued down the runway covered in flames.</p>
<p>When the plane stopped, crew members and all 379 passengers slid down emergency<strong> chutes</strong> within 20 minutes. All survived. The captain of the coast guard plane got out, but five members of the crew died in the crash.</p>
<p>Safety experts are praising the airline's crew and the passengers for escaping the burning plane. The crew shouted, warning the passengers to run away from the plane.</p>
<p><strong>The composite material</strong></p>
<p>Composite materials have been used for many years inside commercial aircraft. But the first commercial plane to have its body, or fuselage, and wings reinforced with carbon fibers was the Boeing 787. It went into service in 2011. About 1,100 of the planes have been produced.</p>
<p>The Airbus A350 followed in 2018. About 570 have been sold.</p>
<p>Aircraft designers use composite materials because they strengthen plastics and other materials. Boeing says the material can save 20 percent of the weight of aluminum. The reduced weight saves fuel.</p>
<p>Boeing and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) tested the strength of composites to get <strong>certification</strong> for the 787 jet. But concerns remain about gases released from such materials when they burn.</p>
<p>John Goglia is a former member of the National Transportation Safety Board, which investigates aircraft accidents. He said, "There has always been a concern about composites if they catch fire." Goglia noted that the gases released when composites burn are dangerous. They can even be dangerous after the fire is put out because the fibers might remain in the air.</p>
<p>The FAA has said for more than 20 years that there are dangers related to composite materials. FAA officials say the main health dangers include sharp pieces of material, dust and poisonous gases caused by burning substances<strong> </strong>that hold the material together.</p>
<p><strong>Did it make a difference?</strong></p>
<p>Although the inside of the passenger plane filled with smoke after the explosion, all 379 passengers were able to escape.</p>
<p>John Cox, a safety expert, noted: "That fuselage protected them from a really horrific fire — it did not burn through for some period of time and let everybody get out."</p>
<p>Goglia said there is no real evidence whether composite materials or aluminum are better at resisting fire long enough to protect people.</p>
<p>However, one passenger on the JAL flight said the smoke "<strong>stung</strong>" very much.</p>
<p>Todd Curtis, a safety expert and former Boeing engineer, warned that injuries from dangerous smoke could take a long time to show up. Passengers involved in accidents usually are in shock and often do not recognize their injuries.</p>
<p>Another concern, experts noted, was the amount of time it took firefighters to put out the fire. Pictures show the JAL flight's burned wreckage near one of the runways. The body was almost completely destroyed by fire.</p>
<p>In 2013, a fire at London's Heathrow Airport involving an Ethiopian Airlines Boeing 787 was difficult to stop. Safety expert Curtis said, "putting out the fire took much more effort that a typical airliner fire." Curtis said he worried at the time about composite fuselage fires.</p>
<p>Those concerns, he said, have not gone away.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>David Koenig reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>collide</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to crash together with force, usually because both objects are in motion</p>
<p><strong>composite</strong><em>–adj.</em> made up of at least two different materials</p>
<p><strong>fiber </strong><em>–n.</em> a long thin piece of material</p>
<p><strong>certification </strong>–n. a process of official approval of a product for use by industry or the public</p>
<p><strong>resin </strong><em>–n.</em> a substance that causes things to stick together firmly</p>
<p><strong>sting </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause sharp paint</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>American Teenager Becomes First Human to Beat Video Game Tetris  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/american-teenager-becomes-first-human-to-beat-video-game-tetris.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A 13-year-old American boy has become the first person ever to beat the popular video game Tetris.</p>
<p>The young gamer, Willis Gibson, completed 157 levels of Tetris before the game technically surrendered.</p>
<p>Gamers call this kind of ending a "kill screen." The Tetris program had no more plays to make and so it crashed, freezing the video game.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image taken from video, 13-year-old Willis Gibson reacts after beating the video game Tetris. (Willis Gibson via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-addd-08dc0d4cda58_cx3_cy0_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image taken from video, 13-year-old Willis Gibson reacts after beating the video game Tetris. (Willis Gibson via AP)</span></div>
<p>Gibson lives in the Midwestern state of Oklahoma and goes by the gaming name "Blue Scuti." He can be heard repeatedly shouting "Oh my God" <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=piXi6HM_GQ4">on a video</a> recording as he beat the game.</p>
<p>"I can't feel my fingers," Gibson says in the video.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Gaming experts had long considered Tetris unbeatable. This is partly because the video game does not have a clear ending point.</p>
<p>Tetris came out in 1984 and quickly became a worldwide favorite. Its creator, Alexey Pajitnov, was a computer programs engineer at the Russian Academy of Sciences in the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>During the game, players move and join together seven different shapes of falling blocks. The goal is for players to fit the blocks together to form solid lines inside a box. The blocks fall faster as players progress through higher levels of the game.</p>
<p>On December 21, Gibson reached level 157 and dropped a final piece into place. This caused a single line of blocks to disappear and the game to enter a permanent freeze.</p>
<p>"This is unbelievable," Vince Clemente, CEO of Classic Tetris World Championship, told Reuters news agency. "Developers didn't think anyone would ever make it that far and now the game has officially been beaten by a human being." </p><p>For some time, gamers have known Tetris would eventually reach an ending point and technically shut down. But in the past, only a computer program could force such a game-ending shut-down.</p>
<p>Other fans of the game were quick to share Gibson's excitement. Classic Tetris World Champion Justin Yu – who goes by the name fractal161 – declared in his own video, "He did it, he did it!"</p>
<p>Tetris chief executive Maya Rogers joined in the celebration. She said in a statement it was fitting Gibson had beat the game just ahead of 2024, when Tetris was entering its 40th anniversary.</p>
<p>"Congratulations to 'blue scuti,'" Rogers said. She added that the "extraordinary" event "<strong>defied</strong>" any previous known limits of the game.</p>
<p>Gibson uses a "rolling" controller playing method popularized in 2021. It permits players to operate the controls in different ways to be able to keep playing longer to reach higher levels.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>defy </strong><em>– v. </em>to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Personification, Adjectives in 'Take Me Home, Country Roads'  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/personification-adjectives-in-take-me-home-country-roads.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many Americans have returned to work or school as the holiday season comes to an end. Some traveled far to be with loved ones for Christmas and New Year's Day.</p>
<p>Last month, we looked at the song <em>Take Me Home, Country Roads.</em> For many people from the state of West Virginia and the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/discover-americas-appalachian-trial/2766408.html">Appalachia</a> mountains, the song reminds them of home. John Denver recorded the hit song in 1971. Lana Del Rey recently recorded her version of the song.</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will continue looking at parts of Del Rey's version of the song and connect it to grammar and <strong>figurative</strong> language.<strong> </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="More Personification and Adjectives in Take Me Home, Country Roads " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-36b8-08dc0cb9bd41_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">More Personification and Adjectives in "Take Me Home, Country Roads" </span></div>
<p>Let's look at the last section of the song.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p><em>All my memories gather 'round her</em></p>
<p><em>Miner</em><em>'s lady, stranger to blue water</em></p>
<p><em>Dark and dusty, painted on the sky</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Misty</em></strong><em> taste of moonshine, teardrop in my eye</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>I hear her voice in the morning hour, she calls me</em></p>
<p><em>The radio reminds me of my home far away</em></p>
<p><em>Driving down the road, I get a feeling</em></p>
<p><em>That I should have been home yesterday, yesterday</em></p>
<p><strong>More personification </strong></p>
<p>In the first two <strong>verses </strong>of each section, West Virginia is humanized once again using personification. Personification is the humanization of a non-living thing.</p>
<p>The use of the subject and object pronouns "she" and "her" give a female quality to the state. That personification of West Virginia as a woman also appears in the <strong>chorus</strong> of the song when it is referred to as <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-and-figurative-language-in-take-me-home-country-roads-/7406288.html">"mountain mama." </a></p>
<p>"Her voice" and "she calls me" add to the female <strong>characteristics </strong>of the state.</p>
<p>"Miner's lady" and "stranger to blue water" are other personified comparisons in the song. West Virginia is known for its coal and limestone mines throughout the state. Many European immigrants came to West Virginia in the late 1800s and early 1900s to work in the mines.</p>
<p>"Stanger to blue water" is a reference to West Virginia's geographic location as a landlocked state. A stranger is an unfamiliar person. The phrase is noting that the state is not near an ocean and is unfamiliar to blue ocean waters.</p>
<p><strong>Adjectives </strong></p>
<p>And finally, we have more adjectives. Today we look at descriptive adjectives, not comparative adjectives.</p>
<p><em>Dark and dusty, painted on the sky</em></p>
<p><em>Misty taste of moonshine, teardrop in my eye</em></p>
<p>"Dark and dusty" refer to the "miner's lady" line and coal mining. Coal is a dark, natural substance found in the earth. West Virginia and other parts of the Appalachian region are rich in this resource. It also creates dusty particles that fill the air. That combination "paints" or covers the sky.</p>
<p>The line "misty taste of moonshine" also has a descriptive adjective. "Misty" has several meanings. "Mist," the noun form of the word, means water in the form of very small drops floating in the air. So, "misty" means full of mist. It can also describe something that is not clearly seen or remembered. Finally, it can describe eyes that are full of tears. In fact, "misty-eyed" means the same thing as "tearful."</p>
<p>Moonshine is a kind of alcohol that is made illegally. Making moonshine was especially common in the hills of Appalachia during Prohibition, which lasted from 1920 to 1933.</p>
<p>The alcohol was moved by car at night and the <strong>bootleggers</strong> could only see by the light of the moon. That is where it got its name.</p>
<p>It is not common to describe a taste or flavor as "misty." But there are a few possible meanings. Since "moonshine" was strong, drinking it could leave one's eyes "misty" or filled with tears. The "misty" flavor of moonshine could also refer to the illegal way of producing and transporting the alcohol without anyone knowing.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today we looked at the rest of the song <em>Country Roads</em>. We found even more personification by comparing West Virginia to a woman with words like, "miner's lady" and "her voice."</p>
<p>We found even more adjectives that were used to describe parts of Appalachian culture like "dark and dusty" for coal mining and "misty taste of moonshine" to describe a strong alcohol flavor that could bring tears to one's eyes.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>figurative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used with a meaning that is different from the basic meaning</p>
<p><strong>misty </strong>– <em>adj</em>.<strong> </strong>full of or covered with mist.</p>
<p><strong>verse</strong> – <em>n. </em>writing in which words are arranged in a rhythmic pattern: poetry or song</p>
<p><strong>chorus </strong><em>– n.</em> part of a song that is repeated; a large organized group of singers</p>
<p><strong>characteristic </strong><em>–n.</em> a quality that a person has that makes them different, or similar, to others</p>
<p><strong>bootlegger</strong> - <em>n</em>. someone who sells products illegally, often without providing the requires taxes to government</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Experiment Breaks Record for Internet Traffic Speed  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-experiment-breaks-record-for-internet-traffic-speed.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Japanese researchers say they have broken the world speed record for sending internet data.</p>
<p>The recent experiment involved sending data over <strong>fiber-optic</strong> lines enclosed inside <strong>cables</strong>. Fiber optic technology is currently the fastest way to transport, or transmit, internet data.</p>
<p>Fiber-optic cables use signals of light to send data over long distances. The fiber material is very thin, about one-tenth the thickness of a human hair.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Fiber optic cables are seen running into a server room at Intergate.Manhattan, a data center owned and developed by Sabey Data Center Properties, during a tour of the facility in lower Manhattan, in New York, March 20, 2013. (REUTERS/Mike Sega)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-95d6-08dc0c9b0939_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Fiber optic cables are seen running into a server room at Intergate.Manhattan, a data center owned and developed by Sabey Data Center Properties, during a tour of the facility in lower Manhattan, in New York, March 20, 2013. (REUTERS/Mike Sega)</span></div>
<p>Fiber-optic technology was meant to replace an older internet transmission method that uses cables made mainly of copper wiring. This method can also carry data over the internet, but at much reduced speeds and <strong>capacity</strong> compared with fiber-optics.</p>
<p>A report released last year by the United Nations' International Telecommunication Union (ITU) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.itu.int/hub/2023/05/space-division-multiplexing/">suggested</a> current worldwide internet data transmission is reaching full capacity levels.</p>
<p>The Japanese data transmission experiment used fiber-optic cables. But the engineers involved made some changes to the cables in an effort to greatly expand speed and capacity.</p>
<p>Such methods are known as multiplexing technologies. They aim to increase the amount and speed of internet data with existing transmission equipment. These technologies combine multiple communication signals into a single transmission line.</p>
<p>One multiplexing technology – called Wave Division Multiplexing (or WDM) – aims to increase the <strong>wavelength</strong> capacity within transmission cables. Another method – called Space Division Multiplexing (or SDM) – can involve increasing the size or number of fiber-optic centers, called cores.</p>
<p>Engineers from Japan's National Institute of Information and Communications Technology (NCIT) led the researchers who carried out the experiment. The tests measured speeds in petabits. One petabit equals 1 million gigabits.</p>
<p>The record transmission demonstrated a data transmission capacity of 22.9 petabits per second in a single fiber-optic cable. The previous record for data transmission was 10.66 petabits per second, set by the same team at NCIT.</p>
<p>Major progress has been made in recent years in internet data transmission speeds. In October 2022, an international group of researchers <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.dtu.dk/english/newsarchive/2022/10/new-data-transmission-record">announced</a> they had broken the world record. That team reported they had reached a test rate of 1.8 petabits per second using a single optical cable.</p>
<p>Results of the Japanese experiment were officially presented in a paper released at the 49th <a class="wsw__a" href="https://ecoc2023.theiet.org/">European Conference on Optical Communications</a> in October. The team said it was able to beat the previous record by a large amount using new methods to expand and combine different WDM and SDM elements.</p>
<p>The method used a fiber-optic cable that contained 38 cores. The researchers said expanding the number of cores resulted in an "increased number of optical paths" for high-speed data transmission.</p>
<p>One researcher was Chigo Okonkwo of Eindhoven University of Technology in the Netherlands. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://nltimes.nl/2023/12/25/eindhoven-researchers-break-record-fastest-data-transfer-speed-ever#:~:text=Scientists%20based%20in%20Eindhoven%20have,That%20was%20achieved%20in%202020.">told</a> the country's <em>NL Times</em> the rate of 22.9 petabits per second represented "about 20 times the global internet traffic per second." Okonkwo also noted the speed is about 229 times the total capacity of the kinds of fiber-optic cables currently in use today.</p>
<p>Worldwide, the estimated average internet data transmission speed in 2023 was about 46.8 megabits per second, international research service <em>Statista</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/chart/31075/global-average-internet-download-speed/#:~:text=As%20detailed%20in%20the%20Cable,major%20differences%20between%20world%20regions.">reports</a>. The rate reached 118.7 megabits per second in Western Europe, while Northern Africa had the lowest estimated rate at 9.8, <em>Statista </em>said.<em> </em></p>
<p>The American-based Pew Research Center studies internet data transmission rates across the United States. Pew <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/fact-sheets/2022/07/how-do-americans-connect-to-the-internet">reports</a> the fastest current data transmission method available in the U.S. – called Fiber to Home – is about 10 gigabits per second. This amount is equal to about 10,000 megabits per second.</p>
<p>Most Americans receive much slower data transmission rates, an average of just under 50 megabits per second. Pew estimates Fiber to Home service only accounts for about 20 percent of the U.S. internet service market.</p>
<p>The NCIT team described its latest test results as "a major step toward the realization of future ultra-large capacity optical communication networks." But in order to reach this goal, the team said its current methods must be further perfected.</p>
<p>For example, the researchers pointed to one major issue that could delay future deployments of its super-fast fiber-optic system. This will be the need to complete "significant <strong>upgrades</strong>" to current telecommunication hardware systems in order<strong> </strong>to support the new cable technologies.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fiber optics </strong><em>– n. </em>the use of very thin glass or plastic wires through which light can travel to carry data, especially for internet and computer applications</p>
<p><strong>cable </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of wires covered by plastic coverings</p>
<p><strong>capacity </strong><em>– n. </em>the total amount of something that can be produced or contained</p>
<p><strong>wavelength </strong><em>– n. </em>the distance between two waves of energy</p>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of equipment or software that improves the quality or usefulness of a computer or machine</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lancashire Heeler: Small Dog with Big Smile  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/lancashire-heeler-small-dog-with-big-smile.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>It is a small dog with a big "smile." And it is ready to compete with 200 other kinds of dogs, known as breeds.</p>
<p>Say hello to the Lancashire Heeler.</p>
<p>The American Kennel Club (AKC) announced Wednesday that the rare dog breed can now compete in thousands of dog shows across the United States. That includes the famous Westminster Kennel Club show.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Lex, a Lancashire Heeler, sits at attention on Dec. 29, 2023, in Morristown, N.J. The breed is the latest recognized by the American Kennel Club to compete in thousands of U.S. dog shows. (Michelle Barlak via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-320f-08dc0c815fdc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Lex, a Lancashire Heeler, sits at attention on Dec. 29, 2023, in Morristown, N.J. The breed is the latest recognized by the American Kennel Club to compete in thousands of U.S. dog shows. (Michelle Barlak via AP)</span></div>
<p>The AKC <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.akc.org/dog-breeds/lancashire-heeler/">describes</a> the breed as "a medium to high energy dog." The organization says the dogs are intelligent, friendly and quick to learn new tasks. They are happy, talkative and always ready for a walk.</p>
<p>Lancashire Heelers have long bodies and short coats of hair, or fur, in black and tan. The breed stands about 30 centimeters high and weighs up to 7.7 kilograms. Historically, they helped to drive farm animals and chase away rats. The breed can also perform several dog-related sports and activities.</p>
<p>"They're <strong>gritty</strong> little dogs, and they're very intelligent little dogs," says Patricia Blankenship of Flora, Mississippi, who has bred them for many years. "It's an enjoyable little breed to be around."</p>
<p>The breed is often described as "<strong>courageous</strong>, happy, <strong>affectionate</strong> to owner." And owners say they sometimes pull back their lips into a "smile."</p>
<p>Lancashire Heeler Club President Sheryl Bradbury says the breed "has to have a job" or stay active with its owners. It is also helpful for them to meet different people and dogs.</p>
<p>Lancashire Heelers have lived in Britain for hundreds of years, but they are now at risk of dying out as a breed. Britain's Kennel Club has added an average of just 121 Lancashire heelers yearly to its registry in recent years. The AKC says only about 5,000 exist worldwide.</p>
<p>Founded in 1884, the AKC is the United States' oldest <strong>purebred</strong> dog registry. It also organizes dog shows where 201 recognized breeds compete for the traditional "best in show." To get recognized, a breed must have an official breeding <strong>standard</strong> and there must be at least 300 of the animals in at least 20 states.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Jennifer Peltz reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gritty</strong> <em>–adj. </em>showing toughness or courage</p>
<p><strong>courageous</strong> <em>–adj.</em> being brave or showing courage</p>
<p><strong>affectionate </strong>–adj. showing love or good feeling</p>
<p><strong>purebred </strong>–adj. having parents of the same breed</p>
<p><strong>standard </strong>–n. a level of quality involving observance of certain rules</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Record Half-million Migrants Crossed Dangerous Darien Gap Last Year  (2024/1/4) | 2023年穿越达连峡谷人数创新纪录</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/record-half-million-migrants-crossed-dangerous-darien-gap-last-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A record 520,000 migrants crossed the difficult and dangerous Darien Gap wilderness area between Colombia and Panama in 2023. Panamanian officials say that total is more than double the number recorded the year before.<br/>
2023年，创纪录的52万移民穿越了哥伦比亚和巴拿马之间艰难而危险的“达连峡谷”荒野地带。巴拿马官员表示，这一数字是前一年的两倍多。</p>
<p>The Panamanian government's migration agency says most of the migrants in 2023 were from Venezuela, Ecuador, and Haiti. And, agency chief Samira Gozaine said minors represented about 25 percent of the group traveling through the dense jungle.<br/>
巴拿马政府移民局表示，2023年的大多数移民来自委内瑞拉、厄瓜多尔和海地。该机构负责人萨米拉·冈萨伊内表示，在穿越茂密丛林的人群中，未成年人约占25%。</p>
<p>"This is a national security problem," she told reporters at a government event. "Unfortunately, we do not have a quick solution to solve it."<br/>
她在一次政府活动中对记者说：“这是国家安全问题，不幸的是，我们没有快速解决方案。”</p>
<p>The number of migrants crossing the Darien has sharply increased since 2019, when Laurentino Cortizo took office as Panama's president. Officials have called for international assistance to deal with the problem.<br/>
自2019年劳伦蒂诺·科尔蒂佐就任巴拿马总统以来，穿越“达连峡谷”的移民人数急剧增加。官员们呼吁国际社会提供援助以解决这一问题。</p>
<p>A major increase in Venezuelans fleeing the economic and social collapse of their country accounts for some of the migration flow. The United Nations says more than seven million Venezuelans have fled their country in recent years.<br/>
逃离本国经济和社会崩溃的委内瑞拉人大幅增加，这是移民潮的一部分原因。联合国表示，近年来已有700多万委内瑞拉人逃离本国。</p>
<p>Those who cross the Darien risk murder, rape, human trafficking, and other violence. Natural dangers include heavy rains, sudden floods, poisonous snakes and other wildlife. Migrants must cross jungle rivers as well. There are no roads, bridges or services, including police and emergency workers.<br/>
那些穿越“达连峡谷”的人有被谋杀、强奸、贩卖人口和其他暴力的风险。自然危险包括暴雨、突发洪水、毒蛇和其他野生动物。移民还必须穿越丛林河流。这里没有道路、桥梁或包括警察和急救人员在内的相关服务。</p>
<p>In September, Reuters reported that African migrants heading to the United States are flying to Nicaragua to avoid the dangers of the Darien Gap.<br/>
9月，路透社报道称，前往美国的非洲移民正飞往尼加拉瓜，以避免“达连峡谷”的危险。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Displaced Afghans Cross Borders to Survive  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/displaced-afghan-cross-borders-to-survive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The desert in the mountains of eastern Afghanistan is filled with hundreds of thousands of people. Some live in tents. Others live out in the open after they were forced to leave neighboring Pakistan.</p>
<p>More than 40 years of war, violence and poverty have turned 6 million Afghans into refugees. Another 3.5 million people are displaced within the country of 40 million. Many were driven from their homes by war, earthquakes and <strong>drought</strong>.</p>
<p>Afghanistan's economy collapsed after the Taliban returned to power following the withdrawal of the United States and NATO allies in 2021. Now, two-thirds of its population depends on international aid to survive.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An internally displaced woman takes care of her sick child in a camp on the outskirts of Kabul, Afghanistan, Thursday, Feb. 9, 2023. She has no money to treat her sick child. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f57b-08dc0bd04827_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An internally displaced woman takes care of her sick child in a camp on the outskirts of Kabul, Afghanistan, Thursday, Feb. 9, 2023. She has no money to treat her sick child. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)</span></div>
<p>Displaced Afghans live in camps around the country. They do not have enough food or firewood for heat in the winter. Women and children often turn to <strong>begging</strong>. Others marry off their young daughters to families willing to pay them money.</p>
<p>In May, for example, 15-year-old Shamila was married at a camp for internally displaced people outside Kabul. She stood in a bright-red dress among the women of the family who congratulated her. But the girl was unhappy.</p>
<p>"I have no choice. If I don't accept, my family will be hurt," said Shamila, whose father did not give the family's name because he feared the Taliban. The <strong>groom's</strong> family is giving her father money to pay off debts taken to support his wife and children.</p>
<p>"I wanted to study and work, I should have gone to school," Shamila said. "I have to forget all my dreams...so at least I can help my father and my family a little and maybe I can take the <strong>burden off their shoulders</strong>."</p>
<p>Last year, Pakistan decided to <strong>deport</strong> Afghans who entered the country illegally. Many Afghans lived for years in Pakistan. They were afraid of continuing conflicts at home. When Pakistan's order was announced, hundreds of thousands feared arrest and fled back to Afghanistan. The Afghans said Pakistani officials often prevented them from taking anything with them.</p>
<p>Their first stop has been the camp in Torkham, where they might spend days or weeks before Taliban officials send them to another place. With little food and little to protect them from the mountain cold, many in the camp are sick.</p>
<p>In a camp at the foot of a mountain, 55-year-old Farooq Sadiq sat with his wife and children on the ground among some of their belongings. Sadiq said he had been living in the Pakistani city of Peshawar for 30 years and owned a home there. Now they had nothing, not even a tent. He said they had been sleeping on the ground for the past eight nights.</p>
<p>"I have nothing in Afghanistan, no house, no place to live, not enough money to buy a house," he said. He hopes to settle somewhere in Afghanistan and get a visa to Pakistan so he can go sell his home there to use the money for his family.</p>
<p>The deportations from Pakistan have greatly increased the large numbers of Afghans who try to migrate into Iran, hoping to find work.</p>
<p>Every month, thousands cross into Iran at the border near Zaranj. At night, with the help of <strong>smugglers</strong>, they climb over the border wall and jump to the other side.</p>
<p>Mostly young men, from age 12 to their 20s, flee Afghanistan this way. They plan to work in Iran and send money home to their families. Many are caught by Iranian border guards and sent back.</p>
<p>Others take a longer trip by car through mountains and deserts on Afghanistan's southwestern border through Pakistan to reach Iran. There is no border wall there. But fighters from the Sunni militant group Jundallah often attack the migrants, killing or kidnapping Shiites among them.</p>
<p>Over several months, <em>Associated Press </em>photographer Ebrahim Noroozi traveled across Afghanistan from its eastern border with Pakistan to its western border with Iran to report their stories.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Ebrahim Noroozi reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a severe lack of rain for an extended period</p>
<p><strong>beg </strong><em>–v.</em> to ask people for money or food</p>
<p><strong>groom </strong><em>–n.</em> a man about to be married</p>
<p><strong>burden off (one's) shoulders </strong><em>–idiom</em> to solve a difficult problem or responsibility</p>
<p><strong>deport </strong><em>–v.</em> to legally expel a person, who is not a citizen, from a country</p>
<p><strong>smuggler </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who move goods or people from country to country secretly and illegally</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Woman, Cat Help Others through Therapy  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/woman-cat-help-others-through-therapy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Every day Juanita Mengel, a 67-year-old woman from the state of Ohio, wakes up and puts on her manufactured leg. The device is called a prosthetic.</p>
<p>Then, Mengel does the same for Lola-Pearl, her colorful five-year-old cat. Lola-Pearl is missing her back left leg.</p>
<p>Mengel has many cats. Most of them have disabilities. But Lola-Pearl is special. She is a <strong>therapy</strong> cat. And, she and Mengel are partners of a kind. They are among 200 therapy cat teams registered in the United States by the nonprofit group, Pet Partners.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image taken from video shows kitten Lola-Pearl looking up at attendees during a Amputees Coming Together Informing Others' Needs meeting on Monday, Dec. 11, 2023, in Troy, Ohio. (AP Photo/Patrick Orsagos)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fc1086e2-7ae0-414d-a684-626c301584f8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image taken from video shows kitten Lola-Pearl looking up at attendees during a Amputees Coming Together Informing Others' Needs meeting on Monday, Dec. 11, 2023, in Troy, Ohio. (AP Photo/Patrick Orsagos)</span></div>
<p>The group helps humans and pets alike by setting them up into teams to provide animal-assisted intervention. The teams visit hospitals, nursing homes and schools and assist those in need.</p>
<p>Taylor Chastain Griffin is national director of animal-assisted interventions at Pet Partners. She said, "A therapy animal is an animal who's been <strong>assessed</strong> based on their ability to meet new people and not just <strong>tolerate</strong> the interaction, but actively enjoy it."</p>
<p>Chastain Griffin is a researcher who studies the effects of therapy cats. She said there needs to be more research done in cat therapy. She said that there is a lot of research on other therapy animals like dogs, and many people are surprised to learn that cats can be therapy animals too.</p>
<p>"They go into a setting and people are like, 'Whoa, there's a cat on a <strong>leash</strong>. What's happening? It kind of <strong>inspires</strong> people to connect in a way we haven't traditionally heard talked about in other therapy animal interventions," Chastain Griffin said.</p>
<p>Besides dogs and cats, Pet Partners registers seven other species as therapy animals, including horses, rabbits, rats, guinea pigs, birds, mini pigs, and llamas and alpacas.</p>
<p>Mengel said Lola-Pearl showed signs that she would make a good therapy cat soon after the animal joined her family. Mengel took her new cat to a meeting for <strong>amputees</strong>.</p>
<p>"She was so good with people I just knew she would be a good therapy cat. People really were attracted to her, too," Mengel said.</p>
<p>Recently people who attended a support group for amputees were able to meet Lola-Pearl. They petted her as she woke up from a rest. On the side of the cat carrier she rode in was a sign: "Therapy Cat" it read.</p>
<p>Mengel was a traveling nurse when she was in a car accident that almost killed her. One of her legs could not be saved.</p>
<p>Later, she connected with a friend in the state of Missouri who had a severely injured kitten. Her legs were <strong>twisted</strong> together. An animal medical specialist worked to repair the damage but, in the end, they had to remove one of the baby cat's legs.</p>
<p>That kitten was Lola-Pearl.</p>
<p>Mengel took Lola-Pearl as her cat after talking with her friend. Despite the difficulties Mengel has faced, she is thankful for Lola-Pearl and their work together.</p>
<p>"It's a really rewarding experience," she said, "I get just as much out of it as the people that I visit."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Patrick Orsagos reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>therapy </strong>– <em>n</em>. the treatment of physical or mental illnesses</p>
<p><strong>assess </strong><em>– v. </em>to make a judgement about a person or a thing</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong><em>– v.</em> to permit something to happen; to be able to bear the results of something</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>– n.</em> a powerful or major influence or effect</p>
<p><strong>leash </strong><em>– n. </em>a long, thin piece of rope, chain, etc., that is used for holding a dog or other animal</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone want to do something</p>
<p><strong>amputee </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who has had an arm or leg cut off</p>
<p><strong>limb </strong>– <em>n.</em> a leg or arm</p>
<p><strong>twisted </strong>—<em> v. </em>to bend or turn in order to change its shape</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Childhood Education Programs at Risk  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/early-childhood-education-programs-at-risk.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) says "The period from birth to eight years old is one of <strong>remarkable</strong> brain development for children." The organization adds that it represents an important time for their development and education.</p>
<p>The U.S. National Institutes of Health says that supporting children's early learning can lead to higher test scores and a better chance of staying in school and going to college. Studies even suggest early learning can lead to fewer <strong>teen</strong> pregnancies, improved mental health, and a longer life.</p>
<p><strong>Early learning in OECD countries</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Elijah Rollings, 2, plays with a train set at Bumble Art Studio daycare center in Astoria, Ore., Friday, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Craig Mitchelldyer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ac7c-08dc0b0435db_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Elijah Rollings, 2, plays with a train set at Bumble Art Studio daycare center in Astoria, Ore., Friday, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Craig Mitchelldyer)</span></div>
<p>The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) is made up of 38 democracies with market-based economies. The organization aims to build better policies for better lives.</p>
<p>In a recent education <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/0a156279-en/index.html?itemId=/content/component/0a156279-en#:~:text=The%20highest%20enrolment%20rates%20of,primary%20education%20across%20OECD%20countries.">study</a>, the OECD found that most of its member countries provide care or education for children under 5. In countries, including Belgium, Denmark, France, Hungary, Iceland, Israel, Norway, Spain and Britain, at least 95 percent of 3-year-olds are <strong>enrolled</strong> in an early education program.</p>
<p>However, within OECD countries, there can be a large difference in enrollment. In the United States, for example, 80 percent of 3 to 5-year-olds in the capital city of Washington, D.C. are enrolled in early education programs. That is compared to 46 percent in the western state of North Dakota.</p>
<p>The differences also exist in European countries like Greece, Lithuania, and Switzerland. Places with higher rates of women in the workforce usually have higher rates of enrollment for children under 3.</p>
<p><strong>Child care and kindergarten</strong></p>
<p>During the pandemic, the U.S. government provided an additional $24 billion to help child care programs nationwide. The funding finally ended last October.</p>
<p>The Century Foundation is a research organization in New York City. It <a class="wsw__a" href="https://tcf.org/content/report/child-care-cliff/">estimates</a> that one-third of the programs could close as a result. That affects more than 2.2 million children. The organization says that child care is important for the economy at large since child care permits parents to stay at work.</p>
<p>Around the world, governments invest little in early childhood education, UNESCO says. About 6.6 percent of education budgets are put toward early education programs, 2 percent in poor countries. That is well below the target of 10 percent by 2030 suggested by the children's organization UNICEF.</p>
<p>In the U.S., parents can choose to put their children at age 5 in <strong>kindergarten</strong> or a child care program.</p>
<p>Kindergarten enrollment has dropped since the COVID-19 pandemic. Concerned about the virus or wanting to avoid online school, hundreds of thousands of families delayed the start of school for their young children.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> found that kindergarten enrollment remained down 5.2 percent in the 2022-2023 school year compared with the 2019-2020 school year.</p>
<p>Deborah Stipek is a former head of the Graduate School of Education at Stanford University. She said kindergarten is where children learn to follow directions, learn good <strong>behavior</strong>, and get used to learning. Stipek said missing that year of school can put kids at a <strong>disadvantage</strong>.</p>
<p>Last year, Aylah went to a children's program that met mainly outdoors instead of enrolling in kindergarten in the state of California. Aylah now has to <strong>adjust</strong> to being inside a classroom and learning the right way to hold a pencil.</p>
<p>"It's harder. Way, way harder," Aylah said of the new way she learned to hold a pencil.</p>
<p>Still, her mother Hannah Levy says it was the right decision to skip kindergarten. She wanted Aylah to enjoy being a child. There is plenty of time, she reasoned, for her daughter to develop study skills.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English, with additional reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>remarkable </strong><em>— adj. </em>unusual or surprising</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>teen </strong><em>— n. </em>someone who is between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enroll </strong><em>— v. </em>to enter as a member of or participant in something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>kindergarten </strong><em>— n. </em>a school or class for very young children</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>behavior </strong><em>— n. </em>the way a person or animal acts or behaves</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>disadvantage </strong><em>— n. </em>something that makes someone or something worse or less likely to succeed than others</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adjust </strong><em>— v. </em> to change in a minor way so that it works better</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Growth Slows, but World’s Population Moves Past 8 Billion to Start 2024  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/growth-slows-but-world-s-population-moves-past-8-billion-to-start-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A U.S. government agency says the world's population grew by about 75 million people in 2023.</p>
<p>The U.S. Census Bureau notes the worldwide growth rate in the past year was just under 1 percent. The agency also said there will be 4.3 births and two deaths around the world every second in 2024.</p>
<p>The United States' growth rate is about half that of the world overall. On January 1, 2024, the U.S. had a population of 335.8 million, the Census Bureau said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A busy platform is seen at Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Terminus on World Population Day in Mumbai, India, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Rajanish Kakade)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8e81-08dc0bccffdb_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A busy platform is seen at Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Terminus on World Population Day in Mumbai, India, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Rajanish Kakade)</span></div>
<p>The numbers look large. But growth rates around the world have been slowing. The United Nations notes the world population will reach 9 billion in about 15 years. That is three years longer than it took to move from 7 billion to 8 billion. The world population reached 8 billion people in November 2022.</p>
<p>If the current rate continues, the 2020s are likely to be the slowest growing decade in American history, the Census Bureau said.</p>
<p>William Frey is a population expert at the Brookings Institution, a research group based in Washington, D.C. He said the growth rate in the U.S. from 2020 to 2030 will be under 4 percent. The slowest-growing decade recorded in the U.S. took place in the 1930s, after the long economic <strong>depression</strong>. The growth rate for that decade was 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>Frey said the predicted growth rate could "<strong>tick up</strong>" in the next few years. But he said it is not likely to be higher than 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>Immigration is the reason why the U.S. will not suffer a population loss in 2024. There should be one birth every nine seconds and one death every 9.5 seconds. But there will likely be two new American immigrants every minute in 2024. As a result, every 24.2 seconds, the U.S. population will increase by one person.</p>
<p>The two most populous countries are India and China. India moved ahead of China at some point in 2023. The two countries both have more than 1.4 billion people. By 2050, China's population is expected to decrease by 2.7 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>depression <i></i>173;</strong>–n. a long period of time when a country's economy contracts instead of grows</p>
<p><strong>tick up (expression) </strong>–v. to increase by a small amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Rescuers Search for Survivors after Deadly Earthquake  (2024/1/3) | 日本救援人员搜寻地震幸存者</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-rescuers-search-for-survivors-after-deadly-earthquake.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A series of powerful earthquakes in western Japan have left at least 55 people dead and damaged thousands of buildings, automobiles and boats.<br/>
日本西部发生的一系列强烈地震已造成至少55人死亡，数千栋建筑、汽车和船只受损。</p>
<p>The first quake struck New Year's Day, registering 7.6 in magnitude, or strength. The shaking caused major damage across Ishikawa prefecture.<br/>
第一次地震发生在元旦，震级为7.6级。地震对整个石川县造成了严重破坏。</p>
<p>Japanese media reports said the quake destroyed tens of thousands of homes and cut water, power and phone services in some areas.<br/>
日本媒体报道称，地震摧毁了数以万计的房屋，并切断了一些地区的水、电和电话服务。</p>
<p>The mayor in the town of Suzu, near the quake's center, said up to 90 percent of homes may have been destroyed, Reuters news agency reported.<br/>
据路透社报道，震中附近的宿州市市长表示，多达90%的房屋可能已被摧毁。</p>
<p>The earthquake set off tsunami warnings along Japan's western coast. Officials ordered about 100,000 people to leave their homes Monday night. They were sent to schools and sports centers to take shelter. Many returned to their homes Tuesday after the warnings were lifted.<br/>
地震在日本西海岸引发海啸警报。周一晚上，官方下令约10万人离开家园。他们被送到学校和体育中心避难。警报解除后，许多人于周二返回家园。</p>
<p>Japan's Meteorological Agency said about 200 aftershocks had struck since the main quake and that more were expected in coming days.<br/>
日本气象厅表示，自主震以来，已经发生了大约200次余震，预计未来几天还会有更多余震。</p>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida told reporters the government had deployed teams that included military troops, police and local rescuers. "We have received reports that there are still many people waiting to be rescued under collapsed buildings," he said.<br/>
日本首相岸田文雄告诉记者，政府已经部署了包括军队、警察和当地救援人员在内的队伍。他说：“我们收到报告称，仍有许多人困在倒塌的建筑物下等待救援。”</p>
<p>Kishida added that saving lives is the top goal.<br/>
岸田文雄补充说，拯救生命是首要目标。</p>
<p>Japan sits on the so-called Ring of Fire, a collection of volcanoes and fault lines found around the Pacific Basin. About 20 percent of the world's earthquakes of magnitude 6 or greater happen in that area.<br/>
日本位于所谓的环太平洋火山带上，这是太平洋盆地周围发现的火山和断层带的集合。世界上大约20%的6级及以上地震发生在该地区。</p>
<p>Monday's earthquake was Japan's deadliest since 2016. Emergency teams battled fires in several cities, as rescuers searched for people trapped in wreckage.<br/>
周一的地震是日本自2016年以来死亡人数最多的一次地震。紧急救援队在几个城市灭火，救援人员正在搜寻被困在废墟中的人员。</p>
<p>Shoichi Kobayashi lives in the city of Wajima. He told Reuters he was at home celebrating New Year's with his wife and son when the quake hit and sent furniture flying across the house. "I've never experienced a quake that powerful," Kobayashi said.<br/>
小林昭一住在和岛市。他告诉路透社，地震发生时，他正在家里与妻儿庆祝新年，家具在房子里乱飞。小林说：“我从未经历过如此强烈的地震。”</p>
<p>In the city of Nanao, Fujiko Ueno said she was celebrating with about 20 people in her home when the earthquake struck. The quake caused walls to collapse onto a parked car. Ueno said no one in the group was injured. "It all happened in the blink of an eye," she said.<br/>
南尾市的上野藤子说，地震发生时，她正在家中与大约20人一起庆祝。地震导致围墙砸到一辆停着的汽车上。上野说，团队中没有人受伤。她说：“这一切都发生在眨眼之间。”</p>
<p>Toshitaka Katada is a University of Tokyo professor who specializes in disasters. He told The Associated Press that people were better prepared for this event because the area had been hit by quakes in recent years. "There is probably no people on earth other than Japanese who are so disaster-ready," Katada said.<br/>
片田敏孝是东京大学专门研究灾害的教授。他告诉美联社，人们对这一事件有了更好的准备，因为该地区近年来遭受过地震袭击。片田说：“除了日本人，地球上可能没有其他人做好了这种灾难准备。”</p>
<p>Government officials said several nuclear centers in the area were operating normally. A 2011 earthquake and tsunami caused three reactors to melt down and release large amounts of radiation at the Fukushima nuclear power center in northeastern Japan.<br/>
政府官员表示，该地区的几个核电站运行正常。2011年的地震和海啸导致日本东北部福岛核电站的三个反应堆熔毁并释放出大量辐射。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Aims to Put Human-like Robots in Space  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/nasa-aims-to-put-human-like-robots-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA's human-like robot Valkyrie looks powerful. It stands 188 centimeters tall and weighs 136 kilograms.</p>
<p>Valkyrie is named after supernatural females in Norse <strong>mythology</strong>. The robot is being tested at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>The robot is designed to operate in "...damaged human-engineered environments," like areas hit by natural disasters, NASA said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="NASA's humanoid robot Valkyrie opens a bag at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, U.S., November 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Evan Garcia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/82577d22-7057-443e-8c7d-aaf9d007bf25_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">NASA's humanoid robot Valkyrie opens a bag at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, U.S., November 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Evan Garcia)</span></div>
<p>But robots like Valkyrie could also work in space one day.</p>
<p>Robots that look like humans, or humanoid robots, have a <strong>torso</strong>, head, two arms and two legs. Engineers believe that humanoid robots will be able to work similarly to humans and use the same tools and equipment. They just need the right software.</p>
<p>NASA Dexterous Robotics team leader Shaun Azimi said humanoid robots in space could do dangerous jobs. Such jobs include cleaning <strong>solar panels </strong>or dealing with equipment outside the spacecraft. As a result, human astronauts could pay more attention to exploration and discovery.</p>
<p>"We're not trying to replace human crews, we're really just trying to take the<strong> dull</strong>, dirty and dangerous work off their plates to allow them to <strong>focus </strong>on those higher-level activities," Azimi said.</p>
<p>NASA is partnering with robotics companies like Apptronik, which is based in Austin, Texas. The goal is to learn how humanoid robots developed for purposes on Earth could help the development of future humanoid robots meant for space.</p>
<p>Apptronik is developing Apollo, a humanoid robot whose jobs on Earth will include working in warehouses and manufacturing plants. The robot can move packages and organize objects. Apptronik plans to start providing the humanoid robots to companies in early 2025.</p>
<p>Apptronik Chief Technology Officer Nick Paine said Apollo has strengths in comparison to humans.</p>
<p>"We're targeting having this system online 22 hours a day," Paine said. "This does have a <strong>swappable</strong> <strong>battery</strong>, so you can work for four hours, swap the battery and then keep going."</p>
<p>Apptronik chief Jeff Cardenas said there are many possibilities as new software and development increase Apollo's abilities.</p>
<p>"The approach is we're starting in the warehouse and on the manufacturing floor, but then it can move into retail...to <strong>delivery </strong>and out more into what we call unstructured spaces," Cardenas said.</p>
<p>In years to come, those "unstructured" areas could include space, Azimi said. He said the robots are being designed so they can be easily changed to do many different jobs.</p>
<p>"Robots like Apollo are designed with <strong>modularity </strong>in mind to be able to adapt to many <strong>applications</strong>," Azimi said.</p>
<p>Azimi added that NASA is aiming to find out what areas it needs to look into "to bring a<strong> terrestrial </strong>system into the space environment..."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Evan Garcia reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________</em>_____________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mythology </strong><em>– n. </em>the myths of a particular group or culture</p>
<p><strong>torso </strong><em>–n.</em> the part of the human body below the neck and above the waist</p>
<p><strong>dull </strong><em>– adj. </em>not interesting</p>
<p><strong>solar panel</strong> <em>– n. </em>a flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>– v. </em>to direct your attention or effort at something specific</p>
<p><strong>swappable </strong><em>–adj.</em> describes an act of giving or taking one thing in return for another thing</p>
<p><strong>battery</strong><em> –n. </em>a device that stores electricity and provides direct electrical current to electronics</p>
<p><strong>delivery</strong> <em>–n. </em>the act of taking something from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>modularity </strong><em>– n.</em> the quality of consisting of separate parts</p>
<p><strong>application<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the ability to be used for practical purposes</p>
<p><strong>terrestrial </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to on happening on the Earth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Treatments for Sickle Cell Remain Out of Reach for Many  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-treatments-for-sickle-cell-remain-out-of-reach-for-many.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>United States health officials recently approved two new gene treatments for sickle cell disease (SCD). The treatments provide hope that the disease might be curable. But experts say high costs and limited availability will prevent many people from receiving them.</p>
<p>SCD is a genetic disorder that causes oxygen-carrying red blood cells in the body to become misshapen. The condition can block blood flow and cause severe pain and organ damage.</p>
<p>SCD is more common among Black Americans, Africans and Middle Easterners than other population groups. Many children with the most severe form of the disease die before age five, usually from an infection or severe blood loss.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gautam Dongre, of the National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations, sits for a portrait with his daughter, Sumedha, 13, at their residence in Nagpur, India, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2775-08dc0187f1c0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Gautam Dongre, of the National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations, sits for a portrait with his daughter, Sumedha, 13, at their residence in Nagpur, India, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)</span></div>
<p>Worldwide, the disease is believed to affect millions. It is known to be common in places with high cases of malaria, like Africa and India. Scientific research has shown that people who have SCD seem to react less severely when they are infected with malaria.</p>
<p>While an estimated 1 million people suffer with the condition in India, many of them will not get the chance to receive the new gene treatments. The situation is not new to developing countries. Many have long faced limitations on medicines and other treatment methods for disease.</p>
<p>But the problem is even more severe with the new SCD treatments and other gene-based methods. This is mainly because of the high cost of treatment. The two methods approved in the U.S. – both of which are given as a single treatment – cost between $2.2 million and $3.1 million.</p>
<p>In addition, the treatment itself can be difficult to carry out in developing nations. This is because the process generally involves several steps and requires longer stays in well-equipped hospitals.</p>
<p>Vertex's treatment, called Casgevy, is designed to repair the genetic condition that causes misshapen cells in sickle cell sufferers. It uses a <strong>gene editing</strong> technology called CRISPR to do so. The other treatment, offered by a company called Bluebird Bio, does not use CRISPR technology. But it requires a similar treatment process as Vertex's version.</p>
<p>Dr. David Altshuler is the chief scientific officer at Vertex. He told <em>The Associated Press</em> that while there is clearly a "great unmet need" for the new SCD treatments, the process also presents "<strong>challenges</strong>."</p>
<p>Altshuler said Vertex is working to simplify the treatment process to make it be available to more people. For example, his team is seeking to develop a medication in pill form that could perform similarly to the gene editing method.</p>
<p>But experts have warned that simpler treatments will likely still be too costly for many people. This has led to calls for governments and non-profit organizations to get involved to help provide financial assistance to patients.</p>
<p>Gautam Dongre lives in the city of Nagpur in central India. His two children suffer from SCD. He told the AP he has been "praying the treatment should come to us."</p>
<p>Dongre's son is now 19 years old and his daughter is 13. They both currently take a drug called hydroxyurea. That drug has long been used to help prevent the formation of sickle-shaped red blood cells in an effort to control pain and other damaging effects.</p>
<p>Dongre leads India's National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations. He said many patients in rural parts of India are dying at very young ages without getting effective treatment.</p>
<p>He added that if the gene treatments for SCD one day make it to India, he would like his children to be among the first to get them.</p>
<p>But Dongre noted that people in all countries – rich or poor – should be able to get the latest treatments available. "We are all part of one single planet," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gene editing </strong><em>– n. </em>the process of changing genes using scientific methods in an effort to prevent or cure disease</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>– n. </em>something difficult that tests one's ability or determination</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Connected Are You to the World?  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/how-connected-are-you-to-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Saodat Sadikova is an English teacher in Jizzakh, Uzbekistan. As a young girl, she dreamed of becoming a flight attendant and traveling the world. Her parents told her she would have to learn at least three languages in order to reach that goal.</p>
<p>Although she was not able to become a flight attendant, Sadikova did study languages. She speaks Uzbek, Russian, English and Turkish.</p>
<p>Sadikova has never traveled outside Uzbekistan. Even so, she reports feeling connected to people around the world. "The whole world is for human beings," Sadikova said. She still dreams of visiting many countries.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency's Digital Map of the World Project. (Graphic: BAE Systems)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7d6c4a69-ddbc-48cf-8962-dfbdd7379717_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency's Digital Map of the World Project. (Graphic: BAE Systems)</span></div>
<p>American Trina Bright worked in education for nearly 25 years. Today, she lives in the southern U.S. state of Arkansas. During her career, she traveled to many countries, including China and South Africa.</p>
<p>Bright used stories from her travels to help her students in the U.S. understand their place in the world. She spent most of her career in a minority-serving school district. Sharing stories from her travels helped her students see value in their own cultures. "There's value in all experiences, not just <strong>typical</strong> American ones," Bright said.</p>
<p>Bright has visited more than 20 countries. But Bright, unlike Sadikova, does not report feeling connected to people around the world.</p>
<p>Bright is not alone. She is among the more than half of Americans who report they do not feel especially close to people around the world.</p>
<p>That information comes from a new report by Pew Research Center, an organization that aims to inform the public about the issues, beliefs and trends shaping the world. The report, called <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/12/06/attitudes-on-an-interconnected-world/" target="_blank">Attitudes on an Interconnected World</a></em>, was released on December 6.</p>
<p>Pew recently asked people in 24 countries a series of questions about how connected they feel to their own communities and countries as well as to people around the world. Pew researchers looked at, among other things, how international travel experience relates to feelings of connectedness.</p>
<p>About half of all <strong>respondents</strong> reported they feel at least <strong>somewhat</strong> close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>Feeling close to others around the world is more common in Europe than in most other places, the study found. In the United States, only 35 percent of the respondents said they feel at least somewhat connected to those in other countries. The percentage was even lower in Argentina (28 percent) and Indonesia (22 percent).</p>
<p>The study found that, in general, respondents who had traveled to at least one other country feel more connected to people around the world.</p>
<p>Ninety-nine percent of respondents in the Netherlands reported having visited at least one other country and about half said they had visited 10 or more countries. The Pew researchers found that 77 percent of respondents from the Netherlands said they feel at least somewhat close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>But international travel does not always mean a person feels a closeness to people around the world. Bright, the retired American schoolteacher, is one such exception. She said, "I don't know a bunch of people around the world, just some." And, she said, her connections to them are not especially deep.</p>
<p>Pew researchers found a similar case in Sweden. Ninety-nine percent of Swedish respondents said they had visited at least one other country. Yet a much smaller share of Swedish respondents – 47 percent – report feeling close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>In fact, a higher number of Indian respondents – 68 percent – report feeling at least somewhat close to people all over the world. Yet just 3 percent of respondents from India said they had traveled to another country. Such findings show that international connectedness can be formed in ways other than traveling overseas.</p>
<p>Sadikova, the Uzbek English teacher, told VOA Learning English she feels connected to people all over the world even though she has never traveled outside Uzbekistan. She said, "Some years ago it was difficult for us to get information about people in the world, but currently, because of media, it is quite easy to get <strong>acquainted with</strong> events and news."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for Learning English with additional information from Pew Research Center.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>typical</strong>–<em>adj</em>. normal</p>
<p><strong>respondent</strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who answers a question</p>
<p><strong>somewhat</strong>–<em>adj</em>. a moderate amount</p>
<p><strong>acquainted with</strong>—<em>phrasal verb</em>. to be informed about someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>2023 Was Another Big Year for Space Missions  (2024/1/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/was-another-big-year-for-space-missions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>As 2023 comes to a close, we are taking a look back at some of the biggest space stories of the year.</p>
<p><strong>Asteroid sample returns to Earth</strong></p>
<p>A container carrying asteroid material captured in space three years ago <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-s-first-asteroid-samples-arrive-on-earth/7283121.html">arrived safely</a> on Earth in September. The container, or capsule, was released by the American space agency NASA's Osiris-Rex spacecraft. It floated to Earth and landed in a desert area in the western state of Utah.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The first full-color image released by NASA from the James Webb Space Telescope shows the galaxy cluster SMACS 0723, in a composite made from images at different wavelengths taken with a Near-Infrared Camera and released July 11, 2022. (NASA)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/09680000-0a00-0242-06b8-08da64e835e7_cx0_cy17_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The first full-color image released by NASA from the James Webb Space Telescope shows the galaxy cluster SMACS 0723, in a composite made from images at different wavelengths taken with a Near-Infrared Camera and released July 11, 2022. (NASA)</span></div>
<p>The spacecraft captured the asteroid material, or sample, from the <strong>asteroid</strong> Bennu in 2020. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasas-bennu-asteroid-sample-contains-carbon-water/">announced</a> in October the first examinations of the sample showed evidence of high-carbon material and water. These two substances suggest the possibility that "the building blocks of life on Earth may be found in the rock."</p>
<p><strong>Psyche mission</strong></p>
<p>NASA's Psyche spacecraft launched on a <strong>mission</strong> to observe an asteroid made mostly of metal. It is expected to travel 3.6 billion kilometers over six years to reach the asteroid, also called Psyche.</p>
<p>NASA believes the asteroid could have separated during violent crashes that happened during our solar system's early creation. Scientists think data collected on the asteroid could provide new details about how rocky planets, including Earth, formed.</p>
<p><strong>Laser communication demonstration</strong></p>
<p>The Psyche spacecraft is also being used <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-laser-communication-test-gets-data-from-16-million-kilometers-away/7366203.html">to test a laser-based communication method</a>. The system aims to greatly improve data links between Earth and spacecraft exploring deep space.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/cat-steals-the-show-in-video-sent-by-laser-from-space/7405809.html">demonstrated the technology</a> with a short video sent by the laser technology over 30 million kilometers to Earth. The space agency said it took less than two minutes for the video to reach an observatory in California. The video showed a cat repeatedly chasing a red laser light.</p>
<p><strong>Oldest black hole discovery</strong></p>
<p>Scientists <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-scientists-discover-oldest-black-hole-yet-/7345766.html">announced</a> last month they had discovered the oldest black hole ever found. The huge object is believed to have formed about 470 million years after the Big Bang. The researchers said the findings confirm their theory that supermassive black holes existed in the very early universe.</p>
<p><strong>European telescope shows ‘dark universe'</strong></p>
<p>Last month, the European Space Agency (ESA) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/new-space-telescope-aims-to-show-dark-universe-/7347238.html">released</a> the first images from its new Euclid space telescope. ESA designed Euclid to study dark matter and dark energy. Scientists think those hidden forms of matter and energy make up 95 percent of the universe. ESA said the newly-released images covered 1,000 galaxies about 240 million light years away from Earth.</p>
<p><strong>Webb telescope observes distant black hole </strong></p>
<p>Data collected by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/webb-telescope-observes-most-distant-black-hole/7179285.html">helped astronomers identify</a> the most distant, active supermassive black hole ever discovered. Researchers said the black hole sits at the center of a galaxy called CEERS 1019. The galaxy is estimated to have existed about 570 million years after the Big Bang.</p>
<p><strong>Ingenuity helicopter keeps exploring Mars</strong></p>
<p>Earlier this month, NASA said its Ingenuity helicopter continues to perform well in tests carried out on Mars. So far, Ingenuity has completed at least 66 flights over the past two-and-a-half years. NASA said it is also <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-continues-mars-helicopter-experiments-tests-new-design-on-earth/7379281.html">testing equipment on Earth</a> that it plans to include in future helicopters built for space exploration. The latest tests on Earth involved new <strong>rotor blades</strong> the space agency said reached speeds near the speed of sound in experiments.</p>
<p><strong>India lands spacecraft on moon</strong></p>
<p>In August, India became the fourth country to successfully <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/india-successfully-lands-spacecraft-on-moon/7238173.html">land a spacecraft on the moon</a>. The moon lander, called Chandrayaan-3, also became the first spacecraft to land near the moon's south pole. The south pole is thought to be an important area, with scientists saying it may contain large amounts of frozen water and minerals.</p>
<p><strong>Chinese water discovery on moon</strong></p>
<p>Chinese scientists <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/china-research-mission-finds-new-source-of-water-on-moon/7025621.html">announced in March</a> they had discovered water in materials collected during the country's Chang'e 5 mission. Researchers from Nanjing University reported the water was in the form of extremely small <strong>beads</strong> found in dirt collected in 2020. The scientists noted that billions, if not trillions, of these beads could exist on the moon, possibly providing a huge water source. But the team said mining the water would be difficult.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid</strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>a flight by a spacecraft to perform a specific task</p>
<p><strong>rotor blade </strong><em>– n. </em>a thin, flat pieces of material that spin to make aircraft lift off the ground and travel</p>
<p><strong>bead </strong><em>– n. </em>a small, round drop of liquid (such as water or blood)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Louisiana’s Creole Culture Extends Far and Wide  (2024/1/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/louisiana-s-creole-culture-extends-far-and-wide.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 December 2023</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">Language experts estimate as many as 10,000 people still speak the French-based language Louisiana Creole.</p>
<p class="MsoBodyText">In addition, many others in New Orleans and across the southern U.S. state consider themselves part of the culture that draws tens of thousands of people to events. The celebrations include autumn's Festival Acadiens et Creoles, summer's Creole Tomato Festival, and spring's Tremé Creole Gumbo &amp; Congo Square Rhythms Festival.</p>
<p class="MsoBodyText">But for locals and visitors alike, everyday evidence shows how strong Creole culture is in Louisiana. The state's performance spaces and airwaves are often filled with the driving, <strong>rhythmic</strong> sound of zydeco and other Creole and Cajun music. Louisiana's restaurants offer <strong>dishes</strong> with rich, complex flavors including gumbo, hot sausage, red beans and rice, and shrimp étouffée.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The Cheyenne and 7th Ward Creole Hunters Mardi Gras Indians are pictured at the New Orleans Jazz and Heritage Festival in New Orleans, May 4, 2017. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5f19-08dbe24a75ff_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The Cheyenne and 7th Ward Creole Hunters Mardi Gras Indians are pictured at the New Orleans Jazz and Heritage Festival in New Orleans, May 4, 2017. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)</span></div>
<p>"To celebrate Creole culture is to wake up and live in New Orleans," said Christina Bragg. She is a member of the Mahogany Blue Babydolls, a parade group for Black and mixed-race women.</p>
<p>"Celebrating Creole is celebrating our day-to-day lives. The food we eat. The music we dance to. The way we gather with friends to parade during <strong>Mardi Gras</strong>," she said. "Every day I open my eyes and breathe, it's a celebration of Creole culture, because that's who I am."</p>
<p><strong>Difficult to define</strong></p>
<p>So, what is Creole?</p>
<p>"It's food, it's music, it's architecture, it's <strong>style</strong> and it's traditions," Mona Lisa Saloy told VOA. "There are millions of Creole people in countries across the world...we are all so much more alike than we are different. We create beautiful cultures everywhere we go, and I think that's evident here in Louisiana."</p>
<p>Saloy is the writer of the poetry collection <em>Black Creole Chronicles</em> and served as Louisiana's poet laureate from 2021 to 2023. She said Creole cultures all over the world have similarities to Louisiana's.</p>
<p>"<strong>Architectural</strong> styles common in New Orleans like the Creole Cottage or the Shotgun home can be found in other places with Creoles, such as in other parts of the American South and the Caribbean," she said. "Much of our music <strong>derives</strong> from the rhythms of Africa and the Caribbean, as does much of our food — elements of gumbo such as the long rice and okra, for example, or the <strong>prevalence</strong> of beans."</p>
<p>How the word "Creole" is defined changes from place to place and person to person.</p>
<p>The word "Creole" is believed to have come from the Portuguese word crioulo, which developed from the Latin word for "to create." Some say it was used in the European slave trade to describe a slave born in the New World and not in Africa. The word took on different meanings in different places. Creole in much of Africa and part of the Caribbean, for example, came to mean people of mixed ethnic or racial backgrounds.</p>
<p>In Louisiana, the definition has changed over the years.</p>
<p>"Here, the definition kind of depends on who you ask," said Vance Vaucresson. He is a New Orleans-based Creole and owner of a local restaurant, the Vaucresson Sausage Company.</p>
<p>"I prefer an inclusive definition," he said. "By that definition, anyone born in Louisiana could be Creole. During our colonial <strong>era</strong>, it was meant to differentiate people born in the Americas — usually of French, Spanish or African descent — from those born in Europe or Africa."</p>
<p>Describing his definition, Vaucresson added: "...it doesn't matter. If you're born here and embrace the culture, you can be Creole."</p>
<p>In Louisiana of the 1700s and 1800s, the more inclusive definition was possibly the most accepted. White people with European ancestry were just as likely to call themselves Creole as mixed-race people of African ancestry.</p>
<p>White Creoles claimed the term because it set them apart from settlers who were coming from Northern states after The Louisiana Purchase from France in 1803. Mixed-race Creoles, too, claimed the term because it differentiated them from enslaved people.</p>
<p>Don Vappie is a Creole jazz musician in New Orleans. He described the idea of Creole before the Civil war as organized into three levels. "It was more of a three-<strong>tier</strong> racial <strong>hierarchy</strong> here, instead of the two-tiered Black-or-white experienced elsewhere in the U.S," he said.</p>
<p>After the American Civil War, however, many of these differences in New Orleans disappeared.</p>
<p>"Creole or not, white people had more in common with white people and Black people had more in common with Black people," Vappie told VOA.</p>
<p>Saloy believes Creole is firmly connected to African culture and should stay that way.</p>
<p>"The <strong>ingredients</strong> in our food, the rhythm in our music and dance, the details in our architecture — it's all connected to West African culture," she said, "That's our heritage."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Matt Haines reported this story for VOANews. Caty Weaver adapted it for Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rhythmic </strong>–adj. having a regular sound or movement</p>
<p><strong>dish </strong>–n. a kind of food that is prepared in a particular way</p>
<p><strong>Mardi Gras (Fat Tuesday) </strong>–n. the Tuesday before the Catholic Lent religious observance</p>
<p><strong>style </strong>–n. a particular way of designing something, doing some activity, or behaving</p>
<p><strong>architectural </strong>–adj. related to the design of buildings</p>
<p><strong>derive </strong>–v. to come from</p>
<p><strong>prevalence </strong>–n. something that is widespread or usual</p>
<p><strong>era </strong>–n. a period of time</p>
<p><strong>tier </strong>–n. a level, especially one in an organization or a group</p>
<p><strong>hierarchy </strong>–n. a system in which things are ordered by importance or status</p>
<p><strong>ingredient </strong>–n. a material that is used to make something, especially food</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mexican 'Nuns' Grow Cannabis  (2024/1/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/mexican-nuns-grow-cannabis.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Beneath each full moon, a group of women in religious clothing surround a fire near a village in central Mexico.</p>
<p>They breathe in deeply from a<strong> joint</strong> and blow clouds of <strong>marijuana </strong>smoke out toward the fire.</p>
<p>Despite their religious clothing, the women are not religious. They are part of an international group founded in 2014 called Sisters of the Valley. The group has promised to spread its ideas about the healing powers of the drug marijuana.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Members of Sisters of the Valley, a non-religious international group check hemp that is drying at a house on the Sisters of the Valley's farm on the outskirts of a village in central Mexico, September 2, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha ) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/45a52a89-6715-48c7-93b7-6e679fa46c60_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Members of Sisters of the Valley, a non-religious international group check hemp that is drying at a house on the Sisters of the Valley's farm on the outskirts of a village in central Mexico, September 2, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha ) </span></div>
<p>The group also launched a successful small business in the United States, where about twenty states have legalized recreational marijuana use. It sells products made from <strong>cannabis</strong>, the plant from which marijuana comes.</p>
<p>The Sisters of the Valley business made over $500,000 last year.</p>
<p>But in Mexico, a drug war has hurt the country, and Christianity is built into society. The group says its image of marijuana-smoking nuns is like an act of rebellion, the women say.</p>
<p>The sisters often post on social media, mainly Instagram. The pictures show them caring for cannabis crops, leading workshops, and attending cannabis-related events.</p>
<p>Their business makes around $10,000 each year, small compared to their partners in the U.S.</p>
<p>The five women are careful to hide possible personal and workplace identifiers in the images they post. They do business out of a building with a false storefront.</p>
<p>Cannabis production is a legal gray area in Mexico. Much of the activity remains tied to criminal organizations, called cartels. The women say they worry that both police and crime groups could threaten them.</p>
<p>On a recent weekend, reporters from Reuters news agency visited.</p>
<p>One of the nuns, who uses the name "Sister Bernardet" online, said "The Sisterhood is in a totally different <strong>context</strong> here in Mexico – because of how religious the country is and because of the plant's ties to cartels."</p>
<p>She asked Reuters to not report her real name as she feared attack or punishment if her identity is discovered. In her main job as a <strong>homeopathic </strong>caregiver, she prescribes marijuana to her patients with cancer, joint pain and sleep problems.</p>
<p>"We want to take the plant back from the" drug dealers, she said.</p>
<p>The Sisters have borrowed some ideas from the Beguines, a religious movement that existed for a few hundred years starting in the 1100s. The group, made up of single women, devoted itself to spirituality, scholarship and providing aid to the needy. It was not officially connected to any religion.</p>
<p>The Sisters worldwide say they wear religious clothing called habits to demonstrate uniformity and show respect for the plant.</p>
<p>With the help of Alehli Paz, a chemist and marijuana researcher working with the group, the Sisters in Mexico grow a small crop.</p>
<p>They grow the plants in old paint containers and place them in lines between four walls on a rooftop.</p>
<p>Later, the Sisters move the larger plants to private gardens.</p>
<p>Their work is limited to weekends, when they care for the plants and produce cannabis goods.</p>
<p>The women visit other groups in the expanding cannabis community in Mexico City pushing for full legalization. The women also give workshops that touch on everything from how to make products like cannabis infusions to the chemistry behind the plant.</p>
<p>Business possibilities aside, the women argue that the fight against drugs in Latin America has been a failure, leading to violence and mass imprisonment.</p>
<p>The Sisters of the Valley founder in Mexico calls herself "Sister Camilla" online. She would not give her real name to Reuters. She said she grew up in a religious family. She left home at 16 partly because of her mother's strong religious ideas, she said. When she started Sisters of the Valley Mexico, their relationship became even more difficult.</p>
<p>"It was hard for her to accept," she said about her mother. "She had certain ideas, heavily shaped by religion."</p>
<p>But today, after long talks about the plant and the legalization movement, her mother helps with the group's operations, she said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Sarah Kinosian reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>joint </strong><em>– n. informal - </em>a marijuana cigarette</p>
<p><strong>marijuana </strong><em>– n.</em> the dried leaves and flowers of the hemp plant that are smoked as a drug</p>
<p><strong>cannabis<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> a drug such as marijuana or hashish that comes from the hemp plant</p>
<p><strong>context</strong> <em>– n.</em> the conditions that exist where and when something happens</p>
<p><strong>homeopathic </strong><em>– adj. </em>describes a system of alternative medicine</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Arizona Company Works to Recycle Old Solar Panels  (2023/12/31) | 美国企业致力于回收太阳能旧面板</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/arizona-company-works-to-recycle-old-solar-panels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The first generation of solar panels in use on homes and other buildings will soon be too old to work anymore. Owners will need to replace them.<br/>
用于家庭和其他建筑的第一代太阳能电池板很快就会太旧，无法再使用。业主们需要更换它们。</p>
<p>But, what can be done with the old equipment, aside from adding it to waste landfills?<br/>
但是，除了将旧设备送到垃圾填埋场之外，还能对其做些什么呢？</p>
<p>Adam Saghei in the U.S. state of Arizona hopes he has the answer.<br/>
美国亚利桑那州的亚当·赛葛希望他能解决。</p>
<p>He is the leader of a business called We Recycle Solar.<br/>
他是一家名为“We Recycle Solar”的公司的负责人。</p>
<p>He said most solar panels last about 30 years. So many of the first panels put to use in America are reaching the end of their usefulness. Most will go to landfills, he said.<br/>
他说，大多数太阳能电池板的使用寿命约为30年。许多最早在美国投入使用的面板已经到了实用性的极限。他说，大部分将被送往垃圾填埋场。</p>
<p>However, his company, and a few others, are working to collect old panels and make them useful again.<br/>
然而，他的公司和其他一些公司正在努力收集旧面板，并使其再次可利用。</p>
<p>He said the process is part of what he called "the circular economy."<br/>
他说，这个过程是他所说的“循环经济”的一部分。</p>
<p>"(Solar) is a sustainable form of energy; there needs to be a plan for the retirement of those assets," he said.<br/>
他说：“（太阳能）是一种可持续的能源形式；需要有一个退役这些资产的计划。”</p>
<p>For example, Saghei said many of the panels that fail only have a small problem. Often it can be easily fixed. Then, the repaired piece can be offered in new markets, often in other countries.<br/>
赛葛说，例如，许多失效的面板只有一点小问题。通常情况下，它可以很容易地修复。然后，修复后的零件可以提供给新市场，通常是在国外。</p>
<p>Saghei said the company's engineers learned how to recover valuable material from the old solar panels. They can remove silver, copper, glass, and silicone from the broken panels. All the materials have market value.<br/>
赛葛说，该公司的工程师学会了如何从旧太阳能电池板中回收有价值的材料。它们可以分离破损面板上的银、铜、玻璃和硅树脂。所有这些材料都有市场价值。</p>
<p>It took the engineers three years to perfect the materials recovery process, which Saghei called "urban mining."<br/>
工程师们花了三年时间完善了材料回收过程，赛葛称之为“城市采矿”。</p>
<p>The company can process up to 7,500 solar panels every day at its center in Yuma. Saghei said they can recover up to 99 percent of the useful material from each panel.<br/>
该公司位于尤马的工厂每天可以处理多达7500块太阳能电池板。赛葛说，他们可以从每块面板中回收高达99%的有用材料。</p>
<p>Meng Tao is a professor at Arizona State University and an expert on sustainable energy systems.<br/>
孟涛是亚利桑那州立大学教授，也是可持续能源系统专家。</p>
<p>He said solar panel installations will reach their highest numbers in about 20 years. At that point, he said, the number of new panels being produced will equal the number of old panels going out of service. The cost to recycle the old panels, however, may be too high.<br/>
他说，太阳能电池板的安装数量将达到20年来的最高水平。他说，到那时，正在生产的新面板数量将等于停用的旧面板数量。然而，回收旧面板的成本可能太高。</p>
<p>At that point, he said, it will be very easy for homeowners to decide to send their panels to a landfill. But the U.S. government, he said, should provide money for solar panel recycling projects as part of its environmental policies.<br/>
他说，到那时，房主很容易决定把他们的电池板送到垃圾填埋场。但他说，美国政府应该为太阳能电池板回收项目提供资金，作为其环境政策的一部分。</p>
<p>That way, making a better choice will be easier for homeowners.<br/>
这样，对房主来说，也更容易做出更好的选择。</p>
<p>Saghei said he hopes his company is getting into the business at the right time. Recovering the materials from old panels is costly work. He said it takes a lot of labor, time and energy.<br/>
赛葛说，他希望他的公司是在正确的时间进入这项业务。从旧面板中回收材料是一项成本高昂的工作。他说这需要大量的劳动力、时间和精力。</p>
<p>But he thinks taking out the valuable materials and sending them back into the supply chain is a winning idea.<br/>
但他认为，取出有价值的材料并将其送回供应链是一个成功的想法。</p>
<p>"These are markets that are growing," Saghei said. "What's exciting is we're at the forefront."<br/>
赛葛说：“这是增长中的市场，令人兴奋的是，我们站在了最前沿。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Affirmative Action Decision Tops Higher Education News in 2023  (2023/12/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/affirmative-action-decision-tops-higher-education-news-in-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 December 2023</span><br/>
<p><em>As 2023 comes to a close, we take a look back at the top stories and developments in higher education. They include a major high court decision on college admissions, the return of international students at U.S. colleges, the closure of small colleges and study programs, and an Ivy League president stepping down under pressure. </em></p>
<p><strong>Affirmative Action decision</strong></p>
<p>In late June, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that universities could no longer consider the race of a student when making admissions decisions.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Demonstrators protest outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, DC on June 29, 2023, after the Supreme Court struck down affirmative action in college admissions, saying race cannot be a factor. (AP Photo/Jose Luis Magana, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-4f95-08db7e332d43_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Demonstrators protest outside of the Supreme Court in Washington, DC on June 29, 2023, after the Supreme Court struck down affirmative action in college admissions, saying race cannot be a factor. (AP Photo/Jose Luis Magana, File)</span></div>
<p>The announcement effectively ended the idea of <strong>Affirmative Action</strong>, which had been in place in higher education and the workforce for over 50 years.</p>
<p>In making its decision, the court looked at cases involving Harvard University and the University of North Carolina. Chief Justice John Roberts wrote: "students must be treated based on his or her experiences as an individual – not on the basis of race."</p>
<p>He noted that many who make choices about which students will be permitted to attend universities have given too much importance to the color of a person's skin. "Our constitutional history does not <strong>tolerate</strong> that choice," he continued.</p>
<p>A group called Students for Fair Admissions brought the case through the U.S. court system over a number of years. The group believed that many Asian and white students were not getting a fair chance to attend the most selective colleges and universities in the U.S. because some places were being held for Black students.</p>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden spoke in favor of racially <strong>diverse</strong> colleges and universities after the decision came out.</p>
<p>Many universities said they will change the writing requirements of their applications in order to learn of the life experiences of applicants. The first group of students affected by the new rules will be applying to college in early 2024.</p>
<p>The next step for activists who want to change the way colleges choose students? <strong>Legacy</strong> admissions. A group based in Boston took legal action against Harvard University, saying it should no longer give preference to students whose parents attended Harvard or give money to the school.</p>
<p><strong>Indian students boost numbers</strong></p>
<p>More and more young people from India are now attending college in the United States. As a result, the number of international students studying in the U.S. has returned to pre-pandemic levels.</p>
<p>While students from China are still the largest group, the number of Chinese international students in the U.S. is dropping. But the 269,000 Indian students made up that difference.</p>
<p>Costas Chassapis works at the Stevens Institute of Technology in New Jersey. Chassapis told VOA Learning English that many university leaders in the U.S. are "<strong>ecstatic</strong>" about the increase in Indian students. But he said the increase will not last forever.</p>
<p>The increase is partly due to new rules put in place by Joe Biden's administration. They permit students who complete study programs in STEM – science, technology, engineering and math – to stay in the U.S. for extra work experience.</p>
<p><strong>American students question college</strong></p>
<p>As international students return to the United States, many American young people are expressing concern about the value of a college degree.</p>
<p>The number of American college-age students seeking higher education started falling before the COVID-19 pandemic. Today's young people find that they have work possibilities that pay well even without a college degree. Some say the cost of attending college is simply too high.</p>
<p>West Virginia is the only state in America with a population that is lower today than it was in 1950. The state's public university, West Virginia University (WVU), feels the effects of the population loss. Today, its main campus has about 25,000 students. That number is 10 percent lower than it was in 2015. WVU is facing a $45 million budget deficit.</p>
<p>Last summer, WVU announced plans to cut some study programs. The school will end some language studies, music instruction and writing programs. In addition, 100 educators will likely lose their jobs.</p>
<p>Lisa Di Bartolomeo is one of the language professors concerned about her students. She said: "The best and the brightest students don't see a future for themselves in West Virginia."</p>
<p>But at least WVU remains open. Some small colleges and universities closed or made plans to close in 2023.</p>
<p>One of those schools was Alliance University in New York City. Heather Garcia studied and worked there. She said the university tried to remain open, but its financial problems were too large. She said she is sad to see the school close.</p>
<p>Bryan Alexander is a researcher who looks at the future of higher education. He said small American colleges first try to reduce their costs. When they can no longer cut their costs, they must close. He said many people in higher education are concerned about the number of small schools that have closed in recent years.</p>
<p>"I think, within higher ed, the <strong>alarm</strong> has already been sounded," Alexander said. "Presidents, Deans, <strong>Provosts</strong>...this is the stuff that keeps them up at night."</p>
<p><strong>Ivy League president leaves job under pressure</strong></p>
<p>Liz Magill of the University of Pennsylvania stepped down from her job in early December.</p>
<p>Magill, along with Harvard President Claudine Gay and Sally Kornbluth of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology appeared in front of Congress on December 5. Lawmakers asked the presidents if they felt calls for violence against Jewish people should be against school rules.</p>
<p>The Republican-led congressional committee chose the three leaders because their schools "have been at the center of the rise in <strong>antisemitic</strong> protests," a committee spokesperson said in a statement. The protests are related to the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas.</p>
<p>None of the three school leaders directly spoke against calls for violence against Jewish people. Instead, they said some speech, even "deeply hateful speech," is protected by the U.S. Constitution.</p>
<p>On December 9, Magill resigned from her position under pressure from influential donors and <strong>alumni</strong>.</p>
<p>Gay and Kornbluth received support and criticism. But both were permitted to keep their jobs.</p>
<p>One group of professors at Harvard said colleges and universities should not be influenced by political pressure.</p>
<p>A top legal expert from Harvard, Laurence Tribe, said universities should not be "<strong>bullied</strong> into <strong>micromanaging</strong> their policies."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p>And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English with additional reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>majority </strong><em>–n. </em>more than one half of a group</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong><em>–v. </em>to accept, permit or allow</p>
<p><strong>ecstatic </strong><em>–adj. </em>very excited or happy</p>
<p><strong>legacy </strong><em>–n. </em>how someone will be remembered, a person with ties to the past</p>
<p><strong>estimate </strong><em>–v. </em>to make a guess about something based on experience or understanding about a topic</p>
<p><strong>ecstatic </strong><em>–adj. </em>very excited or happy</p>
<p><strong>alumni </strong><em>–n.</em> the people who graduated from a school or university</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>–v.</em> to frighten, hurt, or threaten (a smaller or weaker person) : to act like a bully toward (someone)</p>
<p><strong>micromanage </strong><em>–v.</em> to try to control all parts of something usually in a way that is not wanted</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Goal! Do You Have One for 2024?  (2023/12/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/goal-do-you-have-one-for-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>December 31, 2023, means the new year 2024 is nearly here! At this time of the year, many people set New Year's <strong>resolutions</strong>. Many people want to make a change in life and others set a <u>goal.</u></p>
<p>So, today we talk about the word <u>goal</u>. You may know this word because you shout "gooaaal" when your team <strong>scores</strong>. It is exciting! It is also exciting when we reach our personal goals.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Chelsea's Levi Colwill, top center, scores a goal during a soccer match between Chelsea and Brighton and Hove Albion, at Stamford Bridge stadium in London on Dec. 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Alastair Grant)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-8988-08dbf42a856a_cx3_cy0_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Chelsea's Levi Colwill, top center, scores a goal during a soccer match between Chelsea and Brighton and Hove Albion, at Stamford Bridge stadium in London on Dec. 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Alastair Grant)</span></div>
<p>A goal is something we want to reach. It is something we work toward. It is important to have goals in life and a plan to <strong>achieve</strong> them. A football player's goal is to score a goal, and a goalie's goal is to stop a ... goal.</p>
<p>Let's continue talking about sports. Many sports involve not only goals but also a <u>goal line</u>. A <u>goal line</u> gives the space on the field in which you can score or make a goal.</p>
<p>Let's talk about American football for a minute. That sport involves tall <u>goal posts.</u> To make a point, a kicker can kick a football between the posts and score. Now, imagine if you are kicking that ball. You have the <u>goal posts</u> in your sights. You kick! It looks good! It looks like the ball is going to go between the posts. But then, at the last minute, someone moves the <u>goal posts,</u> and your ball does not go through.</p>
<p>To <u>move the goal posts</u> as you are kicking the ball would not be fair. If someone <u>moves the goal posts</u>, they are changing the rules of the game or a situation to meet their own needs.</p>
<p>Let's say you are building a house for someone. Both of you agree on a design, plan and price to build the house, and a date to complete the building. As the date of completion arrives, the soon-to-be owner wants to change the design of the house. She says that she wants the new design for the same price.</p>
<p>You could say that she has <u>moved the goal post</u>! Or you could say that she has <u>moved the goal line</u> because some sports use a line and not a post. And some sports use both.</p>
<p>People who have the <u>goal line</u> or <u>goal post</u> moved on them may <u>fall short of their goals</u>. If you fall short of your goal you do not <strong>accomplish</strong> it. You do not succeed.</p>
<p>To reach your goals, it is a good idea to have a plan. Set out small steps you can do to reach your goals. And when you complete those small steps on your way to your end goal ... make sure to celebrate! And make sure no one moves the goal line on you.</p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next year ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>resolution </strong><em>– n.</em> a promise to yourself to do or to not do something</p>
<p><strong>score </strong><em>– v. </em>to win or get a point, goal, etc. in a competition, sport, or game</p>
<p><strong>achieve </strong><em>– v. </em>successfully bring about or reach</p>
<p><strong>accomplish </strong><em>– v. </em>to bring about (a result) by effort</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Barack Obama: African-American  (2023/12/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-barack-obama.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Barack Obama.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Barack Obama" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c610d8ab-a9b4-42fe-a6fb-942ebb9ce341_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Barack Obama</span></div>
<p>He first took office in 2009 and was re-elected in 2012. Because his presidency is so recent, this program will not try to offer a historical<strong> perspective</strong>.</p>
<p>But one part of his legacy is already clear. Obama is the United States' first African-American president. His father was a black man from Kenya; his mother was a white American from the Midwestern state of Kansas.</p>
<p>For many Americans, Obama's presidency was an important symbol in a country that permitted black people to be enslaved.</p>
<p>And, even after the U.S. Constitution officially banned slavery in 1865, African-Americans have been <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2016/06/28/blacks-have-made-gains-in-u-s-political-leadership-but-gaps-remain/">extremely under-represented</a> in the U.S. government.</p>
<p>By 2009, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.senate.gov/pagelayout/history/h_multi_sections_and_teasers/Photo_Exhibit_African_American_Senators.htm" target="_blank">only five </a>African-Americans had <em>ever</em> served in the U.S. Senate – and Obama was one of them.</p>
<p>Even many people who did not vote for Obama said his election to the country's highest office made them proud or hopeful. A <a class="wsw__a" href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/politics/election2008/2008-11-06-poll_n.htm">public opinion survey</a> immediately after Election Day found that two-thirds of Americans believed that the country's racial conflicts could be resolved.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Obama's parents met as students at the University of Hawaii. His father had won a scholarship to study economics. His mother went on to earn a degree in math there, as well as a graduate degree.</p>
<p>The two married and had a son, whom they named after his father: Barack Hussein Obama, Jr.</p>
<p>But the couple soon separated. The older Barack Obama returned to Kenya, where he later died in a car accident.</p>
<p>Barack's mother went on to marry another man. He was from Indonesia. The family moved to Jakarta, and the couple had a daughter named Maya.</p>
<p>When Barack was 10, his mother sent him back to Hawaii to live with her parents. She wanted him to get a good education. Barack finished high school in Hawaii, then went on to Occidental College in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>After two years, he transferred to Columbia University in New York. There, he completed a degree in political science.</p>
<p>But Obama said the best education he received was in one of his first jobs. He worked as a community organizer in Chicago. He helped people who lived in public housing put pressure on the city government to improve their conditions.</p>
<p>Obama later said the work showed him how important it was to understand the legal process. So he entered Harvard Law School.</p>
<p>Over the next years, Obama worked as a lawyer, wrote a <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.nytimes.com/1995/08/06/books/review/06obama-dreams.html">book</a> about his experience as a person of mixed race, and married <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/about-the-white-house/first-ladies/michelle-obama/" target="_blank">Michelle Robinson</a>, a woman he worked with at a law<strong> firm</strong>.</p>
<p>She and Barack Obama settled in Chicago and had two daughters, Malia and Sasha.</p>
<p>When he was in his mid-30s, Obama began his political career. He was elected three times to the Illinois state senate. After 10 years there, he won a seat in the U.S. Senate in a landslide victory.</p>
<p>That same year, Obama attended the Democratic National Convention – the meeting where the party officially nominates a presidential candidate. Obama was not one of the candidates. But the Democrats asked him to make an important speech.</p>
<p>In it, Obama famously <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/?pid=76988" target="_blank">talked about</a> how his life story was an American story. He said he was confident the U.S. could overcome its divisions and achieve unity.</p>
<p>"There's not a<strong> liberal </strong>America and a<strong> conservative</strong> America," he said. "...There's not a black America and white America and Latino America and Asian America. There's a United States of America."</p>
<p>Only four years later, Obama would be elected its 44th president.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Hai Do was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<p><strong>perspective</strong> - <em>n.</em> a way of thinking about and understanding something</p>
<p><strong>firm</strong> - <em>n.</em> a business organization</p>
<p><strong>liberal </strong>-<em> adj.</em> believing that government should be active in supporting social and political change</p>
<p><strong>conservative </strong>- <em>adj.</em> believing in the value of established and traditional practices in politics and society</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Remembering Newsmakers Who Died in 2023  (2023/12/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/remembering-newsmakers-who-died-in-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>2024 is just hours away. Before the world welcomes a new year, we remember some of the influential people who died in 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Sandra Day O'Connor</strong></p>
<p>We start with U.S. Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - President Joe Biden attends a funeral service for retired Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor at the Washington National Cathedral, December 19, 2023, in Washington, D.C. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fbb20de5-880f-4b08-b66d-74a56da7636d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - President Joe Biden attends a funeral service for retired Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor at the Washington National Cathedral, December 19, 2023, in Washington, D.C. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)</span></div>
<p>O'Connor died on December 1. She made history in 1981 when she became the first woman appointed to the United States' highest court. She served in the position for 25 years.</p>
<p>The judge was considered a centrist, or a moderate, in her court opinions. She was often considered the "<strong>swing vote</strong>" on major issues such as abortion, affirmative action and voting rights.</p>
<p>Sandra Day O'Connor was born in El Paso, Texas in 1930. She grew up on a large cow farm there.</p>
<p>The young Sandra was an excellent student and entered Stanford University in California when she was 16, earning a degree in economics. She went on to study law at Stanford. She graduated in the top 10 percent of her class in 1952.</p>
<p>President Ronald Reagan nominated her to the U.S. Supreme Court in 1981. In announcing his choice, he described the judge as "a person for all seasons."</p>
<p>American President Joe Biden spoke at her funeral. He called her "a daughter of the West" and "a pioneer in her own right." He praised her for seeking, in his words, "equal justice under law her whole life."</p>
<p>O'Connor died from problems linked to the disease dementia and a lung infection. She was 93 years old.</p>
<p><strong>Henry Kissinger </strong></p>
<p>The world also said goodbye to former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger, who died November 29.</p>
<p>He was 100 years old.</p>
<p>The German-born Jewish refugee served as the U.S. top diplomat under two presidents, Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford. He won praise and severe criticism in the U.S. and around the world.</p>
<p>Kissinger helped restore ties between the United States and China. He also negotiated the U.S. withdrawal from Vietnam.</p>
<p><strong>Rosalynn Carter</strong></p>
<p>American former first lady Rosalynn Carter died on November 19. She was the closest adviser to her husband, former President Jimmy Carter.</p>
<p>She served as first lady from 1977 to 1981. She <strong>advocated </strong>for better mental health care and help for caregivers in millions of American families. Overseas, she fought disease, mass hunger and the abuse of women and girls. She continued humanitarian work with her husband for 40 years following their time in the White House.</p>
<p>The couple had been married for 77 years when Rosalynn Carter died at the age of 96.</p>
<p>Others from the world of politics who died this year include: former Italian Premier Silvio Berlusconi, former Pakistani leader Pervez Musharraf, and former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang.</p>
<p><strong>Tina Turner</strong></p>
<p>The world also lost cultural leaders in 2023, including the so-called "Queen of Rock ‘n' Roll."</p>
<p>American Singer Tina Turner died in May at the age of 83.</p>
<p>The entertainer teamed up with husband Ike Turner for a series of hit records and live shows in the 1960s and '70s. Ike was abusive and beat Tina. She left the marriage and returned as a solo artist with a best-selling album, <em>Private Dancer,</em> in 1984.</p>
<p>"How do we say farewell to a woman who owned her pain and <strong>trauma</strong> and used it as a means to help change the world?" actor Angela Bassett said in a statement. Bassett played Turner in the 1993 movie <em>What's Love Got to Do With It</em>.</p>
<p>Turner sold more than 150 million records worldwide and won 12 Grammys. The performer was voted along with Ike Turner into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 1991, and individually in 2021. Turner's life story was made into a movie and Broadway musical.</p>
<p>Mick Jagger of the music group The Rolling Stones called Turner "<strong>inspiring</strong>, warm, funny and <strong>generous</strong>" in an Instagram post. And he wrote that Turner "helped me so much when I was young, and I will never forget her."</p>
<p><strong>Kenzaburo Oe </strong></p>
<p>Several Nobel Prize winners died this year, including Japanese writer Kenzaburo Oe. The Nobel literature laureate wrote darkly poetic novels based on his childhood memories from Japan's postwar occupation. He also wrote from his experiences as the parent of a disabled son. Oe died on March 3 at the age of 88.<br type="_moz"/>
</p>
<p><strong>World's oldest person</strong></p>
<p>And the world lost its oldest resident in 2023. French religious worker, or nun, Lucile Rando, died at home in southern France a few weeks before her 119th birthday.</p>
<p>Sister André, as she was known, was born in the town of Alès, southern France, in 1904. The Gerontology Research Group, which confirms details about people thought to be 110 or older, listed her as the oldest known person in the world after the death of Japan's Kane Tanaka, aged 119, in 2022.</p>
<p>Sister André was also one of the world's oldest survivors of COVID-19.</p>
<p>She tested positive for the coronavirus in January 2021, shortly before her 117th birthday. She showed so few signs of the virus that she did not even realize she was infected. News media around the world reported her survival.</p>
<p>In April last year, she was asked about her exceptional <strong>longevity</strong> through two world wars. Sister André told French media, "Working...makes you live. I worked until I was 108."</p>
<p>She was also known to enjoy a daily glass of wine and chocolate.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver wrote this report with additional information from the Associated Press. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>swing vote </strong><em>–n. </em>a person whose vote could go to either side in a dispute, providing a majority with their decision</p>
<p><strong>advocate for </strong><em>–v.</em> (phrasal) to support or argue for a cause or a person</p>
<p><strong>trauma </strong><em>–n.</em> an injury to the body or mind</p>
<p><strong>inspiring<em> </em></strong><em>–adj. </em>something that gives hope to others</p>
<p><strong>generous </strong>–<em>adj.</em> giving time or possessions freely</p>
<p><strong>longevity </strong><em>–n.</em> the condition of living a long time</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The World in Other Words in 2023  (2023/12/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-world-in-other-words-in-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many people consider choices from dictionary publishers, including <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/ai-hallucinate-authentic-or-rizz-for-word-of-the-year/7385065.html">artificial intelligence, authentic or rizz</a>, to be "words of the year." But the Associated Press reported on some words used in other parts of the world that have been gaining popularity.</p>
<p>So today, we will look at other words from around the world for 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Password child in Australia</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Brazilian tourists hold hands standing in a circle in the Pueblo Encanto park in Capilla del Monte, Argentina, July 19, 2023. Known as the nones, they describe themselves as atheists or nothing in particular. (AP Photo/Natacha Pisarenko, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-fadb-08dc070c609d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Brazilian tourists hold hands standing in a circle in the Pueblo Encanto park in Capilla del Monte, Argentina, July 19, 2023. Known as the "nones," they describe themselves as atheists or "nothing in particular." (AP Photo/Natacha Pisarenko, File)</span></div>
<p>In Australia, the local Macquarie Dictionary has been selecting a "word of the month" all year. One was "cozzie livs," a word that Australians use to <strong>complain</strong> about the high cost of living. Another was "murder noodle" for a snake in a country that is home to the world's most poisonous snake.</p>
<p>But "password child" is a word that many parents can recognize. Australians use the term to describe children seen as favored over their brothers or sisters because their name is used in their parents' passwords.</p>
<p><strong>Kitawaramba in Kenya (Swahili) </strong></p>
<p>Paul Mackenzie, a cleric in the East African nation of Kenya, said the word "kitawaramba" on his way to court. He was accused of asking his followers to starve themselves in order to meet Jesus. More than 400 people died as a result.</p>
<p>The unfamiliar word appeared to be a threat. Now Kenyans use it to warn others that something bad might happen to them for their actions.</p>
<p><strong>Bwa kale in Haiti (Creole)</strong></p>
<p>Criminal groups have brought violence, including killings and kidnappings, to the daily lives of people in Haiti, an island nation in the Caribbean Sea.</p>
<p>Civilians have been fighting back and saying "bwa kale" as they chase suspected criminals. "Bwa Kale" means "<strong>peeled</strong> wood" in the Haitian Creole language.</p>
<p>The term had long been used to express male <strong>dominance</strong> and power. Now it has spread overseas. A video on social media shows a group of Latino soccer fans saying "Bwa kale!" after their team beat an opponent.</p>
<p><strong>税 (zei) in Japan (Japanese)</strong></p>
<p>The top Buddhist leader at the Kiyomizu Temple in Kyoto wrote the word 税 (zei) in a closely watched yearly event.</p>
<p>The Japanese public chose "zei," which means taxes, to best represent the year 2023. Many expect taxes to increase to pay for the country's military buildup. Under the latest national security plan, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida's government aims to double Japan's yearly defense spending to about $69 billion. That would make the country the world's third largest military spender after the U.S. and China.</p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 9pt;">The nones around the world</strong></p>
<p>In many countries, there has been a big increase in the number of people who select the word "none" when asked about their religion.</p>
<p>The nonbelievers, atheists, or agnostics have become known as the "nones."</p>
<p>The "nones" are believed to make up of 30 percent or more of the adult population in the United States and Canada, as well as several European countries. Japan, Israel and Uruguay are among other nations where large numbers of people are "nones."</p>
<p>And that's the world in "other" words for 2023.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>complain</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to express your unhappiness about a situation or something someone has done</p>
<p><strong>peel</strong> <em>–v.</em> to remove the skin or outer layer from a fruit or similar object</p>
<p><strong>dominance </strong><em>–n.</em> the quality of being the most powerful or the leader of others</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Change and Vary  (2023/12/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/change-and-vary.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the words "change" and "vary."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello Teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Change and Vary" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4c54-08dc07f9f5ba_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Change and Vary</span></div>
<p>I'm Ali, and I live in Mashhad, Iran.</p>
<p>What is the difference between "change" and "vary?"</p>
<p>I'm keen on knowing how American people use "vary" in different forms in daily conversations.</p>
<p>Thank you,</p>
<p>Ali</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for writing to us, Ali!</p>
<p>Here is the first major difference between the word "change" and the word "vary": Only one of them is a noun and a verb.</p>
<p>"Change" is that word. You can "change your opinion" for example. That's change as a verb.</p>
<p>You can also have "<em>a</em> change of opinion." That's change as a noun!</p>
<p>"Vary" is more narrow in meaning. It means to make a partial change in something, or to diversify something.</p>
<p>Sometimes change and vary are <strong>synonyms</strong>.</p>
<p>Let's look at each one more closely.</p>
<p><strong>Change as a verb</strong></p>
<p>While "change" can be either a noun or a verb, we will compare the verbal meanings and uses to "vary."</p>
<p>It can be used in a lot of different situations and can be a synonym for many other verbs like transform, exchange, switch or alter.</p>
<p>"Change" meanings range from making a difference or altering something particular to completely transforming or replacing something.</p>
<p><em>Many schools are changing the college application requirements in response to the ending of</em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-colleges-ask-for-more-writing-after-affirmative-action-ban/7209025.html"><em> Affirmative Action.</em></a></p>
<p><em>Water changes from a liquid to a solid when it freezes at zero degrees Celsius</em>.</p>
<p>"Change" can also mean making a slight modification in something to switching or making a shift from one thing to another.</p>
<p><em>The leaves change colors every autumn. </em></p>
<p><em>Emma changed her shirt because she spilled something on it.</em></p>
<p><em>Derek changed his money from dollars to euros when he went to France. </em></p>
<p>Andrey's <strong>accent</strong> changed after he moved to the big city.</p>
<p><strong>Vary </strong></p>
<p>Now let's look at "vary."</p>
<p>"Vary" is a verb. It can mean to make a partial change or to differentiate between items by size, amount or degree.</p>
<p><em>I like to vary my meals with different types of grains and greens.</em></p>
<p><em>Insects vary in size from large to very small.</em></p>
<p>It can also mean to show or experience a change.</p>
<p><em>The night sky varies depending on the Earth's rotation and orbit around the sun.</em></p>
<p><em>Interest rates vary due to how the economy is.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Ali.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>synonyms </strong><em>–</em> <em>n</em>. a word that is similar in meaning to another word</p>
<p><strong>accent </strong><em>–</em> <em>n</em>. a way of pronouncing words that occurs among the people in a particular region or country</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Year in Social Media  (2023/12/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-year-in-social-media.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>This year, social media services gained a lot of attention for their growth methods and for their influence.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> recently looked back at 2023 to see what developments in social media were most important and what might be ahead.</p>
<p><strong>Twitter becomes X</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An X sign rests atop the company headquarters in downtown San Francisco, on July 28, 2023. Elon Musk's social media company, formerly known as Twitter, has filed a lawsuit against liberal advocacy group Media Matters. (AP Photo/Noah Berger, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-bf20-08dc0663bff1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An "X" sign rests atop the company headquarters in downtown San Francisco, on July 28, 2023. Elon Musk's social media company, formerly known as Twitter, has filed a lawsuit against liberal advocacy group Media Matters. (AP Photo/Noah Berger, File)</span></div>
<p>In October of 2022, businessman Elon Musk <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/twitter-introduces-new-x-logo-to-replace-blue-bird/7194172.html">took over</a> Twitter. He promised to make big changes at the social media service. Musk is known for leading the electric vehicle company Tesla and SpaceX, a space transport company. He bought Twitter for $44 billion dollars.</p>
<p>Musk dismissed about 75 percent of the company's workforce soon after the deal was completed. He said the dismissals were necessary to make Twitter more effective and to increase profits. He also announced plans to have Twitter users pay eight dollars a month to keep their verified accounts. Verified accounts are identified as belonging to people with a lot of followers.</p>
<p>As chief, Musk also lifted some existing restrictions on users, including many well-known people who had been barred by earlier Twitter leadership. Former U.S. President Donald Trump was among the Twitter users whose accounts were <strong>reinstated</strong>.</p>
<p>Musk said those changes were part of a larger effort to protect the free speech of Twitter users. But critics said his plans were likely to increase the amount of harmful content and hate speech on the service.</p>
<p>This year, the AP noted that some LGBTQ groups have raised concerns that X is less safe. Some activist groups said they have left the service.</p>
<p>Many Twitter users chose to leave the service earlier this year because of Musk's changes. Some advertisers stopped doing business with the company. In October, X said it had over 500 million users and is adding users all the time. The company also said it has improved in combating misleading or false information by using Community Notes. X says it uses over 100,000 people to help confirm information.</p>
<p>Musk has said he hopes to change X into an "everything app" like China's WeChat. But it remains unclear if U.S. and Western users like the idea of using one app for nearly all their needs.</p>
<p><strong>Social media competition</strong></p>
<p>Many users criticized the changes Musk was putting in place at X. Other services aimed to provide competition.</p>
<p>Mastodon is a service from a German software developer that lets users share information across several apps. Bluesky is a service that came out of Twitter and has connections to former Twitter chief Jack Dorsey. Bluesky operates by invitation only.</p>
<p>Some users who did not like the changes to Twitter went to those services.</p>
<p>In July, the parent company of Facebook, Meta, launched another <strong>rival</strong> to X called Threads. Millions of people joined after the announcement. In December, Meta chief Mark Zuckerberg announced that the company was testing "interoperability." That is an idea that lets people use their accounts on different services, or platforms. Zuckerberg said the company was performing a "test where posts from Threads accounts will be available on Mastodon and other services that use the Activity Pub protocol."</p>
<p><strong>Is social media good for children's mental health?</strong></p>
<p>Social media's influence on children's mental health gained a lot of attention this year. The U.S. surgeon general warned in May that there is not enough evidence to show that children and teenagers are safe using the services. Dr. Vivek Murthy called for technology companies and parents to take "immediate action to protect their kids now."</p>
<p>Murthy noted how social media is pushing big changes in the way children think of themselves, form friendships and experience the world.</p>
<p>In October, about 33 states brought legal action against Meta for harming young people's health. The legal action said the company regularly collects information on children under 13 years of age.</p>
<p>And in December, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) proposed major changes to laws controlling the way companies can follow and advertise to children. The agency proposed turning off targeted advertisements to children under 13 and limiting <strong>notifications</strong> to them.</p>
<p><strong>And in 2024...</strong></p>
<p>Artificial intelligence powers chatbots that perform writing tasks and create material for users of services like ChatGPT. In the fall, Meta chief Zuckerberg said his company was "building the future of human connection." He said that people will soon communicate with <strong>hologram</strong> versions of their friends, coworkers and others. The company demonstrated AI bots using the images of famous people such as Snoop Dogg and Paris Hilton. Meta believes many social media users will want to interact with <strong>celebrities</strong>.</p>
<p>Enberg, the social media expert, said AI will be used throughout social media platforms. "Social apps will use AI to drive usage, ad performance and <strong>revenues</strong>, <strong>subscription</strong> sign ups," and business activity, she said. Experts say social media services learned from Musk's X that subscriptions are a good way to make money.</p>
<p>Important elections will take place in the United States, India and other places in 2024. Some experts are worried about AI's abilities to create materials that can contain misinformation and then spread on social media.</p>
<p>A.J. Nash is an official with ZeroFox, an internet security company based in the state of Maryland. Nash said materials spread this way will have a "major" influence on elections.</p>
<p>"We're not prepared for this," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Barbara Ortutay reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English with additional information from AP and VOA sources. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rival</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person or group which is trying to be more successful than another or trying to defeat its opponent</p>
<p><strong>revenues</strong><em>–n.</em> money from business, investment or taxes <strong>subscriptions </strong>–n. (pl.) agreements for payment in exchange for a regular service</p>
<p><strong>hologram </strong>–n. a projected image that looks like it has depth, width and length but is only an image</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Vatican Experts Restore Masterpieces  (2023/12/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/vatican-experts-restore-masterpieces.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Alessandra Zarelli works to keep the artwork of the Vatican Museums in good condition. She says, whenever she works on a masterpiece, she must calm her heart so her thinking can center on her work.</p>
<p>Vatican City is a small country surrounded by the Italian capital, Rome. It is the headquarters and seat of government of the Roman Catholic Church. The Vatican Museums contain thousands of artworks hundreds of years old including paintings by Michelangelo.</p>
<p>"The emotion of working on something like a Michelangelo is truly indescribable," said Zarelli. She helped repair one of his wall paintings in Vatican City's Pauline Chapel.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Restorers Alessandra Zarelli and Rossana Giardina work on paintings at the painting and wood materials restoration laboratory inside the Vatican Museums, at the Vatican, December 11, 2023. (REUTERS/Guglielmo Mangiapane)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c5bc0212-d6f6-4539-aaf5-b609902737ed_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Restorers Alessandra Zarelli and Rossana Giardina work on paintings at the "painting and wood materials restoration laboratory" inside the Vatican Museums, at the Vatican, December 11, 2023. (REUTERS/Guglielmo Mangiapane)</span></div>
<p>Michelangelo painted during the Renaissance period of European history during a growth of interest in science, art, and literature.</p>
<p>Zarelli is part of a special team at the Vatican Museums' repair laboratory for paintings and wood pieces.</p>
<p>The team is responsible for looking after thousands of square meters of wall paintings, including the famous ceiling and walls of the Sistine Chapel. They also look after some 5,300 oil paintings and wooden statues.</p>
<p><strong>A century of restoration</strong></p>
<p>The painting and wood lab is one of eight specialized groups in the museums. It permitted several news organizations, including Reuters, the chance to see its inner workings to mark its 100th anniversary.</p>
<p>Care and repair methods change often and today's workers often have to repair mistakes from care workers that came before them. They repair work from recent history to many centuries ago.</p>
<p>Another problem, usually from the distant past, is that restorers were not technicians but artists in their own right. Francesca Persegati is chief restorer at the Vatican Museums. She said that some of those artists thought they could "improve" the original by adding their own work.</p>
<p>"It's important to be <strong>humble</strong> in this job, to respect the work but also to have a scientific background to understand the materials," she said.</p>
<p>Before a painting even reaches the lab, another team carries out tests to see if paint or color has been added since the piece was first made. They also check it for possible other work below the surface.</p>
<p>In another part of the lab, Caterina Manisco was working on an 1895 painting called <em>Madonna and Child Between St. Teresa and St. Francis</em>. Italian Emma Richards was the artist. She painted for the rich and powerful, like Queen Victoria and Prince Albert. Such work was a rarity for women artists of the time.</p>
<p>"Because she was a woman, I somehow feel very close to her," said Manisco, an external restorer at the lab.</p>
<p>To mark the 100th anniversary of the paintings and wood lab, the Vatican Museums are using special technology. It permits visitors to use their phones to connect with information about the artwork they are looking at.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Philip Pullella reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>museum </strong>– <em>n</em>. a building in which interesting and valuable things (such as paintings and sculptures or scientific or historical objects) are collected and shown to the public</p>
<p><strong>restore </strong>– <em>v</em>. to return (something) to an earlier or original condition by repairing it or cleaning it</p>
<p><strong>concentrate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to think about something: to give your attention to the thing you are doing or reading</p>
<p><strong>paralyze </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make (a person or animal) unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
<p><strong>humble </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not proud: not thinking of yourself as better than other people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Data Shows More Women Live in East, More Men in West  (2023/12/29) | 美国数据显示女性多居东部男性多居西部</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-data-shows-more-women-live-in-east-more-men-in-west.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Official population data show more men live in the western United States, while more women live in the East and South.<br/>
官方人口数据显示，更多男性生活在美国西部，而更多女性生活在东部和南部。</p>
<p>The data was collected by the U.S. Census Bureau. The numbers appear in the 2022 American Community Survey, released last week. The report gives state and local leaders the latest population and demographic information each year in order to plan investments for their communities.<br/>
这些数据是由美国人口普查局收集的。这些数字出现在上周发布的2022年美国社区调查中。该报告每年向州和地方领导人提供最新的人口数量和人口信息，以便为其社区规划投资。</p>
<p>The report found that women outnumber men in the most populated counties east of the Mississippi River. Women also outnumber men along the U.S. East Coast and in southern states.<br/>
报告发现，在密西西比河以东人口众多的县，女性人数超过男性。美国东海岸和南部各州的女性人数也超过了男性。</p>
<p>The highest population of men was found west of the Mississippi and on the U.S. West Coast.<br/>
密西西比河以西和美国西海岸的男性人口最多。</p>
<p>The American Community Survey found that across the U.S., there were 96.6 adult men for every 100 adult women.<br/>
美国社区调查发现，在美国，成年男性和成年女性的比例是96.6比100。</p>
<p>The report seeks to identify a sex ratio, meaning the number of male and females living in a particular area. The ratio numbers do not consider sexual preference, gender identity or whether people included in the report were looking for partners.<br/>
该报告试图确定一个性别比例，即生活在特定地区的男性和女性人数。该比例数字没有考虑性偏好、性别认同，也没有考虑报告中的人是否在寻找伴侣。</p>
<p>Adult women outnumbered adult men around the eastern cities of Baltimore, New York, Atlanta and Philadelphia.<br/>
东部城市巴尔的摩、纽约、亚特兰大和费城的成年女性人数超过成年男性。</p>
<p>The biggest imbalances of men to women - with ratios above 103 for those age 18 and over - were recorded in the West. The highest ratios were found in Colorado Springs, Colorado, and Austin, Texas. Men to women ratios were highest in California, including areas around San Francisco, San Jose and Bakersfield.<br/>
男性与女性之间最大的不平衡发生在西部，其18岁及以上男女比例超过103比100。比例最高的是科罗拉多州的科罗拉多斯普林斯和得克萨斯州的奥斯汀。加利福尼亚州的男女比例最高，包括旧金山、圣何塞和贝克斯菲尔德周围的地区。</p>
<p>Population researchers say the ratios are influenced partly by the presence of certain organizations and industries that appeal more to one sex or the other. San Diego, California, for example, has several large military bases populated with a majority of men. And Austin, San Francisco, Seattle and San Jose have a large number of technology companies. Industry groups estimate men make up about three-quarters of the tech workforce.<br/>
人口研究人员表示，这一比例在一定程度上受到某些组织和行业的影响，这些组织和行业对男性或女性更具吸引力。例如，加利福尼亚州的圣地亚哥有几个大型军事基地，那里男性居多。奥斯汀、旧金山、西雅图和圣何塞都有大量的科技公司。行业组织估计，男性约占科技劳动力的四分之三。</p>
<p>At birth, the sex ratio in the U.S. has historically been 105 men for every 100 women. That ratio begins to change around age 30.<br/>
从历史上看，美国出生时的男女性别比例是105比100。这个比例在30岁左右的年龄开始发生变化。</p>
<p>The U.S. death rate is higher for men than it is for women in nearly every age group. Researchers say this is because more men are affected by violence, drinking, smoking, job risks and suicide. But the ratio decreases over time until age 90. Around that age, there are generally two women to every man.<br/>
美国几乎所有年龄段的男性死亡率都高于女性。研究人员表示，这是因为更多的男性受到暴力、饮酒、吸烟、工作风险和自杀的影响。但随着年龄段的推移，这一比例会下降，直到90岁。在90岁左右，通常男女比例为1比2。</p>
<p>Michal Naisteter is a professional matchmaker in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. A matchmaker is someone who tries to bring two people together for a romantic relationship. She told the Associated Press she sees a difference in where single men and women choose to live. In the Philadelphia area, for example, she says single women are more likely than men to live within the city limits. But single men are more willing to live in areas outside the city, called suburbs.<br/>
Michal Naisteter是宾夕法尼亚州费城的一名职业媒人。媒人是指试图把两个人撮合在一起建立恋爱关系的人。她告诉美联社，她发现单身男女选择生活的地方有所不同。例如，在费城地区，她说单身女性比男性更有可能生活在市区。但单身男性更愿意住在郊区。</p>
<p>Naisteter notes that because of such differences, people looking for a partner need to put in solid, thoughtful efforts to make connections. She suggests that people expand their search areas to include more available singles.<br/>
Naisteter指出，由于这些差异，寻找伴侣的人需要付出坚实、深思熟虑的努力来建立联系。她建议人们扩大搜索范围，以纳入更多可以找到的单身人士。</p>
<p>Such searches "should take work," Naisteter noted. "Because nothing is sweeter than something you have to work for."<br/>
Naisteter指出，这样的搜索“应该会奏效”。“因为没有什么比你必须努力追求伴侣更甜蜜了。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and New Year’s Resolutions  (2023/12/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/grammar-and-new-year-s-resolutions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Alice Bryant</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The New Year comes on different dates for different cultures. And most of the Western world celebrates it on January 1st.</p>
<p>One thing many cultures have in common is the idea of New Year's resolutions. A New Year's resolution is a personal goal to change unwanted behavior, make a life improvement, or try something new.</p>
<p>In the United States, popular New Year's resolutions often include losing weight, improving your finances, volunteering for an organization, or spending less time on social media.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: Grammar and New Year's Resolutions " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-24a1-08dc065fe300_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: Grammar and New Year's Resolutions </span></div>
<p>On today's Everyday Grammar, we will show you how to talk about resolutions in English.</p>
<p><strong>Asking a question</strong></p>
<p>First, let's learn how to <em>ask</em> people about their resolutions.</p>
<p>Listen to a short <strong>conversation</strong>:</p>
<p><em>Hey there, Faith. Happy New Year! Great to see you.</em></p>
<p><em>Hi, Greg. Happy New Year to you too! How was yours?</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>It was crazy! We went to New York and watched the ball drop in Times Square. It was really crowded and loud – but still really fun.</em></p>
<p><em>Sweet! <u>Do you have any New Year's resolutions</u>?</em></p>
<p>Faith asked Greg about <strong>resolutions</strong> simply by saying, "Do you have any New Year's resolutions?"</p>
<p>You can also say, "What are your New Year's resolutions?" to ask about more than one or "What is your New Year's resolution?" to ask about one.</p>
<p>Now, let's find out how to answer the question.</p>
<p><strong>Using phrasal verbs</strong></p>
<p>When we make statements about our resolutions, we often use <strong>phrasal verbs</strong>.</p>
<p>We can use the phrasal verb "take up" to say that we will start a new activity as a <strong>hobby</strong>.</p>
<p>Listen to Faith and Greg continue their conversation:</p>
<p><em>Sweet! Do you have any New Year's resolutions?</em></p>
<p><em>Yes, I do. I plan to <u>take up</u> kickboxing starting next week. I'm excited to finally do it rather than just talk about it! How about you?</em></p>
<p>Another phrasal verb for resolutions is "give up," which is to stop doing or using something. We can use this verb to talk about ending bad <strong>habits</strong> or changing behavior for a time.</p>
<p>Let's hear Faith respond using the verb "give up":</p>
<p><em>How about you?</em></p>
<p><em>I am <u>giving up</u> sugar for the month of January. Then, for the rest of the year, I'm avoiding soft drinks.</em></p>
<p><em>Wow!<strong> </strong>I wish I could join you but the kickboxing class starts soon. I'll probably want some sweets after class!</em></p>
<p>Another phrasal verb, "cut out," has the same basic meaning as "give up." For example, Faith could say, "I am cutting out sugar for the month of January."</p>
<p>But in many situations, we do not need phrasal verbs to talk about resolutions, as you will soon see.</p>
<p><strong>Using future forms</strong></p>
<p>Next, let's talk about verb <strong>tenses</strong> and forms. Greg talked about his new kickboxing activity using the verb "plan" followed by the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/getting-to-know-gerunds-and-infinitives/3111996.html" target="_blank">infinitive</a> verb form and Faith talked about giving up sugar using the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/everyday-grammar-present-progressive/3255195.html" target="_blank">present continuous</a> verb tense, also called "BE + ing."</p>
<p>We can also use the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/everyday-grammar-fun-with-future-tenses/2935173.html" target="_blank">simple future</a> tenses: one with "will" and the other with "going to." These tenses are especially useful when the New Year has not come yet.</p>
<p>Imagine it's the last week of the year and a few people are talking to each other about resolutions: Here are some things you might hear:</p>
<p><em>In 2024, I'<u>m going to visit</u> my friends every month.</em></p>
<p><em>By the end of March, I <u>will stop</u> eating sweets.</em></p>
<p><em>In the new year, I'<u>m going to </u>practice kickboxing every week.</em></p>
<p>When we use simple future tenses to talk about resolutions, we're expressing that we are making a promise to or plan for ourselves. The noun "resolution" comes from the verb "resolve," which means to make a serious decision to do something.</p>
<p><strong>Infinitives and gerunds</strong></p>
<p>You may have noticed that the statements so far today did not actually use the word "resolution." That is because the subject was already known by the listeners. But it is still perfectly normal to start your statements with, "My New Year's resolution is..." or "My New Year's resolutions are..." An <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/everyday-grammar-gerunds-infinitives/2722827.html" target="_blank">infinitive verb or a gerund</a> must come after these phrases. Here is an example:</p>
<p><em>My New Year's resolution is <u>to call</u> my sister on video every week.</em></p>
<p>The infinitive verb here is "to call."</p>
<p>You can also use a gerund, like this:</p>
<p><em>My New Year's resolution is <u>calling</u> my sister on video every week.</em></p>
<p>Well, that's all for today's program. Tell us about your New Year's resolutions in the comments below. Or email us at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>Happy New Year!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Alice Bryant wrote this lesson for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conversation </strong>– n. an informal talk involving two people or a small group of people</p>
<p><strong>resolution</strong></p>
<p><strong>phrasal verb</strong> – n. a group of words that functions as a verb and is made up of a verb and a preposition or an adverb, or both</p>
<p><strong>habit</strong> – n. something that a person does often in a regular and repeated way</p>
<p><strong>tense </strong>– n. a form of a verb that is used to show when an action happened</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Top Technology Stories of 2023  (2023/12/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/top-technology-stories-of-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The past year <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/a-big-year-for-artificial-intelligence/7403954.html">marked the rise</a> of ChatGPT and other artificial intelligence (AI) tools. But here is a look back at some of the other noteworthy technology stories we covered in 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Google, Apple face major legal challenges</strong></p>
<p>Both Apple and Google faced lawsuits accusing them of carrying out unfair business methods linked to their <strong>app</strong> stores. The cases might cost the companies billions of dollars and change the way similar app stores do business.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The Google logo displayed at the company's European headquarters in Brussels, Belgium, March 23, 2010." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C9423EC6-B00F-4264-A935-198256C8807E_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The Google logo displayed at the company's European headquarters in Brussels, Belgium, March 23, 2010.</span></div>
<p>A decision in the Google case was reached earlier this month when an American jury <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/jury-rules-google-app-store-operates-as-monopoly/7396589.html">found</a> Google's app store operates as an illegal <strong>monopoly</strong>. The case was brought by video game company Epic Games.</p>
<p>One of the main questions in the case was whether Google had the right to require app developers to use Google's app store's payment systems. The jury ruled Google's monopoly covered both its app selling system and payment processing within the app. Google condemned the decision and appealed the ruling.</p>
<p>Epic brought a similar lawsuit against iPhone maker Apple that was decided in April. In that case, a judge in California mostly sided with Apple. But the judge did order Apple to permit developers to add their own links to process payments within iPhone apps.</p>
<p><strong>EV battery technology and production</strong></p>
<p>The worldwide demand for electric vehicle (EV) <strong>batteries</strong> continues to grow. But supplies of the materials used to make them are limited. Currently, China controls most mining and processing of a group of 17 metals known as rare earths.</p>
<p>One of the main materials used to produce the batteries is lithium, a light metal substance. Other necessary materials include the metallic elements cobalt, manganese and nickel. Even though some of the minerals are mined in nations outside China, Chinese companies still hold ownership over the operations.</p>
<p>In an effort to avoid a dependence on Chinese controlled materials, the United States and other countries are <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/demand-for-electric-car-batteries-drives-nations-to-seek-own-materials/6526662.html">seeking to mine and process more materials at home</a>.</p>
<p>In February, U.S. President Joe Biden announced federal assistance programs to help companies mine and process lithium and other rare metals. Similar efforts were announced in other countries, including Britain and Germany.</p>
<p>In addition, major automakers said they were <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/automakers-seek-to-produce-ev-vehicles-with-fewer-rare-earths/7362904.html">seeking new EV engine designs</a> that are less dependent on rare earth minerals. EV market leader Tesla said it plans to remove rare earths from its next-generation EVs. Other automakers said they are in the process of researching or developing EV motors that use little or no rare earth minerals. These include General Motors, Jaguar Land Rover, and BMW.</p>
<p><strong>Robotic developments</strong></p>
<p>We covered several developments involving robotic systems.</p>
<p>A team of American researchers <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/soccer-playing-robot-set-to-compete-in-robo-cup-/7064373.html">announced</a> it had built a human-like robot that can play soccer at a high level. The robot, named ARTEMIS, is one of only a few humanoid robots that can run. It also can walk and jump on different kinds of surfaces without losing its balance. The robot also can kick a ball and remain standing even when kicked or hit, the team said.</p>
<p>In Germany, many companies – large and small – <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/german-companies-turn-to-robots-to-fill-jobs-for-retiring-workers/7332773.html">turned to robots</a> to fill jobs as the country faced a severe labor shortage. The International Federation of Robotics estimated that about 26,000 robotic machines were put into use in Germany last year. Experts say increasing robotic operations are a sign that robots have become easier to use, with no special skills required.</p>
<p>However, the risks of using machines in the workplace <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/industrial-robot-crushes-worker-in-south-korea/7348375.html">were demonstrated</a> in South Korea, where an industrial robot crushed a worker to death at a vegetable processing center. Police said the victim was an employee of a company that deploys industrial robots to businesses.</p>
<p>NASA even <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-tests-snake-like-robot-to-search-for-life-in-the-solar-system/7099496.html">tested</a> a snake-like explorer designed to search for signs of life in hard-to-reach places. The American space agency said the robot is equipped to move in ways that traditional explorer vehicles, called rovers, cannot. In the future, NASA plans to send the robot to space to search for signs of life in an underground ocean on Saturn's moon Enceladus.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device</p>
<p><strong>monopoly </strong><em>– n. </em>complete control of the entire supply of goods or of a service in a certain area or market</p>
<p><strong>battery </strong>–n. a device that chemically stores electricity so it can be used as direct current in electrical circuits such as computers and motors</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Looking at the Endangered Species Act after 50 Years  (2023/12/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/looking-at-the-endangered-species-act-after-50-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Endangered <strong>Species</strong> Act had widespread support when President Richard Nixon signed it into law late in 1973. In the 50 years since, the effects of the legislation have been both successful and complex.</p>
<p>Most Americans celebrated the law that helped save animals such as the bald eagle and bison. But when the law stood in the way of economic progress, many questioned whether it was too strong.</p>
<p>The act took effect around the same time as other laws designed to protect natural resources such as water, air and the wilderness. In the 1960s and 1970s, no other country in the world had put such wide protections into place.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A California condor named Hope takes to flight at the Condor habitat at the Los Angeles Zoo, Tuesday, May 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7c914db5-7b6b-4a57-8442-72f37d8e1647_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A California condor named Hope takes to flight at the Condor habitat at the Los Angeles Zoo, Tuesday, May 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel, File)</span></div>
<p>Concerns came later when the law prevented projects such as a hydroelectric dam in Tennessee from moving forward. The concern? A small river fish no one had ever heard of.</p>
<p>That fish is called the snail darter. Plans to protect the fish held up progress on the Tellico Dam for more than two years. Biologists eventually decided to catch the small fish and move it to other rivers.</p>
<p>The fish population grew over time and the snail darters were removed from the endangered species list in 1984. About one year ago, the fish had fully recovered.</p>
<p>Jim Williams was the first so-called "fish guy" in the Office of Endangered Species. When his group listed the fish, he recalled, the decision made a lot of people upset.</p>
<p>He said his director told him not to list the fish. But Williams said he planned to follow the law and make decisions based on facts, not on possible public reaction.</p>
<p>The snail darter decision showed the U.S. government that the law was going to be difficult to <strong>manage</strong>. Some said the government should not try to save all species. Others said all animals and plants should be safe from extinction. The debate continues today.</p>
<p>Many more disputes over the protection of species came up over the next 45 years. In each case, employees at the Endangered Species Office made decisions that upset some people but ultimately saved the animals.</p>
<p><strong>Gray wolves</strong></p>
<p>In northern Minnesota in the 1980s, the gray wolf population had recovered from only around a few hundred to about 1,000. The Endangered Species Act had helped save the gray wolf.</p>
<p>With the population growing, people wanted permission to hunt the animals. The Fish and Wildlife Service sought to cooperate with the state of Minnesota and open the gray wolf to hunting.</p>
<p>The move required a <strong>regulation</strong> showing that a hunting season would help the wolves and was the only way to control their population.</p>
<p>Ron Nowak was a wolf expert in the Endangered Species Office at the time. The Fish and Wildlife Service told Nowak to write the regulation. "And I said, ‘It would be illegal,'" Nowak said.</p>
<p>The Fish and Wildlife Service found someone else to write the regulation. <strong>Conservation</strong> groups took legal action and called Nowak as a witness. He traveled to Minnesota to tell the government that wolves should not be open to hunting.</p>
<p><strong>California condor</strong></p>
<p>LaVerne Smith started working in the Endangered Species Office in 1978. Soon after came a major decision involving the California condor, the largest bird native to North America. By 1982, only 23 California condors were left. Biologists were looking at whether the species could be saved.</p>
<p>The office made a plan to move the remaining birds into a safe and closed area and <strong>breed</strong> them.</p>
<p>The plan worked. Today, there are more than 400 California condors. They can even be seen flying over the Grand Canyon.</p>
<p>Smith said, "the day I saw one sail over the Grand Canyon, I was like, ‘Oh my God! That was all worth it.'"</p>
<p>Later in her career, Smith led the effort to list the polar bear as endangered. It marked the first time an animal was listed as endangered because of climate change.</p>
<p><strong>Freshwater mussels</strong></p>
<p>Marc Imlay began working at the Endangered Species Office in 1971, two years before the current Endangered Species Act was passed.</p>
<p>Imlay is an expert on mollusks – small animals including snails, mussels and slugs. He had concerns that hydroelectric dams were putting freshwater mussels in danger in states such as Missouri and Tennessee.</p>
<p>At one point, Imlay decided to make a phone call to a conservation group in Missouri to tell them that a planned dam would put the mussels in danger.</p>
<p>The call worked. He got locals to pay attention to the organism and the dam was stopped. In time, his work prevented a number of dams from being built.</p>
<p>While some could argue that Imlay slowed economic progress, he said in other cases he found a way to help development move forward.</p>
<p>"Time and time again," he said, "you can work with a developer" to save high-quality land.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species</strong>—<em>n</em>. a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>manage </strong>–<em>v</em>. to oversee or run</p>
<p><strong>regulation </strong>–<em>n</em>. a law or rule</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong>–<em>adj</em>. dealing with the protection of nature</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong>–<em>v</em>. to put two animals together with the goal of mating them and creating young</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Afghan Girls Banned from Education after Sixth Grade  (2023/12/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/afghan-girls-banned-from-education-after-sixth-grade.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Bahara Rustam is 13 years old. She took her last class at Bibi Razia School in Kabul, Afghanistan, on December 11 knowing it was the end of her education. Under Afghan law, she is unlikely to ever step foot in a classroom again.</p>
<p>In September 2021, the country's ruling Taliban announced that females would be barred from education after sixth grade, or about age 13. The government said it was acting in line with Islamic religious law.</p>
<p>The United States and NATO troops had withdrawn from Afghanistan a month earlier, after 20 years of war.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Afghan girls attend a religious school, which remained open since the last year's Taliban takeover, in Kabul, Afghanistan, on Aug. 11, 2022. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6067b961-83d7-4e99-8954-03c6d3d04739_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Afghan girls attend a religious school, which remained open since the last year's Taliban takeover, in Kabul, Afghanistan, on Aug. 11, 2022. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi, File)</span></div>
<p>In December 2022, the restrictive measure was expanded to include university education.</p>
<p>The international community has continued to condemn the Taliban for the actions. Countries have warned the Taliban that it its actions will bar it from gaining international recognition as a lawful government.</p>
<p>Last week, United Nations special diplomat for Afghanistan Roza Otunbayeva appeared before the UN Security Council. She said she worried that a generation of Afghan girls is falling behind with each day that passes.</p>
<p>An Afghan Education Ministry said last week that girls of all ages are permitted to study in religious schools called madrassas. They have traditionally been boys-only.</p>
<p>The UN is trying to confirm the ministry's statement. But Otunbayeva said it was unclear if that education system included wider study of non-religious subjects.</p>
<p>For now, Bahara is holding onto her education and looks over school books at home. "<strong>Graduating</strong> (from sixth grade) means we are going to seventh grade," she said. "But all of our classmates cried and we were very <strong>disappointed</strong>," she added.</p>
<p>There was no graduation ceremony for the girls at Bibi Razia School.</p>
<p>In another part of Kabul, 13-year old Setayesh Sahibzada wonders what the future holds for her. She is sad she cannot go to school anymore to follow her dreams.</p>
<p>"I can't stand on my own two feet," she said. "I wanted to be a teacher. But now I can't study, I can't go to school."</p>
<p>Researcher Muhammad Saleem Paigir warned that banning women and girls from education would be disastrous for Afghanistan. "We understand that<strong> illiterate</strong> people can never be free and<strong> prosperous</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>The Taliban have banned women from many public spaces and most jobs, all but keeping women inside their homes.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Mohammad Habib Rahmani</em><em> reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>graduate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to earn a degree or diploma from a school, college, or university</p>
<p><strong>disappointed </strong>– <em>adj</em>. feeling sad, unhappy, or displeased because something was not as good as expected or because something you hoped for or expected did not happen</p>
<p><strong>illiterate </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not knowing how to read or write</p>
<p><strong>prosperous </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having success usually by making a lot of money</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Las Vegas Could Set Record for Marriages on New Year’s Eve  (2023/12/28) | 拉斯维加斯新年前夕结婚人数创纪录</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/las-vegas-could-set-record-for-marriages-on-new-year-s-eve.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>For better or for worse, the number of couples getting married in the city of Las Vegas, Nevada, on New Year's Eve could set a record.<br/>
不管是好是坏，内华达州拉斯维加斯市新年前夕结婚的夫妇数量都可能创下纪录。</p>
<p>That is because the date 12/31/23 is known in the Las Vegas wedding industry as a "specialty date." The Las Vegas Review-Journal reported that the repeating number pattern of 1-2-3 1-2-3 is very popular.<br/>
这是因为2023年12月31日（12/31/23）这天在拉斯维加斯婚礼行业被称为“特色日期”。《拉斯维加斯评论杂志》报道称，1-2-3 1-2-3的重复数型非常受欢迎。</p>
<p>What makes it even more special is that the date falls on a holiday famous for big celebrations.<br/>
更特别的是，这一天恰逢一个以大型庆祝活动闻名的节日。</p>
<p>"It's a double whammy," said Melody Willis-Williams, president of Vegas Weddings, which owns several wedding venues. "Anytime you get these specialty dates, they're always hugely popular. But tie that in with New Year's Eve and it's a showstopper."<br/>
“这是双重冲击，”拉斯维加斯婚礼公司总裁梅洛迪·威利斯-威廉姆斯说，该公司拥有多个婚礼场地。“每当遇到这些特色日期时，它们总是非常受欢迎。但把它与新年前夕联系起来，它就会引人注目。”</p>
<p>Las Vegas is famous for fast marriage ceremonies, and many marriages take place there every year.<br/>
拉斯维加斯以快速举行婚礼而闻名，每年都有许多婚礼在那里举行。</p>
<p>The number to beat on New Year's Eve is 4,492. That is the single-day record for marriages in Las Vegas set on July 7, 2007. The second-most popular specialty wedding date on record with the county's marriage bureau is November 11, 2011, when 3,125 couples married.<br/>
新年前夕要打败的数字是4492。这是拉斯维加斯2007年7月7日创下的单日结婚记录。2011年11月11日是该县婚姻局有记录以来第二受欢迎的特色婚礼日期，当时有3125对新人结婚。</p>
<p>Since 2018, somewhere between 450 and 550 marriage ceremonies take place each year in Las Vegas on New Year's Eve, the Review-Journal reported.<br/>
据《拉斯维加斯评论杂志》报道，自2018年以来，拉斯维加斯每年新年前夕都会举行450至550场婚礼。</p>
<p>This year, the company Vegas Weddings is fully booked for midnight at all its venues, including a church in downtown Las Vegas.<br/>
今年，拉斯维加斯婚礼公司的所有场地，包括拉斯维加斯市中心一座教堂在内午夜时段都被预订一空。</p>
<p>Willis-Williams said her company expects to marry more than 120 couples on New Year's Eve. Five of those couples will marry as the clock is counting down to midnight.<br/>
威利斯-威廉姆斯说，她的公司预计在新年前夕将有120多对新人结婚。其中五对将在新年倒计时的时候结婚。</p>
<p>Clark County Clerk Lynn Marie Goya said couples married on a specialty date in Las Vegas have described them as "magic dates" that are easy to remember.<br/>
克拉克县办事员林恩·玛丽·戈雅说，在拉斯维加斯特色日期结婚的夫妇将它们称为非常容易记住的神奇日期。</p>
<p>"I think the celebration that has a group dynamic is really appealing," Goya said. "When everyone is in line and they're all getting married and excited about being in love, it just enhances their own experience."<br/>
戈雅说：“我认为具有团体活力的庆祝活动真的很有吸引力。当每个人排着队，他们都将结婚，并对陷入爱河感到兴奋时，这只会增强他们自己的体验。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>California Permits Turning Wastewater to Drinking Water  (2023/12/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/california-permits-turning-wastewater-to-drinking-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>California officials recently approved new rules to let water agencies <strong>recycle</strong> wastewater and put it right back into the pipes that carry drinking water to homes, schools, and businesses.</p>
<p>It is a big step for California. The state has struggled for many years to secure drinking water for more than 39 million people. It shows a change in public opinion on a subject that as recently as twenty years ago was met with criticism and ended similar projects.</p>
<p>Since then, California has been through several extreme <strong>droughts</strong>. That includes the most recent one that scientists say was the driest three-year period on record. And it left the state's water supply at dangerously low levels.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Lakeisha Bryant, public information representative at the Santa Clara Valley Water District, holds flasks of water before and after it is purified at the Silicon Valley Advance Purification Center on December 13, 2023, in San Jose, California. (AP Photo/Terry Chea)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cdb74d74-c5e7-4549-9ca4-00b7a3588a0f_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Lakeisha Bryant, public information representative at the Santa Clara Valley Water District, holds flasks of water before and after it is purified at the Silicon Valley Advance Purification Center on December 13, 2023, in San Jose, California. (AP Photo/Terry Chea)</span></div>
<p>"Water is so <strong>precious</strong> in California. It is important that we use it more than once," said Jennifer West. She is director of WateReuse California, a group that supports recycled water.</p>
<p>California has been using recycled wastewater for many years. A team has used it to make ice surfaces for the game of hockey. It has been used to make snow for the sport of skiing. And farmers use it to water their crops.</p>
<p>But it has not been used directly for drinking water. Orange County, a suburban area of Los Angeles, operates a water cleaning system that recycles wastewater and then uses it to refill underground <strong>aquifers</strong>. That water then mixes with the groundwater for months before being pumped up and used for drinking water again.</p>
<p>California's new rules would let – but not require – water agencies to take wastewater, treat it, and then put it right back into the drinking water system. California would be just the second U.S. state to permit this, following Colorado.</p>
<p>It has taken officials more than 10 years to develop these rules, a process that included several studies by independent groups of scientists. A state law required the California Water Resources Control Board to approve these rules by December 31. It was met with just a few days left.</p>
<p>The vote was met with approval by some of the state's biggest water agencies. All of which have plans to build huge water recycling plants in the coming years.</p>
<p>A project in San Diego is aiming to produce nearly half of the city's water through recycling water by 2035. And the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California aims to produce up to nearly 570 million liters a day for its 19 million people. Adel Hagekhalil is with Metropolitan Water. He said the new rules will permit new projects that have not yet been considered.</p>
<p>Water agencies will need public support to complete these projects. That means proving to people that recycled water is not only safe to drink but also not dirty.</p>
<p>California's new rules require the wastewater be treated for all bacteria and viruses, even if they are not present in the wastewater. That is different from regular water treatment rules, which only require treatment for known diseases, said Darrin Polhemus. He is a director of the drinking water group for the California Water Resources Control Board.</p>
<p>In fact, the treatment is so intense it removes all of the minerals that make fresh drinking water taste good. That means the minerals need to be added back at the end of the process.</p>
<p>"It's at the same drinking water quality, and probably better in many <strong>instances</strong>," Polhemus said.</p>
<p>Polhemus added that it takes time and money to build these treatment centers. So, they will only be available for bigger cities at first.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recycle </strong>– <em>v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
<p><strong>drought </strong>– <em>n</em>. a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p><strong>precious </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very valuable or important: too valuable or important to be wasted or used carelessly</p>
<p><strong>aquifer </strong>– <em>n</em>. a layer of rock or sand that can absorb and hold water</p>
<p><strong>instances </strong><em>– n.</em> an example of a particular type of action or situation: an occasion of something happening</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Years after Pandemic, Students Still Far Behind  (2023/12/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/three-years-after-pandemic-students-still-far-behind.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>In the third full school year since the COVID-19 pandemic began, students continued to feel the effects of school closures. Some leading experts and education officials worry that the learning loss caused by the pandemic may be long-term.</p>
<p>Making matters worse, many students are missing school. <strong>Chronic</strong> <strong>absenteeism</strong> is becoming more common at school <strong>districts</strong> around the country. Some students went missing from the attendance rolls during the pandemic and have never been accounted for.</p>
<p>And in a year of growing artificial intelligence technology, AI has also entered the classroom. Some schools have banned the use of chatbots like ChatGPT. Other teachers are using the new technology to help students, hoping they use the technology in <strong>appropriate</strong> ways.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Jenes Ochoa Rojas goes over the lines of a three-scene play written by ChatGPT in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c5aa-08db135b1214_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Jenes Ochoa Rojas goes over the lines of a three-scene play written by ChatGPT in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.<i>&amp;#</i>160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)</span></div>
<p>Here is a look at the big issues that shaped education in 2023 and will shape education in the year to come.</p>
<p><strong>Continued learning loss </strong></p>
<p>In June, the U.S. Department of Education released the scores from a national math and reading test that is given to 13-year-olds. About 8,700 students took the test in both math and reading in late 2022.</p>
<p>The results showed a drop of nine points in math and four points in reading compared to 2020, the last year the test was administered. The department's information shows that those are the largest point decreases between tests recorded since 1973.</p>
<p>The test asks students to read short <strong>passages</strong> and identify the main idea or some facts. In math, students had to answer simple multiplication and geometry questions.</p>
<p>The latest test scores show that American 13-year-old students are back to their lowest level in math since 1990 and lowest reading level since 2004.</p>
<p>Math and Reading scores were no better outside the U.S. Students around the world suffered historic setbacks in reading and math. That information comes from results of the latest Program for International Student Assessment (PISA).</p>
<p>The PISA is an international comparative study of the scores of 15-year-old students on tests in reading, math and science. It is administered by OECD. Nearly 700,000 students worldwide took part in the study.</p>
<p>PISA is given every three years. The latest results showed an "<strong>unprecedented</strong> drop in performance" since 2018. The 2022 results were released on December 5. It is the first extensive study with data on how the pandemic has affected student performance around the world.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic was a major reason for the worldwide score drops. But science and reading scores were dropping even before the pandemic. This suggests there are other reasons for the decrease.</p>
<p>Factors such as the level of investment in education, the social value and pay levels of teachers, and educational beliefs of students have all influenced educational results, OECD found.</p>
<p><strong>Absent, missing students</strong></p>
<p>Students are not going to make gains in learning if they miss school. Education officials and activists are concerned about an increase in the number of students who are absent for many days during the school year.</p>
<p>Education policy experts call the problem "chronic absenteeism." Chronic absenteeism is defined as missing more than 10 percent out of the days in a school year.</p>
<p>There are many reasons why students miss a lot of school. Certain physical problems and mental health problems, which have increased since the pandemic, are possible causes.</p>
<p>Certain community conditions also can affect attendance, says Joshua Childs, a professor of education policy at the University of Texas at Austin. These include whether a student has safe transportation to and from school and whether the school itself is a safe environment. Childs added that if families do not feel connected with the school community or do not value education that can add to absenteeism.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of American students have also dropped out of public schools since the start of the COVID-19 pandemic. They have essentially gone missing from schools.</p>
<p>A recent examination found an estimated 240,000 students in 21 states whose absences from school could not be explained. These students did not move out of state. They also did not sign up for private school or home-school.</p>
<p>The issue of missing students received a lot of attention in 2020 after the pandemic closed schools around the country. In the years since, however, the issue has largely become a budgeting problem.</p>
<p>There is no longer urgency to find the students who disappeared from school. Early in the pandemic, school workers would go to the students' homes to try and help them return to the classroom. Most of those efforts have ended.</p>
<p><strong>Changing technology</strong></p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic showed how useful digital technology could be for schools. But it also showed the limitations of technology in the educational setting. Millions of students were able to attend classes online and avoid spreading the virus. But many students failed to learn by such methods.</p>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization ( or UNESCO) argues against unsupervised wide use of digital tools and AI in education. A recent UNESCO report says there is little evidence that wide technology use improves learning.</p>
<p>The organization says digital educational tools can never replace the human connection of teacher and student. There is a very large divide, or gap, between rich and poor countries when it comes to digital resources</p>
<p>"Even if connectivity was <strong>universal</strong>, it would still be necessary to demonstrate ...that digital technology offers real added value in terms of effective learning," the UNESCO report says.</p>
<p>Many educators fear students will use the AI tool ChatGPT to write their reports or <strong>cheat</strong> on homework. New York City school officials started blocking the writing tool on school devices and networks in January. But other teachers are including it in the classroom.</p>
<p>Donnie Piercey is a teacher in Lexington, Kentucky. He told his fifth-grade students to try and outsmart the tool that was creating writing <strong>assignments</strong>. Piercey says his job is to prepare students for a world where knowledge of AI will be required.</p>
<p>He describes ChatGPT as just the latest technology in his 17 years of teaching that raised concerns about the possibility of cheating. Other tools include Google, Wikipedia and YouTube.</p>
<p>"As educators, we haven't <strong>figured</strong> out the best way to use artificial intelligence yet," he added. "But it's coming, whether we want it to or not."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>chronic </strong><em>— adj. </em>continuing or occurring again and again for a long time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>absent</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— adj. </em>not present at a usual or expected place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>district</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— n. </em>an area established by a government for official government business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>appropriate </strong><em>— adj. </em>right or suited for some purpose or situation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>passage </strong><em>— adj. </em>a usually short section of a book, poem, speech, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>— adj. </em>not done or experienced before</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em> a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>universal </strong><em>— adj. </em>done or experienced by everyone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cheat </strong><em>— v. </em>to break a rule or law usually to gain an advantage at something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>assignment </strong><em>— n. </em>a job or duty that is given to someone : a task someone is required to do</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>figure </strong><em>— v. </em>to understand or find by thinking</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia's Involvement in Sports Likely to Grow in 2024  (2023/12/27) | 沙特金元体育2024年可能继续大杀四方</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/saudi-arabia-s-involvement-in-sports-likely-to-grow-in-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>At the beginning of 2023, Saudi Arabia's growing influence on professional golf, and sports in general, was a concern for players and their fans.<br/>
2023年初，沙特阿拉伯对职业高尔夫和整个体育运动的影响力越来越大，这引起了球员及其球迷的忧虑。</p>
<p>Twelve months later, discussions are very different. Worries about the supposed threat of "sportswashing" - using sports to improve a country's reputation – have declined. Concerns about moral issues - the line between "right" and "wrong" - have also gone down. Attention now is fixed on just how rich the Saudis might make the athletes.<br/>
12个月后，议论情况大不相同。人们对所谓的“体育洗白”（利用体育运动来提高国家声誉）威胁的担忧有所减少。对道德问题，即“对”和“错”之间界限的担忧也有所下降。现在，人们的注意力集中在沙特人可能会让运动员变得多么富有上。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What has changed?<br/>
发生了什么变化？</span></p>
<p>Two major events caused the change. On June 6, the PGA Tour announced it was looking to go into business with the Saudi group that was paying for the kingdom's LIV Golf, which the tour had labeled as a threat.<br/>
两件大事导致了这一变化。6月6日，美国职业高尔夫球巡回赛宣布，它正寻求与赞助LIV Golf的沙特组织开展业务，该巡回赛曾称其为威胁。</p>
<p>Then, six months later, Jon Rahm, the world's third-ranked professional golfer and an early resister of LIV, decided to join LIV for a deal reported to be worth about $500 million.<br/>
六个月后，世界排名第三的职业高尔夫球手、LIV的早期抵制者琼·拉姆决定加入LIV，据报道这笔交易价值约5亿美元。</p>
<p>Other important events included the continuing talks between the Saudis and leaders of professional tennis organizations. In addition, the push into soccer will bring the world's biggest sporting event, the World Cup, to Saudi Arabia in 2034.<br/>
其他重要活动包括沙特人与职业网球组织领导人之间的持续会谈。此外，进军足球将在2034年为沙特阿拉伯带来世界上最大的体育赛事世界杯。</p>
<p>
Dan Durbin is director of the Institute of Sports, Media and Society at the University of Southern California (USC). Durbin said of the Saudi plans: "You're investing in sports, which is one of the few growth industries in the world....It is, as far as we can see, an almost endless growth industry."<br/>
丹·德宾是南加州大学体育、媒体和社会研究所所长。德宾在谈到沙特的计划时说：“投资体育是世界上为数不多的增长型行业之一……就我们所见，这是一个几乎增长无止境的产业。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Saudi's investments<br/>
沙特的投资</span></p>
<p>In early 2022, the discussion about golf centered on Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund, or PIF, in LIV Golf. At the time, six-time major winner Phil Mickelson made a critical comment about Saudi Arabia related to the murder of the Washington Post writer Jamal Khashoggi.<br/>
2022年初，关于高尔夫的讨论集中在沙特阿拉伯公共投资基金对LIV golf的投资上。当时，六届大满贯得主菲尔·米克尔森就沙特卷入《华盛顿邮报》作家贾迈勒·卡舒吉的谋杀案发表了批评性评论。</p>
<p>Mickelson's comment set the dividing line in what was viewed as a moral question. And the discussion ignored how important Saudi Arabia is in the world economy. The Saudis gain much of their importance by supplying around 15 percent of the world's petroleum.<br/>
米克尔森的评论划下了一个道德问题的分界线。这些讨论忽略了沙特阿拉伯在世界经济中的重要性。沙特通过供应全球约15%的石油而获得了很大的重要性。</p>
<p>Besides golf, the fund offered one of soccer's biggest stars, Cristiano Ronaldo, $200 million to join a Saudi team. And it also owns the Premier League's Newcastle soccer club.<br/>
除了高尔夫，该基金还出资2亿美元邀请足球巨星克里斯蒂亚诺·罗纳尔多加盟了沙特球队。它还拥有英超联赛的纽卡斯尔足球俱乐部。</p>
<p>As the calendar turns to 2024, there is no sign of Saudi involvement in sports slowing. The Saudis are hosting a Formula One auto race. They are also looking to invest some $5 billion into cricket's Indian Premier League with an eye on making it bigger in other countries.<br/>
随着日历转到2024年，沙特对体育运动的参与没有放缓的迹象。沙特正在举办一场一级方程式赛车比赛。他们还希望向印度板球超级联赛投资约50亿美元，为的是扩大该项运动在其它国家的规模。</p>
<p>The ATP, which runs men's professional tennis, has a five-year deal to hold one of its biggest events in the Saudi port city of Jeddah. Talks between the Saudis and the women's tour are reportedly ongoing.<br/>
经营男子职业网球的职业网球联合会签订了一份为期五年的协议，它将在沙特港口城市吉达举办其最大的赛事之一。据报道，沙特和女子职业网球巡回赛之间的谈判正在进行中。</p>
<p>In a sign of how public discussions have changed, Billie Jean King, who fought for equal pay for women in sports, has said bringing women's tennis to the kingdom might not be all bad despite its poor record on women's rights.<br/>
比莉·让·金曾为女性在体育运动中的同工同酬而奋斗，她表示，尽管沙特在女权方面的记录不佳，但将女子网球带到沙特可能并不完全是坏事，这表明公众讨论已经发生了变化。</p>
<p>"I don't think you really change unless you engage," she said earlier this year.<br/>
她今年早些时候说：“我不认为你真的会改变，除非你参与进来。”</p>
<p>Durbin says sports is a way for the kingdom to be seen as more than an oil-producer with a bad human-rights record.<br/>
德宾说，体育运动是沙特被视为不仅仅是一个人权记录不佳的石油生产国的途径。</p>
<p>"For decades, sports has been the center of soft diplomacy," he said. "You try to create a positive response and feeling about your ethics because you're holding to the rules of sports."<br/>
他说：“几十年来，体育一直是软外交的中心。各国试图对自己的道德标准做出积极的回应和感受，因为你坚持体育规则。”</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我叫约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Millions Infected with Dengue as Temperature Rises  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/millions-infected-with-dengue-as-temperature-rises.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The disease dengue is spreading across the Western Hemisphere in numbers not seen since record-keeping began in 1980. Experts are warning that rising temperatures and growing cities are increasing the rate of infection.</p>
<p>More than 4 million cases have been reported throughout the Americas and the Caribbean so far this year, breaking a record set in 2019. Officials from the Bahamas to Brazil are warning of crowded health centers and new infections daily. Reports say there have been more than 2,000 deaths across the wide area.</p>
<p>Thais dos Santos is with the Pan American Health Organization, the area office of the World Health Organization (WHO) in the Americas. She said diseases like dengue, "provide us a really good <strong>sentinel</strong> of what is happening with climate change."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Children with dengue wait to be seen by doctors at the Mario Ortiz Children's Hospital in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, Feb. 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Ipa Ibanez,File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c907-08dbffd9834e_cx7_cy0_cw86_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Children with dengue wait to be seen by doctors at the Mario Ortiz Children's Hospital in Santa Cruz, Bolivia, Feb. 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Ipa Ibanez,File)</span></div>
<p>A lack of good <strong>sanitation</strong> and strong health systems have added to the rise in cases. But experts say <strong>droughts</strong> and floods linked to climate change are causing greater spread of the virus. That is because stored water and heavy rains appeal to mosquitoes.</p>
<p>Dr. Gabriela Paz-Bailey is chief of the dengue branch for the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Puerto Rico. She noted that higher temperatures also are expanding the mosquito's habitat and helping the virus develop faster inside the mosquito. That leads to higher viral loads and a higher chance of transmission.</p>
<p>This year's Northern Hemisphere summer was the hottest ever, with August about 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer than pre-industrial period averages. And Copernicus, the European climate service, reported that 2023 is the second hottest year on record.</p>
<p>Worldwide, more than 4.5 million cases of dengue had been reported as of early November. There have been more than 4,000 deaths reported in 80 countries.</p>
<p>Countries like Bangladesh are seeing a record number of cases and deaths. The government in the South Asian country has reported more than 313,700 cases and more than 1,600 deaths. Most of the deaths happened within three days of hospitalization.</p>
<p>The mosquito that carries dengue also has been identified in 22 European countries, with local spread of the disease seen in France, Italy and Spain. In August, the central African country of Chad reported its first dengue outbreak in history.</p>
<p>Dengue affects some 129 countries, with roughly half the world's population at risk, says the WHO. Infected female mosquitoes pass the virus when they feed on animals. The sickness can cause severe headaches, fever, vomiting, rash and other signs. While most infected people do not get symptoms, severe cases can lead to <strong>plasma</strong> leakage and death.</p>
<p>What is worse, experts say, repeated infections means a higher risk of developing severe dengue.</p>
<p>The Caribbean also is battling an increase in cases. The area had reported a 15 percent increase in confirmed cases by early October compared with the same period last year, says the Caribbean Public Health Agency.</p>
<p>Officials on the French Caribbean islands of Guadeloupe and Martinique declared an epidemic in August that is still ongoing. Martinique is reporting an average of 800 cases a week on the island of some 394,000 people.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Jamaica and the Bahamas declared an outbreak in September followed by Barbados in October.</p>
<p>Poor countries struggle the most with dengue. Bad sanitation creates a good reproduction environment for infected mosquitoes. Poor housing conditions leave people at greater risk of exposure to mosquitoes. Dengue outbreaks can crush already poor and overworked health systems.</p>
<p>Jeremy Farra is chief scientist for the WHO. He said dengue is very difficult to treat partly because patients often delay in seeking medical care. The virus can progress so quickly, he said. Treating those with the disease requires very close patient supervision and a lot of time.</p>
<p>Farra said, "Imagine that you have a thousand people like that requiring all that <strong>delicate</strong> clinical care. It can very quickly <strong>overwhelm</strong> a system."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sentinel </strong><em>— n. </em>sometimes used figuratively</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>drought</strong><strong><em> </em></strong><em>— n. </em>a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pre-industrial </strong><em>— adj. </em>relating to a time before industrialization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>plasma </strong><em>— n. </em>the watery part of blood that contains blood cells</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>delicate </strong><em>— adj. </em>easily broken or damaged</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What White House Gardens Say about America  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-white-house-gardens-say-about-america.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The earliest presidents who lived in the White House did not want the large outdoor areas that the <strong>monarchs</strong> of Europe might enjoy.</p>
<p>Marta McDowell is writer of <em>All the Presidents' Gardens. </em>She said, "You can understand that, given our democratic form of government." But she said she thinks that a visit to the home of the British royal family, Buckingham Palace, caused President John Kennedy to expand the White House <strong>gardens</strong>.</p>
<p>From the start, presidents and their families influenced the 7.2 hectares of open space in the front and back of the White House differently. Their choices often showed their values and traditions of their day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A view of the restored Rose Garden at the White House in Washington, Saturday, Aug. 22, 2020. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-637d-08dbfcd82e88_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A view of the restored Rose Garden at the White House in Washington, Saturday, Aug. 22, 2020. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)</span></div>
<p>McDowell said that the White House is "really their home" while they are in office. She added that as long as they work with the historic plan of the gardens the National Park Service tries to meet the desires of the administration. The National Park Service oversees the gardens.</p>
<p>John Quincy Adams, America's sixth president, worked in the garden. Theodore Roosevelt, the 26th president, took down glass structures called greenhouses that were first built by James Buchanan, the 15th president, in the 1850s.</p>
<p>John Kennedy, the 35th president, redesigned one garden called the Rose Garden in the 1960s. First lady Michelle Obama, wife of the 44th president, built a food garden using plants and seeds from the home of Thomas Jefferson, the third president. Today, the garden has more than 50 kinds of vegetables.</p>
<p>Pierre L'Enfant was the city planner and <strong>architect</strong> for America's first president, George Washington. At first, he planned for a 30-hectare presidential garden. However, as a believer in small government, Jefferson reduced the White House grounds to just 2 hectares. The gardens were expanded to the current 7.2 hectares</p>
<p>Jefferson, like many Americans who had just freed themselves from a British monarch, was concerned about creating a new <strong>king</strong>.</p>
<p>"Avoid <strong>palaces</strong> and gardens of palaces," William Thornton, a Washington city representative warned. "If you build a palace with gardens, I will find you a king."</p>
<p>Over time, several different plants and flowers were planted at the White House. They include roses which have been around since at least Jefferson's time. They also include peonies, wanted by first lady first lady Nancy Reagan of the 40th president, and Texas bluebells, asked for by first lady Laura Bush of the 43rd president.</p>
<p>Oak and elm trees have also been on the White House grounds almost since the beginning. One tree, a chestnut oak southeast of the White House, might be the oldest tree on the grounds. The White House says it has been around since 1800.</p>
<p>McDowell says the White House gardens represent gardening tradition over time. First it followed designs in Europe, and then it was shaped by local traditions, the area, and the climate.</p>
<p>But she said, "It's not that they are always the leader. In fact, sometimes they're following."</p>
<p>The White house grounds were open to the public up until 1923. That was when Calvin Coolidge, the 30th president, permanently closed them to unapproved visitors.</p>
<p>These days, the White House Garden planned visits for the public are usually available for the public twice a year, one weekend in the spring and again in autumn.</p>
<p>McDowell said, "They are full of tradition. They're full of beauty."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>monarch </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person (such as a king or queen) who rules a kingdom or empire</p>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n</em>. an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>architect </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who designs buildings</p>
<p><strong>king </strong>– <em>n</em>. a male ruler of a country who usually inherits his position and rules for life</p>
<p><strong>palace </strong>– <em>n</em>. the official home of a king, queen, or president</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rohingya Girls Forced into Dangerous Marriages in Malaysia  (2023/12/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/rohingya-girls-forced-into-dangerous-marriages-in-malaysia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Rohingya girl from Myanmar wanted to do anything she could to provide some money for her parents and three younger siblings. They needed food.</p>
<p>The 14-year-old and her family are members of the Muslim minority in Myanmar. The group is always in danger of attack by government forces and others there.</p>
<p>Last year, the girl, M, agreed to marry a man in Malaysia who promised to send about $4,000 to her family.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rohingya refugee, S, age 16, stands in the hallway of a friend's home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, on Oct. 6, 2023. S traveled to Malaysia from Myanmar in 2023 to marry an older man who paid for her passage. (AP Photo/Victoria Milko)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f1ec8071-da5b-441c-90f4-671ed68f3b86_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rohingya refugee, S, age 16, stands in the hallway of a friend's home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, on Oct. 6, 2023. S traveled to Malaysia from Myanmar in 2023 to marry an older man who paid for her passage. (AP Photo/Victoria Milko)</span></div>
<p>She and all the girls in this report are identified by only the first letter of their names for their safety.</p>
<p>M told the <em>Associated Press</em> she was not ready for marriage. But she had an urgent need to help her family.</p>
<p>Now, a year later in Kuala Lumpur, her 35-year-old husband rapes her almost every night.</p>
<p>M's experience is not unusual, the <em>AP</em> reports.</p>
<p>Many underage girls are now in Malaysia living in forced marriages to older men.</p>
<p>The girls say conditions for Rohingya in Myanmar and refugee camps in Bangladesh were very bad. Soldiers and others were raping and killing people. Others had their homes burned and property stolen. Malaysia seemed like a possibility for a safer life.</p>
<p><strong>Difficult journey</strong></p>
<p>The AP interviewed 13 Rohingya for the report. All had arrived in Malaysia since 2022. The youngest girl was 13. They all say they feel like hostages. They are rarely permitted outside their homes. They say they are not prepared to be mothers. About half are pregnant and some have children already.</p>
<p>The path to flee the refugee camps or Myanmar is dangerous. Some try crossing the Andaman Sea by boat although many die on the long trip. The United Nations said most Rohingya who survived the crossing this year were women and children.</p>
<p>The people who take the girls on dangerous trips to Malaysia are called traffickers. The girls are crowded onto boats and vehicles for the trip. There is little food. The traffickers also rape and beat the girls.</p>
<p>When M arrived in Malaysia, the man she was to marry called for the ceremony to take place at once. M was still bleeding from the rapes she suffered on her journey. A person who helps the Rohingya girls took her to a hospital for care.</p>
<p>When M got home, she found out the man who was now her husband already had a wife and two children. M does not tell her parents what happened to her. She thinks it might cause her husband to stop sending monthly payments to her family.</p>
<p><strong>Pain and unwanted pregnancy</strong></p>
<p>Another girl, D, is in the same situation. She is 13. She plays with a little toy whale as she talks. She wants to play outside or visit a market nearby. But, her husband does not permit her to leave the home. She is forced to have sex every day. She does not want a baby, but she knows there is a good chance she will get pregnant.</p>
<p>"I want to run," D said.</p>
<p>R is 16. She has a newborn. She is one of several girls in a building filled with child <strong>brides</strong> who now have their own children. You can hear the babies crying.</p>
<p>She said life as a refugee in Bangladesh was difficult. But, as one of 11 children in her family, she was never lonely there. She had no one in Malaysia except her husband. She would be alone all day while he was at work.</p>
<p>R gave birth recently. "When I saw my baby's face, I was happy, because now I have a friend," she told the <em>AP</em>.</p>
<p>However, being a mother is not easy. She said she does not know how to be a mother.</p>
<p>"I miss my mom," she said. "I want my parents."</p>
<p>S is pregnant and homeless. Her Malaysian husband forced her to leave when he found out she was pregnant. Without a job, S walks the streets of Kuala Lumpur asking strangers for money.</p>
<p>"I once dreamed of having a happy family," S says. "I don't dream much anymore."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bride </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for the female in a traditional marriage</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Finds Material that Could Support Possible Life on Saturn’s Moon  (2023/12/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/nasa-finds-material-that-could-support-possible-life-on-saturn-s-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>NASA has discovered new evidence that Saturn's moon Enceladus holds material that is important to the early development of life.</p>
<p>The American space agency said the new evidence came from observations made by its Cassini spacecraft. Cassini spent seven years observing seasonal changes around Saturn. During that time, the spacecraft also collected data on Saturn's moons.</p>
<p>Two of Cassini's discoveries involved Saturn's moons Titan and Enceladus. In its observations of Titan, the spacecraft studied the moon's climate activity and recorded data on rivers, lakes and oceans. Cassini also found evidence of several Earth-like qualities of Titan that could support life.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Water from the subsurface ocean of Saturn's moon Enceladus sprays from huge fissures out into space. (Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5839-08dc024b6fe1_cx6_cy8_cw87_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Water from the subsurface ocean of Saturn's moon Enceladus sprays from huge fissures out into space. (Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute)</span></div>
<p>Another Cassini discovery involved the observation of hydrogen molecules in ice particles and <strong>vapor</strong> shooting upward from the moon's surface. Researchers announced that finding in 2017, the same year Cassini officially ended its <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>In announcing that discovery, NASA scientists said the presence of hydrogen molecules could signal deep-sea chemical reactions between water and rock that could create microbial life.</p>
<p>Now, the space agency is sharing a new finding that supports the earlier discoveries. Scientists examining Cassini data said they identified "strong confirmation" of the presence of another molecule seen as important for enabling life.</p>
<p>Evidence of the molecule – hydrogen cyanide – was found in data relating to the same shooting flows of ice and water vapor observed by Cassini on Enceladus.</p>
<p>The team used data collected by an instrument aboard Cassini designed to measure the activity of gas, ions and ice particles around Saturn. The discovery process involved a lot of mathematics aiming to understand the newly examined data.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>The new evidence is described <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-023-02160-0.epdf?sharing_token=9f1fFhF9x9DTwwV3Z4KYPtRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0O62obxNW8k7GDHtvLUshnFEHPyLmkRC9CrS4VWCC4iWzGprsnt-SNu6EBvPgXNhKu_g09avF1rQpc6EgUqbrTYGqv1r68pzsZqFESsPMU6Dvgyq4KlXUNeNP_gtWiJyoM%3D">in a study</a> in <em>Nature Astronomy</em> by scientists from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in California.</p>
<p>The lead writer of the study, Jonah Peter, is currently a doctoral student at Harvard University. He called the discovery of hydrogen cyanide "particularly exciting," saying the molecule is "the starting point for most theories on the <strong>origin</strong> of life."</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-study-finds-life-sparking-energy-source-and-molecule-at-enceladus">said in a statement</a> that for life to exist in space, there must be collections of the right building blocks. One of the most important of these is amino acids. "Hydrogen cyanide is one of the most important and <strong>versatile</strong> molecules needed to form amino acids," NASA noted.</p>
<p>The researchers said hydrogen cyanide molecules can join together in many different combinations. They can also serve as a "<strong>precursor</strong>" for different kinds of amino acids.</p>
<p>In addition, the latest examination of Cassini data suggested the underground ocean on Enceladus "holds a powerful source of chemical energy." The ocean sits beneath the moon's icy surface.</p>
<p>"Unidentified until now, the energy source is in the form of several organic compounds, some of which, on Earth, serve as fuel for organisms," NASA said.</p>
<p>Astronomers involved in the research said that the discovery provides fresh evidence that there may be more chemical energy inside Enceladus than previously thought. The more energy that is available, the team said, the more likely it is that life can form and survive.</p>
<p>"Not only does Enceladus seem to meet the basic requirements for <strong>habitability</strong>," said JPL's Jonah Peter, "we now have an idea about how complex biomolecules could form there, and what sort of chemical pathways might be involved."</p>
<p>The search for possible life on Titan will continue when NASA launches its Dragonfly exploratory mission in 2026. Dragonfly is a drone, or pilotless aircraft. The vehicle is designed to capture images and also land on Titan to collect data.</p>
<p>Tom Nordheim is a planetary scientist at JPL who helped lead the research. He noted that although NASA purposely sent the spacecraft crashing into Saturn's atmosphere to end its service, Cassini is still proving to be a valuable research tool.</p>
<p>"Our study demonstrates that while Cassini's mission has ended, its observations continue to provide us with new <strong>insights</strong> about Saturn and its moons..." Nordheim said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and Nature. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vapor </strong><em>– n. </em>many small drops of liquid that form in the air</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>an important job or task, often involving travel to somewhere</p>
<p><strong>ion </strong><em>– n. </em>an atom or small group of atoms that has an electrical charge because it has added or lost electrons</p>
<p><strong>origin </strong><em>– n. </em>where something begins or comes from</p>
<p><strong>versatile </strong><em>– adj. </em>using for doing a lot of different things</p>
<p><strong>precursor </strong><em>– n. </em>something that happens or exists before something else and influences its development</p>
<p><strong>insight </strong><em>– n. </em>a thing that helps someone gain a deeper understanding of something</p>
<p><strong>habitability </strong>–n. able to support living in or on</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Suggests Obesity Increasing Among US Children  (2023/12/25) | 研究表明美国儿童肥胖率增长</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/study-suggests-obesity-increasing-among-us-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A new study adds to evidence that obesity is becoming more common in young children in America.<br/>
一项新的研究进一步证明，肥胖在美国幼儿中变得越来越普遍。</p>
<p>The study appeared in the medical publication Pediatrics.<br/>
这项研究发表在医学期刊《儿科学》上。</p>
<p>The findings are similar to other national data, which suggests around 2.5 percent of all preschool-aged children were severely obese during the same period.<br/>
这一发现与其他国家数据相似，这些数据表明，在同一时期，约2.5%的学龄前儿童严重肥胖。</p>
<p>One of the study's writers, Heidi Blanck of the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, said "We were doing well and now we see this upward trend....We are dismayed at seeing these findings."<br/>
该研究的作者之一，美国疾病控制和预防中心的海蒂·布兰克说：“我们做得很好，现在我们看到了这种上升趋势……我们对这些发现感到沮丧。”</p>
<p>Dismayed is a term that means very worried or disappointed.<br/>
Dismayed是一个术语，意思是非常担心或失望。</p>
<p>The study looked at children ages 2 to 4 who took part in the Women, Infants and Children (WIC) program. The program gives healthy foods and other services to preschool-aged children in low-income families. The children were weighed and measured.<br/>
这项研究观察了2至4岁参加妇女、婴儿和儿童（WIC）项目的儿童。该计划为低收入家庭的学龄前儿童提供健康食品和其他服务。孩子们测量了体重和身高。</p>
<p>The researchers found that 2.1 percent of kids in the program were severely obese in 2010. Six years later, the rate had dropped to 1.8 percent. But by 2020, it was 2 percent. That amounts to about 33,000 of more than 1.6 million kids in the WIC program.<br/>
研究人员发现，2010年，该项目中有2.1%的儿童严重肥胖。六年后，这一比例降至1.8%。但到2020年，这一比例为2%。这相当于参与WIC项目的160多万儿童中的约3.3万人。</p>
<p>The study showed major increases in 20 states. California's was the highest at 2.8 percent. There also were large increases in some racial and ethnic groups. The highest rate, about 2.8 percent, was among Hispanic children.<br/>
这项研究显示，有20个州的严重肥胖比例大幅增加。加利福尼亚州的比例最高，为2.8%。一些种族和族裔群体的严重肥胖比例也大幅增加。西班牙裔儿童的比例最高，约为2.8%。</p>
<p>Experts say severe obesity at a very early age is nearly irreversible – meaning the damage is nearly impossible to undo.<br/>
专家表示，年幼时期的严重肥胖几乎是不可逆转的，这意味着这种损害几乎不可能消除。</p>
<p>Severe obesity is strongly linked with health problems and an early death.<br/>
严重肥胖与健康问题和过早死亡密切相关。</p>
<p>It is not clear why the increase occurred, Blanck said.<br/>
布兰克说，目前还不清楚为什么会出现这种增长。</p>
<p>When WIC obesity rates dropped, some experts suggested 2009 policy changes might be responsible. Those changes took out juice from infant food packages, provided less saturated fat, and tried to make it easier for people to buy fruits and vegetables.<br/>
当WIC肥胖率下降时，一些专家认为原因可能是2009年的政策改革。这些改革消除了婴儿食品包中的果汁，减少了饱和脂肪，并试图让人们更容易购买水果和蔬菜。</p>
<p>The package has not changed. But "the daily hardships that families living in poverty are facing may be harder today than they were 10 years ago, and the slight increases in the WIC package just weren't enough," said Dr. Sarah Armstrong, a Duke University childhood obesity researcher.<br/>
这些食品包没有改变。但是，杜克大学儿童肥胖研究人员萨拉·阿姆斯特朗博士说：“如今生活在贫困中的家庭每天面临的困苦可能比10年前更严重，而WIC项目食品包的小幅增加还不够。”</p>
<p>The researchers faced difficulties. The number of kids in WIC declined in the past ten years. And the study included 2020, the year the COVID-19 pandemic hit. At the time, fewer parents brought their children in to see doctors. That reduced the amount of complete information available.<br/>
研究人员面临困难。在过去的十年里，WIC项目的孩子数量有所下降。这项研究包括新冠肺炎大流行的2020年。当时，带孩子来看病的父母越来越少。这减少了可用的完整信息量。</p>
<p>Despite its limitations, it was a "very well done study," said Deanna Hoelscher, a childhood obesity researcher at the UTHealth Houston School of Public Health. She added, "It gives you a hint of what's going on."<br/>
休斯顿公共卫生学院健康科学中心的儿童肥胖研究员迪安娜·霍尔舍说，尽管有局限性，但这是一项“做得很好的研究”。她补充道，“这提示了现状。”</p>
<p>What has happened since 2020 is not yet known. Some small studies have suggested an increase in childhood obesity — especially during the pandemic. During the pandemic, kids were kept home from schools. Their eating and bedtime schedules were changed and physical activity decreased.<br/>
自2020年以来发生了什么还不得而知。一些小型研究表明，儿童肥胖率有所上升，尤其是在疫情期间。疫情期间孩子们被关在家里不上学。他们的饮食和就寝时间发生了改变，体育锻炼也有所减少。</p>
<p>"We are thinking it's going to get worse," Hoelscher said.<br/>
“我们认为情况会变得更糟，”霍尔舍说。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我叫约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ukraine's Army Struggles with Mental Effects of Combat  (2023/12/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/ukraine-s-army-struggles-with-mental-effects-of-combat.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mental health expert Oleh Hukovskyi recently stood in a temporary classroom in eastern Ukraine speaking to a group of soldiers. They were attending a class on how to deal with the <strong>stress </strong>of war.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi is one of hundreds of professionals and volunteers across Ukraine treating soldiers for mental health problems. It is a growing issue for an army facing <strong>fatigue</strong> as soldiers fight a larger enemy.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency spoke to 13 people involved in supporting troops and four soldiers undergoing treatment. The treatment can last for a few days to several weeks in more serious cases. It also includes soldiers who have lost arms or legs and who are learning to live with their injuries.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Serhii Rostikov, (R) head of a unit for combat stress control of the 21st Separate Mechanized Brigade, speaks with a soldier, Nov. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Sofiia Gatilova)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-98da-08dc01aad0f0_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Serhii Rostikov, (R) head of a unit for combat stress control of the 21st Separate Mechanized Brigade, speaks with a soldier, Nov. 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Sofiia Gatilova)</span></div>
<p>Soldiers spoke of stress, <strong>anxiety</strong>, fear, guilt and being extremely tired. But they also spoke of friendship, a sense of <strong>obligation</strong> to hurry back to their units and a strong desire to repel the enemy.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi is one of the soldiers Reuters spoke to. He is a former <strong>psychiatrist</strong>. He joined the armed forces about six months after Russia launched an invasion in February 2022.</p>
<p>Now, he runs a mental health support group attached to the 67th Separate Mechanized Brigade. The brigade is in the area of Lyman, a town heavily damaged by the war.</p>
<p>"They have obligations and have to return to the front line," Hukovskyi said of the troops.</p>
<p>Some of the soldiers are being treated for light wounds and battle stress at a medical aid center.</p>
<p>Hukovskyi said Ukrainian soldiers were not given enough breaks from fighting.</p>
<p>"Forty-five days is a <strong>critical</strong> period when soldiers can stay and...have a chance to stay mentally healthy," he said. He added that in some situations they might remain in battle longer. When that happens, they experience more head injuries and more battle fatigue.</p>
<p><strong>Citizen soldiers</strong></p>
<p>Many of those fighting joined as volunteers. They had little, if any, preparation for sometimes fierce combat conditions.</p>
<p>The soldiers attending the class answer questions and suggestions. However, Hukovskyi knows there are limitations. Soon, the soldiers will have to return to fighting.</p>
<p>"Ukraine has an army of <strong>mobilized</strong> citizens who just yesterday were teachers, artists, poets, IT specialists, or workers," said Dana Vynohradova. He is deputy brigade commander for mental health support.</p>
<p><strong>Nightmares and fear</strong></p>
<p>"DJ" attended Hukovskyi's class last month. Before the war, he was a factory worker from central Ukraine. Like most other soldiers, he goes by his <strong>call sign</strong>, DJ.</p>
<p>"I have <strong>nightmares</strong> and they <strong>exhaust</strong> me. When I get some time to rest, I don't sleep at all," DJ told the group. Later, the 50-year-old explained that he was not prepared for the fierce combat.</p>
<p>DJ said his position near the front line was under continuous attack by Russian forces. Like others, he said he suffers from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and a <strong>concussion</strong>.</p>
<p>On a rainy November day in a nearby village, Dmytro, a 24-year-old soldier, talks with his unit's stress control group leader. He is a man named Serhii Rostikov. The Russians occupied the village in 2022. The two men walk and talk among damaged houses.</p>
<p>Rostikov said soldiers decide for themselves whether to seek mental health support. However, other specialists said unit commanders could make recommendations if they see signs for concern.</p>
<p>"After the artillery shelling, I developed a fear of going back to (combat) positions," said Dmytro. He is with the 21<sup>st</sup> Separate Mechanized Brigade.</p>
<p>He told Reuters that he reached out to his former group leader Rostikov for help. After working together, Rostikov sent Dmytro to <strong>rehabilitation</strong>. Dmytro said, "...I have no fear now and can easily go back to a combat position. I think we need <strong>psychologists</strong>, because soldiers suffer from a lot of stress."</p>
<p>Many soldiers who seek psychological support return to battle after short breaks. Some more serious cases are sent away from the front for more treatment.</p>
<p>DJ later said he had been kept away from combat for further treatment. Dmytro has rejoined his unit.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian military has tried to recruit more people for psychological support.</p>
<p>Ukraine's armed forces declined to answer questions about efforts to get support workers. It also did not release how many soldiers had been treated for psychological conditions since the start of the invasion. Such details are often treated as military secrets.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Mario Ritter.</p>
<p><em>Charlotte Bruneau reported this story for Reuters with additional reporting by Sofiia Gatilova and Stefaniia. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stress </strong>–n. a state of mental tension</p>
<p><strong>fatigue </strong>–n. a condition of being very tired</p>
<p><strong>anxiety </strong>–n. fear or worry about something</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong>–n. the feeling of having a responsibility to do something</p>
<p><strong>psychiatrist</strong> –n. a medical doctor who deals with mental health</p>
<p><strong>critical </strong>–adj. very important</p>
<p><strong>mobilize </strong>–v. (military) to organize and use people and resources for war</p>
<p><strong>call sign </strong>–n. a set of letters or numbers that is used to identify a person on radio or for special purposes</p>
<p><strong>nightmare </strong>–n. a frightening dream</p>
<p><strong>concussion </strong>–n. an injury that results from a blow to the head</p>
<p><strong>rehabilitation </strong>–n. treatment for an injury that is physical or mental that aims to return the patient back to normal life</p>
<p><strong>psychologist </strong>–n. a health worker who deals with mental health but is not a doctor and cannot order the use of medication</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit from St. Nicholas'  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-visit-from-st-nicholas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>
In 1822, an American professor named Clement Clarke Moore wrote a poem that redefined the image of Saint Nicholas. It was called "Account of a Visit from Saint Nicholas." He did not expect it to be published. He wrote it as a Christmas present for his young children. In recent years, experts have questioned whether Moore actually wrote the poem.</p>
<p>Some believe it was written by Henry Livingston, a map maker in New York who wrote and published funny poems in his spare time.</p>
<p>But whoever wrote this classic poem, it has since become a favorite around the world. This poem combines the traditions of Santa Claus, seasonal decorations and gift-giving that have come to define Christmas in America.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit From St. Nicholas'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9BC4B48F-8C2D-4097-B73E-B411786E115D_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">VOA Learning English Presents 'A Visit From St. Nicholas'</span></div>
<p>We give you the staff of Learning English reading Clement Clarke Moore's poem, popularly known as "'Twas the Night Before Christmas."</p>
<p>
<em>‘Twas the night before Christmas, when all through the house<br/>
Not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.<br/>
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care,<br/>
In hopes that Saint Nicholas soon would be there.</em></p>
<p><em>The children were nestled all snug in their beds,<br/>
While visions of sugar plums danced in their heads.<br/>
And mamma in her ‘kerchief, and I in my cap,<br/>
Had just settled our brains for a long winter's nap.</em></p>
<p><em>When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter,<br/>
I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.<br/>
Away to the window I flew like a flash,<br/>
Tore open the shutters and threw up the sash.</em></p>
<p><em>The moon on the breast of the new-fallen snow<br/>
Gave lustre of mid-day to objects below.<br/>
When, what to my wondering eyes did appear,<br/>
But a miniature sleigh, and eight tiny reindeer.</em></p>
<p><em>With a little old driver, so lively and quick,<br/>
I knew in a moment it must be Saint Nick.<br/>
More rapid than eagles his coursers they came,<br/>
And he whistled, and shouted, and called them by name!</em></p>
<p><em>"Now Dasher! Now, Dancer! Now, Prancer and Vixen!<br/>
On, Comet! On, Cupid! On Donder and Blitzen!<br/>
To the top of the porch! To the top of the wall!<br/>
Now dash away! Dash away! Dash away all!"</em></p>
<p><em>As dry leaves that before the wild hurricane fly,<br/>
When they meet with an obstacle, mount to the sky.<br/>
So up to the house-top the coursers they flew,<br/>
With the sleigh full of toys, and Saint Nicholas, too.</em></p>
<p><em>And then, in a twinkling, I heard on the roof<br/>
The prancing and pawing of each little hoof.<br/>
As I drew in my head, and was turning around,<br/>
Down the chimney Saint Nicholas came with a bound.</em></p>
<p><em>He was dressed all in fur, from his head to his foot,<br/>
And his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and soot.<br/>
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back,<br/>
And he looked like a peddler, just opening his pack.</em></p>
<p><em>His eyes -- how they twinkled! His dimples how merry!<br/>
His cheeks were like roses, his nose like a cherry!<br/>
His droll little mouth was drawn up like a bow,<br/>
And the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.</em></p>
<p><em>The stump of a pipe he held tight in his teeth,<br/>
And the smoke it encircled his head like a wreath.<br/>
He had a broad face and a little round belly,<br/>
That shook when he laughed, like a bowlful of jelly!<br/>
He was chubby and plump, a right jolly old elf,<br/>
And I laughed when I saw him, in spite of myself!<br/>
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head,<br/>
Soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.</em></p>
<p><em>He spoke not a word, and went straight to his work,<br/>
Filled all the stockings, then turned with a jerk.<br/>
And laying his finger aside of his nose,<br/>
And giving a nod, up the chimney he rose!</em></p>
<p><em>He sprang to his sleigh, to his team gave a whistle,<br/>
And away they all flew like the down of a thistle.<br/>
But I heard him exclaim, ‘ere he drove out of sight,<br/>
"Happy Christmas to all, and to all a good-night!"</em></p>
<p><em>Dorothy Gundy produced the video.</em></p>
<p><em>Do you have a favorite holiday poem? Tell us about it in the comments section.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Tis the Season!  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/tis-the-season.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about the word "season." We use this word in many different ways.</p>
<p>"Season" can <strong>refer to </strong>one of the four parts of the year. For example, Washington, D.C. is in a part of the United States that has four seasons: winter, spring, summer, and autumn. Some parts of the U.S. do not have four seasons.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A diver dressed as Santa Claus performs amongst fish during a Christmas-themed underwater show at an aquarium in Seoul, South Korea on December 4, 2019. (Photo by Jung Yeon-je / AFP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/A98A677E-54CF-4C5F-867A-156CD807A4D4_cx6_cy0_cw91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A diver dressed as Santa Claus performs amongst fish during a Christmas-themed underwater show at an aquarium in Seoul, South Korea on December 4, 2019. (Photo by Jung Yeon-je / AFP)
</span></div>
<p>"Season" can also describe the periods marked by warmth and growth or cold weather and falling leaves. For example, when the weather becomes warmer and days are lighter longer, the growing season begins for some plants. When the weather gets colder and the days darker, the <strong>hibernation</strong> season begins for some animals.</p>
<p>We also use "season" to describe periods that are only related to the weather. For example, some areas of the world have <u>rainy seasons</u> and <u>dry seasons</u>. Some parts of the U.S. have <u>tornado season</u>. And in other parts of the world there are <u>monsoon seasons</u>.</p>
<p>"Season" can also refer to the time before and during a major holiday. December is a busy <u>holiday season</u> in many parts of the world. Holidays include Christmas, Hanukkah, Kwanzaa, the Feast of Our Lady of Guadalupe and the Winter Solstice. December is often a time to take a break from work and spend time with loved ones.</p>
<p>Speaking of Christmas, when we say <u>‘tis the season</u> we are talking about something dealing with this holiday – its good side and its not-so-good side. For example, let's say I give a co-worker a big box of homemade cookies. They might say to me, "Thanks! But why are you giving me so many cookies?" I can answer, "'Tis the season!"</p>
<p>Here is another example. If I go out to a store and it is packed with holiday shoppers, I could <strong>complain</strong> to a friend. And they could respond, "Well, ‘tis the season!" What they <em>really </em>mean is this: At this time of the year, stores are usually very busy with Christmas shoppers.</p>
<p>In fact, Christmas is like <u>open season</u> on shopping deals. "Open season on" something means that it is being hunted, targeted, or in this case ... bought.</p>
<p>"Open season" also describes a period of time when a particular activity or opportunity is unrestricted. It is widely available. This term probably comes from hunting. Hunting traditionally has many restrictions. People can hunt only at certain times of the year and even then, there are restrictions on which animals and how many you can hunt. Fishing too has similar restrictions. But if it is open season, there are few restrictions.</p>
<p>As in our earlier shopping example, we can use this term for just about anything that is targeted with few restrictions. When talking about the best times to travel, for example, it is a good idea to travel <u>off-season</u>. If few people are traveling, it is a good time to find <strong>cheap</strong> air travel, hotels, and <strong>rental</strong> cars. It is open season on travel deals.</p>
<p>And like <u>hunting season</u>, we can have other "seasons" too. For example, beach areas are popular during <u>tourist season</u>. And people with <strong>allergies</strong> probably do not like <u>hay fever season</u> or <u>allergy season</u>.</p>
<p>So, "season" can simply mean a time of the year marked by a special activity. Sports seasons, for example, are popular with fans of sports.</p>
<p>We also have different seasons in our lives: Our time as children, going off to college, becoming parents, helping our aging parents, starting new careers or starting retirement. These are all different seasons of life. And they all have different <strong>aspects</strong> to enjoy and to be thankful for.</p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>refer </strong><strong>to </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to talks about or describe</p>
<p><strong>hibernate </strong><em>–v. </em>to pass winter in a resting state : <strong>hibernation</strong><strong> </strong>–n.</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong><em>–v.</em> to say that you are unhappy with something</p>
<p><strong>cheap </strong><em>–adj.</em> not costly; low cost</p>
<p><strong>rental </strong><em>–adj.</em> something you have paid for the temporary use of</p>
<p><strong>allergy </strong>–n. a condition of being especially sensitive to things like pollen, mold or foods which can make a person suffering from it feel sick</p>
<p><strong>career </strong>–n. the period of working and doing a job in one's life, especially within one field or profession</p>
<p><strong>aspect </strong>–n. a part of something</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you have similar expressions in your language? Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>George W. Bush: Wartime President  (2023/12/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-george-w-bush.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about George Walker Bush. He took office in 2001 as the 43rd president.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - George W. Bush" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/39fec087-a03f-4396-8a32-cdca08f06a08_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - George W. Bush</span></div>
<p>He has a similar name to another president -- his father, George Herbert Walker Bush.</p>
<p>To simplify things, Americans sometimes call the younger Bush "43," or simply "W." Here we will just call him Bush.</p>
<p>Because Bush is a recent president, historians have not reached a broad agreement on his time as a leader.</p>
<p>But he will surely be remembered for facing one of the biggest challenges to any president: the attacks against the U.S. on September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>George Bush was born in the northeast state of Connecticut. But his parents soon moved to the southwest state of Texas. George grew up there and considered Texas home.</p>
<p>The Bush family had a long background in politics. Bush's grandfather was a senator. His father held many public offices. In some ways, George was prepared for a career in politics, too.</p>
<p>He went to the same private <strong>boarding school</strong> as his father. Then, like his father and grandfather, George went to Yale for college. He also worked on several political campaigns. But he said he did not consider pursuing politics.</p>
<p>Instead, he earned a degree in business at Harvard and took a job in an oil company in Texas. In time, he founded his own oil business.</p>
<p>And he married <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/about-the-white-house/first-ladies/laura-welch-bush/">Laura Welch</a>, who was a teacher and librarian in their hometown. They had <strong>twin </strong>daughters named Barbara and Jenna.</p>
<p>In these years as a young adult, Bush began to make some changes. He began attending a Christian church regularly. He decided to stop drinking alcohol because it was creating problems in his personal life. And he turned his attention to politics.</p>
<p>Bush lost the first election in which he competed, a race to become a member of Congress. So, for a while, he focused on business investments and helping his father's political career.</p>
<p>But in 1992, his father lost re-election to the presidency. And the younger Bush saw a chance to enter politics himself again. In 1994, Bush ran for governor of Texas. To many people's surprise, he won.</p>
<p>Four years later, he was overwhelmingly re-elected. Many voters liked his image as, what he called, a "<strong>compassionate</strong> conservative." In other words, he wanted to use traditional Republican ideas about government to help society.</p>
<p>Following two successful terms as governor, Bush turned his attention to the presidency. In 2000, he competed against the vice president at the time, Al Gore. The winner was not announced until more than a month following the election – usually, the winner is announced within hours.</p>
<p>Both sides disputed the process of counting votes in the state of Florida. Finally, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled on the process. The Court ordered state officials to stop re-counting votes. Bush's lead stood.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>Bush entered office expecting to bring many of the ideas he pursued in Texas to the entire nation. For example, as president he permitted religious groups to receive government funding, and set national standards for public schools.</p>
<p>These moves were popular with many voters. But they also challenged some American traditions: the separation of church and state, and the ability of public schools to govern themselves.</p>
<p>For many presidents, these policies might have created a <strong>legacy</strong>. But early in Bush's term, he faced a crisis that defined much of his time in office.</p>
<p>Hijackers linked to the al-Qaeda group seized four airplanes on September 11, 2001. They purposely crashed two planes into the twin towers of the World Trade Center in New York City, eventually killing more than 2,700 people.</p>
<p>Another plane was flown into the Pentagon, the country's military headquarters outside of Washington, DC. About 200 people died there.</p>
<p>The fourth plane was aimed at another important target. But passengers fought the hijackers. The plane lost control and crashed in a field in Pennsylvania. All 44 people on board died there.</p>
<p>President Bush was visiting an elementary school in Florida that morning. He learned about the attacks while he was reading with the children.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, Bush spoke to the nation. He said the U.S. would answer both the terrorist groups and the countries that permitted terrorist groups to <strong>thrive</strong>.</p>
<p>Over the next years, Bush took a number of actions to create a new national security strategy. They included creating a Department of Homeland Security, making changes to the country's intelligence operations, and reforming the U.S. military.</p>
<p>He also sent U.S. forces into Afghanistan to destroy terrorist networks there. Bush was especially targeting the person who had designed the September 11 terrorist attacks, Osama bin Laden.</p>
<p>The struggle in Afghanistan was successful at first, but continued throughout Bush's time in office. And bin Laden was not captured while Bush was president.</p>
<p>In 2003, Bush opened another front on what some called the "war on terror." He and other government officials said the leader of Iraq, Saddam Hussein, was developing weapons that could kill many people. They said Hussein – and his connections to terrorist groups – threatened Americans and people in other countries.</p>
<p>Hussein did not agree to leave Iraq. So U.S. and British forces launched bombs at targets in the country's capital. Additional troops destroyed what was left of the targets. Hussein was quickly overthrown.</p>
<p>But the weapons of mass destruction were not found.</p>
<p>For the rest of Bush's presidency, U.S. forces remained in Iraq. Bush promised that Americans would stabilize the country and help Iraqis create a democratic government.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>The presidency of George W. Bush is too recent to understand its impact. But there is some evidence of the public's reaction at the time.</p>
<p>Bush received some of the highest ratings of any president. In the weeks following the September 11 attacks, 90 percent approved of his leadership.</p>
<p>He was re-elected in 2004. But his popularity steadily decreased .</p>
<p>At the end of his second term, he had one of the lowest public approval ratings of any president: 33 percent.</p>
<p>The U.S. economy had entered a recession. More Americans disagreed especially with his decision to invade Iraq. And some criticized his government for responding too slowly after Hurricane Katrina struck New Orleans and the country's Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>Since Bush left the White House in 2009, his approval ratings have – like those of many presidents – risen again. He has mostly avoided public appearances. Instead, he has enjoyed playing sports, helping charities, and reading U.S. history.</p>
<p>He also began a new hobby: painting. He has created <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/president-george-bush-portraits-of-courage/3748579.html">portraits</a> of dozens of veterans to honor their service in the military.</p>
<p>
I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this report for Learning English. Hai Do was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>boarding school </strong>- <em>n. </em>a school where students can live during the school term</p>
<p><strong>twin</strong> - <em>adj. </em>used to describe two children who are born to the same mother at the same time<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>compassionate </strong>- <em>adj. </em>feeling or showing concern for someone who is sick, hurt or poor</p>
<p><strong>legacy</strong> - <em>n. </em>something that happened in the past or that comes from someone in the past</p>
<p><strong>thrive</strong> - <em>v. </em>to grow or develop successfully</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South African Company to Make Rings that Protect Against HIV  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/south-african-company-to-make-rings-that-protect-against-hiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A South African company will make <strong>vaginal</strong> devices that protect against HIV. Medical experts say that should at some point make them less costly and more easily available.</p>
<p>HIV is a virus that causes AIDS, a serious disease that affects the body's natural defense system, or immune system.</p>
<p>The Population Council is an international nonprofit that does medical research. It announced recently that the South African healthcare company Kiara Health will start making the devices, or rings, from the medical product silicone in the next few years. It estimates that 1 million could be produced each year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman dances as she listens to music while attending a World AIDS Day commemoration at Nkosi's Haven in Johannesburg on Nov. 30, 2019 on the eve of World AIDS Day. (AP Photo/Denis Farrell, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/435ab65d-af4d-48f0-97c8-061c7a637024_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman dances as she listens to music while attending a World AIDS Day commemoration at Nkosi's Haven in Johannesburg on Nov. 30, 2019 on the eve of World AIDS Day. (AP Photo/Denis Farrell, File)</span></div>
<p>The devices release a drug that helps prevent HIV infections. They are approved by nearly 12 countries and the World Health Organization (WHO).</p>
<p>The nonprofit group owns the rights to the ring, which are now made by a Swedish company. About 500,000 rings are currently available to women in Africa at no cost, bought by donors.</p>
<p>Ben Phillips is a spokesman at the U.N. AIDS agency. He said the ring gives women the freedom to use it without anyone else's knowledge or agreement.</p>
<p>"For women whose partners won't use a condom or <strong>allow</strong> them to take <strong>oral</strong> (preventative HIV) medicines, this gives them another option," he said. A condom is a device worn by a male partner to prevent pregnancy and the spread of sexual diseases.</p>
<p>HIV remains the leading cause of death among women of <strong>reproductive</strong> age in Africa. And 60 percent of new infections are in women, information from WHO shows.</p>
<p>The ring releases the drug dapivirine in small amounts over a month. It currently costs $12 to $16, but experts expect the price to drop once it is widely produced in Africa. Developers are also working on a version that will last up to three months, which should also lower the yearly cost.</p>
<p>WHO has suggested the ring be used as an additional tool for women at high risk of HIV. Officials in more than 12 African countries, including South Africa, Botswana, Malawi, Uganda and Zimbabwe have also approved it.</p>
<p>WHO pointed to two studies in its approval, saying the ring reduced women's chances of getting HIV by about a third. While other research has suggested the risk could be dropped by more than 50 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Cheng reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vagina </strong>– <em>n</em>. the passage in a woman's or female animal's body that leads from the uterus to the outside of the body</p>
<p><strong>allow </strong>– <em>v</em>. to permit (something)</p>
<p><strong>oral </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used to describe a medicine that you eat or swallow</p>
<p><strong>substantial </strong>– <em>adj</em>. large in amount, size, or number</p>
<p><strong>reproductive </strong>– <em>adj</em>. relating to or involved in the production of babies, young animals, or new plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>A History of Christmas in America  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/a-history-of-chrismas-in-america.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>Today, Steve Ember and Shirley Griffith present a special program on Christmas traditions in the United States during the first half of the 19th century.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Santa Claus drives his reindeer and sleigh float along Central Park West during the Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade, Thursday, Nov. 23, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Jeenah Moon)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d7b8-08dbef5b9edb_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Santa Claus drives his reindeer and sleigh float along Central Park West during the Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade, Thursday, Nov. 23, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Jeenah Moon)
</span></div>
<p>During this period, there was no set way of celebrating the day, which was not yet an official holiday. Communities around the country honored the day in different ways. Some observed Christmas as an important Christian religious day honoring the birth of Jesus. Others celebrated the day with parties, music, drinking and eating. And, some communities did not celebrate the day at all.</p>
<p>But, it was during this period that Americans began to reinvent the holiday. They combined ancient Christmas traditions from different cultures with modern American influences.</p>
<p>Here are Steve Ember and Shirley Griffith.</p>
<p>In 1819, the popular American writer Washington Irving wrote a series of five essays<strong> </strong>published in a book called <em>The Sketchbook of Geoffrey Crayon, Gent</em>.</p>
<p>The essays describe a wealthy British landowner who invites his farm workers into his home to celebrate Christmas. The landowner recreates a traditional Christmas as it would have been celebrated in the distant past. Irving praised this looking back to ancient traditions. He liked the idea of different levels of <strong>society</strong> coming together to enjoy a<strong> festive</strong> and peaceful holiday. Washington Irving seemed to express concern about the lack of such <strong>unifying </strong>Christmas traditions in modern America.</p>
<p><strong>Immigrants shape Christmas traditions</strong></p>
<p>Penne Restad wrote a book <em>Christmas in America: A History</em>. It shows how Americans began to slowly shape Christmas into a unifying national holiday during the first half of the 19th century. She describes how Christmas had different meanings for Americans who came from different cultural and religious backgrounds. Many immigrants brought Christmas traditions from their own countries.</p>
<p>Religion played a big role in how an American might celebrate the holiday. Calvinist Christians banned the celebration of Christmas. But groups such as Episcopalians and Moravians honored the day with religious services and seasonal <strong>decorations</strong>.</p>
<p>By mid-century, Christian groups began to ignore their religious differences over the meaning of Christmas and honored the day in special ways.</p>
<p>Christmas became an important time for families to celebrate at home. More and more Christian Americans also began to follow the European traditions of Christmas trees and giving gifts. Christians believed that the tree represented Jesus and was also a sign of new beginnings. German immigrants brought their tradition of putting lights, sweets and toys on the branches of evergreen trees placed in their homes.</p>
<p>This tradition of setting up a Christmas tree soon spread to many American homes. So did the <strong>practice</strong> of giving people presents. As these traditions increased in popularity, the modern trade and business linked to Christmas also grew.</p>
<p><strong>Christmas as a holiday</strong></p>
<p>As Christmas became more popular, some states declared the day a state holiday. Louisiana was the first state to make the move in 1837. By 1860, 14 other states had followed. It was not until 1870 that President Ulysses Grant made Christmas a federal holiday.</p>
<p>Americans already knew old Christmas songs that came from England and other areas of Europe. But many new American Christmas songs started to become popular. For example, in eighteen forty-nine, a religious leader from Massachusetts wrote the words to <em>It Came Upon a Midnight Clear</em>.The song <em>J</em><em>ingle Bells </em>appeared seven years later. And, a year later, a religious leader in Williamsport, Pennsylvania wrote the song <em>We Three Kings of Orient Are</em>.</p>
<p>And of course, no discussion of Christmas would be complete without talking about of one of the holiday's most famous representations, Santa Claus.</p>
<p>This character is based on the story of Saint Nicholas, a Christian holy person believed to have lived in the third century. Saint Nicholas became known as a protector of children. Different cultures have given him different names. These include Sinterklaas, Kris Kringle and Father Christmas. But for most Americans his most popular name would become Santa Claus.</p>
<p>In the 19th century, many Dutch immigrants living in the United States celebrated the feast of Saint Nicholas on December 6. Saint Nicholas was especially important to New Yorkers because of their history as a Dutch colony. In 1809, Washington Irving published his <em>History of New York</em>. It lists Saint Nicholas as the patron saint of New Yorkers. He describes the saint wearing a low hat, large pants, and smoking a pipe. Does this description sound familiar?</p>
<p><em>Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>society </strong>- <em>n. </em>people in general thought of as living together in organized communities with shared laws, traditions, and values</p>
<p><strong>festive</strong> - <em>adj. </em>cheerful and exciting: suited to a celebration or holiday</p>
<p><strong>unifying</strong> - <em>v. </em> to cause (people or things) to be joined or brought together</p>
<p><strong>decoration </strong>- <em>n. </em>something that is added to something else to make it more attractive</p>
<p><strong>practice </strong>- <em>n. </em>something that is done often or regularly</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Assessment and Evaluation  (2023/12/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/assessment-and-evaluation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the words "assessment" and "evaluation."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>What is difference between Assessment and evaluation?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Assessment &amp; Evaluation" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f32e-08dc0101902a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Assessment &amp; Evaluation</span></div>
<p>Noor</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Noor. This is a good question.</p>
<p>Many people use the terms assessment and evaluation interchangeably. That means they see little or no difference between them in most cases. The terms are related. They both involve performance and education, but they are not the same thing. It is a mistake to use them interchangeably.</p>
<p>Assessment <strong>focuses on</strong> student learning, documenting what students know and what they can do. Assessment has many purposes. They include finding out a student's overall ability, measuring to what <strong>degree</strong> a student has gained control of an identified set of <strong>criteria</strong>, and providing students with information about their strengths and weaknesses. Assessment is a continual process. Its goal is to help students improve.</p>
<p>Here are some sentences using assessment.</p>
<p><em>Teachers should use classroom assessments to inform instruction.</em></p>
<p><em>The students completed a weekly assessment.</em></p>
<p><em>The school uses a variety of assessment tools.</em></p>
<p>Evaluation often focuses on the performance of an organization. Evaluation involves using criteria and evidence to find out if an organization is meeting its goals. Evaluation only happens at set times, and its goal is to judge the quality of an organization. Assessment can be a part of the evaluation process. That is because assessment results are often used to make judgements.</p>
<p>Here are some sentences using evaluation.</p>
<p><em>The class was canceled due to results from the curriculum evaluation.</em></p>
<p><em>The school district completed its special education program evaluation last month.</em></p>
<p><em>The governor focused on the lack of school counseling evaluations.</em></p>
<p>Although assessment and evaluation are both used in education and relate to measuring performance, they have different focuses, purposes, timing, and <strong>outcomes</strong>. The terms are also used a lot in other fields such as finance, medicine and engineering.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Noor.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>focus on</strong>–<em>v</em>. pay attention to</p>
<p><strong>degree</strong> –<em>n</em>. a level which can be measured in some way and compared to other levels</p>
<p><strong>criteria</strong>—<em>n</em>. conditions which must be met</p>
<p><strong>outcome</strong>–<em>n</em>. final product or end result</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
