<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>These Coral Reefs Are Doing Well in Gulf of Mexico  (2023/11/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/these-coral-reefs-are-doing-well-in-gulf-of-mexico.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) says changes in ocean temperature are the leading cause of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/coral_bleach.html">coral bleaching</a> around the world.</p>
<p>From Australia's Great Barrier Reef to the waters of Florida, it happens when warm water causes corals to expel their colorful <strong>algae</strong> and turn white.</p>
<p>Derek Manzello is the head of Coral Reef Watch, which is part of NOAA. He said at least 35 countries and territories across five oceans and seas reported coral bleaching.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Andy Lewis positions to photograph brain coral at the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary, off the coast of Galveston, Texas, Friday, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9baf1318-4076-4c37-aa83-4b69cf6ffb9e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Andy Lewis positions to photograph brain coral at the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary, off the coast of Galveston, Texas, Friday, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)</span></div>
<p>He said that by the year 2040, all of the world's coral will suffer from bleaching if water temperatures do not cool. He said coral needs extended periods of cooler water to recover from bleaching. If the water does not cool, he said, "the corals aren't going to have a chance to recover."</p>
<p><strong>Gulf of Mexico corals</strong></p>
<p>But in the Gulf of Mexico, about 160 kilometers south of Galveston, Texas, a large <strong>coral</strong> <strong>reef</strong> is still doing well.</p>
<p>The reef is part of the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary. The reef formation covers over 400 square kilometers. It started with just two reef areas, called banks, in 1992. It now has 17 banks. It is described as undersea mountains of yellow, orange and pink coral as far as the eye can see.</p>
<p>Michelle Johnston oversees the protected marine area for the federal government. She said seeing that much coral in one place is "<strong>magnificent</strong>" and rare.</p>
<p>Johnston said fishermen used to tell the story of a colorful area in the Gulf of Mexico far from shore 100 years ago. But, scientists were uncertain that a coral reef could exist in such deep water. When divers finally reached the reef in the 1960s, they were surprised to find marine life. Johnston said the plants and animals do so well because the reef formed on top of mountain-like salt <strong>domes</strong>, high enough to catch sunlight.</p>
<p>During the recent summer of record-breaking heat, Johnston said, the reef did experience some bleaching but nothing as serious as in other parts of the world. But that does not mean the reef in the Gulf of Mexico is not <strong>vulnerable</strong> to climate change. She is concerned about the area getting too hot and the coral dying off.</p>
<p>Officials who watch over Flower Garden Banks say the reef has suffered more serious bleaching in the past, but its depth and health helped it recover. The reef is deeper – 18 meters - than many others that are often just offshore.</p>
<p>Andy Lewis of Houston, Texas first saw the reef about 10 years ago. He loved it so much that he became an expert diver and started a company that leads dives to Flower Garden Banks.</p>
<p>"It's just a real adventure," he said.</p>
<p>Scientists are working to help the reefs stay healthy. For example, boats are not permitted to <strong>anchor</strong> themselves to the reefs. They must connect to special floating cables to stay in one place. Other workers help remove <strong>invasive</strong> fish and creatures from the area.</p>
<p>Kelly Drinnen is an education and outreach specialist for the Flower Garden Banks. She said, "because coral reefs are declining all over the <strong>globe</strong>, when we find ones that are healthy, we want to keep them that way." Drinnen added that they could also provide information that can help other reefs stay healthy or recover from bleaching.</p>
<p>In 2010, the Flower Garden Banks corals were not damaged by the large oil spill that followed the Deepwater Horizon explosion. Other reefs in the Gulf of Mexico were. So, researchers are using data from the reef to help guide the restoration of the damaged ones.</p>
<p>Researchers are also comparing the genetics of Flower Garden Banks corals to corals in other parts of the world. And they hope to grow and possibly replant them in other places.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>algae </strong><em>–n.</em> simple plants that grow in or near water</p>
<p><strong>coral reef </strong><em>–n.</em> a long line of coral that lies in warm, often shallow, water</p>
<p><strong>magnificent </strong><em>–adj.</em> used to describe something that is unusual and very impressive</p>
<p><strong>dome </strong><em>–n.</em> something tall and with a rounded top, like the rounded top of a building</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>–adj.</em> having the possibility of being hurt or injured</p>
<p><strong>anchor </strong><em>–v.</em> to connect something such as a boat to the ocean floor or another object so that it will not move</p>
<p><strong>invasive </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is living in an area where it does not belong and has no other predators</p>
<p><strong>globe </strong><em>–n.</em> the world, Earth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Automakers Seek to Produce EV Vehicles with Fewer Rare Earths  (2023/11/24) | 汽车制造商寻求生产无稀土电机</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/automakers-seek-to-produce-ev-vehicles-with-fewer-rare-earths.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Major automakers are seeking new ways to make electric vehicle (EV) motors that depend less on rare earth minerals.<br/>
主要汽车制造商正在寻找新的方法来制造对稀土矿物依赖较少的电动汽车发动机。</p>
<p>China controls most mining and processing of a group of 17 metals known as rare earths. These minerals are used to produce permanent magnets. Many experts consider permanent magnets to be the most effective way to power EVs.<br/>
中国控制着17种稀土金属的大部分开采和加工。这些矿物被用来制造永磁体。许多专家认为永磁体是驱动电动汽车最有效的方式。</p>
<p>But new motor designs show that permanent magnets are not necessary to produce a commercially successfully EV. And some Western EV makers are finding new solutions to produce motors that avoid rare earth minerals.<br/>
但新的电机设计表明，生产商业上成功的电动汽车并不需要永磁体。一些西方电动汽车制造商正在寻找新的解决方案来生产不含稀土矿物的电机。</p>
<p>EV market leader Tesla announced earlier this year it planned to remove rare earths from its next-generation EVs.<br/>
电动汽车市场领导者特斯拉今年早些时候宣布，计划从下一代电动汽车中去除稀土。</p>
<p>Other automakers are also in the process of researching or developing EV motors that use little or no rare earth minerals. These include General Motors, Jaguar Land Rover and BMW.<br/>
其他汽车制造商也在研究或开发几乎不使用稀土矿物的电动汽车发动机。其中包括通用汽车、捷豹路虎和宝马。</p>
<p>Nissan says it plans to develop newer motors with low rare earth content, as well as permanent magnet motors that will one day no longer need the minerals.<br/>
日产表示，计划开发低稀土含量的新型电机，以及有朝一日不再需要稀土的永磁电机。</p>
<p>German technology supplier ZF has developed a new kind of motor the company says is very similar to the size and performance of permanent magnet motors. This kind of motor, known as EESM, uses electricity to produce a magnetic field.<br/>
德国技术供应商采埃孚开发了一种新型电机，该公司表示，这种电机的尺寸和性能与永磁电机非常相似。这种被称为EESM的电机利用电力产生磁场。</p>
<p>ZF's Chief Technology Officer, Otmar Scharrer, told Reuters news agency such development is "an important contribution to making us a little more independent of China."<br/>
采埃孚首席技术官奥特玛·绍尔告诉路透社，这类研制成果是“使我们更加独立于中国的重要贡献”。</p>
<p>ZF is in talks with U.S., European and Chinese automakers to supply the motor and could start producing EV models within two years, Scharrer said.<br/>
绍尔表示，采埃孚正在与美国、欧洲和中国的汽车制造商就供应这款电机进行谈判，并可能在两年内开始生产电动汽车。</p>
<p>Besides being mostly controlled by China, some rare earth development produces poisonous waste that can harm people and the environment. The problem could also be helped by using motors that do not depend on rare earth minerals.<br/>
除了主要由中国控制外，一些稀土开发项目还产生有毒废物，可能危害人类和环境。这个问题也可以通过使用不依赖稀土矿物的电机来解决。</p>
<p>"If you get it right, you've got a much more sustainable product," said Ben Chiswick. He directs engineering business development for Detroit-based Drive System Design. The company is working to create rare earth-free motors with three different automakers.<br/>
本·奇西克说：“如果实现了，就会得到一种更可持续的产品。”他在底特律驱动系统设计公司指导工程业务开发。该公司正与三家不同的汽车制造商合作开发无稀土电机。</p>
<p>Some companies, like BMW, say they have already made great progress after years of research. "It was not a home run... but it works very well without rare earths," said Uwe Deuke of BMW's latest development efforts. He leads engineering efforts for the company's EESM motor planned for its next-generation EVs.<br/>
宝马等一些公司表示，经过多年的研究，他们已经取得了巨大进展。乌韦·德乌卡在谈到宝马的最新开发工作时说：“这不是一次本垒打……但它在没有稀土的情况下运行得很好。”他领导该公司计划用于下一代电动汽车的EESM电机的工程工作。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Serena Williams, Ruby Bridges to Be Honored at Women’s Hall of Fame  (2023/11/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/serena-williams-ruby-bridges-to-be-honored-at-women-s-hall-of-fame.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Serena Williams and Ruby Bridges will be <strong>inducted</strong> into the National Women's Hall of Fame in March of next year. The American organization in Seneca Falls, New York made the announcement Thursday.</p>
<p>The tennis great and the civil rights leader were added to a list to be honored during Women's History Month in March.</p>
<p>"The 2024 inductee class has broken barriers, <strong>challenged</strong> the <strong>status quo</strong>, and left an <strong>impact</strong> on history," the Hall of Fame said in its announcement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Serena Williams, of the United States, reacts during a match at the U.S. Open tennis championships, Sept. 2, 2022, in New York. Williams and Ruby Bridges will be inducted into the National Women's Hall of Fame next year. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, file)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5fd74681-46fc-458e-8bf9-de7f3ad1a997_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Serena Williams, of the United States, reacts during a match at the U.S. Open tennis championships, Sept. 2, 2022, in New York. Williams and Ruby Bridges will be inducted into the National Women's Hall of Fame next year. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, file)</span></div>
<p>Eight other honorees were announced in the spring. Williams and Bridges became available after the ceremony plans changed, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 42-year-old Williams has won major events in tennis, called Grand Slam events, 23 times. She holds the record for the longest <strong>ranking</strong> as the top competitor. She retired from tennis last year. Earlier this month, Williams became the first athlete to win the Fashion Icon award from the Council of Fashion Designers of America.</p>
<p>The 69-year-old Bridges was six years old when she became the first Black student at a Louisiana public school where non-whites had been barred. The event took place in 1960. In 1963, painter Norman Rockwell recreated the scene in his painting, T<em>he Problem We All Live With</em>. Bridges established the Ruby Bridges Foundation in 1999. It offers educational programs and resources to guide and support younger generations toward a peaceful future.</p>
<p>Others to be inducted include Peggy McIntosh, an activist known for her explorations of <strong>privilege</strong>; Kimberlé Crenshaw who helped develop the <strong>academic </strong>idea called critical race theory; and Judith Plaskow, considered by some people as the first Jewish feminist <strong>theologian</strong> for criticizing the lack of female ideas in Jewish history.</p>
<p>The founder of the National Center for Human Rights Education in Atlanta, Loretta Ross, will also be inducted. So will Allucquére Rosanne "Sandy" Stone, a transgender woman born in 1936 and considered a founder of transgender studies in colleges.</p>
<p>Three women will be inducted <strong>posthumously</strong>. Dr. Patricia Bath was an early leader of laser eye operations and the first Black woman doctor to receive a medical patent. Dr. Anna Wessels Williams made a disease discovery that led to a treatment for diphtheria. And Elouise Pepion Cobell, known as Yellow Bird Woman, started the first bank established by a Native American tribe on a reservation in Browning, Montana.</p>
<p>For the first time, the induction ceremony will be broadcast nationally in prime time from New York City, the Hall of Fame said. The past 30 ceremonies have taken place in places around Seneca Falls, New York. The town was the site of the first Women's Rights Convention and is home to the National Women's Hall of Fame.</p>
<p>"The 2024 class of inductees are scientists, activists, performers, and athletes who are changemakers of today and <strong>inspiration</strong> for the women of tomorrow," said National Womens Hall of Fame chief, Jennifer Gabriel.</p>
<p>The American public nominates women to be considered for the Hall of Fame. A group of experts examines those nominations and makes the final decision.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Carolyn Thompson reported this story for the Associated Press. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>induct </strong><em>–v.</em> to accept into something</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>–v.</em> to question authority</p>
<p><strong>status quo </strong><em>–n.</em> the way things are now</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>–n.</em> influence</p>
<p><strong>rank </strong><em>–v.</em> to place things in order of where they place in a competition</p>
<p><strong>privilege </strong><em>–n.</em> having something that others do not or cannot have</p>
<p><strong>academic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to teaching in universities but not in normal life</p>
<p><strong>theologian </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who is an expert in religious matters</p>
<p><strong>posthumously </strong><em>–adv.</em> after someone has died</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Aims to Increase Battery Production  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/us-aims-to-increase-battery-production.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United States Department of Energy (DOE) is making an effort to increase <strong>battery</strong> production in the country.</p>
<p>The DOE recently announced it would provide $3.5 billion to companies that produce batteries and the important minerals that go into them.</p>
<p>Officials see batteries as an important climate solution. The devices can power cars and store clean electricity made from solar <strong>panels</strong> or wind <strong>turbines</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A truck is parked between brine evaporation ponds at Albemarle Corp.'s Silver Peak lithium facility, Oct. 6, 2022, in Silver Peak, Nev. (AP Photo/John Locher, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c7b49a98-a4f1-4b8c-9f52-af4a543e1a16_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A truck is parked between brine evaporation ponds at Albemarle Corp.'s Silver Peak lithium facility, Oct. 6, 2022, in Silver Peak, Nev. (AP Photo/John Locher, File)</span></div>
<p>The idea is to use fewer <strong>fossil fuels</strong> for cars and power plants.</p>
<p>Lithium ion is currently the favored battery for electric vehicles and clean electrical storage. The DOE wants to strengthen the supply. The agency estimates that by 2030 demand for lithium batteries will increase by as much as 10 times.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden's administration has set a goal of lowering the pollution that causes climate change to zero by 2050. It also wants electric automobiles to represent half of all new car sales by 2030.</p>
<p>Some officials, industry experts and others are concerned that the supply of battery materials will not keep up with the demand. Others worry that too much of the industry is located in Asia.</p>
<p>Jodie Lutkenhaus of the Texas A&amp;M University said she is closely watching U.S. battery production and manufacturing. "I'm worried that we may not catch up and end up in the same situation we're in now with the <strong>semiconductor</strong> industry," she said. Pandemic closings and suspensions slowed manufacturing in Asia. A microchip shortage resulted, affecting the availability of vehicles and electronic products.</p>
<p>"The same thing can happen with batteries if we don't diversify where batteries are made and where materials are sourced," Lutkenhaus said. She said the U.S. must take part in battery production and manufacturing to avoid possible worldwide shortages in the future.</p>
<p>A measure called the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $6 billion in total financing for battery manufacturing, including the processing of materials needed to make them.</p>
<p>So far, 15 projects are receiving the assistance. They include companies that mine minerals like graphite and nickel that are used in lithium batteries. Later, contracts will go to other companies, including finance and chemistry businesses.</p>
<p>Here's how it works: A company might want to build a factory to make special materials for electric cars. It estimates the cost of building the facility and commits to covering half of the cost. If the company is selected for the program, the government payment would cover the other half.</p>
<p>Albemarle, a major lithium producer, received financing for a factory in Kings Mountain, North Carolina. The factory processes lithium from ore collected around the world. The company said that in addition to EVs, demand for lithium also comes from electronics like medical devices and smartphones. Without the DOE financial support, the project "would have likely progressed along a different time scale,"Albemarle said in an email.</p>
<p>Matthew McDowell is with the Georgia Institute of Technology. He said the law has changed U.S. battery manufacturing in the past three years. He is excited, he said, about the new batteries for clean energy storage, including solid state batteries, which could possibly hold more energy than lithium ion.</p>
<p>Tom Moerenhout of Columbia University's Center on Global Energy Policy said it will be difficult to increase the worldwide supply of minerals for the predicted battery demand in 2030. "It's pretty huge," he said, noting that a new mine on average takes 16 years to begin commercial production.</p>
<p>But with the price of lithium rising, Moerenhout said, different battery types become more interesting. One he hopes to see increase is sodium ion batteries to help with the electrical grid. "The potential is quite huge," he said, because they are safe and not costly.</p>
<p>Companies can officially request financing through mid-March.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Isabella O'Malley reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>battery</strong> <em>– n.</em> a device that is placed inside a machine to supply it with electricity</p>
<p><strong>panel</strong> –<em> n. </em>a flat surface</p>
<p><strong>turbine </strong><em>– n.</em> an engine that has blades that are caused to spin by wind</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel</strong> <em>-- n.</em> a fuel such as coal, oil, or natural gas</p>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– n.</em> an object that allows some electricity to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indian Cloud-seeding Project Aims to Produce Rain to Clear Pollution  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/indian-cloud-seeding-project-aims-to-produce-rain-to-clear-pollution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Indian scientists plan to add substances to clouds above the capital New Delhi in an effort to produce rain to reduce pollution.</p>
<p>The method to <strong>artificially</strong> produce rain is called cloud seeding. The process involves adding different chemicals to clouds to cause rain. When rain falls from the sky, water droplets can attach to pollution particles and bring them down to the ground.</p>
<p>New Delhi has been rated the city with the most air pollution in the world. Reports say the problem has worsened across the city in recent weeks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Commuters make their way along a road amid heavy smoggy conditions in New Delhi, Nov. 5, 2023. (Photo by Arun SANKAR / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-adbd-08dbdecc68ab_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Commuters make their way along a road amid heavy smoggy conditions in New Delhi, Nov. 5, 2023. (Photo by Arun SANKAR / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Air quality decreases in the city ahead of winter each year. During this time, cold air can trap many pollutants, including gases from vehicles, industry, building projects and agricultural burning.</p>
<p>Scientists expect some clouds over the city around November 20. They hope the clouds will result in heavy rainfall – when sprayed with a <strong>salt</strong> mixture.</p>
<p>The project is being led by Manindra Agrawal, a scientist at the Indian Institute of Technology in the central city of Kanpur. He told Reuters news agency the salt mixture will include silver iodine to help produce rain. It is to be sprayed on clouds over a 100 square kilometer area. Agrawal said the project will cost about $120,000.</p>
<p>The local government in New Delhi, a city of 20 million people, has already closed schools, stopped building activities, and said it will place restrictions on vehicle use to control pollution.</p>
<p>The air quality index in the city was 506 on November 9. This level is considered "hazardous" by <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iqair.com/">IQAir</a>, a Swiss company that describes itself as an "air quality solutions" business.</p>
<p>Gufran Beig is head of the Indian government's air-quality measuring agency SAFAR. He told Reuters the city needs heavy and widespread rain to wash away the pollutants. Beig added that light rain could worsen the situation.</p>
<p>The SAFAR head said current airflow is carrying smoke from crop burning in the states of Punjab and Haryana to Delhi. This smoke adds to the city's existing pollution sources. "So, unless a huge pressure is established by intense rain, this chain of transport from Punjab to Delhi will not be broken," Beig said.</p>
<p>About 38 percent of pollution in the capital has been caused by <strong>stubble</strong> burning in Punjab and Haryana, a recent government statement said. Farmers carry out stubble burning to clear material left behind from rice harvests so they can plant other crops. Indian officials directed leaders in both states to "take effective actions" to identify and limit stubble burning, the statement added.</p>
<p>Officials in New Delhi are seeking approval for the project from the Supreme Court, Reuters reported.</p>
<p>Several countries have used cloud seeding in an effort to produce rain, improve air quality and water crops in times of extreme dryness. These include Mexico, the United States, China, Indonesia and Malaysia.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>artificial </strong><em>– adj. </em>not natural, but made by people</p>
<p><strong>salt </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for one of many chemical combinations of two elements; sodium chloride</p>
<p><strong>stubble </strong><em>– n. </em>small pieces of dried plant stems left behind in a field after it has been cut</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Children in South Africa Walk a Long Way to School  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/children-in-south-africa-walk-a-long-way-to-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Fourteen-year-old Luyanda Hlali walks 10 kilometers to school. She lives in the little village of Stratford in South Africa's KwaZulu-Natal <strong>province</strong>.</p>
<p>There are no school buses. There is only the long road where robbers and bad men can harm her.</p>
<p>Luyanda is one of tens of thousands of children in South Africa who live a long way from their public school. The communities they live in are mostly rural and poor.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Luyanda Hlali, left, and her friend Mimi Dubazane embark on their routine 2 hour-long walk from the village of Stratford to their school in Dundee, South Africa, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. (AP Photo/ Mogomotsi Magome)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1a20-08dbea9eaef1_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Luyanda Hlali, left, and her friend Mimi Dubazane embark on their routine 2 hour-long walk from the village of Stratford to their school in Dundee, South Africa, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. (AP Photo/ Mogomotsi Magome)</span></div>
<p>Observers say students having to travel long distances to public schools shows the country's inequality when it comes to attending school. It has been nearly 30 years since the nation ended its <strong>apartheid</strong> system and the African National Congress party took power bringing democratic change.</p>
<p>There is a lack of school transportation paid for by the government.</p>
<p>Girls face the threat of attack and robberies are common. Parents, local leaders, and activists say the situation increases existing inequalities. The World Bank says South Africa is the most unequal country in the world.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal, campaigners and activists are pressing government officials to provide transportation for over 200,000 schoolchildren. The children have to walk three kilometers or more to school.</p>
<p>President Cyril Ramaphosa's government policy requires officials to provide transportation for the students who have to walk that distance. But school buses are not a concern in an area where unemployment is over 25 percent and people are poor.</p>
<p>A 2020 Amnesty International report said a child's experience in South Africa "still very much depends on where they are born, how wealthy they are, and the color of their skin."</p>
<p>South Africa's education system, the report said, "has deep roots in the <strong>legacy</strong> of apartheid, but which are also not being effectively <strong>tackled</strong>" by the government.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal, more than 30 percent of the province's 12.4 million people are unemployed. Many say they have to choose between buying food or paying $19 a month for public transportation.</p>
<p>"Sometimes these children go to school without eating breakfast," said Bongiwe Nhlangothi, Luyanda's grandmother.</p>
<p>She is the most scared when her grandchildren are traveling.</p>
<p>"There are drug <strong>addicts</strong> around here, when they come across the children in the early hours of the morning, they rob them of their phones, threaten them with knives and try to rape them," Nhlangothi said.</p>
<p>A school <strong>principal</strong> in a village about 50 kilometers from the coalmining town of Dundee, told of his struggle to get more school buses approved. The principal said some of the school's female students had been raped by local criminals.</p>
<p>The school has two old buses, but they can only carry about 65 children. There are more than 400 students at the school. The principal said he fears one of the buses could permanently break down or crash.</p>
<p>In September 2022, reports said 18 students were killed in the province when their overcrowded minivan crashed on the way to school in the town of Pongola.</p>
<p>Some parents have decided to pay to have their children to live closer to their schools. But boarding a student is costly and leaves parents without help at home.</p>
<p>Activist Tebogo Tshesane works for the nonprofit organization Equal Education. He said the campaign for better school transportation across KwaZulu-Natal started back in 2014. It started after students wrote letters because they were walking for up to two hours to school.</p>
<p>Government information says 1,148 schools in KwaZulu-Natal are on a waiting list for school transportation paid for by the government.</p>
<p>The provincial department of education did not wish to talk to <em>The Associated Press</em> for this story.</p>
<p>The answer from the education department is that there is no money, so the children keep walking.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>province </strong><em>— n. </em>a large part or division of a country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>apartheid </strong><em>— n. </em>the system of racial separation in South Africa which was legal until it was abolished in the early 1990s</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>legacy </strong><em>— n. </em>what people leave to their children after they die</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tackle </strong><em>–v. idiom </em>to deal with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>addict </strong>–n. a person who cannot stop taking drugs</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>principal </strong><em>— n.</em><strong> </strong>the leader of a grade school or secondary school</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving: An American Tradition  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/thanksgiving-american-tradition-2017.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Ashley Thompson</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American holiday of Thanksgiving is celebrated every year on the fourth Thursday in November. The holiday is during autumn -- the main season for harvesting crops. Thanksgiving is an autumn harvest <strong>festival</strong> like those found in many cultures around the world.</p>
<p>On this day, most Americans gather with friends and family. Many take time to think about what they are thankful for, cook <strong>up a storm</strong>, and eat.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A VOA Learning English Thanksgiving" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1acdaeb8-5890-43e7-9251-a0272d935591_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A VOA Learning English Thanksgiving</span></div>
<p>A lot.</p>
<p>The star of most Thanksgiving dinners is a <strong>roasted </strong>turkey. Turkeys are large birds native to North America.</p>
<p>The turkey is cooked in an oven for many hours, often with a mix of celery, bread, onions and spices inside the bird. This mix becomes <strong>stuffing </strong>-- another star of the Thanksgiving dinner table.</p>
<p>Anna Matteo here at Learning English says the smell of turkey and stuffing roasting together is the quintessential smell of Thanksgiving. "Quintessential" means the perfect example of something.</p>
<p>After the bird is cooked, the stuffing is taken out and served as a side dish.</p>
<p>One of <em>many </em>side dishes. Families often make other foods like mashed potatoes, sweet potatoes, cranberry sauce and vegetable casseroles. A casserole is a dish that cooks slowly in an oven.</p>
<p>And do not forget about the gravy. This rich sauce is made from the fatty liquid that comes off the turkey as it cooks. People cover their turkey meat, stuffing and mashed potatoes with gravy.</p>
<p>The meal does not end with the turkey, stuffing, and side dishes, though. For some people, the best part of the meal is dessert.</p>
<p>The quintessential Thanksgiving dessert is pie. Pumpkin, cherry, apple or pecan pie are all great ways to finish off a Thanksgiving meal...if you are not too full of food by that point!</p>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving travel </strong></p>
<p>Some Americans must travel long distances to be with their families. In fact, the Sunday after Thanksgiving is the busiest travel day of the entire year. This is usually when people return home from family gatherings.</p>
<p>Not everyone can make the return home each Thanksgiving. So, young people living in cities away from their hometowns sometimes celebrate "Friendsgiving" -- a Thanksgiving meal with their friends instead of their family. They gather at someone's apartment or house and have a "<strong>potluck</strong>." This is a meal where everyone who is invited brings food to share with others.</p>
<p><strong>Beyond the table</strong></p>
<p>Thanksgiving is a big day for television, games and other entertainment.</p>
<p>One tradition is the television broadcast of Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade. It takes place each year in New York City. Workers of the Macy's store on Herald Square organized the first parade in 1924. Many of the workers were immigrants and wanted to hold a big parade like the ones in Europe. So, they dressed in costumes and borrowed some animals from the zoo. They also carried small balloons that floated just overhead.</p>
<p>Many professional American football games are also played on Thanksgiving. Fans of the sport enjoy relaxing and watching a game or two after eating a big Thanksgiving meal.</p>
<p>Some start Thanksgiving Day early - and in a healthy way. So-called "Turkey <strong>Trot</strong>" races take place in many towns and cities. These events involve runners dressing up in a Thanksgiving-related costume and running a short distance -- usually five kilometers.</p>
<p>Many Turkey Trots urge runners to bring canned food to donate to local food banks -- non-profit organizations that give food to poor people in a community.</p>
<p><strong>Serving those less fortunate</strong></p>
<p>Certainly, not everyone in America has an easy Thanksgiving. The United States is home to many poor and homeless people. Some cannot afford a Thanksgiving dinner. Others are without friends or families. Many religious and service organizations around the country try to fill these needs. Some provide community dinners at churches and other centers. Some groups also deliver Thanksgiving meals to people too sick or old to leave their homes.</p>
<p>The writer O. Henry called Thanksgiving the one holiday that is purely American. It is not linked to a religion or a certain group. Anyone in the United States on the fourth Thursday of November is welcome to celebrate Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>And I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Ashley Thompson wrote this story for Learning English. It was first published in 2017.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>festival</strong> - <em>n</em>. a special time or event when people gather to celebrate something</p>
<p><strong>up a storm</strong> - <em>idiom</em>. used to say that something is being done with a lot of energy or enthusiasm</p>
<p><strong>roasted </strong>- <em>adj</em>. cooked with dry heat in an oven or over a fire</p>
<p><strong>stuffing</strong> - <em>n</em>. a seasoned mixture of food that is put inside another food and cooked</p>
<p><strong>potluck</strong> - <em>n</em>. a meal to which everyone who is invited brings food to share</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers: Report Cards Unclear about Students Knowledge, Learning  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/researchers-report-cards-unclear-about-students-knowledge-learning.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A recent opinion study says a big majority of parents in the United States believe their child is performing at grade level in school. However, standardized tests show far fewer students are <strong>on track</strong>.</p>
<p>Polling company Gallup and the nonprofit group Learning Heroes released the public opinion <strong>poll</strong> this month.</p>
<p>Report cards show students' school performance. Parents depend on them to understand their child's progress. But report cards do not show all of a student's performance, researchers say. Without more knowledge about their child's learning, parents might not seek extra support for their children if it is needed.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Students work in the library during homeroom at D.H.H. Lengel Middle School in Pottsville, Pa., March 15, 2022. (Lindsey Shuey/Republican-Herald via AP, File) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-eb5e-08dbea15e985_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Students work in the library during homeroom at D.H.H. Lengel Middle School in Pottsville, Pa., March 15, 2022. (Lindsey Shuey/Republican-Herald via AP, File) </span></div>
<p>Bibb Hubbard is the founder and president of Learning Heroes, based in Arlington, Virginia. Report cards are "the number one <strong>indicator</strong> that parents turn to to understand that their child is on grade level, yet a grade does not equal grade-level <strong>mastery</strong>. But nobody's told parents that."</p>
<p>In the Gallup poll, 88 percent of parents believed their child was on grade level in reading, and 89 percent of parents believed their child was on grade level in math. However, a federal survey of school officials said half of all U.S. students started the last school year behind grade level in at least one subject.</p>
<p>One report examined <strong>grade point averages</strong> and test scores in the state of Washington over the past 10 years. Researchers found grades increased during the COVID-19 pandemic. Many school systems had eased their grading policies because of the difficulties students were experiencing.</p>
<p>Some of those policies could still be in place, <strong>masking</strong> the lack of learning that is showing up in standardized tests, but not in grades, said Dan Goldhaber. He is a co-author of the report and the director of the Center for Analysis of Longitudinal Data in Education Research, in Arlington, Virginia.</p>
<p>School systems across the U.S. have spent federal aid money from the COVID-19 crisis on programs to get students back on track. For example, school systems have introduced more <strong>tutoring</strong> and summer academic programs. But Goldhaber said fewer students attended these programs than the system had planned.</p>
<p>For programs like summer school or online tutoring, the family chooses whether to <strong>participate</strong>. "What we see is that it's only a <strong>fraction</strong> of the students that are invited or <strong>eligible</strong> that are actually participating," he said.</p>
<p>The Gallup poll findings suggest that parents might not know they could be taking action to help their child's school performance.</p>
<p>The poll involved more than 2,000 parents of students from kindergarten to twelfth grade. Half the respondents said they have discussed their child's academic progress with a teacher. Among parents who know their child is behind grade level in math, the percentage greatly increases: 74 percent have spoken with a teacher.</p>
<p>Report cards do not give enough information, said Sarah Carpenter. She is director of The Memphis Lift, an education activist group in Tennessee.</p>
<p>"A report card is really tricky in our opinion, because you're just looking at A's and B's and C's," Carpenter said. She said a report card does show whether a child's reading or math level is where it should be and added that parents do not understand this.</p>
<p>Trenace Dorsey-Hollins is a parent and founder of another activist group Parent Shield Fort Worth in Texas. She said if educators spoke to parents about issues like reading and grading, families would be better able to support their children.</p>
<p>She said, "Parents don't know what they don't know. So, we don't want them to blame themselves. But now that you have the information, use the information to demand better and ensure that your child and all children get exactly what they need."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>on track </strong><em>–phrase</em> happening in a way that is expected or planned</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>poll </strong><em>— n. </em>a study in which researchers as people their opinions about a subject to learn what people think about it</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>indicator </strong><em>–n.</em> a sign that shows the condition or the existence of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mastery </strong><em>— n. </em>being able to do something expertly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grade point average </strong>–n. a number that shows the average grade that a student has in school</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mask </strong><em>— v. </em>to hide something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor</strong><em> –v. </em>to teach either one or a small group of students outside of normal class time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>participate </strong><em>— v.</em><strong> </strong>to take part in something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fraction </strong><em>–n.</em> a part of a whole</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>eligible </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to join something or receive something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Did Thanksgiving 'Turkey' Get Its Name?  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/thanksgiving-turkey-name-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Ashley Thompson and Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Thanksgiving holiday is <strong>symbolized </strong>by its traditional food, a large bird we call a turkey. But turkey is certainly not from Turkey.</p>
<p>In fact, its English name is based on one big mistake. We could say it is a case of mistaken identity.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="President Joe Biden speaks after pardoning the national Thanksgiving turkey, Liberty, during a pardoning ceremony at the White House in Washington, Monday, Nov. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b0b6-08dbea009118_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">President Joe Biden speaks after pardoning the national Thanksgiving turkey, Liberty, during a pardoning ceremony at the White House in Washington, Monday, Nov. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)</span></div>
<p>Let's set the record straight.</p>
<p>The word "Turkey" has meant "the land of the Turks" since ancient times. The word "turkey" as it refers to the bird first appeared in the English language in the mid-1500s.</p>
<p>The misunderstanding over the word happened because of two similar-looking kinds of birds.</p>
<p>There is an African bird called the guinea fowl. It has dark feathers with white spots and a patch of brown on the back of its neck. Portuguese traders brought the guinea fowl to Europe through North Africa.</p>
<p>This foreign bird came to Europe through Turkish lands. So, the English thought of the bird as a "Turkish chicken."</p>
<p>When Europeans came to North America, they saw a bird that looked like the guinea fowl. This bird was native to the North American continent.</p>
<p>Orin Hargraves is a lexicographer, someone who writes dictionaries. Hargraves explains what happened.</p>
<p>"Some Europeans saw an American turkey, thought that it was the guinea fowl, which at that time was called the ‘turkey cock,' and so gave it the same name."</p>
<p>Hundreds of years later, we continue to call this North American bird "turkey," even though it has no connection at all with the country Turkey, or even with Europe.</p>
<p>But English is not the only language with interesting -- and even questionable -- names for this North American bird.</p>
<p>The Turkish, for their part, call turkey "hindi," the Turkish name for India<em>.</em> The reference to India probably comes from the old, wrong idea that the New World was in Eastern Asia.</p>
<p>The French call it "dinde," a name that also connects the bird to India. "D'Inde" means "from India" in the French language. "Turkey" has similar names in several other languages.</p>
<p>So, what do they call this North American bird in India? Well, in the Hindi language, "turkey" is "tarki."</p>
<p>But wait, there's more. In Portuguese, the same bird is called "Peru," after the South American nation.</p>
<p>Thanks to our VOA Learning English Facebook friends, we have a few more names for "turkey" to share with you.</p>
<p>The Vietnamese word for the bird is "gà t<i></i>226;y" or western chicken. Our Facebook friend Nguyen Duc explains that "local chicken is smaller than western chicken."</p>
<p>A Facebook friend in Myanmar explained that the Burmese word for "turkey" is "kyat sin." The name <strong>translates </strong>to "elephant chicken" in English.</p>
<p>"That animal looks like a big chicken," Zaw Myo Win explained.</p>
<p>The Dari language name for the bird, "fel murgh" also translates to "elephant chicken."</p>
<p>Abdulla Kawer explained to us that "here in Afghanistan this name represents the size of this delicious meal." He adds that he thinks the descriptive name "elephant chicken" is "better than a country name."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Ashley Thompson and Anna Matteo wrote this report for Learning English. It was first published in 2017.</em></p>
<p><em>How do you say 'turkey' in your language? Let us know in the comments section!</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>symbolize </strong><em>- v. </em>to represent or express a particular idea or quality</p>
<p><strong>translate<em> </em></strong><em>- v. </em>to change words from one language into another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Poor’ New Hampshire Man Leaves Millions to Small Town  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/poor-new-hampshire-man-leaves-millions-to-small-town.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>When Geoffrey Holt of Hinsdale, New Hampshire died earlier this year at 82, not many people knew he had over $1 million.</p>
<p>He wore worn-out clothes. He did not do jobs that paid a lot of money. He rode a bicycle instead of owning a car, and he had a small home.</p>
<p>But when he had extra money, he invested it well. One friend said he put money into a mutual fund that held stock in communications companies. This was in the days before mobile phones.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by Ed Smith, Geoffrey Holt rests his leg on top of his riding mower in Hinsdale, N.H., on April 4, 2020. Holt left the town of Hinsdale nearly $4 million when he died last June. (Ed Smith via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/732da797-835b-461f-b5cf-e59fe821829b_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by Ed Smith, Geoffrey Holt rests his leg on top of his riding mower in Hinsdale, N.H., on April 4, 2020. Holt left the town of Hinsdale nearly $4 million when he died last June. (Ed Smith via AP)</span></div>
<p>Holt told one friend, Edwin Smith, that the money had grown more than he expected.</p>
<p>Holt died with $3.8 million.</p>
<p>He left all the money to the town of Hinsdale.</p>
<p>The town has about 4,200 people and is about 160 kilometers northwest of Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>In Holt's will, the document he left when he died, he said the money should be used for education, health, recreation and culture.</p>
<p>Steve Diorio is one of the town leaders. He called the money "a <strong>tremendous</strong> gift."</p>
<p>No determination has been made yet about how the town will use the money. However, it seems as if the money will go into a special <strong>fund</strong>, and organizations can submit their ideas for approval.</p>
<p>Some have suggested upgrading the town hall clock, others have talked about repairing <strong>civic</strong> buildings or buying a vote-counting machine.</p>
<p>Kathryn Lynch is another town leader. She said Hinsdale will use the money carefully, or "<strong>frugally,</strong>" which is how Holt lived.</p>
<p>Smith, Holt's friend, said "he seemed to have what he wanted, but he didn't have much."</p>
<p>Holt would ride his bicycle or his lawn mower around town. He would go to a small store to buy a newspaper and he would sit on the lawn mower reading it or watching cars pass.</p>
<p>When he was younger, he worked as a manager for a grain production center. After the center closed, he did small jobs around town – helping people fix things in their homes or teaching teenagers how to drive. He did not have a television, and his friend said his home was not in perfect condition – the legs of his bed made holes in the floor.</p>
<p>But Smith said Holt studied financial magazines and carefully decided how to invest his money. He also liked reading about history – some of his favorite topics included World War II and learning about the auto manufacturer Henry Ford. He also enjoyed listening to classical music and had a record collection that included works by Handel and Mozart.</p>
<p>Holt's sister, Alison, is 81. She lives in California. She said she knew her brother invested his money and did not like to spend wastefully. She said their father passed the ideas along to his children.</p>
<p>Alison said her brother had a learning disability called dyslexia, so he had trouble reading and writing. "But he was very smart in certain ways."</p>
<p>She thought that Geoffrey was disappointed he could not succeed in education, so "maybe <strong>socking</strong> <strong>away</strong> all that money was a way to compete."</p>
<p>The Holts grew up nearby in Springfield, Massachusetts. Geoffrey Holt went to Marlboro College in Vermont and also served in the U.S. Navy.</p>
<p>Neither Geoffrey nor his sister had any children. Alison said her brother did not need a lot to be happy. But she is sad he never used the money to "<strong>indulge</strong> himself a little bit."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based a story by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tremendous </strong><em>–adj.</em> very large or great</p>
<p><strong>fund </strong><em>–n.</em> an amount of money that is meant to be used for or serves a specific purpose</p>
<p><strong>civic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to a city or town</p>
<p><strong>frugally </strong><em>–adv.</em> being careful not to spend money when it is not necessary; the careful use of money</p>
<p><strong>sock</strong> <strong>away </strong><em>–v. </em>(phrasal, informal) to save a supply of something, often money, by putting it in a safe place</p>
<p><strong>indulge </strong><em>–v.</em> to permit yourself or someone else to do something purely for the pleasure of it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Workers Trapped in Tunnel in India Given Hot Meal  (2023/11/22) | 印度受困隧道工人吃上热饭</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/workers-trapped-in-tunnel-in-india-given-hot-meal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The 41 workers who have been trapped in a collapsed tunnel in northern India for over a week are finally getting hot meals on Tuesday. The meals of rice and lentils are sent through a newly placed steel pipe as rescuers are working on a plan to dig them out vertically.<br/>
被困在印度北部一条坍塌隧道中超过一个星期的41名工人终于在周二吃到了热饭。大米和扁豆通过一根新放置的钢管输送，救援人员正在制定垂直挖掘将他们救出的计划。</p>
<p>For the last nine days, the workers survived with dry food sent through a smaller pipe. They also received a supply of oxygen through another one.<br/>
在过去的九天里，工人们靠一根较小的管道输送的干粮生存了下来。他们还通过另一根管道获得了氧气供应。</p>
<p>Officials released a video on Tuesday showing the workers in their safety hats moving around the blocked tunnel. It also showed them communicating with rescuers on the ground through small radio equipment called walkie-talkies. Family members said they felt better after seeing images of their loved ones.<br/>
官方周二发布了一段视频，显示工人们戴着安全帽，在被堵塞的隧道附近走动。视频还显示工人们通过被称为对讲机的小型无线电设备与地面救援人员进行通信。家属们表示，看到亲人的影像后，他们感觉好多了。</p>
<p>The tunnel collapsed in Uttarakhand state. It is a mountainous area that has been difficult for the drilling machine. It broke down as rescuers attempted to dig horizontally toward the trapped workers. Movement from the machine has also caused more rocks to fall. After more rocks fell, officials suspended rescue operations for a moment.<br/>
北阿坎德邦的隧道坍塌。这是一个对钻机来说很困难的山区。当救援人员试图向被困工人水平挖掘时，它发生了故障。机器的移动也导致了更多的岩石掉落。在更多的岩石掉落后，官方暂停了救援行动。</p>
<p>Currently, rescuers are creating a path to the top of the hill from where they will dig vertically. Officials said Monday that from the vertical direction, drilling to the tunnel will take a few days and rocks could fall during the digging. Rescue teams will need to dig 103 meters downwards to reach the trapped workers, nearly double the distance.<br/>
目前，救援人员正在开辟一条通往山顶的道路，从那里他们将进行垂直挖掘。官员们周一表示，从垂直方向钻通隧道需要数天时间，在挖掘过程中可能会有岩石掉落。救援队需要向下挖掘103米才能找到被困工人，这几乎是距离的两倍。</p>
<p>Officials said they would also continue digging horizontally from the mouth of the tunnel toward the workers.<br/>
官员们表示，他们还将继续从隧道口向工人方向进行水平挖掘。</p>
<p>The workers have been trapped since November 12. A landslide may have caused part of the tunnel they were building to collapse 200 meters from the opening.<br/>
这些工人自11月12日以来一直被困。一场山体滑坡可能导致他们正在修建的隧道在距离洞口200米处坍塌。</p>
<p>Mahmood Ahmed is head of the state-run National Highways and Infrastructure Development Corporation. He said, "We might be able to get a breakthrough in the next 30-40 hours."<br/>
马哈茂德·艾哈迈德是国营国家公路和基础设施发展公司的负责人。他说：“我们可能会在接下来的30-40小时内取得突破。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Top Leadership Changes at ChatGPT Maker OpenAI  (2023/11/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/top-leadership-changes-at-chatgpt-maker-openai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) system developer OpenAI was under new leadership Monday after a series of recent changes that included the removal of former chief executive Sam Altman.</p>
<p>OpenAI said on Friday it had dismissed Altman after a "breakdown of communications," with the company's board of directors, several news services reported. Altman's "behavior and lack of <strong>transparency</strong>" had limited "the board's ability to effectively supervise the company," the <em>New York Times</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/20/technology/openai-altman-ceo-not-returning.html">reported</a> a non-public company document as saying.</p>
<p>OpenAI announced it had replaced Altman with Emmett Shear, a technology executive who formerly led live video gaming service Twitch.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Sam Altman, left, appears onstage with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at OpenAI's first developer conference, on Nov. 6, 2023, in San Francisco. Microsoft hired Altman after his sudden departure from OpenAI. (AP Photo/Barbara Ortutay, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-786c-08dbea0b4fe7_cx7_cy16_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Sam Altman, left, appears onstage with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at OpenAI's first developer conference, on Nov. 6, 2023, in San Francisco. Microsoft hired Altman after his sudden departure from OpenAI. (AP Photo/Barbara Ortutay, File)</span></div>
<p>Greg Brockman, a president and co-founder of OpenAI, along with several company leaders, quit after Altman's removal. Some wrote on X, "OpenAI is nothing without its people."</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> reported that several hundred OpenAI employees also signed a letter calling for the board to step down and Altman to return.</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft investment</strong></p>
<p>Microsoft has invested billions of dollars in OpenAI in recent years. The company has supported the AI developer's machine learning models with its knowledge and experience in building powerful computing machines. Both Microsoft chief Satya Nadella and OpenAI's Shear said they remain committed to their existing business partnership.</p>
<p>Microsoft also announced on Monday that it had hired Altman, along with Brockman, to lead a new specialized AI research team at the company.</p>
<p>Nadella wrote on X that he was "extremely excited" to bring on the former executives of OpenAI and looked "forward to getting to know" Shear and the rest of the leadership team. Altman wrote on X, "the <strong>mission</strong> continues," while Brockman promised, "We are going to build something new &amp; it will be incredible."</p>
<p>Altman became the face of a new generation of AI systems, called chatbots, that have captured a flood of media attention in recent years. Chatbots are designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. The technology is also known as "generative AI." The launch and widespread popularity of OpenAI's ChatGPT tool started a wave of development in the field.</p>
<p>In a statement on X, Shear dismissed media reports suggesting Altman's removal came because of disputes between top OpenAI leaders over the safety of the company's AI methods. Shear promised to hire an independent investigator to look into what led to Altman's ouster and offered to give a report within 30 days.</p>
<p>"It's clear that the process and communications around Sam's removal has been handled very badly, which has seriously damaged our trust," wrote Shear. He noted he also plans in the coming weeks to "reform the <strong>management</strong> and leadership team in light of recent departures into an effective force" and speak with employees, investors and users of OpenAI products.</p>
<p>Shear noted the reason behind the board removing Altman was not a "specific disagreement on safety." Media reports have suggested disputes within OpenAI's leadership about the company's stated plans to safely build AI that is "generally smarter than humans."</p>
<p>On a podcast in June, Shear said he is generally <strong>optimistic</strong> about technology. But he noted he has serious concerns about a possible path to create systems that are "a lot smarter than us" and could endanger humans.</p>
<p>Shear wrote that he had accepted the job "because I believe that OpenAI is one of the most important companies currently in existence."</p>
<p>Richard Windsor heads the British-based financial research company Radio Free Mobile. He told Reuters there had been conflicts between OpenAI's mission to build technology to help people and that of its investors, who have expected a financial return on their investments in the company.</p>
<p>"This weekend was simply the <strong>detonation</strong> of a bomb that has been waiting to go off," Windsor said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transparent </strong><em>– adj. </em>clear and easy to understand or recognize</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>an important job or task, often involving travel to somewhere</p>
<p><strong>management </strong><em>– n. </em>being in control of a company or organization</p>
<p><strong>optimistic</strong><em> – n. </em>thinking in a positive way about something</p>
<p><strong>detonate</strong><em> – v. </em>to blow up</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Drug Trials Often Do Not Include Overweight People  (2023/11/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/drug-trials-often-do-not-include-overweight-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>More than 40 percent of American adults are considered obese, or medically overweight. But the medications many of these individuals take are rarely tested in bigger bodies.</p>
<p>Obese people are currently not required to be included in drug studies. Often, they are purposefully left out.</p>
<p>This is a problem because the amount of drugs an obese person should take to be safe is unknown, says Christina Chow. She is a researcher who has sought to bring attention to the need to include obese people in drug development and testing. "There's no real <strong>emphasis</strong> for them to be studied at all," Chow told <em>The Associated Press.</em></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Tablets of ibuprofen are arranged for a photograph in New York on Thursday, Nov. 2, 2017. Even a drug as common as ibuprofen, sold as Advil, may not relieve pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows. (AP Photo/Patrick Sison, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6b82de11-6031-43a4-afd6-338dc037edb7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Tablets of ibuprofen are arranged for a photograph in New York on Thursday, Nov. 2, 2017. Even a drug as common as ibuprofen, sold as Advil, may not relieve pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows. (AP Photo/Patrick Sison, File)</span></div>
<p>Medications can work differently in people who are obese, but exactly how and at what amount is not clear. Research suggests this includes antibiotics and antifungal drugs, medications used to treat serious infections. It even includes ibuprofen, a commonly used painkiller that can be bought without a doctor's orders.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the National Institutes of Health (NIH) are the agencies that control and provide money for drug testing. At a gathering last year, FDA Commissioner Dr. Robert Califf noted a "deficit of evidence" about how medicines act in patients who are obese. The NIH now asks researchers to think about the results of not including obese people in their studies, an agency spokesperson said.</p>
<p>At a recent medical conference, Chow presented a review of more than 200 studies for new drugs in the U.S. last year. Nearly two-thirds of the studies failed to include weight or body mass index, a numerical value noting if a person is obese.</p>
<p>Historically, some populations have not been included in drug testing to avoid harm, including pregnant women and children. In the past, women, racial and ethnic minorities and aged people have also not been included.</p>
<p>Dr. Caroline Apovian is a researcher at Brigham and Women's Hospital in Boston. She is the co-author of Chow's study. Apovian told the AP there are many reasons people who are obese are not included in drug tests.</p>
<p>She noted that people who volunteer for trials are often thin and healthy and this does not effectively represent the general population. Obese individuals can have many health difficulties, and researchers often worry this will affect results of their work.</p>
<p>"Sometimes patients with obesity have many more <strong>comorbidities</strong> than others. They'll have more diabetes, more heart disease, more strokes," Apovian said.</p>
<p>But if drugs are not studied in a condition that affects 42 percent of the U.S. population, the real-world effects can be <strong>dire</strong>, experts say.</p>
<p>Some drugs remain in the body longer in obese people. That could result in harmful drug interactions if another medication is added too soon. There can also be less medication in the blood, leading to undertreatment, Apovian said.</p>
<p>Rexulti is a drug often used to treat people with <strong>schizophrenia</strong> or depression, Chow noted. Research has shown that in obese patients it may take much longer to reach the amount of Rexulti needed to be effective. As a result, many patients and their doctors may stop treatment too early or believe the drug does not work.</p>
<p>"Not treating or undertreating schizophrenia may be dangerous to themselves and the people around them," Chow said.</p>
<p>Even a drug as common as ibuprofen may not reduce pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows.</p>
<p>But without testing and clear directions, doctors won't know the amount of medicine needed for obese people, said Dr. Colleen Tenan. She is a board member of the Association of Clinical Research Professionals. Tenan said it is very hard to be a doctor and direct patients to take amounts of medication that have not been tested.</p>
<p>Change is coming, but progress is slow, said Dr. Alison Edelman. She is an obstetrician and researcher at Oregon Health &amp; Science University. She told the AP that in 2019, the FDA suggested that researchers permit obese women in studies on birth control. Even though the suggestions are not required, they have already changed how she and other researchers structure their studies.</p>
<p>"Because unless we see representation in our study population, we don't end up with treatments that work well for individuals," Edelman said.</p>
<p>Apovian, from Brigham and Women's Hospital, said patients can ask their doctors about whether the usual amount of a medication is acceptable for their weight. Even if the doctors do not know, the question could start an important discussion about the most effective treatments.</p>
<p>"This is a big issue," Apovian said. "It can be important for patients to speak up."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Jonel Aleccia reported this story for The Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>emphasis </strong>–<em>n</em>. special importance</p>
<p><strong>comorbidities - </strong><em>n</em>. two or more diseases or medical conditions in a patient</p>
<p><strong>dire </strong>– <em>adj</em>. extremely serious or urgent</p>
<p><strong>schizophrenia </strong>– <em>n</em>. a disease that affects the way the brain processes information and causes a loss of touch with reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Argentine’s President Must Deal with Inflation, Weak Economy  (2023/11/21) | 阿根廷新总统上任面临高通胀和经济低迷</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/new-argentine-s-president-must-deal-with-inflation-weak-economy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Libertarian Party politician Javier Milei has won Argentina's presidential election with 56 percent of the vote.<br/>
自由党政治家哈维尔·米莱以56%的选票赢得了阿根廷总统大选。</p>
<p>Now President-elect Milei must face the South American country's economic problems.<br/>
现在，当选总统米莱必须面对这个南美国家的经济问题。</p>
<p>Inflation has been measured at over 140 percent. The country lacks foreign currency for international trade, people who aim to save are selling the Argentine Peso, and a recession appears likely. About 40 percent of Argentines live in poverty.<br/>
通货膨胀率已超过140%。该国缺乏用于国际贸易的外汇，旨在储蓄的人们正在出售阿根廷比索，经济衰退似乎很可能发生。大约40%的阿根廷人生活在贫困之中。</p>
<p>Milei is promising to close Argentina's central bank. He also supports dollarization. Dollarization means Argentina would stop using its peso and instead use the U.S. dollar for money.<br/>
米莱承诺关闭阿根廷央行。他还支持美元化。美元化意味着阿根廷将停止使用比索，转而使用美元作为货币。</p>
<p>Milei won a second-round of voting on Sunday with about 56 percent against opponent Sergio Massa's 44 percent.<br/>
米莱在周日的第二轮投票中以56%的得票率战胜了对手塞尔吉奥·马萨的44%。</p>
<p>Now he will try to turn around the economy once he takes office on December 10. Failure could lead to the country's tenth debt default, increased poverty, and possible social unrest.<br/>
现在，他将在12月10日上任后努力扭转经济形势。失败可能导致该国第十次债务违约，加剧贫困，并可能引发社会动荡。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Inflation<br/>
通货膨胀</span></p>
<p>Argentina's high inflation rate creates huge problems in its markets and for consumers. Prices change weekly. Economic experts predict a yearly rate of 185 percent inflation by the end of the year.<br/>
阿根廷的高通胀率给其市场和消费者带来了巨大的问题。价格每周都会变化。经济专家预测，到今年年底，年通货膨胀率将达到185%。</p>
<p>To reduce inflation, Argentina's central bank has increased the interest rate to 133 percent, which pushes people to save Argentine pesos. However, this move makes it too costly to borrow money and hurts economic growth.<br/>
为了降低通货膨胀，阿根廷央行将利率提高到133%，这促使人们储蓄阿根廷比索。然而，此举使借贷成本过高，并损害了经济增长。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Peso controls<br/>
比索控制</span></p>
<p>Capital controls have harmed the value of Argentina's peso since a stock market crash there in 2019. However, different exchange rates for currencies of other nations have led to problems. For example, the U.S. dollar's official exchange rate is about 350 pesos per dollar, but news reports say it can trade for a far higher price under different controls.<br/>
自2019年阿根廷股市崩盘以来，资本管制损害了阿根廷比索的价值。然而，其他国家货币的不同汇率导致了问题。例如，美元的官方汇率约为每美元350比索，但新闻报道称，在不同的控制下，美元的交易价格可能会高得多。</p>
<p>Milei has promised to quickly undo capital controls and to dollarize the country's economy.<br/>
米莱承诺将迅速取消资本管制，并使该国经济美元化。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Central bank reserves<br/>
中央银行准备金</span></p>
<p>Argentina's central bank reserves of foreign currency are near their lowest level since 2006. A major drought affected the exports of important crops like soy, corn, and wheat, which used to bring in enough foreign exchange money.<br/>
阿根廷央行的外汇储备接近2006年以来的最低水平。一场严重的干旱影响了大豆、玉米和小麦等重要作物的出口，这些作物过去可以带来足够的外汇。</p>
<p>Low reserves threaten the country's ability to repay its debts to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and private bondholders. It will also be difficult to pay for imported goods.<br/>
低储备威胁到该国偿还国际货币基金组织和私人债券持有者债务的能力。进口商品的付款也将很困难。</p>
<p>The government has agreed on an extended currency swap with China to help enable it to carry out foreign trade. Argentina also had to delay some payments to important trade partners like neighboring Brazil.<br/>
政府已同意延长与中国的货币互换，以帮助其开展对外贸易。阿根廷还不得不推迟向邻国巴西等重要贸易伙伴支付部分款项。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Recession<br/>
经济衰退</span></p>
<p>Argentina is Latin America's third-largest economy. But it is expected to shrink by two percent this year, the central bank predicted. The recession is partly being blamed on the drought that cut corn and soy crops in half.<br/>
阿根廷是拉丁美洲第三大经济体。但央行预测，今年其经济预计将萎缩2%。经济衰退的部分原因是干旱导致玉米和大豆作物减产一半。</p>
<p>With very high inflation, poverty will likely increase as workers' pay and savings decrease.<br/>
在通货膨胀非常高的情况下，随着工人工资和储蓄的减少，贫困可能会增加。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Possible improvement<br/>
可能的改进</span></p>
<p>Argentina, rich in important grains, natural gas, and lithium, could see an increase next year as improved weather helps crops. A new gas pipeline will reduce dependence on costly imports, and demand is rising for the lithium needed for electric vehicle batteries.<br/>
阿根廷拥有丰富的重要谷物、天然气和锂，随着天气改善有助于作物生长，明年的产量可能会增加。一条新的天然气管道将减少对昂贵进口的依赖，电动汽车电池所需的锂需求正在上升。</p>
<p>Soy and corn are expected to have stronger harvests, which will bring in much-needed foreign currency.<br/>
大豆和玉米预计将有更强劲的收成，这将带来急需的外汇。</p>
<p>Eugenio Marí is head economist at Libertad y Progreso Foundation. He said agriculture and oil and gas from rocks, called shale, can help the economy. The "harvest will help bring a greater flow of income in the economy, as will the greater production of (shale oil formation)," he said.<br/>
欧赫尼奥·马里是利伯塔德·普罗格雷索基金会的首席经济学家。他说，农业和来自页岩的石油和天然气可以帮助经济发展。他说：“农业丰收将有助于为经济带来更大的收入流，页岩油产量也将增加。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Recent Study Gives New Information about Mysterious Planet  (2023/11/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/recent-study-gives-new-information-about-mysterious-planet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Eris, a very small planet similar in size to Pluto, has remained a mystery since its discovery in 2005. The American spacy agency, NASA, explored Pluto in 2015 using its spacecraft New Horizons. Eris - about 40 percent farther from the sun - has never been visited.</p>
<p>But scientists are gaining a fuller understanding of Eris and its differences with Pluto. A recent study provides details about the little planet's structure and composition based on its relationship with its moon Dysnomia.</p>
<p>Eris, researchers said recently, appears to have a rocky inside under a level of ice. Pluto also has an icy outside with rock below, but has a higher ice content and is thought to have an underground liquid ocean.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An artist's concept of the dwarf planet Eris and its moon Dysnomia is seen in this undated illustration released by NASA. The sun is the small star in the distance. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/50f48ec9-4b75-4ccf-ad7b-36fb3c395b91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An artist's concept of the dwarf planet Eris and its moon Dysnomia is seen in this undated illustration released by NASA. The sun is the small star in the distance. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>"We already knew that Eris is more rock-rich than Pluto, but what we didn't know was whether Eris had separated the rock from the ice," said study lead writer Francis Nimmo of the University of California Santa Cruz. The study appeared in the publication <em>Science Advances</em>.</p>
<p>Nimmo said Eris got hot enough at some point in history to melt, and all the rock sank to the center.</p>
<p>"The ice is not motionless but is experiencing a slow <strong>churning</strong> motion, driven by leftover heat from the inside. Most likely there is no liquid ocean inside Eris," Nimmo said.</p>
<p>Eris has a <strong>diameter </strong>of about 2,326 kilometers. Pluto's is a little bigger at about 2,370 km. Both are smaller than the Earth's moon, which has a diameter of 3,475 kilometers. Because of the greater amount of rock, which is denser than ice, Eris has about 25 percent more mass than Pluto.</p>
<p>"As I like to think of it, take Pluto and add every single asteroid in the asteroid belt, and you get Eris," said study co-writer Mike Brown, one of the three scientists who discovered Eris.</p>
<p>Eris orbits at an average of about 68 times further from the sun than Earth. It completes a full turn around the sun in 557 years.</p>
<p>The moon, Dysnomia, is about 700 kilometers in diameter and made up mostly of ice.</p>
<p>"Just like the Earth-moon system, <strong>tides </strong>on Eris slowly push Dysnomia away and slow down the <strong>spin</strong> of Eris. This process has gone to completion: Eris and Dysnomia always present the same face to the other," Nimmo said.</p>
<p>Pluto has this same system with its moon Charon, while the Earth-moon system differs.</p>
<p>"The moon always presents the same face to the Earth, but the Earth does not return the favor," Nimmo said.</p>
<p>Eris and Pluto are located beyond Neptune, the outermost of our solar system's eight bigger planets. The International Astronomical Union, which sets definitions for planetary science, recognizes five very small planets known as dwarf planets - Ceres, Haumea and Makemake, in addition to Eris and Pluto. Eris is the most massive of them.</p>
<p>The new findings fill in some questions about Eris.</p>
<p>"Each of the largest dwarf planets is unique and we should be cautious about inferring too much from what we know about Pluto," Brown said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>churn<em> </em></strong><em>– v. </em>to stir or mix something (such as water or mud) with force</p>
<p><strong>diameter </strong><em>– n.</em> the length of a straight line passing through the center of a figure or body</p>
<p><strong>tide </strong><em>– n.</em> the regular upward and downward movement of the level of the ocean</p>
<p><strong>spin </strong><em>– n.</em> to turn or cause to turn round and round</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: AI Robot Finds Way to Produce Oxygen from Water on Mars  (2023/11/20) | 中科大研究人员称其AI机器人发现火星制氧途径</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/study-ai-robot-finds-way-to-produce-oxygen-from-water-on-mars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Chinese researchers say they have built an artificial intelligence (AI) robot that can carry out chemical reactions to produce oxygen from water on Mars.<br/>
中国研究人员表示，他们已经制造了一个人工智能机器人，可以进行化学反应，从火星上的水中生成氧气。</p>
<p>The system could be another way for space travelers in the future to make much-needed oxygen on Mars. Humans visiting the Red Planet will need oxygen to support life. The gas could also be used to make rocket fuel, which is difficult to transport to space.<br/>
该系统可能是未来太空旅行者在火星上制造急需氧气的另一种方式。访问这颗红色星球的人类将需要氧气来维持生命。这种气体还可以用来制造很难运上太空的火箭燃料。</p>
<p>Scientists have already established from multiple studies that Mars contains large amounts of water. Most of the water exists in the form of ice. Developers of the new robot system in China say it can be used to release oxygen from the planet's water supply.<br/>
科学家们已经通过多项研究证实，火星含有大量的水。大部分水以冰的形式存在。中国这个新机器人系统的开发人员表示，它可以用于从火星的水资源中释放氧气。</p>
<p>Scientists at the University of Science and Technology of China in Hefei led the research. The team explored whether an AI robot could use materials found on Mars to produce catalysts to break down water and release oxygen. A catalyst is a substance that permits certain chemical reactions to happen.<br/>
位于合肥的中国科学技术大学的科学家们领导了这项研究。该团队探索了人工智能机器人是否可以利用火星上发现的材料生产催化剂来分解水和释放氧气。催化剂是一种允许某些化学反应发生的物质。</p>
<p>Experiments were carried out on meteorites that either came from Mars or contained materials similar to the Martian surface. The researchers said the "robot chemist" first used an acid and chemical mixture to separate and examine materials contained in the meteorites. It identified several different metallic elements, including iron, nickel, magnesium and aluminum.<br/>
实验是在来自火星或含有类似火星表面材料的陨石上进行的。研究人员表示，这位“机器人化学家”首先使用酸和化学混合物来分离和检查陨石中所含的物质。它鉴定出几种不同的金属元素，包括铁、镍、镁和铝。</p>
<p>The machine then worked to identify different molecules that could be produced from meteorite materials. The team said the system found more than 3.7 million possible molecule combinations.<br/>
然后，该机器开始识别陨石材料中可能产生的不同分子。该团队表示，该系统发现了370多万种可能的分子组合。</p>
<p>The robot used that data to predict which catalysts would be able to split water molecules to produce oxygen. The catalyst chosen as the best fit was able to operate at minus 37 degrees Celsius. This temperature is similar to current conditions on Mars.<br/>
该机器人利用这些数据来预测哪些催化剂能够分解水分子产生氧气。被选为最佳配合的催化剂能够在零下37摄氏度下运行。这个温度与火星的现状相似。</p>
<p>A press release announcing the experimental findings said the AI chemist was able to complete the whole process without human involvement in just two months. The release claimed such an operation "would take 2000 years for a human chemist" to finish.<br/>
宣布该实验结果的新闻稿称，这位人工智能化学家得以在仅仅两个月内完成整个过程，而无需人类参与。新闻稿称，这样的操作“需要人类化学家花费2000年才能完成”。</p>
<p>The publication Nature Synthesis reported the full results of the study.<br/>
《自然·合成》杂志报道了这项研究的全部结果。</p>
<p>The study's lead writer, Jun Jiang, told the website Space.com that as a boy, he often dreamed of being able to one day travel in space. "So when we finally saw that the catalysts made by the robot could actually produce oxygen by splitting water molecules, I felt like my dream was coming true. I even started to imagine that I, myself, will live on Mars in the future."<br/>
这项研究的主要作者江俊告诉太空网，他小时候经常梦想有一天能在太空旅行。“所以，当我们终于看到机器人制造的催化剂实际上可以通过分解水分子来产生氧气时，我觉得我的梦想成真了。我甚至开始想象我自己将来会生活在火星上。”</p>
<p>The researchers said they plan next to test whether their AI system performs well under a series of other conditions – besides temperature – found on Mars.<br/>
研究人员表示，他们计划下一步测试他们的人工智能系统在火星上发现的除温度外的一系列其他条件下是否表现良好。</p>
<p>A report explaining the study's results in Nature notes Jiang suggests that for every square meter of Martian material, his group’s system could produce nearly 60 grams of oxygen per hour. The researchers say this level of production could remove the need for future astronauts to transport oxygen from Earth. "The robot can work continuously for years," Jiang said.<br/>
《自然》杂志上发表的一份解释这项研究结果的报告特别提到，江俊称他的团队的系统用每平方米的火星物质每小时可以生成近60克的氧气。研究人员表示，这种生产水平可以消除未来宇航员从地球运输氧气的需求。江俊说：“这个机器人可以连续工作好几年。”</p>
<p>Jiang told Nature he thinks his team's robotic system could also be used to produce other useful catalysts on Mars. This could include processes for making substances to support the growth of plants that could be used to produce food for astronauts.<br/>
江俊告诉《自然》杂志，他认为他的团队的机器人系统也可以用于在火星上生成其他有用的催化剂。这可能包括生成支持植物生长的物质，这些植物可以用来为宇航员生产食物。</p>
<p>"Different chemicals can be made by this robot," Jiang said. He noted that Mars might also not be the only place where it could find other uses, suggesting the moon as another possibility.<br/>
江俊说：“这个机器人可以生成不同的化学物质。”他指出，火星可能也不是它唯一的用武之地，暗示月球是另一种可能性。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Turn Moon-like Soil Fertile for Agriculture  (2023/11/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/scientists-turn-moon-like-soil-fertile-for-agriculture.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>If humans are to establish long-term bases on the moon, they will need food resources.</p>
<p>In recent years, scientists have been taking steps toward making moon agriculture possible.</p>
<p>Researchers in China said this month that they have found a way to turn soil, that is similar to lunar soil, fertile. They found that introducing special bacteria into the soil can increase the amount of phosphorus, an important nutrient for plants.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Seedlings of the tobacco relative benth, Nicotiana benthamiana, grow in simulated lunar soil in a laboratory at the China Agricultural University in Beijing, China, in this undated handout image obtained by Reuters on November 9, 2023. (Yitong Xia/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/da9de6e8-27c9-49b6-a7b5-aa23ea6236b7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Seedlings of the tobacco relative benth, Nicotiana benthamiana, grow in simulated lunar soil in a laboratory at the China Agricultural University in Beijing, China, in this undated handout image obtained by Reuters on November 9, 2023. (Yitong Xia/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The Chinese scientists grew a plant that it is related to the tobacco plant in a laboratory in China. They used volcanic soil from the Changbai Mountains in Jilin province that is similar to moon soil, which scientists call lunar regolith. They treated the moon-like soil with three different kinds of bacteria. The researchers found that the plants raised in the bacteria-treated soil grew better than plants that grew in moon-like soil without the bacteria.</p>
<p>The researchers said the bacteria made the soil more acidic. This permitted phosphate from minerals to <strong>dissolve</strong>, making the nutrient available to the plants.</p>
<p>Researcher Xia Yitong of the China Agricultural University in Beijing was the lead writer of the study published in <em>Communications Biology. </em>Xia said the importance of these findings is that scientists may be able to use the bacteria in lunar regolith to grow crops in future <strong>greenhouses</strong> on the moon.</p>
<p>In a study published last year, researchers in the United States grew a flowering plant called Arabidopsis thaliana in small containers. Each container had a gram of moon soil collected during the NASA <strong>missions</strong> to the moon more than 50 years ago.</p>
<p>Arabidopsis, also called thale cress, is a plant widely used in scientific research. In the earlier study, Arabidopsis did grow, but not as well in soil from the moon as it did in volcanic ash from Earth, which the researchers used for comparative purposes. Their study suggests that soil from the moon could become more fertile with improvements.</p>
<p>The new research involved benth, or Nicotiana benthamiana, another plant often used in research.</p>
<p>In the most recent study, the scientists said they used volcanic material from the Changbai mountains to create soil with similar chemical and physical properties to lunar regolith.</p>
<p>The names of the three bacteria used in the study are: Bacillus mucilaginosus, Bacillus megaterium and Pseudomonas fluorescens. The researchers tested other bacteria as well, but those did not produce the same effects.</p>
<p>Xia said carrying food, oxygen, and water to people on the moon would be too costly. Xia added, "A greenhouse for plant <strong>cultivation</strong> on the moon could greatly reduce the need of Earth-moon transportation."</p>
<p>A plant cultivation system on the moon could help meet long-term food and oxygen requirements for humans on the moon, Xia added. Plants produce oxygen from carbon dioxide in the process they use to create energy, called photosynthesis.</p>
<p>Xia said other plans to grow food on the moon that do not require soil are more costly because they require materials to be transported from Earth.</p>
<p>Xia said his team's study met, "...the same goal [of plant cultivation] with much less <strong>consumption</strong> of carrying <strong>capability</strong>" compared to other plans.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dissolve </strong>– <em>v</em>. to mix with a liquid and become part of the liquid</p>
<p><strong>greenhouse </strong>– <em>n</em>. a building or part of a building that has glass walls and a glass roof and that is used for growing plants</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong>– <em>n</em>. a flight by an aircraft or spacecraft to perform a specific task</p>
<p><strong>cultivate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to grow and care for (plants)</p>
<p><strong>consumption </strong>– <em>n</em>. the use of something (such as fuel)</p>
<p><strong>capability </strong>– <em>n</em>. the ability to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Extremist Groups Spread in West Africa  (2023/11/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/extremist-groups-spread-in-west-africa.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Islamist groups linked to al-Qaida and the Islamic State have been spreading across Africa for years.</p>
<p>The groups came from the large area south of the Sahara Desert called the Sahel. They are spreading into wealthier West African coastal nations like Benin.</p>
<p>Militants once were believed to want to use coastal nations like Benin, Togo and Ghana as bases for attacks on Sahel governments. Now the militant groups are strengthening.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - French army military instructors walk on one of the main roads in Tanguietan, northern Benin, March 28, 2022. (AP Photo/ Marco Simoncelli, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-59f2-08dbe45a57e1_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - French army military instructors walk on one of the main roads in Tanguietan, northern Benin, March 28, 2022. (AP Photo/ Marco Simoncelli, File)</span></div>
<p>Benin has been the hardest hit. This year it had more than 10 times the number of violent incidents involving Islamists than Togo did. That information comes from the Armed Conflict Location &amp; Event Data Project.</p>
<p>Attacks by militant Islamists, or jihadis, against civilians in Benin went from more than 30 to about 80. The overall number of incidents involving jihadi groups rose by more than 70 percent.</p>
<p>The jihadis' activity in Benin is mostly in the north of the country. There, they try to <strong>recruit</strong> people and create division within local populations. <strong>Residents</strong> of one small town told <em>The Associated Press</em> recently that civilians can no longer move freely.</p>
<p>People in Materi live in fear because of the jihadi threat. The fighters place explosives and carry out kidnappings in the area. They aim to make people lose trust in the government. The government has put in place a curfew and a ban on gatherings.</p>
<p>"I can't sleep at night, we're not free to travel, to move," Materi resident Florence Bati said. "People are too afraid."</p>
<p>People are being displaced from their homes as attacks increase. Some people fear a humanitarian crisis.</p>
<p>In August, more than 12,000 people were displaced from their homes in the Atacora and neighboring Alibori states. That is an increase from about 5,000 in March, the United Nations said.</p>
<p>The violence is also pushing people from their farms. The U.N. estimates that tens of thousands of people could face hunger.</p>
<p>The government is trying to improve the situation by placing additional security forces along the borders and hiring more soldiers. Local people in the north say they have seen increases in soldiers but say the army is underequipped and is sometimes late when answering attacks.</p>
<p>Neighboring Burkina Faso, Niger and Mali, are being overrun by violence. The nations ousted French troops after the militaries there seized power. But Benin is still open to help from its former colonial power, which left in 1960. The French do not have a permanent base in the country. At Benin's request, however, French troops can take part in training programs with Beninese soldiers, a French military spokesman said.</p>
<p>People in the north told AP that Benin's government is also trying to hide the level of the crisis. The government has limited freedom of speech and arrested reporters who cover insecurity.</p>
<p>Local officials have said the problem does not go beyond the border with Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>"There is no terrorist, no movement, no organization, no group that has settled or tried to settle in our department," said Robert Wimbo Kassa, the mayor of Materi.</p>
<p>Benin is an agricultural nation of 13 million people. It has invested billions of dollars in culture and <strong>tourism.</strong> It is also building a $1.5 billion industrial area outside of the city of Cotonou aimed at creating 300,000 jobs by 2030.</p>
<p>The lack of information has left people in other parts of the country unaware of the security problems in the north. People in Cotonou said they did not know about the jihadi problem. They did not believe the news or said that it was a problem limited to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>Rights groups say the government is attempting to control information, while arresting people believed to be working with the jihadis. The groups say the government is pushing people into the militants' hands.</p>
<p>Bertin Assogba is with Durable and Develop Reference, a local aid and human rights group.</p>
<p>"The jihadis live with the populations, the citizens know them, but they refuse to denounce them because the government doesn't <strong>encourage</strong> people to do so," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>recruit </strong><em>— v. </em>to persuade someone to join a group or the military</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who legally lives in a particular place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tourism </strong><em>— n. </em>the industry that provides places to stay and things to do for people who travel to other places for pleasure</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>encourage </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to make someone more likely to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>International Student Numbers in US Recover  (2023/11/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/international-student-numbers-in-us-recover.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A recent report shows that the number of international students studying in the United States has returned to pre-pandemic levels.</p>
<p>Over 1 million international students attended American colleges and universities in the 2022-2023 school year. Last year's numbers nearly reached the record of 2018.</p>
<p>There are fewer Chinese students, but the largest-ever number of students from India made up the difference. Almost 269,000 Indian students came to study in the U.S. during the 2022-2023 school year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A young man at Howard University campus July 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. The number of international students has returned to pre-pandemic levels at American colleges and universities. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8fc18a28-d777-4503-a8c4-47a7258ccf49_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A young man at Howard University campus July 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. The number of international students has returned to pre-pandemic levels at American colleges and universities. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)</span></div>
<p>The number of Chinese students dropped to 290,000 -- about 90,000 fewer than before the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Many university leaders are celebrating the growth in students. Costas Chassapis is one of them. He is the Senior Vice Provost for Graduate Education at Stevens Institute of Technology in the city of Hoboken, New Jersey.</p>
<p>Chassapis said many university administrators are "<strong>euphoric</strong>" over the growth of students from India. But he warned that it will not last forever.</p>
<p>"The idea that these <strong>applications</strong> will keep on going up, I have a concern about. That's the euphoria. But I don't have a concern about the continued reasonable increase."</p>
<p>Experts say the increase is partly the result of changes made last year by President Joe Biden's administration to permit more students to qualify for work after <strong>graduating</strong>.</p>
<p>Biden's government increased the number of study programs that qualify for what is known as STEM OPT. STEM stands for science, technology, engineering and math. OPT is optional practical training. Students who complete a study program at an American university can stay in the U.S. and work for one year while on their student visa. However, STEM students are permitted to stay in the U.S. for two extra years of OPT.</p>
<p>Three years of OPT, Chassapis said, "makes them highly qualified working professionas by the time they are done."</p>
<p>A report from the U.S. State Department and the nonprofit Institute of International Education showed that many students came to the U.S. for math and computer science <strong>graduate</strong> programs.</p>
<p>Those two subjects saw a 20 percent increase compared to 2021-2022. More than half of all international students in the U.S. are working on degrees in math, science, engineering or business.</p>
<p>Chassapis said international students like Stevens because of its STEM study programs and its location – across the Hudson River from New York City. He added that well over 90 percent of the school's STEM graduates find work in their field.</p>
<p><strong>A reduction in American students</strong></p>
<p>The increase in international students comes as the number of American students attending college has dropped. A study from the National Student Clearinghouse noted the number of first-year American students decreased by 3.6 percent this year.</p>
<p><strong>In search of a different cultural experience</strong></p>
<p>Twenty-nine-year-old Dhruva Rathod of India is a working on a graduate degree in human-computer interaction at DePaul University in Chicago.</p>
<p>Rathod said he is in a group studying how to make digital, three-dimensional images called holograms more interactive with humans.</p>
<p>Rathod is from Hyderabad in southern India. He said he came to the United States because India only has space for 50 students each year in the same kind of study program. In the U.S., he estimated, there are 300 to 400 openings for graduate students.</p>
<p>Rathod said he considered trying to go to school in the U.S. as long ago as 2015, but he had to give up on the idea because it was too costly. He had degrees in mechanical engineering and industrial design. But he added: "in the back of my mind there was always an option that I should be going for a program <strong>abroad</strong> in the U.S. or Europe."</p>
<p>Rathod said he not only wanted to get into a high-quality study program, but he was looking for a "different cultural experience." He wanted to interact with people from all over the world while in the U.S.</p>
<p>It took him about two years to pass tests, send applications, be accepted, and receive a study permit, or visa.</p>
<p>Once he arrived in Chicago, he said he was happy with the mix of people. The only thing he does not like is the cold winter weather. "The state I come from," he said, "is kind of tropical and has sunny and warm weather."</p>
<p>If he stays in the U.S. after his study program, he will look for work in warmer places like California or Texas. But he considers his experience in Chicago as "an experiment with life."</p>
<p>International students make up 5.6 percent of U.S. college students. University leaders say they support the kind of "cultural experience" Rathod talked about.</p>
<p>In addition, many international students pay the full cost of college, which, universities say, lowers the cost of college for American students.</p>
<p>Rathod said it costs over $31,000 for each year of school at DePaul, including his living expenses. That is after about $6,000 in financial aid.</p>
<p>Chassapis in New Jersey said he knows the cost of attending school in the U.S. is a concern for international students. The number of applications to Stevens, though, keeps going up. In 2017, there were 7,000 graduate applications and last year the number was over 15,000.</p>
<p>Chassapis said <strong>pent-up</strong> demand is one reason for the increase last year. He noted that some countries, such as Australia, did not re-open for international students as quickly as the U.S. He called the increase "inflation" that will <strong>moderate</strong> soon.</p>
<p>But Stevens is working to remain popular. The school wants to make itself known in places like Indonesia and Vietnam.</p>
<p>It is a way "of <strong>minimizing</strong> the risk of depending on one country, which would be India," Chassapis said.</p>
<p>Vietnam sends the fifth-most students to the U.S., with nearly 22,000. Indonesia sends about 8,000.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English with additional reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>euphoric </strong><em>–adj.</em> to be very happy</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>–n.</em> documents that are part of the process of seeking to be accepted to an institution like a school, college or program</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong><em>–v.</em> to complete a course of study and a school or college</p>
<p><strong>abroad </strong><em>–adv.</em> in or to a foreign country</p>
<p><strong>pent-up </strong><em>–adj.</em> held in and not released</p>
<p><strong>moderate </strong><em>–v.</em> to go back to a more normal or average state</p>
<p><strong>minimize </strong><em>–v.</em> to reduce; to aim to make something smaller or as small as possible</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'State-of-the-Art' Is the Best of Its Time  (2023/11/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/state-of-the-art.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 November 2023</span><br/>
<p class="CxSpFirst">And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">On this program we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, and notes on usage. Sometimes we use them in short <strong>conversations</strong>.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">When it comes to learning a language, using words in conversations is not a <u>state-of-the-art</u> learning method. It is a traditional method that has stood the test of time because it works.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Humanoid robot Figure 01 is demonstrated at Figure AI's test facility in Sunnyvale, Calif., Tuesday, Oct. 3, 2023. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5cc53d5c-87ca-4ba7-8e43-707a8a0ca075_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Humanoid robot Figure 01 is demonstrated at Figure AI's test facility in Sunnyvale, Calif., Tuesday, Oct. 3, 2023. </span></div>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">So, what method would be considered state-of-the-art? Talking with an artificial intelligence robot or using some other <u>cutting edge</u> computer technology would be considered state-of-the-art. It would be the newest and best available.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">The phrase "state-of-the-art" also describes the highest level of development.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">We can use state-of-the-art to describe advancements in scientific fields. Any major scientific progress can be described as state of the art.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">State-of-the-art can also be called <u>top of the line</u> or <u>best in its class</u>.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">We can also say something is the <strong>pinnacle</strong> of technology, or the <strong>peak</strong> of performance if it is state-of-the-art. Another way to express this thought is to say it is on the <strong>forefront</strong> of technology, development or advancement in a particular field.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">Something that is state-of-the-art is innovative.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">These terms all have a similar meaning: something is the <u>latest and greatest</u>.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">Some word experts say this phrase originated in the early 20th century. It is now very commonly used in both formal and informal situations.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">Now, let's hear some of these terms used in a conversation between two friends.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: Wow, what do you have there?</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: This is my new coffee machine. It is state-of-the-art.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: I can see that! It's really impressive. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: It has an on/off setting that I can control from my phone. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: You can start your coffee from across town. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: Yes, I can! The bean container is split into four parts. So, I can have different kinds of coffee. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: That is a great innovation!</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: It gets better. This machine is the pinnacle of coffee technology! Its state-of-the-art technology can also steam milk and add a choice of five different flavorings.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: Well, enough talking! Let's have a cup of coffee! I'll take mine with caramel flavor and extra frothy milk. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: Um, yeah. That's going to have to wait for a bit. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: Why?</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>B: I don't know how to use it yet. But I will after I read this 20-page instruction book. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>A: Got it. I can help. But first ... I'll go get us some coffee. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">And that's the end of this Words and Their Stories.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>conversation –</strong>n. An informal talk between two or more people</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pinnacle –</strong>n. the highest point of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>peak –</strong>n. the top of something, such as a mountain, that comes to a sharp point</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>forefront –</strong>n. the leading position</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gerald Ford: Unelected  (2023/11/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/americas-presidents-gerald-ford.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>
VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Gerald Ford. Ford was the 38<sup>th</sup> president, but he was never elected to the position.</p>
<p>Instead, an unusual series of events brought him there.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Gerald Ford" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4155384c-7878-4a3c-86d7-50b39b761233_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Gerald Ford</span></div>
<p>Many historians have described Ford as a good man facing a difficult situation. He tried to fix a troubled economy, end United States' involvement in Vietnam, and show people that the U.S. government could continue to operate after a crisis.</p>
<p>Critics from the two main political parties had problems with Ford's efforts. And voters did not elect him president when they had the chance in 1976.</p>
<p>But he is remembered in American history for making many voters feel better about their elected officials.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>When he was born, the future president was given his father's name: Leslie Lynch King.</p>
<p>But the boy's father was abusive. His mother separated from him a short time after their son was born. She asked a court for permission to cancel their marriage. Her request was quickly approved.</p>
<p>She and the boy moved from the Midwestern state of Nebraska to Michigan. In a few years, the mother married a man named Gerald Ford. The couple had three sons together.</p>
<p>The new family was warm and loving. In time, the oldest boy officially took his step-father's name and became Gerald Rudolph Ford, Junior. He was called Jerry for short.</p>
<p>Growing up, Jerry Ford was a well-liked person and a good student. He was also a top football player. He was named the most valuable player on his team at the University of Michigan. After finishing college, he was offered work with <strong>professional</strong> football teams.</p>
<p>But Ford wanted to continue his education instead. He accepted coaching positions for the football and boxing teams at Yale University in Connecticut. In time, he attended the law school there.</p>
<p>Ford's path to politics was similar to that of other presidents during that period. He worked at a law office in his home state. He fought in World War II. He married.</p>
<p>Ford's wife was Elizabeth Bloomer. Her friends called her Betty. She had been a dancer and worked as a fashion model. The Fords went on to have four<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/the-ford-children-all-grown-up/" target="_blank"> </a>children.</p>
<p>When Gerald Ford was 35 years old, he launched his political career. The Republican Party chose him as its candidate for a seat in the U.S. House of Representatives.</p>
<p>Ford was elected to represent his home area of Grand Rapids, Michigan. But unlike many other politicians, he did not move on to the Senate or become governor of a state. Instead, he stayed in the House of Representatives for 25 years.</p>
<p>The job of congressman was, in many ways, a good choice for Ford. He was well-liked by many voters and other lawmakers. He could help different groups come to agreement. He took increasingly important positions on political issues, and in time became the top person in his party in the House.</p>
<p>Ford was a strong supporter of Republican presidents. In the 1968 election, Ford <strong>advocated</strong> for Richard Nixon. Ford liked Nixon's plans for the United States, as well as his efforts to improve relations with China and the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Both Ford and Nixon were re-elected to their positions in 1972.</p>
<p>But by then, major problems had come to light in Nixon's administration.</p>
<p><strong>An unusual path to the White House</strong></p>
<p>One problem in the early 1970s related to Nixon's vice president, Spiro Agnew. Agnew had been vice president since 1969. Five years later, officials found evidence that he had accepted money from <strong>contractors</strong>, both while Maryland's governor and as vice president.</p>
<p>In answer, Agnew resigned from the vice presidency.</p>
<p>Normally, voters elect a vice president along with a president every four years. But by <strong>coincidence</strong>, the U.S. Constitution <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/amendments/2929346.html">had recently been updated</a> to say what happens if the country needs a vice president unexpectedly. It states that the president has to nominate someone for the position. Then, a majority of lawmakers in Congress must agree.</p>
<p>So, in 1973, Nixon nominated Gerald Ford to take Agnew's position. Nixon was not especially close to Ford. But, he knew a majority of lawmakers would likely accept him as vice president.</p>
<p>They did.</p>
<p>However, Ford did not serve in the position long. In eight months, another unexpected event put him in the Oval Office.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>In August 1974, President Richard Nixon resigned from office. He was the first president to do so.</p>
<p>As a result, the vice president, Gerald Ford, became president.</p>
<p>Ford was sworn-in as president on August 9, 1974. Then he spoke to the nation on television. He said, "My fellow Americans, our long national nightmare is over." He told people, "Our Constitution works. Our great republic is a government of laws and not men."</p>
<p>The public had understandably lost a good deal of faith in government officials, and especially in Richard Nixon. Ford wanted to re-establish their trust.</p>
<p>But a few weeks after taking office, Ford used his presidential powers to pardon Nixon. The pardon meant that Nixon would never face a criminal trial or, if found guilty, punishment for his actions.</p>
<p>Ford said he believed pardoning Nixon would help Americans begin to recover from their painful experience with the former president.</p>
<p>But instead, the move angered many people. They believed that Nixon should be held <strong>responsible</strong>. They also lost some of their trust in Ford.</p>
<p>In addition to these political troubles, Ford faced other difficult issues. The American economy was struggling. His administration had to deal with unemployment, inflation and the lasting effects of an <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/energy-crisis">energy crisis</a>. The high price of oil imports came at a time when Americans were using more and more gasoline.</p>
<p>Ford took steps aimed at improving the economy. But critics said he was not <strong>consistent</strong>. Some criticized him for increasing government spending and cutting taxes; others criticized him for reducing government spending and raising taxes.</p>
<p>Ford also oversaw the withdrawal of Americans from Vietnam. An <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/last-united-states-combat-troops-withdraw-from-vietnam-this-day-in-1973/3786745.html">earlier agreement</a> had brought a ceasefire to groups in South Vietnam, North Vietnam, and Communist forces. The U.S. officially withdrew its combat troops in 1973. But the fighting restarted.</p>
<p>Ford asked Congress to approve military and humanitarian aid for the area. But U.S. lawmakers did not approve the full amount. And in time, they cut military aid.</p>
<p>In 1975, <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/south-vietnam-surrenders">Communist forces began to take control of Saigon</a>, the capital of South Vietnam.</p>
<p>Ford ordered all remaining Americans in the country to leave, along with any South Vietnamese who were connected to the United States.</p>
<p>He <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/ford-says-that-war-is-finished-for-america">said</a> that, as far as Americans were concerned, the Vietnam War was finished.</p>
<p>Americans did not appear to blame Ford for the troubling end of the country's involvement in Vietnam. And some recognized that the country's economic and energy problems had started long before he became president.</p>
<p>But, in general, Ford did not have the support of Congress. And many voters did not forgive him for pardoning Nixon.</p>
<p>In 1976, Ford officially campaigned for president for the first time.</p>
<p>He won his party's nomination in a close race against Ronald Reagan, the former governor of California.</p>
<p>But he lost the general election to the Democratic candidate, who said one of his best qualities was that he did not have experience in the federal government.</p>
<p>The argument appeared persuasive to many voters, who still did not appear to be <strong>enthusiastic</strong> about the government. In the 1976 election, nearly half of all people who were legally able to vote chose not to.</p>
<p>Ford left the presidency <strong>graciously</strong>. He said that, because he had not planned to be president, he was thankful for the unexpected opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Although Ford said he was ready to retire from politics, he continued to be active in public life. He advised others on government affairs, published books, and sat on boards and committees.</p>
<p>His wife, Betty Ford, also left a lasting effect on the public.</p>
<p>As first lady, she had spoken about her experience with breast cancer.</p>
<p>After her husband left the presidency, she also spoke openly about her battle with alcohol and drug abuse.</p>
<p>In 1982, Betty Ford co-founded the Betty Ford Center in California to help people get treatment for drug addiction.</p>
<p>She announced her husband's death in 2006. Gerald Ford died of heart disease at the age of 93.</p>
<p>By that time, most the public had accepted that one of Ford's biggest <strong>achievements</strong> was to help the country recover after Nixon resigned. President Bill Clinton gave Ford a Presidential Medal of Freedom for his efforts.</p>
<p>And even Jimmy Carter, who beat Ford in the 1976 presidential election, began his inauguration speech by thanking Ford. Carter said, "For myself and for our Nation, I want to thank my predecessor for all he has done to heal our land."</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>_________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>professional</strong> - <em>adj.</em> paid to participate in a sport or activity</p>
<p><strong>advocate</strong> - <em>v.</em> to support or argue for</p>
<p><strong>contractor</strong> - <em>n.</em> a person who is hired to perform work or to provide goods at a certain price or within a certain time</p>
<p><strong>coincidence</strong> - <em>n.</em> a situation in which events happen at the same time in a way that is not planned or expected</p>
<p><strong>responsible</strong> - <em>adj.</em> used to describe the person or thing that causes something to happen</p>
<p><strong>consistent</strong> - <em>adj.</em> always acting or behaving in the same way</p>
<p><strong>enthusiastic</strong> -<em> adj.</em> feeling or showing strong excitement about something</p>
<p><strong>graciously</strong> - <em>adv.</em> in a way that is very polite and shows respect</p>
<p><strong>achievement</strong> -<em> n.</em> something that has been done or achieved through effort : a result of hard work</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is a Chinese Movie Keeping Away Visitors to Thailand?  (2023/11/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/is-a-chinese-movie-keeping-away-visitors-to-thailand.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A Chinese movie that shows <strong>scams</strong> in Southeast Asia could be frightening visitors from China from traveling to Thailand, researchers and data suggest.</p>
<p>The movie <em>No More Bets</em> was released in August. It is about several Chinese citizens who are tricked into taking a work trip to an unnamed Southeast Asian country. Once they get there, the visitors are forced into operating illegal online investments, <strong>gambling</strong> and digital money called cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>The movie is based on a real-life problem that has increased in recent years. The same month the movie reached theaters, the U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights released a report on criminal groups. It said criminal groups have forced hundreds of thousands in Southeast Asia into illegal activities.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Chinese tourists arrive at Chiang Mai international airport in Chiang Mai province in northern Thailand, January 23, 2023. (AP Photo/Wichai Thaprieo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-36e9-08dbe4588237_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Chinese tourists arrive at Chiang Mai international airport in Chiang Mai province in northern Thailand, January 23, 2023. (AP Photo/Wichai Thaprieo)</span></div>
<p>In China, <em>No More Bets</em> made more than $500 million in the first month of its release. It became the top movie for three weeks in August. And it made the third most amount of money out of films this year.</p>
<p>At one point in the movie, <strong>abducted </strong>Chinese travelers are traveling in a small vehicle, which drives under a road sign for "Sukhumvit." It is a well-known area in the Thai capital of Bangkok.</p>
<p>Experts say the film should not have a lasting effect on Chinese <strong>tourism</strong> to Thailand. But it has raised concerns that it could frighten tourists from traveling to Bangkok.</p>
<p>Thailand is not the only country where the movie's success has caused concerns. Cambodia has banned its showing in the country because the Khmer language is shown in the film. And in Myanmar, the country's military administration said the movie hurts the country's image.</p>
<p>Vincent Zhuang used to work for the Robb Report, a publication about the good life, including travel. He still sees Thailand as a good place for Chinese tourists. But he admits bad news can easily keep away some possible visitors.</p>
<p>"I never think this will be a big problem. I have visited Thailand this year by myself. We know Southeast Asia has lots of interesting places, which fit for Chinese market," Zhuang told VOA by email.</p>
<p>The fact that <em>No More Bets </em>is based on true events means something to <strong>viewers</strong> as well, Zhuang said. There is evidence that the movie may have already had some effect on Chinese tourists visiting Thailand, as arrivals are less than expected.</p>
<p>There have been over 2.2 million mainland Chinese arrivals to Thailand this year through August, government data has found. But Thailand's tourism agency had predicted 5 million Chinese visitors by the end of 2023. That number seems unlikely to be reached by the end of next month.</p>
<p>Other reasons must be considered though.</p>
<p>China has a slowing economy. And <strong>flights</strong> to Thailand are still not at pre-pandemic levels. In addition to that, a September shooting in Bangkok killed three people, including one Chinese national. Local media reported that 60,000 Chinese tourists canceled their trips to Thailand after the shooting.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Tommy Walker reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scam </strong>– <em>n</em>. a dishonest way to make money by deceiving people</p>
<p><strong>gamble </strong>– <em>v</em>. to play a game in which you can win or lose money or possessions : to bet money or other valuable things</p>
<p><strong>abduct </strong>– <em>v</em>. to take (someone) away from a place by force</p>
<p><strong>tourism </strong>– <em>n</em>. the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>viewer </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who watches television</p>
<p><strong>flight </strong>– <em>n</em>. a journey on an airplane</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Landmines Causing More Casualties in Ukraine and Myanmar  (2023/11/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/landmines-causing-more-casualties-in-ukraine-and-myanmar.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>An international report shows increased use of landmines in Ukraine and Myanmar led to sharp rises in <strong>casualties</strong> in those countries last year.</p>
<p>International Campaign to Ban Landmines created the report, called <em>Landmine Monitor 2023</em>. The Switzerland-based group provides research and <strong>monitoring</strong> services on world land mine use. The group is a coalition of non-governmental organizations supported by the group Human Rights Watch.</p>
<p>The devices studied in the report are known as anti-personnel mines. This means the mines are built to target humans, not tanks or other military equipment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sign that reads Mines is placed on the side of the road in the village of Kamyanka, Ukraine, on Feb. 19, 2023. In this war-scarred city in Ukraine's northeast, residents scrutinize every step for land mines.(Vadim Ghirda/AP Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/50b8bd76-ab44-4b0b-9985-7f12f5a94973_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sign that reads "Mines" is placed on the side of the road in the village of Kamyanka, Ukraine, on Feb. 19, 2023. In this war-scarred city in Ukraine's northeast, residents scrutinize every step for land mines.(Vadim Ghirda/AP Photo)</span></div>
<p>The report states that Russia "used antipersonnel mines <strong>extensively</strong> in Ukraine since its all-out invasion of the country in February 2022." The document notes Russia is not part of an international treaty that bans the use of antipersonnel landmines. The anti-personnel mine ban agreement was completed in 1997. The United States is not a party to it.</p>
<p>The report also found evidence that Ukraine, which is part of the mine ban treaty, had used anti-personnel mines in and around the cities of Izium and Kharkiv. It said the mines were found as Russian forces battled Ukrainian troops in the areas.</p>
<p>The Campaign to Ban Landmines recorded 4,710 injuries and deaths in 2022 around the world. This was down from 5,544 casualties in the year before. But in Ukraine, the number of civilian casualties from landmines went from 60 in 2021 to about 600 in 2022.</p>
<p>Mark Hiznay is with Human Rights Watch and helped write the new report. He expressed concern about Russia's use of landmines in its military operations in Ukraine. Hiznay said it was the first time since the mine ban treaty was approved that a country that is not part of the treaty, Russia, had used such weapons against a treaty member, Ukraine.</p>
<p>Hiznay said Russia began using landmines in 2014 in support of pro-Russian separatist forces in the disputed Donbas area of eastern Ukraine. "Russia has made extensive use of landmines in places like Afghanistan and Chechnya," he said. Hiznay said he believed Russia had supplied 35 or 38 different countries with landmines over the years.</p>
<p>Ukraine has said it would look into accusations from a Human Rights Watch report. The report provided details of "numerous cases" of Ukrainian forces deploying banned anti-personnel mines in its war with Russia.</p>
<p>The report said 85 percent of casualties from landmines and "exploded <strong>remnants</strong> of war" last year were civilians. About half of the casualties were children. The highest number of casualties, 834, was recorded in Syria in 2022. This was followed by Ukraine with 608 casualties, and Yemen and Myanmar, which each recorded more than 500 casualties in 2022.</p>
<p>In Myanmar, Hiznay said the government has been using anti-personnel landmines since 1999. But that changed in recent years. "It is just bigger," Hiznay said. "You have more use by the government forces and more use by various non-state armed groups."</p>
<p>Currently, 164 countries have signed onto the mine ban treaty, which bars the use, storage, production, and transport of anti-personnel mines. The report said 30 states who are part of the treaty have cleared all mined areas from their territory since the treaty came into force.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>VOA's Lisa Schlein reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>casualty </strong>–n. a person who is injured or killed in an accident or war</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>– v. </em>watch something carefully and record the results</p>
<p><strong>extensive </strong><em>– adj</em>. covering or affecting a large area</p>
<p><strong>remnant </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of something that continues to exist when the rest of that thing has gone</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Source or Resource?  (2023/11/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/source-or-resource.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between the words "source" and "resource."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello friends,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Source or Resource? " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e4c4-08dbe6125020_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Source or Resource? </span></div>
<p>I'm Isac, one of your followers from Mexico. I have a question. What is the difference between "source" and "resource?" Many thanks.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for your question, Isac. Both "source" and "resource" have similar word histories. One is the root of the other. That is the reason they look similar and might be confused. But these two words are quite different! Let's consider each one.</p>
<p><strong>Source</strong></p>
<p>"Source" can be a noun or a verb.<strong> </strong>As a noun, a "source" is the origin or beginning of something.</p>
<p>For example, we often talk about the source of rivers. This source is where the river starts, like another body of water such as a lake.</p>
<p><em>The Nile River has two sources, the Blue Nile and the White Nile.</em></p>
<p>A source can also be a person or something like a book or an article that supplies information.</p>
<p><em>When you write an essay, you should write down your sources.</em></p>
<p>A source can also be what something is made of.</p>
<p><em>Red bugs called cochineal are the source for a red color used in dyes.</em></p>
<p>"Source" can also be verb. It can mean to find materials for something, or it can mean to provide something.</p>
<p><em>The cook sourced <strong>ingredients </strong>for the dish from her own garden.</em></p>
<p><em>Many jewelry companies source diamonds grown in a lab.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "resource."</p>
<p><strong>Resource</strong></p>
<p>The word "resource" is a noun. It has many meanings. A "resource" is something that can be easily found and used quickly in a time of need. It can be a supply of something, support or aid.</p>
<p>This kind of resource can include money,<strong> assets </strong>or human power in cases of emergencies.</p>
<p><em>The United States supplies military resources to its allies in times of conflict.</em></p>
<p><em>The International Red Cross and Red Crescent provide resources to people following natural disasters.</em></p>
<p>A "resource" can also be something naturally found in the Earth's environment or underneath its surface.</p>
<p><em>Natural resources include metals, oil, water and even sunlight.</em></p>
<p>And lastly, a "resource" can be something or someone that can help you get information or is an expert in a subject or industry.</p>
<p><em>Her college advisor became a great resource to her when she was choosing her field of study.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Isac.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ingredient </strong><em>– n. </em>something that enters into a compound or is a component part of any combination or mixture</p>
<p><strong>asset </strong><em>– n. </em>something that is owned and that has value</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Can a Two-State Solution Survive the Israel-Hamas Conflict?  (2023/11/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/can-a-two-state-solution-survive-the-israel-hamas-conflict.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>For 30 years, many nations around the world considered two states — one Israeli, one Palestinian — as the way to reach peace in the Middle East.</p>
<p>VOA recently spoke to several experts about ideas for peace.</p>
<p>Many people believe two states remain the only path forward even after Hamas' October 7 deadly attack and Israel's strong counter-offensive.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Smoke billows following an Israeli strike on Khan Yunis in the southern Gaza strip on Nov. 16, 2023. (Photo by SAID KHATIB / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3f46-08dbe6be5c4c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Smoke billows following an Israeli strike on Khan Yunis in the southern Gaza strip on Nov. 16, 2023. (Photo by SAID KHATIB / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Israel says Gaza's Hamas rulers killed about 1,200 people and kidnapped more than 240 in their attack. Gaza's Health Ministry, which is led by Hamas, says more than 10,000 people have died in Israel's counter-offensive.</p>
<p>However, political expert Uriel Abulof of Tel Aviv University believes the loss of life on both sides has not made peace impossible.</p>
<p>Abulof said the war has created a chance for people to "understand that this is not a conflict between the majority of Israelis and Palestinians, [both of whom] want to live in <strong>coexistence</strong>, without radical leaders," he said.</p>
<p>"On one side you have Hamas, which you have to deal with militarily, and on the other side are (Israeli Prime Minister) Benjamin Netanyahu and his coalition, which need to be dealt with politically," he told VOA.</p>
<p>Hussein Ibish is with the Arab Gulf States Institute that is based in Washington, D.C. He also believes that a permanent solution to the long conflict is possible only with a two-state model. He said it could be done in steps.</p>
<p>"Israel must finally and formally accept the Palestinian right to a state and the need for it. The <strong>construction</strong> and establishment of settlements must stop completely," he said.</p>
<p>Ibish believes Israeli settlements in the West Bank, one of the two Palestinian territories, should be halted. Israel completely withdrew from the Gaza Strip in 2005.</p>
<p>Ibish also said Palestinians must condemn the Hamas attacks of October 7 and promise to end the violence. He said the Palestinian Authority, which governs the West Bank, must be strengthened.</p>
<p><strong>Actionable plan or unrealistic?</strong></p>
<p>Other experts are doubtful. Omer Bartov is a professor of Holocaust and genocide studies at Brown University in the American state of Rhode Island.</p>
<p>Bartov believes the two-state plan is unrealistic. He said it would create an economically weak Palestine that is dependent on Israel. He added that "because there are between half-a-million and 750,000 Jewish settlers in the West Bank...their removal from the territory would mean civil war."</p>
<p>He also notes there are 2 million Palestinians who live in Israel.</p>
<p>Israel captured the West Bank, along with East Jerusalem, from Jordan in the Six-Day War of 1967. It took Gaza from Egypt in the same war but withdrew from the territory.</p>
<p>Bartov said another possibility is a <strong>confederation</strong> of Palestinian-Israeli states within the 1967 borders.</p>
<p>A confederated state, he said, would permit Palestinian refugees to return to territories their ancestors left when Israel was created. "Jerusalem could be the common capital," he said.</p>
<p>"There would be a difference between citizenship and <strong>residence</strong>," said Bartov. "Jewish settlers could continue to live in the Palestinian state but behave according to its <strong>regulations</strong>. And the Palestinians could return from exile..."</p>
<p>However, he said the single-state solution seems impossible because of the current war.</p>
<p><strong>A part for the U.S.</strong></p>
<p>Ibish of the Arab Gulf States Institute said U.S. involvement would be important to any permanent solution.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. is the only country with the influence to guarantee a two-state peace agreement. However, he said, there is a large political cost in the U.S. to put too much pressure on Israel.</p>
<p>Bartov of Brown University agreed that no plan is possible without the U.S. support on which Israel depends politically and militarily.</p>
<p>Without it, he suggested, the endless warfare would only continue.</p>
<p>Israelis and Palestinians "really don't feel there is hope. That's why the <strong>perspective</strong> must be changed — how to make these two groups of people live side by side, not apart."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Marko Protic reported this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coexistence </strong><em>— v. </em>to live together in peace</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>construction </strong>–n. the act of building structures with workers and heavy equipment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>confederation </strong><em>— n. </em>a group of people, countries, territories or organizations that are connected by rules or laws but that govern themselves</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>residence </strong><em>— n.</em><strong> </strong>to live in a place and legally have it as your home</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>regulation </strong><em>— n. </em>rules and laws</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>perspective </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>the way a person understands or thinks about something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Migrants Overwhelm Spain’s Canary Islands  (2023/11/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/migrants-overwhelm-spain-s-canary-islands.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Fifteen-year-old Guinean Moussa Camara is one of a record 32,000 migrants who have arrived in Spain's Canary Islands this year. They travel an extremely dangerous path by sea from Africa.</p>
<p>Moussa's parents are dead. He left Guinea last month. The teenager crowded into a wooden boat with 240 other migrants for the trip to the Canary Islands. The trip took 11 days. They did not have enough food or fresh water.</p>
<p>Twenty people died during the trip, the travelers said. The path they took is considered one of the most dangerous for migrants.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Several volunteers give Spanish classes to migrants outside the Las Raices Camp in La Laguna, Spain, November 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Borja Suarez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b22a-08dbe6c499b8_cx2_cy12_cw95_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Several volunteers give Spanish classes to migrants outside the Las Raices Camp in La Laguna, Spain, November 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Borja Suarez)</span></div>
<p>Camara arrived October 27 tired and hungry. He soon faced another problem: police registered him as an adult. That meant he was not permitted into a center for minors with better <strong>opportunities</strong> available.</p>
<p>Camara was with a friend also registered as an adult at an old military base in Tenerife's mountains. There, about 2,000 migrants await transfers to mainland Spain or permission to go elsewhere in Europe.</p>
<p>Registering him as an adult means that instead of receiving extra support to find housing and education until age 18, he will have to support himself alone.</p>
<p>A bone test would be required to prove his age. But Red Cross papers support Camara's claim that he is 15 and not 18 as the police said.</p>
<p>Canary Islands president Fernando Clavijo told Reuters that the registration issues show that the government is <strong>overwhelmed</strong> by the numbers of arrivals.</p>
<p>"We have neither the resources nor the calm to deal with the <strong>avalanche</strong> coming in," he added. He blamed police for processing errors as about 100 children a day came into the Canaries.</p>
<p>He said Spain's national government was not dealing with the issue. He said it has only offered to move 347 migrant children to other areas until December.</p>
<p><strong>‘Many more will come'</strong></p>
<p>Additionally, human rights organization Amnesty International said in a recent report that 12 out of 29 migrants it interviewed at adult centers in the Canaries were actually minors.</p>
<p>For children wrongly identified as adults, it is their responsibility to find an aid group to help them. Such supporters can request a bone test for a child to confirm their age. However, the process that can take months.</p>
<p>Amnesty officials said the policy is unfair. The group said such tests should only be used if there was substantial doubt about a migrant's stated age and no other proof.</p>
<p>There are eight Canary Islands. El Hierro is one of those most affected by migration. The island has a population of 9,000. More than 11,000 migrants have landed there this year.</p>
<p>In one weekend this month, 500 people arrived in El Hierro on four boats. Out of those 500, four people died and about 15 others were admitted to the island's 31-bed hospital.</p>
<p>Clavijo said the European Union should do more to fix the causes of migration from Africa. Current policy was "to mistreat them at borders" out of sight of most Europeans, he said.</p>
<p>"Do you know what a mother or father has to go through to put their six-year-old or seven-year-old son in a (small wooden boat) with 200 or more people they don't know and throw them into the open sea at night?" he asked. "These people don't do it for fun."</p>
<p>Mas Fall is 17-year-old from Senegal. He said the Canaries should expect more young migrants like him. He said the dangerous 1,450-kilometer journey to El Hierro is not going to stop people.</p>
<p>"Many more like me will come," he said in Spanish, newly learned.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>opportunity </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>overwhelm </strong><em>— v. </em>to affect very strongly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>avalanche </strong><em>— n. </em>a sudden great amount of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Happy Thanksgiving'  (2023/11/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/happy-thanksgiving.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Americans will soon celebrate Thanksgiving. The holiday involves family, friends and food.</p>
<p>A common expression Americans say to each other at this time of year is "Happy Thanksgiving."</p>
<p>In the spirit of Thanksgiving, we will pay careful attention to the first word in the expression: happy. You will learn about the history and usage of this common, five-letter adjective – and its related noun form.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-9d6b-08dbe5e7f99e_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start.</p>
<p><strong>A helpful way to learn words </strong></p>
<p>We can bring words to life by learning about their histories. In this way, words become like close friends – we know their backgrounds, their beginnings, and how they have changed over time.</p>
<p>Happy is – and always has been – a positive word.</p>
<p>The Online Etymology Dictionary says the word dates to the 1300s. At the time, it meant "lucky, favored by <strong>fortune</strong>... <strong>prosperous</strong>" as well as "very <strong>glad</strong>." Soon after, it came to mean "greatly pleased and content." The Dictionary also tells us that the majority of the words for "happy" in European languages first meant "lucky."</p>
<p>From the word happy, we also have a noun form: happiness.</p>
<p>When we compare the adjective "happy" with the noun "happiness," we find that English speakers use "happy" much more often.</p>
<p>That information comes from Google's Ngram Viewer, an online database that examines thousands of books.</p>
<p><strong>Modern usages </strong></p>
<p>We have learned a little about the history of the adjective "happy." So, how do English speakers use it in modern times?</p>
<p>Perhaps the most common usage is after linking verbs. These are verbs that link their subjects with their <strong>predicates</strong>. Adjectives are commonly used after linking verbs to describe the subject.</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer says some of the most common structures involve the verb BE. For example, you are very likely to hear or read: "I am happy," or "he was happy."</p>
<p>We also use "happy" with other kinds of linking verbs – feel, seem, and others.</p>
<p>Happy is also used with intensifiers – words that make an adjective stronger. Two of the most common, Google's Ngram Viewer tells us, are "so" and "very."</p>
<p>These intensifiers are then used along with linking verbs. Consider these examples:</p>
<p><em>You look so happy! </em></p>
<p><em>We are very happy. </em></p>
<p><em>They seem so happy. </em></p>
<p>In all of these examples, the structure is linking verb + intensifier + happy.</p>
<p>A few final words on the modern usage of "happy." You are also likely to hear the adjective "happy" used to express kind wishes around some holidays – Thanksgiving, for one.</p>
<p>In America, you will often hear statements such as this:</p>
<p><em>Happy Thanksgiving! </em></p>
<p>These statements are a kind of sentence fragment, or an incomplete sentence. There is no subject. The subject and main verb are understood between the speakers.</p>
<p>A complete sentence would be "I wish you a Happy Thanksgiving" or "I hope you have a Happy Thanksgiving."</p>
<p>We shorten these sentences because the first part is understood. That is how we arrive at "Happy Thanksgiving."</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>In today's report, we explored one word: happy. You learned about its history and common usages with linking verbs and intensifiers as well as holiday wishes.</p>
<p>You may or may not celebrate Thanksgiving where you live. But we can end this lesson by wishing you a very happy day.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fortune </strong><em>– n. </em>something that happens by chance; the good and bad things that happen to someone</p>
<p><strong>prosperous </strong><em>– adj.</em> having success usually by making a lot of money</p>
<p><strong>glad</strong> <em>– adj.</em> feeling pleasure, joy, or delight</p>
<p><strong>predicate </strong><em>– n.</em> the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Social Media Influences News Coverage  (2023/11/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/how-social-media-influences-news-coverage.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>News companies are increasingly using video and images from social media to report on the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas. This has led some media organizations to expand their efforts to identify false or misleading information.</p>
<p>Reporters covering the war in Gaza are limited by government restrictions on how they can document the conflict. But they can use a flood of video and pictures published online. Examining this material, however, can be difficult and take a lot of time. In addition, searching through a lot of <strong>graphic</strong> war images can cause emotional harm for the people looking at it.</p>
<p>So far, coverage of the war between Israel and Hamas has included live broadcasts and <strong>dash-cam</strong> video that appeared on social media. News <strong>content</strong> has also been captured by satellite equipment and security cameras placed around Israel and Gaza.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Wounded Palestinians sit in al-Shifa Hospital in Gaza City, central Gaza Strip, after arriving from al-Ahli Hospital following an explosion there, Oct. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Abed Khaled, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-292f-08dbe5f9bf1f_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Wounded Palestinians sit in al-Shifa Hospital in Gaza City, central Gaza Strip, after arriving from al-Ahli Hospital following an explosion there, Oct. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Abed Khaled, File)</span></div>
<p>Using this kind of content in news shows has become very common for major media companies, said Katie Polglase. She is a London-based investigator for CNN. Some news organizations have even created special departments to investigate whether images or videos are real or not.</p>
<p>Last week, CBS News announced the launch of <em>CBS News Confirmed</em>. This team aims to use data and technology to study online evidence in an effort to confirm true facts. Earlier this year, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/reality_check"><em>BBC Verify</em></a> was established to serve the same purpose.</p>
<p>Such newsgathering methods were not available during media coverage of some wars in the past. This meant the public usually only saw reports showing the <strong>aftermath</strong> of military battles. But in today's world, millions of people are carrying phones everywhere that can capture and quickly publish images and video online.</p>
<p>Wendy McMahon is president of CBS News and Stations. She told The Associated Press that many people watching news broadcasts today expect to be part of "a shared viewing experience." This way, they can feel like they are learning what is going on right along with the reporters and news presenters, McMahon said.</p>
<p>In order to create this kind of experience, news reporters and producers have to search through a huge online supply of image and video content. The content comes from services like X (formerly Twitter), YouTube, Instagram, Telegram and Facebook.</p>
<p>"The <strong>degree</strong> to which social media has been used is very <strong>sophisticated</strong>," said Rhona Tarrant. She helps lead the online investigative website <a class="wsw__a" href="https://storyful.com/"><em>Storyful</em></a>. "There's so much information. There's so much content," Tarrant told the AP.</p>
<p>With so much material available, news organizations must also weigh their duty to inform and present a realistic picture against concerns that graphic and violent images could harm viewers.</p>
<p>It has also become increasingly easy for people or organizations to create false images and video using artificial intelligence (AI) methods. Reuters news agency uncovered several images published online that turned out to be false, or fake. Some of the images appeared to show support for the Palestinians, while others expressed support for Israel.</p>
<p>Another case of confirmed misinformation involved a video of model Bella Hadid, who has ancestral ties to Palestine. The video seemed to show Hadid denouncing the Hamas attack in Israel that started the latest conflict.</p>
<p>But the video was fake. Someone used AI methods to change a video of Hadid accepting an award for her activism to raise awareness about Lyme Disease. The new video appeared to show Hadid condemning Hamas' attack because it was changed to make it seem like different words were coming out of her mouth.</p>
<p>Videos changed in this way to present misinformation are known as "deep fakes." In another fake video, U.S. President Joe Biden seemed to claim his administration was planning on sending American troops to assist Israel in its war against Hamas.</p>
<p>A lot of the fake images and videos come from past conflicts but are presented as new happenings. Sometimes even images from video games are published in an effort to trick users, but experts can usually identify those.</p>
<p>McMahon, from CBS, said the Israel-Hamas war has in many ways confirmed a big fear among news executives: "That news organizations would see an <strong>influx</strong> of deep fakes and misinformation at a <strong>scale</strong> that was never seen before."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Radio Free Asia reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>graphic </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely clear and detailed</p>
<p><strong>dash-cam </strong><em>– n</em>. a camera attached to the front of a vehicle in order to record what is happening around the car and on the street</p>
<p><strong>degree </strong><em>– n. </em>the amount or level of something</p>
<p><strong>sophisticated</strong><em> – adj. </em>made in a complicated or intelligent way</p>
<p><strong>influx </strong><em>– n. </em>a large number of people or things arriving at the same time</p>
<p><strong>scale </strong><em>– n. </em>the size or level of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US, China Promise to Work Together on Climate Goals  (2023/11/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/us-china-promise-to-work-together-on-climate-goals.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>United States climate diplomat John Kerry and Chinese climate negotiator Xie Zhenhua recently agreed to restart a suspended climate working group.</p>
<p>The agreement came at meetings from November 4th to the 7th held in Sunnylands, California, a joint statement released Wednesday said. The statement comes ahead of the COP28 meeting, the United Nations gathering on climate change, in Dubai starting on November 30.</p>
<p>The officials said their countries would aim for new targets for <strong>renewable </strong>energy and limits on methane gas and plastic pollution. They said some differences remain, like how to stop using nonrenewable energy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d731-08dbe617c594_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici)</span></div>
<p>"The Sunnylands statement is a timely effort of <strong>aligning</strong> the United States and China ahead of COP28," said Li Shuo. He is incoming director of the China Climate Hub at the Asia Society in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>China and the U.S. are the world's two biggest producers of pollution from gases that some scientists say are warming the atmosphere. Li described the relationship between the two countries as "a precondition for meaningful <strong>global </strong>progress." He said the Sunnylands agreement will help "<strong>stabilize</strong> the politics" ahead of the yearly United Nations climate talks in Dubai.</p>
<p>The officials said the working group will deal with areas in which the two countries can work together. They include reducing methane, increasing <strong>efficiency</strong> and the economic system in which materials are reused, called the "circular economy." Additionally, the group will exchange information on policies and technologies to reduce pollution. It will also aim to reduce forest loss and plastic pollution.</p>
<p><strong>‘Unrealistic'</strong></p>
<p>China continues to approve new power plants that burn coal to guarantee its energy security.</p>
<p>The United States and China said they support a declaration by the G20, a group of the world's largest economies, to <strong>triple</strong> global renewable energy production ability by 2030. They also agreed to speed up the use of energy resources other than coal, oil and gas.</p>
<p>The joint statement said they expect "meaningful" reductions in pollution from the power industry before 2031. But China described the idea of ending nonrenewable energy as "unrealistic."</p>
<p>The statement listed additional points of agreement. Both sides said they agreed to include methane in their 2035 climate goals. It is the first time China has made such a promise. They also promised to start "at least five" large projects in which they will work together to capture, use and store carbon by the end of 2030.</p>
<p>Li said COP28, the yearly UN climate meeting, still "has its work cut out," especially with nonrenewable energy.</p>
<p>"China also needs to consider what further <strong>ambition</strong> can be brought to COP," he added. "Stopping the approval of new coal power projects is a good next step."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>David Stanway reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>renewables </strong>– <em>adj</em>. restored or replaced by natural processes: able to be replaced by nature</p>
<p><strong>align </strong>– <em>v</em>. to join a group that is supporting or opposing something</p>
<p><strong>global </strong>– <em>adj</em>. involving the entire world</p>
<p><strong>stabilize </strong>– <em>adj</em>. in a good state or condition that is not easily changed or likely to change</p>
<p><strong>efficiency </strong>– <em>n</em>. the ability to do something or produce something without wasting materials, time, or energy</p>
<p><strong>triple </strong>– <em>v</em>. to cause (something) to become three times as great or as many</p>
<p><strong>ambition </strong>– <em>n</em>. the strong desire to reach a goal or aim</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Older, More Diverse America by the Year 2100  (2023/11/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/older-more-diverse-america-by-the-year-2100.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Census Bureau is a federal agency that researches information about America's population, housing, and economy.</p>
<p>The latest Census Bureau report shows that the U.S. population will decrease with low immigration, and older adults will outnumber children by the end of the century. The report also says that white, non-Hispanic people will account for less than 50 percent of the population.</p>
<p>The Census report offers an idea of what the nation may look like in the future. But it cannot predict unexpected events like a worldwide pandemic.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A parking lot attendant signals for people going to the Immigration Center in Miaimi to park Friday June 13, 2008. (AP Photo/J. Pat Carter, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ed45926a-5948-4202-940d-d786fd17db6d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A parking lot attendant signals for people going to the Immigration Center in Miaimi to park Friday June 13, 2008. (AP Photo/J. Pat Carter, File)</span></div>
<p>Paul Ong teaches public affairs at the University of California, Los Angeles. He said such predictions can help the U.S. prepare for change, from health care for old people to the number of schools for the young.</p>
<p>"Seeing that possibility also opens up <strong>opportunities</strong> for action," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Population changes</strong></p>
<p>Population changes caused by birth and deaths are more predictable. They may also be caused by changes in immigration policy. Because of that, the Census Bureau offers three different predictions through the year 2100 based on high, <strong>medium</strong>, and low immigration.</p>
<p>In all three situations, the U.S. will become older and more <strong>diverse</strong>. If there is low immigration, the population will decrease; medium or high immigration will increase the population.</p>
<p>By 2029, the report estimates that older people will outnumber children, with 71 million people over 65 as compared to 69 million under the age of 18. The aging of the population is important because this will mean fewer workers. An aging population also means more deaths than births.</p>
<p>The report estimates that, by 2025, the share of the U.S. population that is white and not Hispanic will be under 50 percent for the first time. Also, Asians will pass Hispanics as the largest group of immigrants by race or ethnicity.</p>
<p>Under the medium immigration estimate, the U.S. population reaches its highest total at more than 369 million people in 2081. After that, the Census Bureau predicts a slight population decline, with deaths overtaking births and immigration.</p>
<p>By the end of the 2090s, the report estimates that foreign population will make up almost 19.5 percent of people in the U.S. The number is currently at 13.9 percent.</p>
<p><strong>Immigration</strong></p>
<p>In the past, immigration was linked to economic opportunity in the U.S. Today, immigration is caused by climate change, social issues related to dictators and violence, as well as ever-changing feelings about immigrants in the country.</p>
<p>These issues make immigration more difficult to predict today, says Manuel Pastor, a professor of sociology at the University of Southern California.</p>
<p>Aliana Mediratta is a 20-year-old student at Washington University in St. Louis. She welcomes a future with a more diverse population. She believes immigration "is great for our society and our economy."</p>
<p>But that <strong>optimism</strong> is affected by issues that seem to be getting worse, including climate change and gun violence.</p>
<p>"I feel like I have to be optimistic about the future," Mediratta said. She thinks that if she believes the worst will happen, it might stop her from doing the morally right thing, even if it is hard.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Mike Schneider reported this story for the Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>opportunity</strong>–<em>n</em>. situations that make something possible</p>
<p><strong>diverse</strong>—<em>adj</em>. including different kinds of people</p>
<p><strong>medium</strong>—<em>adj</em>. in the middle</p>
<p><strong>optimism</strong>–<em>n</em>. hopefulness and confidence about the future</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Support Fishermen by Buying from Fukushima Area  (2023/11/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/japanese-support-fishermen-by-buying-from-fukushima-area.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>People from all over Japan are purchasing fish caught in the waters near the Fukushima nuclear power plant.</p>
<p>In August, the power plant started releasing treated and <strong>diluted</strong> radioactive water from holding tanks into the ocean. The power complex had suffered some equipment meltdowns after huge waves flooded the area in 2011 following an earthquake. The water release is part of the Tokyo Electric Power Company plan to shut the plant.</p>
<p>The Japanese government says the water is safe and it will be continually observed. However, some nations that once purchased a large amount of Japanese seafood are no longer doing so.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Local workers arrange the inshore fish during a morning auction at Hisanohama Port, Thursday, Oct. 19, 2023 in Iwaki, northeastern Japan. (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko, Pool, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4b4d3b8b-3700-4adb-a4a5-9e45616eefca_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Local workers arrange the inshore fish during a morning auction at Hisanohama Port, Thursday, Oct. 19, 2023 in Iwaki, northeastern Japan. (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko, Pool, File)</span></div>
<p>China has banned seafood from Japan. The regions of Hong Kong and Macau followed along.</p>
<p>Russia also announced restrictions on Japanese seafood in mid-October.</p>
<p>In South Korea, many people are concerned that the radioactive water will hurt fish close to home. Many people are no longer buying fish in South Korean markets.</p>
<p>But people in Japan are trying to support the fishing industry by buying fish and seafood.</p>
<p>At a fish store near the Onahama Port in Fukushima, one seller said he was "half surprised, half <strong>relieved</strong>." Business owner Kazuto Harada had a tank of live lobsters captured in local waters for sale. He said he has not heard any concerns about the water release.</p>
<p>Fukushima fish sellers are getting orders from all over Japan. People ask for fish called Jaban-mono, which means fish from Fukushima and nearby Ibaraki. The buyers like flounder and greeneye.</p>
<p>Almost all the fish at the market is sold by the <strong>afternoon</strong>.</p>
<p>The water release will continue for many years.</p>
<p>Futoshi Kinoshita is the executive of Foodison, which owns the Sakana Bacca group of seafood stores. He said usual testing of fishing waters is important. But, he said it is more important that people gain trust in the seafood as they watch friends and family eat the fish. "I hope the circle of <strong>confidence</strong> will expand," Kinoshita said.</p>
<p>The International Atomic Energy Agency approved the Japanese plan to release the water. The group said the water release is going well so far and said the plan will have very little effect on fish and the environment. The latest water release took place last week.</p>
<p>So far, fish prices have remained firm, or even gone up a small amount. However, one fisheries official remains watchful.</p>
<p>Katsuya Goto said any mistake could be very damaging to the public's trust that the fish is safe.</p>
<p>"The government and TEPCO have begun this <strong>despite</strong> local fishers' opposition, so we must watch and make sure they do it right," he said.</p>
<p>To support the Fukushima seafood business, the Tokyo government launched a campaign in October called "eat and cheer." It runs through the end of the year. The campaign targets customers interested in high-priced seafood such as lobster.</p>
<p>Then, in 2024, a group of well-known Kaiseki chefs in the city of Kyoto will start menus that use fish from Fukushima.</p>
<p>Yoshinori Tanaka is one of the chefs. His restaurant in Kyoto is called Toriyone. He said fish from local waters are a necessity for Japanese food. He urged the government to continue worrying about water safety. He said seeing people enjoy the Fukushima fish on their menus can also help ease "safety concerns that some people have."</p>
<p>So far, people in the seafood business are happy with all the support. Experts, however, warn that such programs will not last forever. They suggest long-term programs to keep the fishing businesses going and efforts to avoid any accidents with the water release.</p>
<p>Today there are many fewer fishermen in the Fukushima area and they bring in fewer fish than before the nuclear disaster in 2011. And with the recent interest in fish from Fukushima, some fish sellers are not able to meet demand.</p>
<p>Hiroharu Haga is the manager of Ichiyoshi, a fish store in Onahama. He said the supply of Fukushima fish is still limited.</p>
<p>"I wish I could sell more local fish," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p>And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dilute </strong><em>–v.</em> to add water to something to reduce its strength</p>
<p><strong>relieved </strong><em>–adj.</em> feeling better about something</p>
<p><strong>afternoon </strong><em>–n.</em> the time after the middle of the day and before night</p>
<p><strong>confidence </strong><em>–n.</em> a feeling that something is going well</p>
<p><strong>despite </strong><em>–prep.</em> when something happens even though there are some objections</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cheetahs Change Hunting Activity During Hot Weather  (2023/11/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/cheetahs-change-hunting-activity-during-hot-weather.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 November 2023</span><br/>
<p><strong>Cheetahs </strong>usually hunt during the day. But the fast cats change their activity to early morning and early evening hours during warmer weather, a recent study says.</p>
<p>The time change sets the creatures up for more possible conflicts with competing <strong>predators</strong> - such as lions and leopards - that often hunt at night, say the study writers. Their research was published recently in Proceedings of the Royal Society B.</p>
<p>Briana Abrahms of the University of Washington was a study co-writer. Abrahms said that changing temperatures can have an effect on "the behavior .... of large<strong> carnivore</strong> <strong>species</strong> and also the <strong>dynamics</strong> among species."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by Briana Abrahms, a female cheetah and her cub sit watchfully in front of a herd of zebra in northern Botswana on Aug. 23, 2011. (Briana Abrahms via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c2686488-0e6c-4500-9719-239e53726366_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by Briana Abrahms, a female cheetah and her cub sit watchfully in front of a herd of zebra in northern Botswana on Aug. 23, 2011. (Briana Abrahms via AP)</span></div>
<p>While cheetahs only eat fresh meat, lions and leopards will sometimes take food from smaller predators.</p>
<p>"Lions and leopards normally kill <strong>prey</strong> themselves, but if they come across a cheetah's kill, they will try to take it," said Bettina Wachter of the Cheetah Research Project at the Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research.</p>
<p>"The cheetahs will not fight the larger cats, they will just leave," said Wachter, who was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>Hunting at different times of the day is one way to reduce meetings between the different predator species that share northern Botswana's mixed grass and forest lands.</p>
<p>But the new study found that on the hottest days, when daily temperatures got to nearly 45 degrees Celsius, cheetahs became more active at night. This means cheetahs spent 16 percent more time hunting when other big cats hunt.</p>
<p>Kasim Rafiq of the University of Washington and the nonprofit Botswana Predator Conservation Trust was another co-writer of the study. Rafiq said about the shared hunting hours: "There's a greater chance for more unfriendly <strong>encounters</strong> and less food for the cheetahs."</p>
<p>For the current study, researchers placed GPS devices on 53 large carnivores — including cheetahs, lions, leopards and African wild dogs. Researchers then recorded their positions and hours of activity over eight years. They compared this data with the highest daily temperature records.</p>
<p>While seasonal differences explain most temperature changes in the time between 2011 to 2018, the scientists say the observed behavior changes offer information about the future of a warming world.</p>
<p>In future research, the scientists plan to use audio-recording devices and accelerometers — "like a Fitbit for big cats," said Rafiq. The goal is to document the number of meetings between large meat-eating animals.</p>
<p>In addition to competition with lions and leopards, cheetahs already face strong pressure from the loss of living space and conflict with humans.</p>
<p>The fastest land animal, cheetahs are the rarest big cat in Africa, with fewer than 7,000 left in the wild.</p>
<p>"These climate changes could become really critical if we look into the future — it's predicted to become much warmer in this part of Africa where cheetahs live, in Botswana, Namibia and Zambia," said Wachter of the Cheetah Research Project.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong> </strong></h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cheetah</strong> <em>– n.</em> a large wild cat that lives in Africa and Asia</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong><em>-- n. </em>an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals</p>
<p><strong>carnivore </strong>-<em>- n.</em> an animal that eats meat</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>-- n.</em> a group of related animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>dynamics </strong><em>-- n.</em> the way that two or more things behave with each other</p>
<p><strong>prey</strong><em> -- n. </em>an animal that is hunted or killed by another animal for food</p>
<p><strong>encounter</strong> <em>- n.</em> to meet someone or something without expecting to</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Boys Graduate High School at Lower Rates Than Girls  (2023/11/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/us-boys-graduate-high-school-at-lower-rates-than-girls.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. government does not require states to report graduation rates by a student's sex. But in every state reporting high school graduation rates by gender, research shows female students graduate at higher rates than male students.</p>
<p>A report from the Brookings Institution in Washington, D.C., found that, in 37 states reporting the data, more than 45,000 fewer boys than girls graduated high school in 2018.</p>
<p>Richard Reeves was one of the writers of the report from 2021. He said that about 88 percent of girls graduated on time compared with 82 percent of boys that year. A follow up study in 2021 found the difference in graduation between girls and boys in 28 states was six percent. This difference is not just limited to the United States.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Bryant West poses for a portrait on a basketball court built by NBA star Devin Booker, who went to high school here, in Moss Point, Miss., Friday, Oct. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8134-08dbe48bad78_cx8_cy11_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Bryant West poses for a portrait on a basketball court built by NBA star Devin Booker, who went to high school here, in Moss Point, Miss., Friday, Oct. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)</span></div>
<p>The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) measures education data in many countries. Among 38 member countries, including most of North America, South America and Europe, more girls graduate high school than boys.</p>
<p>In 2020, the average graduation rate for girls in OECD countries was 86 percent for girls, but 79 percent for boys. Just two countries that provided data to OECD, the Czech Republic and South Korea, had a higher graduation rate for boys.</p>
<p>OECD's Program for International Student Assessment (PISA) measures student knowledge and skills in mathematics, reading, and science at age 15. Eighty-five countries take PISA. OECD information shows that girls mostly perform better in reading than boys. Boys perform better in science and math.</p>
<p><strong>Gender gap</strong></p>
<p>The difference between graduation rates for girls and boys in the U.S. is being called a "gender gap." Few people talk about it and reports suggest that schools have done little to deal with the issue. But some schools have found ways to fight it.</p>
<p>The city of Yonkers, New York, raised graduation rates for minority boys through support such as mentoring. Former Superintendent Edwin Quezada said dealing with the difference between races in graduation rates was useful toward understanding the gender gap, which was seven percentage points in 2022.</p>
<p>Boys are sent to special education at higher rates than girls in early grades and are suspended at higher rates throughout school. That can all result in not graduating on time, Quezada said.</p>
<p>Schools in the city of Buffalo, New York, have included efforts from My Brother's Keeper. That was the program started by former President Barack Obama to help boys succeed in school. Buffalo also has provided mentoring to male students and hired more men to teach, spokesman Jeffrey Hammond said. Still, the urban school district reported a 10-percentage-point difference between female and male graduation rates in 2022 and an 11-point gap in 2021.</p>
<p>"Girls nationally succeed in school over boys because they are more apt to plan ahead (and) set academic goals," Hammond wrote in an email. He said girls receive fewer school suspensions, showing they are more likely to follow rules and receive more instruction from teachers.</p>
<p>Only 10 states that report graduation rates by gender also measure it by race. That makes it difficult to understand how race influences the graduation gender gap. But Reeves found some important differences in his latest study in the five largest states that do report graduation by race. He found that the difference between the graduation rate of Black girls and Black boys was much larger than the difference between white girls and white boys or Asian girls and Asian boys.</p>
<p>This year, Reeves left the Brookings Institution to start the American Institute for Boys and Men. It is a nonprofit group that says it aims to improve men's lives.</p>
<p><strong>Graduation gap</strong></p>
<p>The graduation gap is also linked to what observers call a success gap between students from wealthy and poor families. But the reasons for the difference between boys and girls are not clear.</p>
<p>Discussions with students, educators and researchers point to several influences. Men can earn the same pay as women with less education. But boys also are more likely to be suspended or face other forms of discipline and punishment. And they do not seek treatment as often as girls do when they face mental health problems.</p>
<p>Some boys are fine when they first drop out of school, finding jobs with good pay. But over the long term, not graduating from high school can hold men back. Studies show young men who drop out of high school earn less money over their lifetimes and are more likely to end up in jail.</p>
<p>In some cases, boys are not as interested in graduating as girls because they have not needed a high school degree to pay for rent and food, said Beth Jarosz. She is with the nonprofit research organization PRB. A man without a high school diploma often earns as much as a woman who has completed a year or two of college, she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p>
<em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press and OECD. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>graduation</strong> –n. the act of being recognized for completing a course of study at a school, college or university</p>
<strong>gender</strong> –n. the state of being male or female<p></p>
<strong>gap</strong> — n. a difference between one thing and another; a space between two things<p></p>
<strong>discipline</strong> — n. the use of rules and punishment to shape behavior to meet certain requirements<p></p>
<strong>apt</strong> — adj. likely to do something<p></p>
<strong>academic</strong> –adj. related to schools and education; not related to the real world<p></p>
<strong>rent</strong> –n. a regular payment for a place to live, which is not owned by the payee<p></p>
<strong>diploma</strong> –n. a document that<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Animals Receive Blessings in Place of Children in Aging Japan  (2023/11/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/animals-receive-blessings-in-place-of-children-in-aging-japan.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A traditional ceremony for children in Japan is growing popular for animals there as well.</p>
<p>Natsuki Aoki recently flew with her two Chihuahua dogs from the western city of Hiroshima to Tokyo, the nation's capital. She took the trip so the little dogs could receive a special <strong>blessing</strong> at the Zama Shrine, a Shinto holy place.</p>
<p>Aoki noted that few religious centers are open to animals. "I think it would be great to see more places like this," the 33-year-old said on Tuesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Animal owners pray with their dogs as they arrive for a Shichi-Go-San blessing, traditionally performed for young children to ask for health and happiness, at Zama Shrine in Zama, Kanagawa Prefecture, near Tokyo, Japan, November 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6eaf-08dbe521cc77_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Animal owners pray with their dogs as they arrive for a Shichi-Go-San blessing, traditionally performed for young children to ask for health and happiness, at Zama Shrine in Zama, Kanagawa Prefecture, near Tokyo, Japan, November 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon)</span></div>
<p>The Zama Shrine dates back to the 6th century. It is about 25 kilometers southwest of Tokyo. The religious center established a prayer area for animals in 2012. It now hosts Shichi-Go-San ceremonies where animal owners can pray for the health and happiness of their dogs and cats.</p>
<p>The ceremony, which means Seven-Five-Three in Japanese, is traditionally celebrated in mid-November for children reaching those ages. Parents dress their girls and boys in <strong>kimonos</strong> and bring them to a Shinto holy place for the ceremony.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, several people led their animals up the steps of the Inuneko Jinja, or Dog-Cat Shrine. They prayed and received a blessing from a Shinto clergy. Six Shiba Inu dogs wearing kimonos lined up for pictures at the event.</p>
<p>Japan's birth rate dropped for a seventh straight year in 2022 to a record low, while deaths increased to an all-time high.</p>
<p>"The number of children is decreasing each year, and as a result, more and more people are pouring their love into their dogs and cats," said Yoshinori Hiraga of the Zama Shrine.</p>
<p>"We want to offer the <strong>pet</strong> owners a place at Zama Shrine for them to thank the gods when their dogs and cats reach the ages of three, five, and seven," said Hiraga. The clergy estimated about 120 pets would be brought to the shrine this season.</p>
<p>Among them was Masayo Tashiro, who brought two dogs, a terrier and a Pomeranian to the center as she made offerings and prayers.</p>
<p>"They are very important to me, like my own children," said the 53-year-old caregiver. "I came here to pray that they will have a safe and healthy life with us together."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Irene Wang reported this story for Reuters. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>blessing</strong> - n. a short prayer</p>
<p><strong>kimono</strong> - n. clothing with wide sleeves that is traditionally worn on formal occasions in Japan.</p>
<p><strong>pet</strong> - n. an animal, such as a dog or cat, that people keep mainly for pleasure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Negotiators Meet in Kenya for Talks on Plastic Pollution  (2023/11/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/negotiators-meet-in-kenya-for-talks-on-plastic-pollution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A large group of international negotiators and United Nations representatives are meeting in Nairobi, Kenya this week. They aim to take the next step in creating a document that hopes to stop plastic pollution around the world.</p>
<p>The meeting is the third of an expected five gatherings of what the UN calls an intergovernmental negotiating committee, or INC, under the UN Environment Programme. The final meeting will be late in 2024. By then, the UN hopes to have an agreement that will have the force of law in countries that agree to it. The agreement would limit plastic production and provide rules on how to throw away or <strong>recycle</strong> plastic products currently in use.</p>
<p>Kenya is one of the most restrictive countries in the world. In 2017, the East African nation banned the manufacture, sale and use of plastic <strong>bags</strong> that can be used only one time. Lawbreakers can face five years in jail and fines. In 2019, Kenya banned single-use plastics such as water bottles and drinking straws from being used in parks, forests, beaches and other protected natural areas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A mound of plastic waste scavenged from various environments including river channels and dump sites sit in the yard at T3 (EPZ) Limited, a recycling and repurposing factory in Athi River town, Machakos county on November 13, 2023. (Photo by Tony KARUMBA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/38b9d005-541f-4048-8195-e02539920e29_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A mound of plastic waste scavenged from various environments including river channels and dump sites sit in the yard at T3 (EPZ) Limited, a recycling and repurposing factory in Athi River town, Machakos county on November 13, 2023. (Photo by Tony KARUMBA / AFP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Gap opens</strong></p>
<p>The most recent meeting was held in Paris in June. There was disagreement over how the rules should affect oil-producing countries. Plastic is largely made from oil. However, the June meeting ended with an agreement to create an "<strong>initial</strong> treaty <strong>text</strong>" or an outline that will be refined this week.</p>
<p>Bjorn Beeler is with the International Pollutants Elimination Network, a group of environmental nonprofits. He said the text is like a large food list at a restaurant — a menu. The job this week is for the negotiators to choose what they want for the treaty. He said the treaty will grow as those in Nairobi this week present their ideas.</p>
<p>Beeler's group hopes the document deals with bad chemicals used in the creation of plastics.</p>
<p>Kenya's president is William Ruto. He said the treaty will be the "first domino" in a move away from plastic. Dominos is a game in which the pieces connect to each other.</p>
<p>Gustavo Adolfo Meza-Cuadra Velasquez is a permanent member of the UN from Peru. He is the head of the negotiating committee. He called the need to deal with the world's plastic pollution "urgent" and said the world needs to work together "to bring a difference at the <strong>scale</strong> required."</p>
<p>Two of the nations pushing an agreement are Norway and Rwanda. The nations released a statement earlier this month calling for an "<strong>ambitious</strong>" treaty that will protect human life and the environment. They are concerned about plastic pollution, plastic waste and greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia is among the countries that have large oil industries. The nations include Iran, China, and Russia. They want the treaty to center on plastic waste control and not reduce the creation of plastic products.</p>
<p><strong>Activist concerns</strong></p>
<p>Environmental activists are concerned that those countries will not cooperate. Graham Forbes is with Greenpeace. He said it was "unfortunate" that a "handful of governments" are putting the interests of chemical companies ahead of "the health of the planet and their own citizens."</p>
<p>Another climate activist is Erik Lindebjerg of the World Wildlife Fund based in Switzerland. He said the oil producing nations want to make the treaty a "<strong>loose</strong> voluntary agreement." He wants the agreement to be "a strong treaty."</p>
<p>Negotiators for the U.S. said the treaty should have "meaningful" terms but also leave room for differences between countries so that an agreement can be reached.</p>
<p>Chemical companies and oil companies such as ExxonMobil say they want the treaty to pay more attention to the lifespan of plastics instead of banning them.</p>
<p>Chris Jahn is a spokesman for the International Council of Chemical Associations. He said the group should center its talks on "ending plastic pollution, not plastic production."</p>
<p>Karen McKee of ExxonMobil noted improvements in the ability to recycle plastics at ExxonMobil's center in Baytown, Texas.</p>
<p>The meeting ends on Sunday. The next meeting of the INC is next April in Ottawa, Canada.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recycle </strong>–v. to make something new from old parts or materials</p>
<p><strong>bag </strong>–n. a container made of thin material such as paper or plastic</p>
<p><strong>initial </strong>–adj. first or at the beginning</p>
<p><strong>text </strong>–n. writing</p>
<p><strong>scale </strong>–n. the level of size, amount, intensity or similar quality</p>
<p><strong>ambitious </strong>–adj. having the desire for power, fame or success</p>
<p><strong>loose </strong>–adj. not closely linked or attached</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Man Receives World’s First Eye Transplant  (2023/11/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/man-receives-world-s-first-eye-transplant.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A hospital in New York City recently said it had successfully performed the world's first eye transplant and the <strong>patient</strong> is doing well.</p>
<p>New York University Langone Health said it performed the surgery last May.</p>
<p>Hospital officials say it will be some time before it is known if the 46-year-old patient, Aaron James, will see with the new eye. But the transplant operation itself went well and the eye looks healthy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Dr. Eduardo D. Rodriguez prepares Aaron James of Hot Springs, Arkansas, for the world's first whole-eye transplant as part of a partial face transplant at NYU Langone in New York City, U.S. May 27, 2023. (Joe Carotta/NYU Langone Health/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c5e2225c-9ff3-46c4-8c4f-4990e998b8db_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Dr. Eduardo D. Rodriguez prepares Aaron James of Hot Springs, Arkansas, for the world's first whole-eye transplant as part of a partial face transplant at NYU Langone in New York City, U.S. May 27, 2023. (Joe Carotta/NYU Langone Health/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>James is an electrician in Hot Springs, Arkansas. He was hit in face by a live electric wire while at work in 2021. James was severely injured and came close to dying. He lost much of his face and one arm as a result. Doctors removed James' left eye because the damage caused so much pain.</p>
<p>James had many surgeries, including a face transplant. The rehabilitation was difficult. He had to breathe and eat through tubes.</p>
<p>Doctors thought his face would look better if they could give him a donor eye.</p>
<p>James says he cannot blink his eyelid and he is not able to move the eye. But he said it feels good.</p>
<p>"I'm getting <strong>sensation</strong> now," James said, adding, "You've got to start somewhere."</p>
<p>He hopes doctors will learn something from his operation that can help the next person.</p>
<p>Eye operations that include transplants of the cornea – the clear tissue in front of the eye – are common. They can treat some kinds of sight loss. But transplanting the entire eye – including its blood supply and optic nerve system – is brand new. Some people call it a "moonshot," which is an activity that has the possibility of great profit but low chance of success. Successful eye transplants could help doctors cure <strong>blindness</strong>.</p>
<p>Dr. Eduardo Rodriguez led the transplant team. He said "we're not claiming that we are going to restore sight ... but there is no doubt in my mind that we are one step closer."</p>
<p>Some surgeons did not think the operation would go well. They worried the new eye would lose its fluid and look like a dried grape, or raisin.</p>
<p>But when Rodriguez examined James' new eye last month it was full of fluid and looked as good as the one he was born with. And, there was no sign of rejection of the new organ.</p>
<p>Dr. Jeffrey Goldberg of Stanford University has long studied the idea of eye transplants. He called NYU's operation a "<strong>validation</strong>" of past transplant attempts using animals.</p>
<p>Goldberg said the next step is to regrow the eye's optic nerve. He noted that animal studies are making progress toward that effort.</p>
<p>The eye transplant was the first of its kind. But James' other major surgery was the face transplant. They are still rare. His was only the 19th performed in the U.S.</p>
<p>James' new eye came from a donor in his 30s when he died. The donor also provided three other people with needed organs.</p>
<p>James' operation took 21 hours. Doctors connected the donor's main optic nerve to the remains of James' optic nerve. The doctors also added stem cells to try to help repair the nerve.</p>
<p>James is not able to open the new eye and he wears a covering to protect it. But last month he said he felt some sensation which signaled growing nerves. He also said he could feel the doctor's touch when Rodriguez was examining his new eye.</p>
<p>Vaidehi Dedania is an NYU eye doctor who also works with James. She said the new eye appears to have special cells called photoreceptors which turn light into electrical signals. Sight happens when the optic nerve sends those signals to the brain.</p>
<p>So far, the nerve is not fully healed but doctors are surprised by its progress. Steven Galetta is NYU's head of neurology. He said only time will tell if James' nerve heals enough to permit sight.</p>
<p>The patient himself agrees.</p>
<p>"We're just taking it one day at a time," James said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>patient </strong><em>–n.</em> the person seen by a doctor</p>
<p><strong>sensation </strong><em>–n.</em> the feeling provided by nerves when you are touched</p>
<p><strong>blindness </strong><em>–n.</em> the condition of not being able to see</p>
<p><strong>validation </strong><em>–n.</em> when an action receives approval because of its result or meaning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ketamine Becomes Pain Treatment Drug with Little Research  (2023/11/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/ketamine-becomes-pain-treatment-drug-with-little-research.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>As doctors in the United States reduce their use of opioid painkillers, another drug is becoming popular: ketamine.</p>
<p>For more than 50 years, ketamine has been used as a painkiller for patients having surgery. Now, for profit medical centers and online health services have increasingly used the drug as a treatment for pain, depression, <strong>anxiety</strong> and other conditions.</p>
<p>However, some experts worry about the increased use of the drug. They say there is not much research about how well the drug works to control pain. And they worry that, like opioids, too many patients may get <strong>prescriptions</strong> for it even though the drug carries safety and abuse risks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Saline fluid runs through a tube demonstrating how ketamine would be administered to a patient at the Duke Speciality Infusion Center on Friday, Oct. 27, 2023, in Durham, N.C. (AP Photo/Matt Kelley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8fb3-08dbe0a50d35_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Saline fluid runs through a tube demonstrating how ketamine would be administered to a patient at the Duke Speciality Infusion Center on Friday, Oct. 27, 2023, in Durham, N.C. (AP Photo/Matt Kelley)</span></div>
<p><strong>Studying ketamine use</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Padma Gulur is a pain specialist at Duke University in the state of North Carolina. She is studying ketamine's use. She says there are few pain medicines that doctors can choose from. So, limited research showing possible <strong>benefits</strong> of ketamine can lead to a big increase in its use, she told <em>The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>Gulur and her co-workers followed 300 patients receiving ketamine at Duke. They found that more than one-third of them reported important side effects that required professional help. These included <strong>hallucinations</strong>, troubling thoughts, and <strong>visual</strong> problems.</p>
<p>Ketamine also did not reduce opioid prescriptions in the months following treatment, Gulur said. The research is <strong>under review</strong> for publication.</p>
<p>Ketamine targets a brain chemical messenger called glutamate, which is thought to effect both pain and depression. A small amount of ketamine can produce strong effects on the brain, including hallucination.</p>
<p>Daniel Bass lives in the state of Kentucky. He was given ketamine for pain related to a rare bone and joint disorder. He said the drug reduced his pain, but the visual effects of the drug were "<strong>horrifying</strong>."</p>
<p><strong>The business of ketamine</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved ketamine 50 years ago as a painkiller for patients having surgery. The drug can now be purchased cheaply and prescribed by most doctors and some healthcare workers, like nurses, with less training.</p>
<p>Since 2017, prescriptions for ketamine have increased more than 500 percent, Epic Research, a medical data company said. Pain was the top condition for which ketamine was prescribed, though depression has been rising quickly.</p>
<p>Dr. David Mahjoubi owns the Ketamine Healing Clinic in Los Angeles, California. He offers ketamine for several conditions including pain, alcohol <strong>addiction</strong> and anxiety. "We want patients to disassociate or feel separate from their pain, depression or anxiety," he said. "If they feel like they're just sitting in the chair the whole time, we actually give them more."</p>
<p>Doctors can buy ketamine for less than $100 per treatment. They then charge between $500 and $1,500 to inject patients with the drug.</p>
<p>Online prescriptions have also become easier since COVID-19. So, health centers face increasing competition from online health services like MindBloom and Joyous. These companies connect patients with doctors who can prescribe mixed <strong>versions</strong> of ketamine, like nasal spray and pills, remotely and send it through the mail.</p>
<p>In May, health officials tried to end the policy permitting online prescriptions of high-risk drugs like ketamine and opioids. But they agreed to extend the policy through 2024 after pushback from online health companies and doctors.</p>
<p>Dr. Samuel Wilkinson is a Yale University psychiatrist who prescribes ketamine and other drugs for depression. He says the current rules for prescribing ketamine are not very strict. "There's good things about that and not-so-good things about that," he said.</p>
<p>Last month, the FDA warned doctors and patients against mixed versions of ketamine. The agency said it does not regulate what goes into the mixtures and cannot say if they are safe. The warning followed a similar one last year about nasal spray versions of ketamine.</p>
<p>For now, experts say it is unlikely health officials will go beyond their recent warnings about mixtures of the drug.</p>
<p>Dr. Caleb Alexander is a drug safety researcher at Johns Hopkins University. He said controlling health centers is beyond the power government officials currently have.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Matthew Perrone wrote this story for the Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>anxiety</strong> <em>-n.</em> a feeling of worry or nervousness</p>
<p><strong>prescription</strong> <em>-n.</em> a signed order from a medical professional for medicine a patient can take</p>
<p><strong>benefit</strong> <em>-n.</em> a good or positive effect or result</p>
<p><strong>hallucination</strong> <em>-n.</em> a mental state of seeing something that is not really there, usually because you are ill or have taken a drug.</p>
<p><strong>visual</strong> <em>-adj. </em>related to vision, or seeing</p>
<p><strong>under review</strong> <em>-adj. </em>phrase; to be looked at and checked carefully</p>
<p><strong>horrifying</strong> <em>-adj.</em> producing strong feelings of fear or extremely upsetting</p>
<p><strong>addiction</strong> <em>-n.</em> a condition of taking harmful drugs and being unable to stop taking them</p>
<p><strong>version</strong><em> -n. </em>a particular form or type of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Body of Water in Hawaii Mysteriously Turns Bright Pink  (2023/11/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/body-of-water-in-hawaii-mysteriously-turns-bright-pink.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A small body of water in Hawaii has turned such a bright pink it could have been used as a set for the movie <em>Barbie</em>. But the unusual color-changing event has some experts concerned.</p>
<p>Scientists say extreme dry weather, or drought, may be the reason for the color. For now, they are warning people not to enter the body of water, called a pond, and not drink from it.</p>
<p>Workers at the Kealia Pond National Wildlife Refuge on the island of Maui have been watching the pink water since October 30.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Nov. 8, 2023, photo provided by Leslie Diamond shows the pond at the Kealia Pond National Wildlife Refuge on Maui, Hawaii, that turned pink on Oct. 30, 2023. (Leslie Diamond via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/095674c0-183d-4b1f-8f41-f0c4ad8a202f_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This Nov. 8, 2023, photo provided by Leslie Diamond shows the pond at the Kealia Pond National Wildlife Refuge on Maui, Hawaii, that turned pink on Oct. 30, 2023. (Leslie Diamond via AP)</span></div>
<p>"I just got a report from somebody that was walking on the <strong>beach</strong>, and they called me up like, ‘There's something <strong>weird</strong> going on over here,'" said Bret Wolfe, who leads the refuge.</p>
<p>Wolfe was concerned the bright pink could be a sign of an event called an algae bloom. An algae bloom happens when simple plants called algae grow out of control and cause harmful effects on humans and animals.</p>
<p>But lab tests found harmful algae was not causing the color. So investigators started looking at an organism called halobacteria as a possible cause.</p>
<p>Halobacteria are a kind of single-celled organism that do well in bodies of water with high levels of salt. The amount of salt inside the Kealia Pond area is currently greater than 70 parts per thousand, which is twice the amount of salt in seawater. Wolfe said the lab will need to perform DNA research in an effort to identify the organism.</p>
<p>Researchers feel that Maui's drought is likely adding to the situation. Normally, another body of water called Waikapu Stream feeds into the pond and raises water levels there. But Wolfe said that has not happened in a long time.</p>
<p>When it rains, water flows from Waikapu Stream into the pond and then into the wider area that is now pink. This reduces the amount of salt and could possibly change the water's color.</p>
<p>"That might be what makes it go away," Wolfe said.</p>
<p>None of the workers, or even some volunteers who have been around for 70 years, have seen the pond this color before. It has been through periods of drought and has had high amounts of salt before. But Wolfe is not sure why the color has changed now.</p>
<p>Visitors have come to the area after photos of the pink pond appeared on social media.</p>
<p>Wolfe said he would love to have visitors come to learn about local aims to protect nature. He joked, "But no, they're here to see the pink water."</p>
<p>He understands everyone's interest. "If that's what gets them there, it's OK," he said.</p>
<p>The wildlife area is a wetland that protects <strong>endangered</strong> birds like the Hawaiian stilt and the Hawaiian coot. It also protects birds that are traveling to warmer areas in the winter.</p>
<p>The water does not appear to be harming the birds, Wolfe said.</p>
<p>As a protected area, people are not supposed to enter the pond or let their animals in the water. But officials have issued a special warning for people not to enter the water or eat any fish caught there.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Audrey McAvoy reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>beach </strong>– <em>n</em>. an area covered with sand or small rocks that is next to an ocean or lake</p>
<p><strong>weird </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very unusual or strange</p>
<p><strong>endangered </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used to describe a type of animal or plant that has become very rare and that could die out completely</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Space Telescope Aims to Show 'Dark Universe'  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/new-space-telescope-aims-to-show-dark-universe.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>European astronomers released the first images from the new Euclid space telescope last week.</p>
<p>The European Space Agency (ESA) and the U.S. space agency, NASA, designed Euclid to study dark matter and dark energy. Scientists think those hidden forms of matter and energy make up 95 percent of the universe.</p>
<p>ESA is leading the six-year mission with NASA as a partner. ESA said the images were the most detailed of their kind. They show the telescope's ability to observe billions of <strong>galaxies</strong> up to 10 billion <strong>light years</strong> away.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An artist's concept shows the Euclid space telescope, built by the European Space Agency (ESA) in operation, in this undated handout image. (European Space Agency (ESA)/Handout via REUTERS )" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6487-08dbe1614f2d_cx11_cy3_cw79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An artist's concept shows the Euclid space telescope, built by the European Space Agency (ESA) in operation, in this undated handout image. (European Space Agency (ESA)/Handout via REUTERS )</span></div>
<p>The images covered four areas of the sky. They include 1,000 galaxies belonging to the Perseus <strong>cluster</strong> of galaxies 240 million light years away. In the background, the image shows more than 100,000 galaxies, ESA said.</p>
<p>The cluster is called the Perseus cluster because it appears in the star group, or constellation, Perseus.</p>
<p>Scientists believe such large structures like the Perseus cluster could only have formed if dark matter exists.</p>
<p>ESA's science director Carole Mundell said, "We think we understand only 5 percent of the universe: that's the matter that we can see."</p>
<p>"The rest of the universe we call dark," she continued, "because it doesn't produce light...But we know its effect because we see the effect on visible matter."</p>
<p>One sign of dark matter's hidden force is that galaxies <strong>rotate </strong>more quickly than scientists expect.</p>
<p>Mundell said it seems to have the effect of pulling together some of the largest structures in the universe, like groups of galaxies.</p>
<p><strong>Dark energy is a new mystery</strong></p>
<p>In the 1990s, scientists largely established the existence of dark matter after studying exploding stars called supernovas. That work resulted in a 2011 Nobel Prize shared between three U.S.-born scientists.</p>
<p>Looking at images from the earlier Hubble Space Telescope, scientists came to believe that the universe was not only expanding but that it was expanding faster and faster. That surprising discovery relied on a new concept: dark energy.</p>
<p><strong>A new galaxy map</strong></p>
<p>Euclid has been in a period of testing since its launch. Now it will start taking the images to make a 3D, or three-dimensional, map covering about a third of the sky. Scientists will use that map to look for small differences caused by the dark universe. Scientists hope the new understanding of dark energy and matter will help us learn about how galaxies formed, and why they are found across the universe.</p>
<p>Mundell said, "The purpose of the Euclid mission is really to start to <strong>probe</strong> that dark <strong>sector</strong> of the universe in ways that we've been unable to presently with current ground and space missions."</p>
<p>She added that the Perseus cluster is a good example of this huge gathering of mass. "We think there's lots of dark matter in that cluster and pulling these galaxies together."</p>
<p>A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launched Euclid from Florida in July.</p>
<p>The mission is expected to last six years. However, ESA hopes that Euclid will continue another six months if there is enough fuel to keep it in orbit around the sun. Euclid is orbiting the sun about 1.5 million kilometers away from Earth at "Lagrange Point Two," or L2. That is a place where the gravity of the sun, moon and Earth are balanced. A spacecraft can stay there, using less fuel. NASA's James Webb Space Telescope is also at L2, but it is not in danger of crashing into Euclid.</p>
<p>Other images released by ESA included an unusual galaxy with no exact form. Another was a <strong>spiral</strong> galaxy, sometimes called the "Hidden Galaxy," which looks much like our home galaxy, the Milky Way.</p>
<p>Speaking of the Perseus cluster, Mundell said, "You'll also see lots of background galaxies there as well, which is <strong>phenomenal</strong>. I think I spotted a new one there last night."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>This story was reported by Tim Hepher and Steve Gorman for Reuters. Jill Robbins adapted it for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>galaxy</strong> – <em>n</em>. a very large group of stars and planets that extends over many billions of light years</p>
<p><strong>light year</strong> – <em>n</em>. the distance that light travels in one year; 9.46 trillion kilometers</p>
<p><strong>cluster </strong>– <em>n</em>. a group of objects gathered close together</p>
<p><strong>rotate</strong> – <em>v</em>. to turn with a circular movement</p>
<p><strong>probe</strong> – <em>v</em>. to ask questions or try to discover facts about something</p>
<p><strong>sector</strong> – <em>n</em>. a part of something or area</p>
<p><strong>spiral</strong> –<em> adj</em>. a shape that winds around and around, with each curve above or outside the previous one</p>
<p><strong>phenomenal</strong> – <em>adj</em>. unusually great or good</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Extreme Dry Condition in Syria, Iraq, Iran due to Climate Change  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/study-extreme-dry-condition-in-syria-iraq-iran-due-to-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A three-year <strong>drought</strong> has left millions of people in Syria, Iraq, and Iran with little water. A new study says it would not have happened without human-caused climate change.<br/>
The west Asian drought started in July 2020. The new study found that it is mostly because hotter-than-normal temperatures are evaporating the little rainfall that fell.</p>
<p>The study is by a team of international climate scientists at World Weather Attribution, a group that researches extreme weather events.</p>
<p>Friederike Otto, an Imperial College of London climate scientist, is the lead writer of the study. She said that without the world warming 1.2 degrees Celsius since the mid-19th century, "it would not be a drought at all."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq on September 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c81130a-45bf-401c-9ab1-c37cc02f3c11_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq on September 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)</span></div>
<p>It is a case of climate change unnaturally intensifying naturally dry conditions into a <strong>humanitarian</strong> crisis that has left people without food, water, and housing, the study says.</p>
<p>Other scientists have yet to confirm if the methods used in this study are correct, in a process called peer review. But it follows scientifically correct methods to look for the signs of climate change.<br/>
The team looked at temperature, rainfall, and <strong>moisture</strong> levels. And they compared what happened in the last three years to many different computer models of the conditions in a world without human-caused climate change.</p>
<p>"Human-caused <strong>global</strong> climate change is already making life considerably harder for tens of millions of people in West Asia," said study co-writer Mohammed Rahimi. He is a professor of climate studies at Semnan University in Iran. "With every degree of warming Syria, Iraq and Iran will become even harder places to live."</p>
<p>Computer models did not find any considerable signs of climate change in the reduced rainfall, which was low but not too rare, Otto said. But evaporation of water in lakes, rivers, wetlands, and soil "was much higher than it would have been" without climate change-increased temperatures, she said.</p>
<p>The study writers found that the drought conditions in Syria and Iraq are 25 times more likely because of climate change, and in Iran, 16 times more likely.</p>
<p>Kelly Smith of the U.S. National Drought Mitigation Center in Nebraska, who was not part of the study, said the research made sense.</p>
<p>Drought is not unusual to the Middle East area. And conflict, including Syria's civil war, makes the area even more likely to have a drought because of weakened water systems, said study co-writer Rana El Hajj. She is with the Red Cross Red Crescent Climate Center in Lebanon.</p>
<p>"This is already touching the limits of what some people are able to <strong>adapt</strong> to," Otto said. She said as long as we keep burning fuels that affect climate change and give out new permits to explore new oil and gas fields, these kinds of events will only get worse. She added that this will continue to destroy lives and keep food prices high.</p>
<p>She said, "And this is not just a problem for some parts of the world, but really a problem for everyone."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em><br/>
________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought</strong> – <em>n</em>. a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<strong>humanitarian</strong> – <em>adj</em>. describing an event or situation that causes or involves a lot of human suffering, especially one that requires aid to be provided to a large number of people<p></p>
<strong>moisture</strong> – <em>n</em>. a small amount of a liquid (such as water) that makes something wet or moist<p></p>
<strong>global</strong> – <em>adj</em>. involving the entire world<p></p>
<strong>adapt</strong> – <em>v</em>. to change your behavior so that it is easier to live in a particular place or situation<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Investigation Finds AI Tool Does Not Improve Adoptions  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/investigation-finds-ai-tool-does-not-improve-adoptions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thea Ramirez is a former social worker. She now runs a non-profit organization called Adoption-Share.</p>
<p>Ramirez has partnered with a computer scientist and developed an artificial intelligence (AI) tool called Family-Match. The tool aims to help social service agencies find the best parents to<strong> adopt</strong> children in foster care. Foster care is a temporary service provided by American states for children who cannot live with their families.</p>
<p>Gian Gonzaga is the computer scientist who worked with Ramirez. He had previously directed the technology behind eharmony, a popular online <strong>dating</strong> tool.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this photo provided by the New York Stock Exchange, Adoption-Share founder and CEO Thea Ramirez, center, and supporters ring the opening bell at the New York Stock Exchange in New York on Aug. 20, 2013. (NYSE via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0295-08dbe1441cfe_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this photo provided by the New York Stock Exchange, Adoption-Share founder and CEO Thea Ramirez, center, and supporters ring the opening bell at the New York Stock Exchange in New York on Aug. 20, 2013. (NYSE via AP)</span></div>
<p>"I was more <strong>excited</strong> about the project than anything I've heard for all of my career," Gonzaga said in a Family-Match video posted to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>Limited results </strong></p>
<p>But an <em>Associated Press</em> (AP) investigation found that Family-Match produced limited results in the states where it has been used. The results raise questions about the ability of AI to solve complex human problems.</p>
<p>Social workers in Florida, Georgia and Virginia told AP that Family-Match was not useful. It often led them to unwilling families.</p>
<p>Virginia and Georgia stopped using Family-Match after a trial experiment. They said the tool only produced one or two adoptions a year.</p>
<p>Tennessee planned to use Family-Match but was unable because of technical issues.</p>
<p>Florida agencies, however, reported a better experience with the tool. They said Family-Match assisted them in finding more possible parents to adopt foster children.</p>
<p>Ramirez did not agree to answer questions from the AP. But she said in an email that "Family-Match is a valuable tool and helpful to users actively using it to support their <strong>recruitment</strong> + <strong>matching</strong> efforts."</p>
<p>And Gonzaga asked all questions to be sent to Ramirez.</p>
<p><strong>Gaining support </strong></p>
<p>Ramirez lives in Georgia, where her nonprofit organization Adoption-Share is based. She got her start by building a website to match possible parents with mothers who wanted their babies to be adopted.</p>
<p>Ramirez marketed her website to organizations that are against abortion. Abortion is a medical process that ends a woman's pregnancy. These organizations seek to provide care for pregnant women to persuade them to give birth.</p>
<p>After the state of Georgia stopped using Family-Match, Ramirez met with the state governor's office and appeared at a legislative hearing to request $250,000 to pay for a statewide expansion.</p>
<p>In July, Georgia decided to use Family-Match again and signed a new agreement. Adoption-Share is permitting Georgia to use Family-Match for free, a state official said.</p>
<p>Family-Match was also used for free in Florida at first. Thanks to a grant, or financial award, from the former head of the company that makes Patrón tequila, a kind of alcohol. The grant ended in October 2022. They would not explain why the grant ended, but said they were very pleased with the work done with Adoption-Share.</p>
<p>After the grant ended, Florida state government paid for Family-Match. Last month, the state awarded Adoption-Share a $350,000 contract.</p>
<p>In May, Family-Match was chosen to receive money from an event supported by Adam Wainwright. At the time, Wainwright was a professional baseball player with the St. Louis Cardinals in the state of Missouri.</p>
<p>This year, Adoption-Share won a contract with the Florida Department of Health to build a tool centered on children with the most severe medical needs and disabilities.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Sally Ho and Garance Burke reported this story for Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>to adopt</strong>–<em>v</em>. to legally make someone else's child your own</p>
<p><strong>match</strong>—<em>v</em>. go well together</p>
<p><strong>recruitment</strong>–<em>n</em>. finding the person you need</p>
<p><strong>dating</strong>—<em>n</em>. a the process of finding a love interest</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Evidence of Crash with Another Planet under Earth's Surface  (2023/11/13) | 科学家发现地球与其它行星相撞的证据藏在地球深处</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/scientists-evidence-of-crash-with-another-planet-under-earth-s-surface.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Scientists have recognized since the 1970s that there are two large, mysterious blobs in the deepest part of Earth's mantle.<br/>
科学家们自20世纪70年代以来就认识到，在地幔最深处有两个巨大而神秘的斑块。</p>
<p>One of the masses is under Africa and the other under the South Pacific Ocean.<br/>
其中一块在非洲海底，另一块在南太平洋海底。</p>
<p>Recent research suggests these masses, which are denser than the material surrounding them, might be from a huge crash early in our planet's history.<br/>
最近的研究表明，这些比周围物质密度更大的斑块可能来自地球历史早期的一次巨大撞击。</p>
<p>Researchers recently said the crash between Earth and a Mars-sized object called Theia might have created the moon.<br/>
研究人员最近表示，地球和火星大小的物体忒伊亚之间的碰撞可能创造出了月球。</p>
<p>Recent research suggests the event happened more than 4.46 billion years ago. Pieces of Theia, however, might have remained inside Earth, sinking to an area just above our planet's hot core of iron and nickel.<br/>
最近的研究表明，这一事件发生在44.6亿年前。然而，忒伊亚的碎片可能留在地球内部，下沉到地球炽热的铁镍核心上方的区域。</p>
<p>Researchers created computer simulations to study their theory of the event. Based on these simulations, they proposed that most of Theia was absorbed into Earth, forming the two masses, while the remaining pieces formed the moon.<br/>
研究人员创建了计算机模拟实验来研究他们对这一事件的理论。基于这些模拟实验，他们提出忒伊亚的大部分被地球吸收，形成了两个斑块，而其余的部分形成了月球。</p>
<p>Qian Yuan is a geophysicist at Caltech and the lead writer of the study that was published recently in Nature.<br/>
钱源（音译）是加州理工学院的地球物理学家，也是最近发表在《自然》杂志上的这项研究的主要作者。</p>
<p>"The bottoms of these blobs are 2,900 kilometers below our feet. The two blobs are about 2 percent of Earth's mass. They were detected by seismology as seismic waves travel slower within these two regions compared to the surrounding mantle. Each of the blobs are twice the mass of the whole moon. So, the blobs are massive," Yuan said.<br/>
钱源说：“这些斑块的底部在我们脚下2900公里处。这两个斑块的质量约为地球质量的2%。它们是由地震学探测到的，因为地震波在这两个区域内的传播速度比周围的地幔慢。每个斑块的质量都是整个月球的两倍。所以，这些斑块非常巨大。”</p>
<p>If the theory is correct, these two masses would represent evidence of the possible moon-forming crash.<br/>
如果理论是正确的，这两个斑块将代表可能形成月球的碰撞的证据。</p>
<p>Caltech professor and study co-writer Paul Asimow said there has not been agreement "on whether we can find evidence for this event not just in the moon but also in some observable property of the modern Earth."<br/>
加州理工学院教授、该研究的合著者保罗·阿西莫表示，“我们是否不仅能在月球上，还能在现代地球的一些可观测特性中找到这一事件的证据，目前还没有达成一致。”</p>
<p>The two masses, Asimow added, are the biggest difference "in Earth structure from a simple layered planet."<br/>
阿西莫补充道，这两个斑块是“地球结构与简单层状行星的最大区别”。</p>
<p>Study co-writer Hongping Deng of the Chinese Academy of Sciences' Shanghai Astronomical Observatory said, "It is incredible because we can uncover relics of another planet - Theia - if we dig deep enough in Earth's mantle."<br/>
该研究的合著者、中国科学院上海天文台的邓宏平说：“这太不可思议了，因为如果我们在地幔中挖得足够深，我们就可以发现另一颗行星忒伊亚的遗迹。”</p>
<p>The increased density of the masses is believed to come from their high level of iron. Moon rocks also contain high iron levels. So, the researchers think it would make sense if they came from the same place: Theia.<br/>
这些斑块密度的增加被认为是由于他们的高铁含量。月球岩石中的铁含量也很高。因此，研究人员认为，如果它们来自同一个地方：忒伊亚，这就讲得通了。</p>
<p>The moon, which orbits Earth at an average distance of about 385,000 km, has a diameter of about 3,475 km, a bit more than a quarter of our planet's diameter.<br/>
月球绕地球运行的平均距离约为38.5万公里，其直径约为3475公里，略大于地球直径的四分之一。</p>
<p>Asimow said that, if the theory is correct, some volcanic rocks that reach Earth's surface might provide pieces of Theia.<br/>
阿西莫说，如果这个理论是正确的，一些到达地球表面的火山岩可能会提供忒伊亚的碎片。</p>
<p>"If our model is correct, the blobs should have isotopes - trace elements - that are similar to the lunar mantle rocks, which can be tested in future lunar missions," Yuan said.<br/>
钱源说：“如果我们的模型是正确的，这些斑块应该具有与月球地幔相似的同位素——微量元素，这可以在未来的月球任务中进行测试。”</p>
<p>Gaining a greater understanding of the hypothesized giant impact could provide information concerning the evolution of Earth and other rocky planets in our solar system and beyond it.<br/>
对假设的巨大撞击获得更多的了解，可以提供有关地球和太阳系内外其它岩态行星演化的信息。</p>
<p>"Earth is still the only confirmed habitable planet, and we do not know why," Yuan said. He added the crash set the early conditions for Earth's development and said: "Studying its consequences may help us to figure out why Earth is different than other rocky planets."<br/>
钱源说：“地球仍然是唯一一颗被确认适合居住的行星，我们不知道为什么。”他补充说这次撞击为地球的发展创造了早期条件，并表示：“研究其后果可能有助于我们弄清楚为什么地球与其他岩石行星有所不同。”</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>English Professor Uses Board Games to Teach Climate Change  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/english-professor-uses-board-games-to-teach-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Isidora Djukic is a biology and chemistry student at John Carroll University near Cleveland, Ohio.</p>
<p>She never thought that one day she would be in a classroom where an English teacher asked her to play a board game in order to learn about climate change.</p>
<p>Djukic is taking a biology class called Climate Change: Global Impacts. At the same time, she is taking an English class called Environmental Literature. Her university requires students to take two connected classes that examine the same subject in different ways.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Debra Rosenthal, top right, worked to bring a climate change board game to her university class." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-f2e6-08dbe16c014d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Debra Rosenthal, top right, worked to bring a climate change board game to her university class.</span></div>
<p>"They both <strong>focus</strong> on global climate change," Djukic said.</p>
<p>Debra Rosenthal is the English professor. At first, Djukic said she was uncertain about Rosenthal's board game idea.</p>
<p>"I was just like: ‘this is interesting. Like we're going to learn about climate change by playing a board game? Like how fun is this actually going to be, and how much are we actually going to take away from it?'"</p>
<p>Rosenthal thought her students would gain a greater understanding about how their own ideas and experiences affect climate change. After testing the games with some adults, she got permission to buy six copies of a game called Solutions. The goal is to pick cards and then add them to the game board in a way that helps reduce global temperatures.</p>
<p><strong>There is no winner</strong></p>
<p>Students do not compete against each other. They work together to choose the best plan of action. The game is different from board games such as Monopoly, where the goal is to win.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said she hoped the games would give students a chance to talk about climate change in a new way. During most classes, students read material and then discuss their ideas.</p>
<p>"But by playing the games, it's a way to be social, to <strong>engage</strong> in <strong>conversation</strong>. There has to be a lot of energy around the table. It's very <strong>collaborative</strong>. And in the game that I chose to play, they really were able to work together and try to come up with a solution so that the planet was not destroyed."</p>
<p>During the class, she said, students laughed, disagreed and had to call for votes as a way to decide how to move forward in the game.</p>
<p>Djukic said it was a "way to have fun...while also learning about such a serious subject."</p>
<p>Both Djukic and Rosenthal said many American high school students do not get a lot of information about climate change. The connected classes at John Carroll permit students to, as Djukic said, "take a <strong>deeper dive</strong> into the science of global climate change...This linked <strong>pair</strong> really opened my eyes."</p>
<p><strong>Climate educator approves</strong></p>
<p>A comment like that would make Megan Yousef smile. She is a climate educator based in Cleveland. She was one of the people who took part in Rosenthal's test event.</p>
<p>Yousef uses a game called Climate Fresk to teach people about the UN's Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Climate Fresk is also a French nonprofit organization.</p>
<p>Yousef said the Fresk is a kind of climate card game that helps people "<strong>get their heads around the problem</strong>. The IPCC report is 4000 pages long."</p>
<p>Yousef's game has 42 cards. She said groups that play the game have a discussion when they place the cards on a long table.</p>
<p>If a player has a card called "destruction of the water cycle," they might start a discussion about severe storms, such as the one that flooded parts of California in August.</p>
<p>The goal of a Fresk is not to win, Yousef said. The idea is for players to learn about climate change and feel "energized" to help their communities.</p>
<p>"It's very powerful for people to come together and <strong>acknowledge</strong> that other people care about this problem too," she said.</p>
<p><strong>World games</strong></p>
<p>Yousef said the Fresk game started in France and 1 million people have played it. She said she knows people like her, in Australia, India, China, Thailand and many European nations, have worked to bring the game to students. They have brought it to health events and financial groups.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said some of the games she looked at would be good for students who are already good at English. One, called Carbonique, is made for French speakers, so her students would need to use a translation program to turn the words into English.</p>
<p>The games are global, Djukic said. That is because she and her classmates said they were able to see how one player's decision about agriculture affected another player on the other side of the world.</p>
<p>She said the games showed her that "in the game of climate change and the climate crisis, no individual wins."</p>
<p>"It's either we all suffer from this, or we all somehow collaborate to work our way out of this and <strong>turn the clock back</strong> on climate change."</p>
<p>In Djukic's opinon, that is a good lesson for any student to learn.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>–v.</em> to place one's attention on something</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong><em>–v.</em> to get involved in an issue or activity</p>
<p><strong>conversation </strong><em>–n.</em> an informal talk involving two or more people</p>
<p><strong>collaborative </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving two or more people working together toward a goal</p>
<p><strong>deep dive </strong>–<em>idiom (informal)</em> to more closely examine something</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>–n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>get one's head around (something) </strong><em>–idiomatic expression (informal)</em> to make an attempt to understand something</p>
<p><strong>acknowledge </strong><em>–v.</em> to show that you know something exists</p>
<p><strong>turn the clock back </strong><em>–idiomatic expression (informal)</em> to bring back the past or make things like they were in the past</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are You 'Sitting Pretty'?  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/are-you-sitting-pretty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about being in a good place. And we begin with an old American pop singer.</p>
<p>When Karen Carpenter sings about being "<u>on top of the world</u>," she describes feeling happy, thankful, and being in a great place.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In its window seat aboard the Royal Albatross, a luxury tall ship, this cat is definitely sitting pretty, August 13, 2023. (Photo by Roslan RAHMAN / AFP) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4570b7b6-3b96-474d-8e6c-6c1dfee751a5_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In its window seat aboard the Royal Albatross, a luxury tall ship, this cat is definitely sitting pretty, August 13, 2023. (Photo by Roslan RAHMAN / AFP) </span></div>
<p>If you are <u>on top of the world</u>, you are in a great position. You are happy with life.</p>
<p>When things are really <u>going your way</u>, you can also say you are <u>sitting pretty</u>. <u>Sitting pretty</u>, means you are in a very favorable situation. You love your job. You have a nice home. And your finances are in good order.</p>
<p>This expression can also mean you are in a good, safe, and secure position. You don't need to worry about the future.</p>
<p>It can also mean you are in an <strong>advantageous</strong> position. For example, when a friend of mine bought property, she found herself in a price war with another buyer. However, she was <u>sitting pretty</u> for several reasons: She offered a big <strong>down payment</strong> and a <strong>flexible</strong> move-in date.</p>
<p>This example shows how <u>sitting pretty</u> can have a little difference in meaning than other similar expressions. It can suggest that you are in a good situation, especially when others are not.</p>
<p>As we said, we have other expressions that mean about the same thing as being <u>on top the world</u> and <u>sitting pretty</u>. If you are in a great situation and have a favorable position, you can also say you <u>have it made</u>. You are <u>ahead of the game</u>. You are <u>going places</u>.</p>
<p>If you feel great about your life and just feel great in general, you might say you are <u>on cloud nine</u>. The origin of this cloud expression comes from the field of agriculture. The <em>Farmer's Almanac</em> explains that scientists wanted to make recording cloud observations easier. So, they rated clouds zero to nine. Zero represented the lowest clouds and nine the highest clouds.</p>
<p>Word experts say this is where the expression <u>to be on cloud nine</u> probably comes from. If you're <u>on cloud nine</u> you'll be very high up which may also describe your feelings.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories.</em></p>
<p>When it comes to your English studies, we hope all of you are <u>on cloud nine.</u></p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advantageous</strong> – <em>adj</em>. helpful; favorable</p>
<p><strong>down payment</strong> – <em>n</em>. a part of the full price paid at the time of purchase or delivery with the balance to be paid later</p>
<p><strong>flexible</strong> – <em>adj</em>. readily changed or changing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Richard Nixon: Resigned  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/americas-presidents-richard-nixon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Richard Nixon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Richard Nixon" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2eb280cd-88b6-472d-a3df-bad2748565c7_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Richard Nixon</span></div>
<p>Nixon is well-known to many Americans for one reason: he was the only president to resign from the position. Facing possible legal action by Congress, Nixon left office early in his second term.</p>
<p>Nixon's early political career was marked by success. He also had some noteworthy achievements during his White House years. And he <strong>attained</strong> his goal of moving the government in a more conservative direction.</p>
<p>In his later years, Nixon and his supporters tried to reclaim his place as an expert on international affairs. But for many Americans, the name "Nixon" remains linked to distrust of national leaders, abuse of power, and political wrongdoing.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Richard Nixon had a difficult early life. He was the second of five sons in a <strong>Quaker </strong>family. His parents owned a lemon ranch in California, near the city of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>But the family struggled financially. And two of Richard's brothers died – one as a small child, and one as a young adult.</p>
<p>In time, his parent's business failed, and the Nixons moved to a nearby town. The parents and children all worked at a filling station that sold fuel and other products.</p>
<p>Despite the many hours he worked at the store, Richard Nixon was a top student in high school. He was offered financial aid to attend Harvard University, but the family needed even more money to send him there.</p>
<p>Instead, he attended a local college, where he became the student body president, joined a debate team, acted in the theater, and played football. Nixon went on to law school at Duke University in North Carolina.</p>
<p>Even with his <strong>impressive</strong> background, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/document-deep-dive-richard-nixons-application-join-fbi-180950329/">he did not get the jobs he sought at the Federal Bureau of Investigation – the FBI</a> – or top law offices. So he returned the California town where he grew up and began working as a lawyer.</p>
<p>There, he married another actor at the community theater. Her name was Thelma Ryan, but she was called Pat. The Nixons went on to have two daughters, Tricia and Julie.</p>
<p>In 1942, Nixon accepted a job with the federal government in Washington, DC. He did not stay in the position long. After the United States entered World War II, Nixon joined the Navy. He served as an officer in the Pacific.</p>
<p>When he returned to the U.S., Republican Party officials asked him to be a candidate for Congress. Nixon agreed. He won two terms in the House of Representatives, and then a seat in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>Two years later, Dwight Eisenhower, the Republican presidential candidate, asked Nixon to be his vice president. The two men won in an electoral <strong>landslide</strong>, and in 1953 Nixon took office as vice president. He was only 40 years old, the second-youngest vice president in U.S. history.</p>
<p><strong>Early political career</strong></p>
<p>Nixon's early political career is remembered for several reasons. One is how quickly he rose to high government office.</p>
<p>Another is for his part in the Alger Hiss case in the late 1940s. Hiss was a top official in the State Department. He was accused of being a Communist in the 1930s and 1940s, and of passing information about the U.S. government to Soviet spies. Hiss denied the accusations.</p>
<p>The case was big news in the United States. It showed the clash between people who believed Hiss was falsely accused as a way to discredit liberal policies, and people who believed the government was protecting communist sympathizers.</p>
<p>Nixon was in the second group. He was part of the investigation against Hiss and pushed for his <strong>indictment</strong>. Nixon's efforts succeeded, and Hiss went to jail for almost four years. Later, <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.nytimes.com/books/97/03/09/reviews/hiss-obit.html">Nixon said</a> that the case was one of the reasons for his rise to power.</p>
<p>Nixon also earned national attention with an event that has become known as the Checkers speech. It happened in 1952, when Nixon was running for vice president.</p>
<p>Some reporters accused Nixon of corruption. They said he was accepting money and gifts from wealthy donors in exchange for his political support.</p>
<p>Nixon went on television to deny the claims personally. At the time, Americans were not used to seeing politicians speaking directly to the public. Yet Nixon spoke informally and emotionally, from what appeared to be a home.</p>
<p>He explained his family's finances. He said he did not accept campaign donations for personal benefit.</p>
<p>But, he added, there was one exception. A supporter had once given the Nixon children a black and white dog they called Checkers. Nixon said he refused to return his daughters' pet.</p>
<p>The public – and Republican Party officials – loved the speech. Nixon appeared warm and likable. Middle-class Americans especially said they could relate to him. Most forgot the claims against him. And Nixon's political career was saved. During the following eight years, he served as vice president in the Eisenhower administration.</p>
<p>But then Nixon's luck turned. In 1960, Nixon lost as a presidential candidate to John F. Kennedy. He blamed, in part, the media. Then in 1962, he lost his efforts to be governor of California.</p>
<p>Nixon said he was retiring from politics. He famously told reporters, "You won't have Nixon to kick around anymore."</p>
<p>Yet seven years later, he was in the White House. It was one of the most memorable <strong>comebacks</strong> in U.S. political history.</p>
<p>
<strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When Nixon took office in 1969, some Americans thought the country was in crisis.</p>
<p>The economy was not doing well. Race riots had been <strong>erupting</strong> in big cities. Many people were still trying to recover from the violence of a year earlier. Civil rights leader Martin Luther King Junior and President John F. Kennedy's brother Robert had both been shot and killed.</p>
<p>Pollution of the environment was becoming a major political issue. Women were pressing for equal rights. And many Americans continued to protest American involvement in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Nixon took action. During his first years in office, he supported reforms and rules to improve the economy; protect the environment; increase workplace and other opportunities for women; support civil rights; and, in his words, bring "peace with honor" in Vietnam.</p>
<p>But, for the most part, Nixon did not have the support of Congress to enact legislation. So he expanded the power of the presidency to carry out his goals.</p>
<p>He is remembered especially for three foreign policy moves. In 1972, he visited China, with which the U.S. government had tense relations since the Chinese Communist Party took power.</p>
<p>As the Alger Hiss case showed, Nixon was strongly anti-communist. But he made establishing diplomatic relations between the two sides possible again.</p>
<p>He also visited the Soviet Union, and was the first U.S. president to visit Moscow. Nixon and the Soviet leader, Leonid Brezhnev, agreed to limit the growth of nuclear arms. Their actions helped ease tensions at a time when U.S. officials were worried about the expansion of communism.</p>
<p>And Nixon did succeed in reaching a peace agreement with North Vietnamese leaders. In 1973, American troops slowly began to leave the country, although fighting there continued.</p>
<p>Nixon's foreign policy achievements helped him in the 1972 election campaign. His first presidential election had been extremely close; the second he won by one of the widest electoral vote margins in U.S. history.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Watergate</strong></p>
<p>Even though he was popular with voters, Nixon had been concerned about his political future. Nixon was so worried that, before the election, he created a secret team to prevent any damaging information from reaching the media. Later, its job expanded to include investigating any information that might hurt his public image.</p>
<p>About five months before Election Day, five men broke into the opposition party's headquarters at the Watergate, a hotel and office complex, in Washington, DC.</p>
<p>The team had already stolen copies of secret campaign documents. Now, in the middle of the night, the men were trying to add listening equipment to the telephones – in other words, spy on the opposition.</p>
<p>But a security guard became suspicious and called the police. The men were caught and arrested.</p>
<p>When the story came to light, Nixon publicly denied that any White House officials were involved in the crime.</p>
<p>But in time, the public learned that Nixon was lying. In fact, he assisted with payments to the men who were arrested.</p>
<p>And he tried to use the Central Intelligence Agency to block an FBI investigation of the crime. Nixon knew that the Watergate break-in was only part of the illegal or questionable acts he could be held responsible for.</p>
<p>Later, people connected with Nixon told investigators that the president had taped everything that happened in his office.</p>
<p>Investigators demanded the tapes. They would prove how much Nixon knew about the illegal operations.</p>
<p>The president refused. He<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/watergate-special-prosecutor-dismissed" target="_blank"> dismissed</a> the lead investigator. Two other Justice Department officials resigned in protest.</p>
<p>A new investigator was appointed, and the U.S. Supreme Court ordered Nixon to release the tapes.</p>
<p>At the same time, the House of Representatives voted to remove Nixon from office. They charged him with <strong>obstructing</strong> justice, abusing his power, covering up a crime, and violating the Constitution.</p>
<p>Finally, Nixon released the tapes. But before the Senate could hold a trial – in which the president would almost certainly be found guilty – Richard Nixon resigned. He left the White House the following day.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Nixon lived for 20 more years. He wrote a number of books, traveled, spent time with his family, and offered foreign policy advice to other leaders. He continued to deny that he had done anything criminal as president; instead, Nixon said he had made bad decisions.</p>
<p>And he did not go to trial. The next president, Gerald Ford, used his power to pardon Nixon "for all offenses against the United States."</p>
<p>But Nixon's image was permanently damaged. Most people found evidence in the tapes that Nixon knew about a related series of crimes commonly known as "Watergate."</p>
<p>They also found that some of his public statements were dishonest. They said he made them to forward his own political goals, not to further the public good.</p>
<p>As a result, Nixon's place in U.S. history is generally thought to be a troubled one. To be sure, he made a number of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nytimes.com/roomfordebate/2012/06/13/did-any-good-come-of-watergate/nixon-had-some-successes-before-his-disgrace"><strong>positive</strong> accomplishments</a>, both within the U.S. and internationally.</p>
<p>But his presidency left the country shaken. When Ford replaced him as president, he said to Americans, "Our long national <strong>nightmare</strong> is over."</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>______________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>attain</strong> -<em> v.</em> accomplish or achieve</p>
<p><strong>Quaker</strong> - <em>n.</em> a member of a Christian religious group whose members dress simply, are against violence, and have meetings without any special ceremony or priests</p>
<p><strong>impressive</strong> - <em>adj.</em> deserving attention, admiration, or respect : making a good impression</p>
<p><strong>landslide</strong> - <em>n.</em> an election in which the winner gets a much greater number of votes than the loser</p>
<p><strong>indictment</strong> - <em>n. </em>an official written statement charging a person with a crime</p>
<p><strong>comeback</strong> - <em>n. </em> a new effort to win or succeed after being close to defeat or failure</p>
<p><strong>erupt </strong>- <em>v.</em> to happen or begin suddenly or violently</p>
<p><strong>obstructing</strong> - <em>v. </em> to slow or block the movement, progress, or action of</p>
<p><strong>positive</strong> - <em>adj. </em> good or useful</p>
<p><strong>nightmare</strong> -<em> n. </em> a very bad or frightening experience or situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Swiss-designed Technology Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/swiss-designed-technology-helps-parkinson-s-patient-walk-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>
Marc Gauthier has Parkinson's disease.</p>
<p>The disease affects his nervous system, weakens his muscles and causes his arms and legs to shake.</p>
<p>The 63-year-old Gauthier had not been able to leave his home for some time. But that was until he became the first person to receive a new Swiss-designed medical device that greatly improved his ability to walk.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Swiss-Designed Tech Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b10a-08dbdfd771af_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Swiss-Designed Tech Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again</span></div>
<p>Gauthier received a medical device called a neuroprosthetic at Switzerland's Lausanne University Hospital (CHUV). Part of the device, called an electrode field, is placed against part of the <strong>nervous system</strong> which runs in the back called the spinal cord. Another part of the device, found under his skin below the stomach, uses electricity to <strong>stimulate</strong> the spinal cord to start up his leg muscles. It is called an electrical impulse generator.</p>
<p>"It changed my life because I'm now independent," said Gauthier, a native of the French city of Bordeaux, as he sat with his doctors at CHUV. "I can leave my home, run <strong>errands</strong>. I even go on foot."</p>
<p>The number of people affected by Parkinson's disease has doubled over the past 25 years, the World Health Organization found. Worldwide estimates showed that more than 8.5 million people suffered from the disease in 2019.<br/>
Grégoire Courtine is one of the doctors leading the project. He said the electrical <strong>pulses</strong> delivered to Gauthier's spinal cord has permitted him to walk the way he would have without the disease.</p>
<p>"We strongly believe that many individuals could benefit from this <strong>therapy</strong>," said Courtine. He is a professor at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), the University of Lausanne and CHUV.</p>
<p>The study was published in Nature Medicine recently. The findings by Courtine's team at the NeuroRestore research center suggest the technology could be used more widely in patients with more progressed Parkinson's. Many of those with more progressed, or advanced, Parkinson's have severe problems with being able to move.</p>
<p>Dave Marver is chief executive officer of Onward Medical, which designed the medical device. He said that the device was similar to another device called an implantable defibrillator and those used to deal with pain. But he added the device is special in the way that it targets the spinal cord.</p>
<p>"For the health care system, it will look and feel <strong>familiar</strong>, but it will offer therapy that doesn't exist today," he said.</p>
<p>Courtine's team plans to carry out continuing researching and test the device on six new patients next year.</p>
<p>Jocelyne Bloch is the doctor who performed the operation on Gauthier and co-director of NeuroRestore. She said with this therapy, if people can gain belief in themselves and can go out, socialize and do more things, it is a big plus "... in their daily activities and quality of life."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Cecile Mantovani and Gabrielle Tétrault-Farber reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em><br/>
______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nervous system</strong> – <em>n</em>. the system of nerves in your body that sends messages for controlling movement and feeling between the brain and the other parts of the body</p>
<strong>stimulate</strong> – <em>v</em>. to make (something) more active<p></p>
<strong>errand</strong> – <em>n</em>. a short journey that you take to do or get something<p></p>
<strong>pulses</strong> – <em>n</em>. a brief increase in an amount of electricity, light, or sound<p></p>
<strong>therapy</strong> – <em>n</em>. the treatment of physical or mental illnesses<p></p>
<strong>familiar</strong> – <em>adj</em>. frequently seen, heard, or experienced<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Strikes End, But When Will Hollywood Get Back to Normal?  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/strikes-end-but-when-will-hollywood-get-back-to-normal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hollywood actors reached a deal to end their four-month strike this week. But it could take some time before you will see your favorite actors on television and in movies again.</p>
<p>The deal permits many actors, writers and technicians to get back to work. And movies and television programs, such as <em>Deadpool</em>, <em>Abbott Elementary,</em> and <em>The Last of Us</em>, are one step closer to returning.</p>
<p>The writers and technicians approved their contract in September after a four-month strike. The actors still have to vote on the deal that their labor <strong>union</strong> leaders made on Wednesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="People cheer after striking actors union reach tentative agreement with Hollywood studios to end the strike in Los Angeles, California,. U.S. November 8, 2023. (REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ba4af444-a3db-4747-898a-4cba806edaef_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">People cheer after striking actors union reach tentative agreement with Hollywood studios to end the strike in Los Angeles, California,. U.S. November 8, 2023. (REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni)</span></div>
<p>The full terms are not yet available, but leaders say the new deal includes pay increases of more than $1 billion. It also covers concerns such as pay for streaming video and protections for the use of artificial intelligence in creating video and audio.</p>
<p>The group that represents producers of television and movies said the agreement "represents a new <strong>paradigm</strong>."</p>
<p>The head of the actor's group is Duncan Crabtree-Ireland. He said the agreement is one "our members can be proud of."</p>
<p>Here are some questions and answers:</p>
<p><strong>What programs will start filming first?</strong></p>
<p>The strike put an immediate stop to the filming of <em>Deadpool 3 </em>with Ryan Reynolds and Hugh Jackman. That movie and a new <em>Gladiator</em> will likely get back to production first.</p>
<p>In television, shows such as <em>Abbott Elementary</em>, <em>The White Lotus</em> and <em>Yellowjackets</em> should start filming again. Writers for those programs started working when their strike ended earlier this year.</p>
<p>However, some films and television programs recently announced delays. They include <em>Yellowstone</em> with Kevin Costner and the next <em>Mission Impossible</em> movie.</p>
<p><strong>What other changes are coming?</strong></p>
<p>Actors who were on strike did not sit for <strong>interviews</strong> or talk about their movies and television shows. As a result, some movies did not get a lot of marketing.</p>
<p>One of the actors in the new movie <em>Killers of the Flower Moon</em> is Lily Gladstone. She will now be able to talk about her big <strong>role</strong> in the movie which also includes Leonardo DiCaprio.</p>
<p><strong>What about the big awards shows?</strong></p>
<p>The Academy Awards, better known as the Oscars, will be back on as usual in 2024. The awards shows will run from mid-January through early March.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any more strikes ahead?</strong></p>
<p>Some strikes could come in the future. Actors who work on video games have approved a strike if negotiations do not work out.</p>
<p>Many actors give their voices and images to video game companies. They are concerned that their voices and faces could be used without their permission in the future.</p>
<p>Another strike could include the people who work <strong>behind the</strong> <strong>scenes</strong> in television and movies. Those workers do things such as plan the lighting and create the sets. Their union said its workers have missed out on a lot of money as film and television projects shut down in 2023.</p>
<p>In addition, people who appear on reality television programs such as <em>The Bachelor</em> or <em>The</em> <em>Real Housewives</em> have started talking about forming a union. The people who appear on those programs do not have a labor group and many have talked about difficult working conditions and long days.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>union </strong><em>–n.</em> an organization of workers formed to protect the rights and interest of its members</p>
<p><strong>paradigm </strong><em>–n.</em> an idea about how something should be done, made or thought of</p>
<p><strong>interview </strong><em>–n.</em> a meeting at which people talk to each other in order to ask questions and get information</p>
<p><strong>role </strong><em>–n.</em> the character played by an actor</p>
<p><strong>behind the scenes </strong><em>–phrase.</em> the activity and work that goes on to support a creative production such as a play or television show</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Many Uses of ‘Get’  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/the-many-uses-of-get.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the use of the word "get."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-91d4-08dbe0812038_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I would like to know more about the use of the word "get." Over time I have realized that it is an important word used in different ways, but I would like a clearer and broader explanation about its use. Could you explain more about this word, please? Thank you very much.</p>
<p>Regards,</p>
<p>Mireya</p>
<p><strong>Answer </strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Mireya. This is a good question.</p>
<p>"Get" is the most common verb in any situation, and it is around the 40th most used word in the English language. In speech, "get" is used almost once per minute on average.</p>
<p>So, your interest in it is well placed.</p>
<p>VOA Learning English has explored "get" several times.</p>
<p>In <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/take-and-get/5605304.html" target="_blank">an earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em></a> program we discussed the difference between "take" and "get." And in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/the-passive-voice-with-get-/4839624.html" target="_blank">an earlier <em>Everyday Grammar</em></a> program we discussed that "get" can be used with the passive voice although it is rare.</p>
<p>We also discussed many meanings of "get" in another <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/getting-to-know-the-verb-get/3617759.html" target="_blank">Everyday Grammar</a></em> program. We shared that "get" has more than 50 uses, and it appears as part of at least 12 phrasal verbs or other expressions.</p>
<p>In earlier programs, we discussed meanings of "get" such as understand, know, obtain, receive, feel, become, buy, fetch, location, and its use to express impatience or <strong>frustration</strong>.</p>
<p>As you can see, there is a lot to know about "get."</p>
<p><strong>Examples of "get"</strong></p>
<p>Here is some additional information about the use of "get."</p>
<p>"Get" is extremely common in spoken language, but it is rare in written language. Careful writers avoid "get" because it is usually informal.</p>
<p>"Get" is often used with subjects that are not living things. This is important because most verbs in speech are used with animate, or live, subjects.</p>
<p>"Get" is the second most common verb used with "do" to demonstrate special importance or difference. For example<em>:</em></p>
<p><em>She finally <u>did get</u> better. </em></p>
<p>There is the structure "get" + adjective presented in the <em>Everyday Grammar</em> program. Adjectives used with "get" describe physical and mental changes.</p>
<p>The most common adjective used with "get" is "worse." Other common adjectives include "older" and "better."</p>
<p>In addition, "get" is often used with adjectives to describe an increasing amount. The most often used phrases for this use are</p>
<p><em>get worse and worse</em> and <em>get bigger and bigger</em>.</p>
<p>We should explain one final use of "get." Some words are used in a fixed series in English. "Get" is used in many fixed series of words in spoken English. They are:</p>
<p><em>I'm going to <u>get</u></em></p>
<p><em>You're going to <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em>I'll have to <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em>You can <u>get</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>I haven't <u>got</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>I haven't <u>gotten</u> any </em></p>
<p><em>You've <u>got</u> to </em></p>
<p><em>If you've <u>got</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>If you/I can <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em><u>get</u> on with it </em></p>
<p><em><u>get</u> rid of it </em></p>
<p><em><u>got</u> a bit of </em></p>
<p><em><u>I got</u> one of them </em></p>
<p><em>haven't <u>got</u> a clue </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Mireya.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>frustration</strong>--<em>n</em>. a poor feeling from lack of solving a problem</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
