<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Why Are Major Powers Interested in the Moon?  (2023/8/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/why-are-major-powers-interested-in-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Russia recently launched its first moon-landing spacecraft in 47 years. The launch comes during a time of competition by major powers including the United States, China and India to discover more about the resources held on the moon.</p>
<p>Russia said that it would launch further moon missions and then explore the possibility of a joint Russian-China crewed mission and even a moon base. NASA has spoken about the possibility of moon mining and a "gold rush" - a situation in which many people go quickly to a place where something valuable has been discovered.</p>
<p>Why are major powers so interested in what is up there?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this handout from the Russian Space Agency Roscosmos on August 11, 2023, a Soyuz 2.1b rocket with the Luna-25 lander blasts off at the Vostochny cosmodrome in the Amur region. (Russian Space Agency Roscosmos/AFP) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5854769c-13ba-4f8a-adbf-41fc21a95e56_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this handout from the Russian Space Agency Roscosmos on August 11, 2023, a Soyuz 2.1b rocket with the Luna-25 lander blasts off at the Vostochny cosmodrome in the Amur region. (Russian Space Agency Roscosmos/AFP) </span></div>
<p><strong>The moon </strong></p>
<p>The moon is about 384,400 kilometers from our planet.</p>
<p>The current thinking is that the moon was formed when a large object crashed into earth about 4.5 billion years ago. Some of the remains from the crash came together to form the moon.</p>
<p>Temperatures are <strong>diverse</strong> on the moon. In full Sun, they rise to 127 degrees Celsius, while in darkness they drop to about minus 173 degrees Celsius. The moon's <strong>exosphere</strong> does not give protection against radiation from the Sun.</p>
<p>The first discovery of water on the moon was made in 2008 by the Indian mission Chandrayaan-1, which detected hydroxyl molecules spread across the moon's surface. The molecules were most commonly found at the poles, NASA says.</p>
<p>Water is necessary for human life and also can be a source of hydrogen and oxygen. These elements can be used for rocket fuel.</p>
<p>The moon also likely has Helium-3.</p>
<p>Helium-3 is a kind of helium that is rare on earth, but NASA reports estimates of a million tons of it on the moon.</p>
<p>Helium-3 could provide nuclear energy in a fusion reactor. But since Helium-3 is not radioactive it would not produce dangerous waste, the European Space Agency says.</p>
<p>Also present on the moon are rare earth metals. Rare earth metals are used in smartphones, computers and other special technologies. Boeing, a very large American aerospace business, says the moon may have rare earth metals including candium, yttrium and the 15 lanthanides.</p>
<p><strong>Moon mining </strong></p>
<p>But it is not entirely clear how mining on the moon would work.</p>
<p>Some sort of <strong>infrastructure</strong> would have to be established on the moon. The conditions of the moon mean robots would have to do most of the hard work, though water on the moon would allow for a long-term human presence.</p>
<p>The laws governing moon mining are unclear and full of holes.</p>
<p>The United Nations 1966 Outer Space Treaty says that no nation can claim rule over the moon. In addition, the treaty says the exploration of space should be done for the good of all countries.</p>
<p>But lawyers say it is unclear whether or not a private business could claim rule over a part of the moon.</p>
<p>"Space mining is subject to relatively little existing policy or governance," The RAND Corporation, a research group, said on its website last year.</p>
<p>The UN's 1979 Moon Agreement says that no part of the moon "shall become property of any State, international intergovernmental or non-governmental organization, national organization or non-governmental <strong>entity</strong> or of any natural person."</p>
<p>But, no major space power has approved the measure.</p>
<p>The United States in 2020 announced the Artemis Accords, named after NASA's Artemis moon program. The agreement aims to build on existing international space law by establishing "safety<strong> zones</strong>" on the moon. Russia and China have not joined in the agreement, however.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Guy Faulconbridge reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>diverse </strong><em>-- adj. </em>different from each other</p>
<p><strong>exosphere</strong> <em>– n.</em> the outer area of the atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>– n.</em> the basic equipment and structures that are needed for a country or organization to function properly</p>
<p><strong>entity </strong><em>-- n. </em>something that exists by itself : something that is separate from other things</p>
<p><strong>zone </strong><em>-- n. </em>an area that is different from other areas in a particular way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>African Leadership Groups Concerned about Military Takeover in Niger  (2023/8/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/african-leadership-groups-concerned-about-military-takeover-in-niger.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Defense leaders from the West African group of nations known as ECOWAS are meeting to discuss the political crisis in Niger.</p>
<p>The leaders are concerned. The military group that ousted Niger's President Mohamed Bazoum in July did not answer an ECOWAS request to stand down or face an invasion.</p>
<p>ECOWAS has 15 member countries and is based in Abuja, Nigeria.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Military personnel gesture as the ECOWAS anthem is played during a meeting of the Committee of Chiefs of Defense staff on the deployment of the ECOWAS standby force in the Republic of Niger, in Accra, Ghana. August 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Francis Kokoroko)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a21b376f-3cd6-41ea-bca8-43b5e43faa83_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Military personnel gesture as the ECOWAS anthem is played during a meeting of the Committee of Chiefs of Defense staff on the deployment of the ECOWAS standby force in the Republic of Niger, in Accra, Ghana. August 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Francis Kokoroko)</span></div>
<p>Outside security experts said ECOWAS has not been able to prevent leadership takeovers in other West African nations. That includes the recent government overthrows in Burkina Faso and Mali.</p>
<p>This time, however, the group organized a "<strong>standby</strong> force" that is ready to move on the Nigerien capital of Niamey if Bazoum is not put back in place. In addition, the group put financial and travel restrictions on Niger.</p>
<p>So far, nothing has changed. Defense experts say ECOWAS is running out of ways to put pressure on the group that took power in Niger.</p>
<p>Andrew Lebovich studies northern Africa for the Clingendael Institute, a research group based in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>He said: "An intervention could <strong>backfire</strong> and damage (ECOWAS) in numerous ways. While a failure to <strong>extract</strong> major <strong>concessions</strong> from (the soldiers in control) could weaken the organization..."</p>
<p>Another group of African states, the African Union, met earlier this week to discuss whether it would support a military move by ECOWAS. The African Union includes 55 nations in Africa. The union could prevent a military action by ECOWAS if it felt that the move would <strong>destabilize </strong>Niger and nearby countries.</p>
<p>The status of who leads Niger is important to western nations, including France and the United States. Both countries have soldiers in Niger. They have been working to train and support local soldiers in their fights against Islamic militant groups. Niger had been one of the last countries in the area with a democratic government.</p>
<p>Since the military group pushed out Bazoum and took control in Niger, the U.S. and France are no longer supporting the Nigerien soldiers.</p>
<p>This makes Niger open to outside attacks. The Associated Press reports that 17 Nigerien soldiers were killed and over 20 were injured in an attack Tuesday in the Tillaberi area in the country's northwest.</p>
<p>In Niamey, locals are concerned both about a military move by ECOWAS and the effects of financial and travel restrictions. Some of the electric power – most of which comes from Nigeria – has been cut off. Restaurant owners say they cannot keep food cold. The ECOWAS restrictions include limits on who can enter and leave Niger. They are also preventing aid workers from coming in with food and supplies.</p>
<p>Louise Aubin is the coordinator in Niger for the United Nations. She is concerned that food and medical supplies inside Niger could <strong>run out</strong> because of the border restrictions. The U.N. and other aid groups said 4 million of the 25 million people in Niger needed assistance before the military takeover. They expect that number to increase.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>standby </strong><em>–adj.</em> ready or available in emergencies or on short notice</p>
<p><strong>backfire </strong><em>–v. </em>to have the opposite result of what was desired or expected</p>
<p><strong>extract </strong><em>–v. </em>to get</p>
<p><strong>concessions </strong><em>–n.</em> (usually pl.) things that are given up in an effort to gain something else</p>
<p><strong>destabilize </strong><em>–v.</em> to make something less secure, steady or predictable</p>
<p><strong>run out </strong><em>–v. (phrasal</em>) to become used up with nothing left</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you worried about Niger now that the military group in control has not stepped down?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Present Tense in 'We Didn’t Start the Fire'  (2023/8/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/present-tense-in-we-didn-t-start-the-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The band Fallout Boy recently released a version of the song, <em>We Didn't Start the Fire. </em>The song was first released in 1989 by the singer/songwriter Billy Joel.</p>
<p>Joel's song was about notable events and people in the United States and throughout the world from the years 1948, when Joel was born, to 1989.</p>
<p>More than 30 years have passed since then. Now, Fallout Boy remade the song to include events from 1989 to 2023. Joel's song was in chronological order, meaning the events are presented in the order in which they took place. Fallout Boy's version is not chronological.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: Present Tense in " didn="" fire="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4e6e-08db9e6ff67c_w268_r1.png" start="" the="" we=""/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: Present Tense in "We Didn't Start the Fire" </span></div>
<p>Another difference between the two is Fallout Boy's remake uses more full sentences. Both songs are mainly lists of people, places and events that many Americans are likely to remember.</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore some of the different ways that the present tense is used in the song and some additional grammar points.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>habit </strong><em>– n. </em>something a person does regularly in a repeated way</p>
<p><strong>consonant</strong><strong> </strong><em>– n.</em> a speech sound (such as /p/, /d/, or /s/) that is made by partly or completely stopping the flow of air breathed out from the mouth</p>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>describing a species that no longer exists</p>
<p><strong>informal</strong> <em>– adj. </em>suited for ordinary or everyday use</p>
<p><strong>contraction </strong><em>–n.</em> a shortened form of a word</p>
<p><strong>passive voice</strong> <em>–</em> <em>n</em>. a way of writing or speaking that uses passive verbs where the subject receives the action of a verb</p>
<p><strong>impeach </strong><em>– v.</em> to charge (a public official) with a crime done while in office</p>
<p><strong>transitive verb </strong><em>– n.</em> a verb that takes a direct object</p>
<p><strong>refer to </strong><em>–v. (phrasal) </em>to talk about or mention something</p>
<p><strong>dramatic </strong><em>– adj. </em>striking in appearance or effect</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Young Chinese Turn to Online Streaming to Earn Money  (2023/8/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/young-chinese-turn-to-online-streaming-to-earn-money.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many young Chinese are increasingly turning to online <strong>streaming</strong> as a way to earn money while selling products for major companies.</p>
<p>The job involves livestreaming on popular social media services in China. A person leading such livestreams is known as a host. The goal is to persuade users to spend money with large <strong>brands</strong> such as Under Armor, Lancome, YSL Beauty and Hugo Boss.</p>
<p>One such streamer is 28-year-old Zhang Jinyu, a former model who studied <strong>fashion</strong> in college. She told reporters from Reuters news agency she has already completed hundreds of hours of live streams to publicize products for YSL Beauty and other brands.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="A host promotes a bag during a live stream at luxury e-commerce platform ZZER in Shanghai, China July 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Xihao Jiang)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a596-08db9e724a59_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">A host promotes a bag during a live stream at luxury e-commerce platform ZZER in Shanghai, China July 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Xihao Jiang)</span></div>
<p>Zhang's livestreams can involve her continuously speaking on camera for up to six hours. In addition, the preparation process requires her to do her hair and makeup and spend time recording sales results after her online broadcasts have ended.</p>
<p>Reuters reports that Zhang is one of millions of young Chinese currently facing record youth unemployment of more than 21 percent. Livestreaming sales is one way social media users can earn money without having to get a full-time job.</p>
<p>"For livestreaming, the <strong>threshold</strong> to enter the industry is very low,” Zhang said. “I can pick up my phone and I'm livestreaming.” She noted, however, that livestream selling is now very competitive, making it difficult for newcomers to gain a following. "If you can <strong>persevere</strong>, you can get better and better,” Zhang said.</p>
<p>Zhang is not alone in her desire to make livestream hosting a career. A recent public opinion study asked more than 10,000 young people on China’s social media service Sina Weibo how they feel about the issue. More than 60 percent said they would be interested in working as an internet influencer or livestreaming host.</p>
<p>A study by China-based marketing agency iResearch found the livestreaming industry employed more than 1.2 million hosts as of 2020. The COVID-19 pandemic helped lead livestreaming sales growth that brought in about $480 billion in China last year.</p>
<p>That growth led to a series of agencies being created that aim to train new hosts and connect them with established brands.</p>
<p>Zhang, for example, works with Shanghai-based agency Romomo. The company is a business partner of Buy Quickly, which helps hosts link up with major fashion-centered brands.</p>
<p>Shining Li is vice president of Romomo. She told Reuters she thinks livestreaming is currently “one of the most important methods of communication” for the international brands she works with.</p>
<p>Shi Jianing is a 28-year-old livestreaming host. She says her broadcasts are a good way for her to build lasting relationships with followers and increase sales for the brands she represents.</p>
<p>"We're like friends with the <strong>consumers</strong>," Shi said. She added, “If you can communicate with some personal <strong>affinity</strong>, that builds a kind of trust, and that relationship makes the consumer want to carry out the sale."</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stream </strong><em>– v. </em>to play a presentation, show or movie over the internet</p>
<p><strong>brand </strong><em>– n. </em>a kind of product made by a particular company under a particular name</p>
<p><strong>fashion </strong><em>– n. </em>the business of creating and selling clothes in new styles</p>
<p><strong>threshold </strong><em>– n. </em>the level at which something starts to happen</p>
<p><strong>persevere </strong><em>– v. </em>to continue to try to do something even though it can be difficult</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>– n. </em>someone who buys or uses goods or services</p>
<p><strong>affinity </strong><em>– n. </em>an attraction to or liking for something</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Map the Deep Ocean Off Alaska’s Coast  (2023/8/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/researchers-map-the-deep-ocean-off-alaska-s-coast.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. weather agency is exploring the ocean around the Aleutian Islands aiming to map the sea floor and make discoveries about undersea life.</p>
<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) research ship, called Okeanos Explorer, is on a five-month <strong>mission</strong>. It is a former U.S. Navy ship, which has been changed to meet current needs. Civilians and members of the NOAA Corps are carrying out the mission.</p>
<p>The ship has a 48-member crew. It has technology and tools to gather information about the deep ocean and to immediately share it with researchers. The hope is that the data will be used for future research.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The NOAA Okeanos Explorer sits at a dock on Friday, June 23, 2023, in Kodiak, Alaska. (AP Photo/Joshua A. Bickel)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/667bf1d2-4624-41a7-b3a8-1fc57d12cb0b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The NOAA Okeanos Explorer sits at a dock on Friday, June 23, 2023, in Kodiak, Alaska. (AP Photo/Joshua A. Bickel)</span></div>
<p>Mission leader Shannon Hoy said that the sea floor near Alaska is full of life. She added, "You would never know that unless we were able to go down there and explore."</p>
<p>Researchers are using several kinds of sonar technology, used to map objects underwater, and two remotely operated vehicles, Deep Discoverer and Seirios. They are designed to map and collect <strong>samples</strong>. The researchers are exploring the Aleutian Trench and Gulf of Alaska, areas of water near the U.S. state of Alaska.</p>
<p>The researchers are also using cameras that can operate at depths of up to 6,000 meters. The cameras permit the researchers to document and immediately share their findings. The ship can also share live video of the dives with the public.</p>
<p>Hoy said that, in two to four weeks, the Okeanos Explorer can map as much as 50,000 square kilometers of ocean floor.</p>
<p>Hoy said the team plans to investigate some of the area's cold "seep communities." These are places where gas from under the sea floor rises through openings. Life in these places is not believed to depend on the sun for food production.</p>
<p>Hoy said the researchers are also going to study the water <strong>column</strong> to see what interesting animals they can find there.</p>
<p>Kasey Cantwell is the ship's operations chief. She said the data will help researchers and the public better understand these areas of the ocean. The information could also help make decisions about fisheries and could also identify dangers at sea and improve maps.</p>
<p>"It's really hard to care for things you don't understand, to love things you don't understand," Cantwell said.</p>
<p>The deep ocean off Alaska's Aleutian Islands is one of the least mapped places in the U.S. Modern mapping has covered just 34 percent of the sea floor off Alaska. The area includes one of America's largest coastal <strong>ecosystems</strong>, and only a small part of that has been seen, the mission's web site says.</p>
<p>Emily Crum is a communications specialist with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. She said filling holes in current information is a mission goal. The effort will also help meet a goal of mapping all of the United States' deep waters by 2030 and near-<strong>shore</strong> waters by 2040.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong>– <em>n.</em> a specific military or naval task</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong>– <em>n.</em> a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>column </strong>– <em>n.</em> something that is tall and thin in shape</p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong>– <em>n.</em> everything that exists in a particular environment</p>
<p><strong>shore </strong>– <em>n.</em> the land along the edge of an area of water</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Humans in Europe Likely Wiped Out by Cold Weather  (2023/8/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-humans-in-europe-likely-wiped-out-by-cold-weather.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists say that an early human <strong>species</strong> that settled in what is now Europe was <strong>wiped out</strong> by a long ice age over 1 million years ago.</p>
<p>The scientists say Homo erectus, considered the first member of the human family tree to have moved out of Africa, was not able to survive a cold period that lasted 4,000 years. They published the research in early August in the journal <em>Science</em>.</p>
<p>Chris Stringer is an anthropologist at the Natural History Museum in London. He was one of the study's writers. Stringer and his co-writers say they studied <strong>fossils</strong> and stone tools found in Europe. The fossils showed a gap in the timeline of about 200,000 years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The skull of the early human species Homo erectus. (REUTERS/David Mdzinarishvili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/275d9a0a-86c3-49ef-be53-2623dc302a57_cx0_cy13_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The skull of the early human species Homo erectus. (REUTERS/David Mdzinarishvili)</span></div>
<p>"There was probably a complete <strong>interruption</strong> in the early human occupation of Europe," Stringer said.</p>
<p>The researchers say early human species likely did not know how to make warm clothing or find ways to make fire in cold places. The cold weather froze the ground and prevented them from gathering food and hunting animals.</p>
<p>The scientists used ancient organic compounds left by <strong>algae</strong> and <strong>pollen</strong> off Portugal's coast to learn about climate change over 1 million years ago. The study showed the average air temperature dropped by 4.5 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>Axel Timmermann is a climate physicist at Pusan National University in South Korea. He said the study shows that human occupation of Europe was not continuous but was interrupted by at least one "climate-<strong>induced</strong> <strong>extinction</strong>."</p>
<p>It is not clear how many early humans died off during this cold period, the researchers said. "Probably at best in the tens of thousands in Europe," Stringer said of the population at the time.</p>
<p>Another study writer was Chronis Tzedakis, a physical geography teacher at University College London. He said humans probably returned to Europe about 900,000 years ago after "<strong>evolutionary</strong> or <strong>behavioral</strong> changes" that permitted them to survive in cold conditions.</p>
<p>Scientists have records of human-like species in Spain and Germany from 800,000 to 600,000 years ago. Homo sapiens are known in Africa from 300,000 years ago and may have briefly come to Europe more than 200,000 years ago. But the main movement of humans into Europe came only 60,000 years ago.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>–n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants : a group of related animals or plants that is smaller than a genus</p>
<p><strong>wipe out </strong><em>–v.</em> to eliminate completely</p>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>–n.</em> something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p><strong>interruption </strong><em>–n.</em> a situation where something stops for a period of time</p>
<p><strong>algae </strong><em>–n.</em> simple plants that have no leaves or stems and that grow in or near water</p>
<p><strong>pollen </strong><em>–n. </em>the very fine usually yellow dust that is produced by a plant and that is carried to other plants of the same kind usually by wind or insects so that the plants can produce seeds</p>
<p><strong>induce </strong><em>–v. </em>to cause something to happen</p>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>–n. </em>when something stops living or dies out</p>
<p><strong>evolutionary </strong><em>–adj. </em>having to do with the way something changes over time</p>
<p><strong>behavioral </strong><em>–adj. </em>having to do with the way someone or something acts</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. What do you think of this news about humans in Europe?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is VinFast Worth More than VW, Ford?  (2023/8/17) | 越南VinFast汽车上市 市值超过大众和福特</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/is-vinfast-worth-more-than-vw-ford.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Shares of Vietnam's electric car company VinFast started publicly trading on the Nasdaq stock exchange on Tuesday. By the end of the first trading day, investors had pushed the market value of stock in the new company to $85 billion.<br/>
越南电动汽车公司VinFast的股票周二在纳斯达克证券交易所上市。截至第一个交易日收盘，投资者已将这家新公司的股票市值推高至850亿美元。</p>
<p>That is more than the market value of Germany's Volkswagen at $69.7 billion, America's Ford at $48 billion, and several other established automakers.<br/>
这超过了德国大众汽车697亿美元、美国福特汽车480亿美元和其他几家老牌汽车制造商的市值。</p>
<p>Share prices of VinFast increased about 270 percent, from around $10 to $37, on Tuesday. On Wednesday morning, the share price had dropped under $30. However, only a very small percentage of shares are being traded because VinFast founder Pham Nhat Vuong currently owns 99 percent of the company.<br/>
周二，VinFast的股价上涨了270%，从10美元左右涨到37美元。周三上午，股价跌至30美元以下。然而，该公司只有很小比例的股票在交易，因为VinFast创始人范日旺目前拥有该公司99%的股份。</p>
<p>Now comes the hard part: VinFast, an electric vehicle (EV) maker, will have to sell a lot more cars to meet the yearly target of 50,000 set by its founder.<br/>
现在困难的部分来了：电动汽车制造商VinFast将不得不销售更多的汽车，以实现其创始人设定的每年5万辆的目标。</p>
<p>For that, the company will need to bring in partners rather than selling directly on its own. It will also need to bring prices down to compete with other EV makers that have been lowering their prices since the start of the year.<br/>
为此，该公司将需要引入合作伙伴，而不是直接自己销售。它还需要降低价格，以便跟那些自年初以来就一直在降价的其它电动汽车制造商竞争。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Bringing in partners<br/>
引入合作伙伴</span></p>
<p>VinFast chief executive Le Thi Thu Thuy said on Tuesday the EV maker would be moving to a new "hybrid model" for sales, bringing in distributors and dealers for overseas markets.<br/>
VinFast首席执行官黎氏秋水周二表示，这家电动汽车制造商将转向一款新的“混合动力车型”进行销售，为海外市场引入分销商和经销商。</p>
<p>"Opening our own stores is great but it takes a lot of time," she said. "Joining forces with other partners to go faster has always been our nature." As of June, VinFast said it has opened 122 showrooms worldwide, mostly on the West Coast of the United States.<br/>
她说：“开自营店很好，但需要很多时间。与其他合作伙伴携手合作，更快发展一直是我们的特性。”VinFast公司表示，截至6月，它已在全球开设了122个展厅，其中大部分位于美国西海岸。</p>
<p>Founder Vuong had said in May that VinFast could sell 50,000 EVs this year. The company has sold over 16,000 vehicles, including its sales in Vietnam, through the first seven months.<br/>
创始人范日旺曾在5月份表示，VinFast公司今年可以销售5万辆电动汽车。该公司前七个月已售出16000多辆汽车，其中包括在越南的销量。</p>
<p>Even with that target, VinFast will only be selling about one sixth of what it can produce at its Haiphong, Vietnam factory. A new factory is being built in the American state of North Carolina. The plant is expected to begin operations in 2025.<br/>
即使是这个目标，VinFast的也只售出了相当于其越南海防工厂大约六分之一产量的汽车。该公司的正在美国北卡罗来纳州建造一家新工厂。该工厂预计将于2025年开始运营。</p>
<p>The Vietnam-based company has sold just 137 VF8 models in the U.S. To increase sales, Vinfast will have to overcome poor reviews from U.S. automotive publications. Road &amp; Track called the vehicle "unacceptable" and MotorTrend said, "return to sender."<br/>
这家总部位于越南的公司在美国只销售了137辆VF8车型。为了提高销量，Vinfast必须解决美国汽车出版物的差评。Road&amp;Track称该车“不可接受”，而MotorTrend表示，“把它退给发货方。”</p>
<p>Business advisor AlixPartners has estimated that EV carmakers need yearly sales of 400,000 vehicles to cover their costs.<br/>
商业顾问公司AlixPartners估计，这家电动汽车制造商每年需要40万辆汽车的销量来覆盖其成本。</p>
<p>In China, most EV makers are losing money in a price competition aimed at increasing market share. In the U.S., EV makers, including Tesla and Ford, have recently lowered their prices in addition to federal government tax credits meant to get people to buy the vehicles. For comparison, the Tesla Model Y is almost $7,000 less than VinFast's VF8 with federal tax credits included.<br/>
在中国，大多数电动汽车制造商为了提高市场份额，都在价格竞争中赔钱。在美国，包括特斯拉和福特在内的电动汽车制造商最近都降低了价格，此外还有联邦政府的税收抵免，旨在让人们购买这些汽车。相比之下，特斯拉Model Y加上联邦税收减免后，比VinFast的VF8便宜了近7000美元。</p>
<p>Thuy said VinFast believed its products were priced competitively but was working to bring prices down. "There is no other automaker in the world that has as low a cost base as in Vietnam," she said. "All of that is leading to cost reduction in the future."<br/>
黎氏秋水表示，VinFast相信其产品的定价具有竞争力，但也在努力降低价格。她说：“世界上没有哪家汽车制造商的成本比越南的公司低。这些都将导致未来成本降低。”</p>
<p><br/>
I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。<br/>
(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How to Help Your Garden Get Through the Heat  (2023/8/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/how-to-help-your-garden-get-through-the-heat.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Record-breaking heat is affecting plants in many places around the world. But <strong>gardening</strong> expert Jessica Damiano says selecting the right plants and a little care could save them.</p>
<p>Damiano wrote recently that her tomato plants have not developed much in the past few weeks, but her flower garden is doing very well. Despite temperatures over 37 degrees Celsius in the New York area, Damiano said she has watered her flower garden just two times this summer.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing heat-tolerant plants</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Ball Horticultural shows a bed of Bounce Pink Flame impatiens growing in a garden bed. (Ball Horticultural via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/11c8c859-6002-4dc6-947b-6d7f2c0a8e4d_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Ball Horticultural shows a bed of Bounce "Pink Flame" impatiens growing in a garden bed. (Ball Horticultural via AP)</span></div>
<p>Damiano says that in extreme heat, and when that heat is dry, soil <strong>moisture</strong> evaporates quickly. Plants will turn to their own limited moisture storage when they need water. This requires them to use energy toward cooling and using water. This energy should be spent on growth, flowering, fruiting and reproducing. The stress often completely weakens the plant.</p>
<p>When plants are native to an area, they naturally develop deep, large root systems. These systems permit the plants to reach distant sources of moisture when the nearby area dries out.</p>
<p>Many foreign plants, including most plants that live for just one year, have root systems that are not deep. This means they must depend on the top few centimeters of soil for all of their water needs. When it dries up, so do they.</p>
<p>To save water, money, and effort, Damiano suggests researching which plants are native to your area. Some native plants for Damiano's New York area include yearly returning plants like bee balm, black-eyed Susan, and purple coneflower.</p>
<p>But she also has some non-native plants that<strong> tolerate</strong> both the heat and dry weather. She keeps yearly returning plants, or perennials, in her beds, and plants that last one growing season, or annuals, in containers.</p>
<p>Damiano says the flowering plant "Bounce" impatiens live up to their name in her containers. They <strong>bounce</strong> <strong>back</strong> from being weakened by a hot and dry day after being watered.</p>
<p>Plants like sedums, or stonecrop, are highly tolerant to dry, hot weather. This is because their leaves store moisture and release it as the plants need it. Other plants that can deal with heat include beardtongue, catmint, floss flower, lavender, and moss rose.</p>
<p><strong>Planting advice</strong></p>
<p>When planting, Damiano says she always dusts root balls with <strong>fungi </strong>called mycorrhizae. It helps grow roots and helps plants deal with severe heat. She also treats her plants once a month with two products: a seaweed-containing fish mixture and a vitamin-hormone-kelp product.</p>
<p>Seaweed and kelp are plants that grow in water. They have been shown to help other plants in difficult environments. These additions also help plants grow quickly after dividing and transplanting.</p>
<p>Finally, Damiano says the last addition is a good amount of <strong>mulch</strong> on top. Mulch not only keeps things looking clean, but it also helps to keep soil moisture and soil temperatures even. And it keeps unwanted plants from growing. Mulch can mean the difference between plant life and death when it gets hot.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>moisture </strong>– <em>n.</em> a small amount of a liquid (such as water) that makes something wet or moist</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong>– <em>v.</em> to experience (something harmful or unpleasant) without being harmed</p>
<p><strong>bounce back </strong>– <em>phr. v.</em> to return quickly to a normal condition after a difficult situation or event</p>
<p><strong>fungus </strong>– <em>n.</em> any one of a group of living things (such as molds, mushrooms, or yeasts) that often look like plants but have no flowers and that live on dead or decaying things</p>
<p><strong>mulch </strong>– <em>n.</em> a material (such as straw, leaves, or small pieces of wood) that is spread over the ground in a garden to protect the plants or help them grow and to stop weeds from growing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Taliban’s Rule in Afghanistan after Two Years  (2023/8/16) | 塔利班对阿富汗两年的统治</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/the-taliban-s-rule-in-afghanistan-after-two-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Two years ago Tuesday, the Taliban seized control of Afghanistan after NATO forces pulled out of the country. The Taliban are still the clear rulers. And the Taliban face no serious opposition that could defeat them.<br/>
两年前的这个周二，在北约部队撤出阿富汗后，塔利班夺取了对阿富汗的控制权。塔利班仍然是明确的统治者。并且塔利班没有遇到任何可以击败他们的强力反对力量。</p>
<p>They have avoided divisions by falling in line behind their leader. They have kept alive a struggling economy, in part by holding investment talks with neighboring countries. They have improved domestic security by suppressing armed groups like the Islamic State. They say they are fighting corruption and opium production.<br/>
他们与领导人保持一致，从而避免了分裂。他们通过与邻国展开投资谈判，在一定程度上维持了陷入困境的经济。他们通过镇压伊斯兰国等武装组织改善了国内安全。他们说他们正在打击腐败和鸦片生产。</p>
<p>But their bans on Afghan girls and women have been a major part of the Taliban's second year in power. They barred women and girls from parks, gyms, universities, jobs and nongovernmental groups and the United Nations. These orders followed an earlier ban, issued in the first year of Taliban rule, on girls going to school beyond sixth grade.<br/>
但他们对阿富汗女性的禁令是塔利班执政第二年的主要内容。他们禁止女性进入公园、健身房、大学、工作场所、非政府组织和联合国。在这些禁令之前，是塔利班统治首年发布的禁止女孩上六年级以上年级的早期禁令。</p>
<p>Here is a closer look at Taliban rule.<br/>
下面我们来仔细看看塔利班的统治。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Why have they excluded women from many areas of public life?<br/>
为什么他们把妇女排除在众多公共生活领域之外？</span></p>
<p>The Taliban say they are putting in place their view of Islamic law, or Sharia, in Afghanistan. This leaves no space for anything they believe is foreign or secular, including permitting women to work or study. This view of Islam is what drove the Taliban in the late 1990s, when they first seized power in the country. It still drives them today.<br/>
塔利班表示，他们正在阿富汗落实他们对伊斯兰教法的见解。这让他们认为是外国或世俗的东西失去了生存空间，包括允许女性工作或学习。这种对伊斯兰教的见解在20世纪90年代末塔利班首次夺取政权时激励着他们。时至今日，它仍然激励着他们。</p>
<p>Hibatullah Akhundzada is the Taliban supreme leader. He has praised the changes since the takeover in August of 2021. He claims life improved for Afghan women after foreign troops left and after the Islamic head covering, or hijab, became required again.<br/>
海巴图拉·阿洪扎达是塔利班最高领导人。他赞扬了自2021年8月掌权以来的变化。他声称，在外国军队离开以及再次要求佩戴伊斯兰头巾后，阿富汗妇女的生活有所改善。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What was the reaction to these bans?<br/>
对这些禁令有何反应？</span></p>
<p>Foreign governments, rights groups and international organizations denounced the restrictions. The U.N. said the bans were a major obstacle to the Taliban gaining international standing as the recognized government of Afghanistan. The country is losing foreign aid as major donors cut off their support.<br/>
外国政府、人权组织和国际组织谴责这些禁令。联合国表示，这些禁令是塔利班作为公认的阿富汗政府获得国际地位的主要障碍。由于主要捐助国切断了支持，该国正在失去外国援助。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are living conditions like in Afghanistan?<br/>
阿富汗的生活条件如何？</span></p>
<p>Nearly 80 percent of the previous, Western-backed Afghan government's budget came from foreign aid. The aid paid for hospitals, schools, factories and government ministries. That money is now largely cut off. The COVID-19 pandemic, medical shortages, climate change and hunger have made life very hard for Afghans. But aid agencies have helped provide basic services, including health care.<br/>
此前，西方支持的阿富汗政府的预算中，有近80%来自外国援助。这些援助用于承担医院、学校、工厂和政府部门的开支。这笔钱现在基本上被切断了。新冠肺炎大流行、医疗短缺、气候变化和饥饿使阿富汗人的生活非常艰难。但援助机构帮助提供了包括医疗保健在内的基本服务。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">How likely are the Taliban to change direction?<br/>
塔利班转向的可能性有多大？</span></p>
<p>If the Taliban changes direction, it would likely be up to Akhundzada. He is behind the bans on women and girls. His laws are formed in the language of Islamic law and are absolute. The bans will only be lifted if Akhundzada orders it.<br/>
如果塔利班要转向，这很可能取决于阿洪扎达。他是对女性禁令的幕后推手。他的法律是用伊斯兰法律的语言形成的，是绝对权威。只有阿洪扎达下令，禁令才会解除。</p>
<p>Some Taliban leaders have spoken out against the way decisions are made. There has been disagreement about the bans on women and girls. But the Taliban's spokesman denounced these reports as propaganda.<br/>
一些塔利班领导人公开反对这种做决定的方式。关于对女性的禁令一直存在分歧。但塔利班发言人谴责这些报道是宣传战。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">International recognition<br/>
国际认可</span></p>
<p>Aid officials say the Taliban consider recognition as an entitlement, not something to be negotiated. The officials also say the Taliban sees meetings with powerful nations like China and Russia as signs that they are building international relations.<br/>
援助官员表示，塔利班将国际认可视为一种权利，而非谈判的对象。这些官员还说，塔利班将与中国和俄罗斯等强国的会晤视为他们正在建立国际关系的标志。</p>
<p>The Taliban are not officially in the international community. But they appear to have enough interaction with countries to slowly move toward normal international relations. Countries like China, Russia and Pakistan want an end to sanctions.<br/>
塔利班没有正式加入国际社会。但他们似乎与各国有足够的互动，缓慢走向正常的国际关系。中国、俄罗斯和巴基斯坦等国希望结束对塔利班的制裁。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What opposition is there to the Taliban?<br/>
有什么塔利班的反对力量？</span></p>
<p>There is no armed or political opposition with enough support to remove the Taliban from power. A fighting force resisting Taliban rule north of Kabul is being violently defeated.<br/>
没有任何武装或政治反对派得到足够的支持，可以推翻塔利班的政权。一支抵抗塔利班在喀布尔北部统治的战斗部队被暴力击败。</p>
<p>The Islamic State has struck targets in deadly bombings. But the militants lack fighters, money and other resources for a major fight against the Taliban.<br/>
伊斯兰国用致命爆炸袭击目标。但这些武装分子缺乏战斗人员、资金和其他资源来对抗塔利班。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Trump Charged with Efforts to Overturn Election in Georgia  (2023/8/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/trump-charged-with-efforts-to-overturn-election-in-georgia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Former U.S. President Donald Trump and 18 others have been <strong>indicted</strong> over efforts to overturn his 2020 election loss in the American state of Georgia.</p>
<p>The indictment is the fourth set of criminal charges against Trump, the leading candidate for the Republican presidential nomination in 2024.</p>
<p>Georgia's state government lawyers accuse Trump, his former lawyers and other aides of a "criminal <strong>enterprise</strong>" to keep him in power. The legal case uses a law, known as the RICO Act, which is often used to target members of organized crime groups. The indictment contains 41 charges.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The indictment in Georgia against former President Donald Trump is photographed Monday, Aug. 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Jon Elswick)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-01f9-08db9da6bd53_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The indictment in Georgia against former President Donald Trump is photographed Monday, Aug. 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Jon Elswick)</span></div>
<p>Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis told reporters late Monday night: "Rather than <strong>abide </strong>by Georgia's legal process for election challenges, the defendants engaged in a criminal, <strong>racketeering </strong>enterprise to overturn Georgia's presidential election result."</p>
<p>The indictment against Trump is a 98-page document. It lists several actions that Georgia government lawyers say Trump, or his allies took to undo the election result. They include a phone call in which Trump reportedly asked a state official to "find" 11,780 votes, <strong>harassing</strong> election workers, trying to create false electoral college electors, and stealing data from a voting machine.</p>
<p>Trump attacked Willis and called the indictment a "witch hunt" in a social media post overnight. He added, "Why didn't they Indict 2.5 years ago? Because they wanted to do it right in the middle of my political campaign."</p>
<p>The indictment comes just two weeks after <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/trump-indicted-accused-of-trying-to-overturn-2020-election/7208659.html">a federal grand jury charged Trump</a> with crimes connected to the 2020 presidential election. The federal indictment said Trump tried and failed to use federal and state officials to overturn the election. It said he blocked the counting of electoral votes <strong>certifying</strong> President Joe Biden's victory on January 6, 2021, as supporters attacked the Capitol building and police where the process was taking place.</p>
<p><strong>Other legal actions against Trump</strong></p>
<p>Trump has been surrounded by legal troubles since leaving office two years ago.</p>
<p>In June, Trump was charged with <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-indicts-former-president-donald-trump-with-crimes/7130540.html">illegally holding classified national security documents</a>, <strong>obstruction</strong>, making false statements, and plotting with others to carry out a crime. A trial has been set for May 2024.</p>
<p>The office of the Manhattan District Attorney in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/former-us-president-trump-to-face-criminal-charges-for-first-time/7036299.html">the state of New York charged Trump</a> with criminally falsifying "business records to conceal crimes that hid damaging information from the voting public during the 2016 presidential election." That trial is set for next March.</p>
<p>The office of the New York State Attorney General charged Trump and his business, the Trump Organization, with misleading banks and tax officials to get loans and tax benefits. A trial will start in state court in October. Additionally, Trump's company was fined $1.6 million after being found guilty of tax <strong>fraud</strong> in another New York court in December.</p>
<p>Last May, a New York jury found Trump guilty of sexually abusing and <strong>defaming</strong> the writer E. Jean Carroll and awarded her $5 million in a civil case. Carroll has brought a second legal case seeking $10 million which is planned for January.</p>
<p>Trump has denied wrongdoing in all cases.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and Reuters sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>indict</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. (legal) </em>to officially bring written charges against a person in a court of law</p>
<p><strong>enterprise</strong> <em>–n.</em> an activity or business that usually involves risk</p>
<p><strong>abide <em>–</em></strong><em>v.</em> to accept</p>
<p><strong>racketeering –</strong>n. The crime of making money by threatening people or selling worthless, immoral or illegal products or services</p>
<p><strong>harass </strong><em>–v.</em> to repeatedly bother or cause problems for someone over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>certify </strong><em>–v.</em> to officially state that a requirement has been reached for something to be approved or declared</p>
<p><strong>obstruction </strong><em>–n. (legal)</em> to prevent the police from learning the truth about something</p>
<p><strong>fraud </strong><em>–n</em>. the crime of dishonestly taking something of value from another person</p>
<p><strong>defame </strong><em>–v.</em> to hurt the opinion that people have of a person by saying things that are not true about that person</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Fluency  (2023/8/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-literacy-fluency.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Fluency is the ability to read a <strong>text</strong> quickly and understand it. It is the bridge between reading a word and <strong>comprehension</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>What fluency looks like</strong></p>
<p>Fluent readers can do the following:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Fluency" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-cd15-08db9383150a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Fluency</span></div>
<ul>
<li>They can read with correct pauses and tone of voice or expression.</li>
<li>They do not spend time figuring out each word.</li>
<li>They make connections between the text and their own knowledge.</li>
<li>They understand the larger meaning of the text.</li>
</ul>
<p>Fluency grows over time, and fluency develops from a lot of practice. To read fluently, readers must be able to divide the text into meaningful "chunks." These chunks, or pieces, include phrases and clauses within a sentence.</p>
<p>Fluency is not a reading stage of development in which students can read all<em> </em>words quickly and easily all the time. Fluency changes depending on the text. A student may be able to read a text they know fluently, but then read a new text very slowly.</p>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for fluency</strong></p>
<p><u>Read a text out loud. Then, read it again.</u></p>
<p>Students need to read and then re-read texts out loud to teachers and classmates. Teachers should give feedback. Use activities that make students re-read texts. A good activity for increasing fluency is "reader's theater." A description of this activity comes at the end of the article.</p>
<p><u>Choose the right text.</u> The texts for fluency practice should not be too easy or too hard. If the text is too hard, students may have to work too hard to say the words while failing to understand them.</p>
<p><u>Read out loud.</u> If a student has a low reading level, reading silently is not very effective. It is better to read out loud alone, with a partner, or with the whole class.</p>
<p><u>Model fluent reading.</u></p>
<p>Teachers should model fluent reading. Students re-read the text out loud.</p>
<p><u>Keep read-aloud activities interesting and active.</u></p>
<p>Students should hear many different texts read fluently. Read the texts out loud with active expressions and body language.</p>
<p><u>Read texts and not separate words.</u></p>
<p>Reading word lists might improve vocabulary. However, it may not help students to learn to read fluently.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies for fluency</strong></p>
<p><u>Strategy: "Reader's Theater"</u></p>
<p>Reader's theater is a fun activity to improve fluency. With reader's theater students read from a <strong>script</strong>. They do not need to memorize. The best scripts for this strategy have lots of dialogue and characters.</p>
<p>Choose a story that can be divided into parts. Give reading parts to each student. If you have more students than parts, you can have two or three groups act out the same story. Ask students to practice. First, they read their parts out loud. Then, the teacher helps them. Once the students have read the texts once or twice, they can design a set or costumes. Finally, they read their parts for an audience or their classmates.</p>
<p>Why use "Reader's Theater?"</p>
<ul>
<li>It helps readers learn to read aloud fluently and with expression.</li>
<li>You can use this strategy for many kinds of writing. You can read science, math, and life skills lessons as theater.</li>
<li>It helps build reading confidence. Reader's theater can be fun for very shy students. Because they are playing a role, they may feel more confident to read out loud.</li>
<li>It allows students to be creative. They can make props, costumes, and design a set. Students can play music.</li>
<li>It also tests a student's listening skills. They must know when one actor finishes a line before saying theirs.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Strategy: Partner Reading</u></p>
<p>With Partner Reading, students read out loud to each other. It helps students to work together and supports <strong>peer </strong>learning. Partner Reading can be used with many kinds of writing.</p>
<p>Pair students with the same reading ability, or pair high-level readers with low-level readers.</p>
<p>Tell students how they will use partner reading. For example, they can read out loud together. They can take turns reading parts. Or one person can read while the other person listens.</p>
<p>Partners can ask each other about the text. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>What was your part about?</li>
<li>What was your favorite part?</li>
<li>What words did you already know?</li>
<li>Which part gave you trouble?</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Strategy: Group Reading </u></p>
<p>Reading together as a class gives less skilled readers the chance to practice and get help. It gives students a model for fluent reading. It helps to provide sight-reading ability. Choose a text that works well for reading out loud as a group.</p>
<p>Group reading should:</p>
<ul>
<li>have repeated grammar patterns and repeated words</li>
<li>be not too long</li>
<li>be at the reading level of most students</li>
</ul>
<p>Give each student a copy of the text or write it on the board. Read the text out loud. Model fluent reading for the students. As you read, ask the students to follow along. Have all the students read the text out loud together.</p>
<p><strong>Assessment for fluency</strong></p>
<p>It is important to assess often. This will guide your instruction. All assessments for fluency should be done one-on-one with each student. Choose a text that fits the level of your student. Have them read out loud. Record how long it takes them and how many mistakes they made.</p>
<p>When it comes to assessing fluency, experts say look for the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Does the student stress appropriate words?</li>
<li>Does the student's voice rise and fall at the right times as they read?</li>
<li>Does the student read punctuation correctly in the text?</li>
<li>Does the student read with emotion, such as happiness?</li>
<li>Does the student pause correctly where subjects and verbs end, at phrases, and with other language chunks?</li>
</ul>
<p>Use the tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve your learners. Change them to fit your students and teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this article for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p><strong><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>text </strong>–n. a piece of writing</p>
<p><strong>comprehension </strong>–n. understanding</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong>–n. the act of placing and keeping one's attention on something</p>
<p><strong>script </strong>–n. a piece of writing that is meant to be read out loud or preformed</p>
<p><strong>peer </strong>–n. a person who belongs to the same age group or social rank as another person</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Worldcoin Draws Attention Due to Privacy Concerns  (2023/8/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/worldcoin-draws-attention-due-to-privacy-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Weeks after its international launch, Worldcoin is drawing the attention of officials around the world. Kenya's government has gone so far as to shut down the service.</p>
<p>The international ID company, backed by big investors in Silicon Valley's technology industry, now has to defend itself in investigations. The central question is whether the <strong>biometric</strong> data that the company is collecting is secure or not.</p>
<p><strong>What is Worldcoin? </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Carlos Jose, 21, has his eyes scanned by an orb, at a Worldcoin registration point in Barcelona, Spain, on Friday, Aug. 4, 2023. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/db3ac04a-64c8-4b47-9a31-a8d42bdf4ce0_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Carlos Jose, 21, has his eyes scanned by an orb, at a Worldcoin registration point in Barcelona, Spain, on Friday, Aug. 4, 2023. (AP Photo/Emilio Morenatti)</span></div>
<p>Worldcoin is the creation of Sam Altman. He is best known as the head of OpenAI, the maker of the artificial intelligence program ChatGPT.</p>
<p>The goal of Worldcoin and the company backing it, Tools for Humanity, is to give people a form of identification that could never be stolen or copied. Worldcoin creates a "World ID", an identification tool, by <strong>scanning</strong> someone's eyes through "orbs." These are special devices that capture images of the irises, the colored parts of the eyes.</p>
<p>One possible use for such an ID tool would be online services. Such services require that people remember passwords and usernames for websites they have signed up for.</p>
<p>The security of those sites can have problems, however. There have been several security issues where usernames and passwords have been stolen. Instead of using old technology like passwords, people could just sign up using their World ID.</p>
<p><strong>What is its connection to crypto? </strong></p>
<p>Worldcoin is an identification project. But it is also using <strong>cryptocurrency</strong> to get people to sign up. The Worldcoin <strong>token </strong>is trading for roughly $1.90. However, its value is largely based on expectations rather than its usability as a form of money.</p>
<p>Worldcoin launched officially in July. As part of the event, early users were given an amount of cryptocurrency worth between $50 and $60. Most of the countries where Worldcoin launched do not widely use or accept crypto.</p>
<p>Further, $50 is a lot of money in developing countries where people are being asked to sign up, including Kenya, where the average monthly wage is around $170.</p>
<p><strong>Why is Worldcoin getting attention? </strong></p>
<p>Thousands of Kenyans lined up in Nairobi in early August at a center where Worldcoin took images of their irises in exchange for 25 coins worth about $50.</p>
<p>The lines included mothers with children on their backs. Some of those in line told local media that they had traveled from a distance after friends said "free money" was being handed out. They admitted not knowing why they needed to scan their irises and where that information would go.</p>
<p>Others who waited for hours included college-educated Kenyans. Many are unemployed and angry over the rising cost of living.</p>
<p>The Kenyan government has since suspended new sign-ups for Worldcoin as it investigates whether people's information is being properly protected.</p>
<p><strong>What are the privacy concerns? </strong></p>
<p>Worldcoin's orbs collect data by taking images of a person's iris. While Worldcoin argues that the data is used to create a special, secure form of identification, privacy experts have concerns that the company may use the information in other ways, like personalized marketing.</p>
<p>That has led some countries to investigate Worldcoin's operations, including France, Germany and now Kenya.</p>
<p>Privacy experts are worried that Worldcoin could, in time, be a victim to criminals, similar to data thefts at other large companies. Privacy experts have said biometric data is already being sold in places like China and that could spread to other places.</p>
<p>Last week, Worldcoin discussed the privacy concerns on its website. The company wrote everything is available as a choice and no personal data "is <strong>disclosed by default</strong>, enabling each holder to decide which (if any) personal data to share with third parties when using World ID."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Ken Sweet and Evelyne Musambi reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>biometric</strong> <em>-- adj.</em> relating to the statistical study of biological data</p>
<p><strong>scan </strong><em> -- v. </em>to use a special machine to read or copy something into a computer</p>
<p><strong>cryptocurrency</strong><em> – n.</em> a digital currency where records are kept in a decentralized system</p>
<p><strong>token </strong>–<em> n.</em> something that is used in place of a coin</p>
<p><strong>disclose</strong> <em>– v.</em> to make (something) known to the public</p>
<p><strong>by default</strong> <em>– phrase </em>used to describe something that happens or is done when nothing else has been done or can be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>COVID-19 Hospitalizations in the US Are Increasing Again  (2023/8/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/covid-19-hospitalizations-in-the-us-are-increasing-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The number of people entering the hospital with COVID-19 has increased in the United States since early July. The increase is similar to the past three summers but with far fewer cases than before.</p>
<p>With an <strong>updated </strong>vaccine still months away, experts worry this summer's increase in hospitalizations could become a bigger problem.</p>
<p><strong>How bad is the increase?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sign announcing a face mask requirement is displayed at a hospital in Buffalo Grove, Ill., on January 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Nam Y. Huh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/bda64afb-134d-4b61-8cd7-f15e612c7b70_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sign announcing a face mask requirement is displayed at a hospital in Buffalo Grove, Ill., on January 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Nam Y. Huh)</span></div>
<p>For the week ending July 29, COVID-19 hospital <strong>admissions</strong> were at 9,056. That is an increase of about 12 percent from the week before. But it is a lot less than the former high points. For example, there were 44,000 weekly hospital admissions in early January, nearly 45,000 in late July 2022, and 150,000 when the Omicron subvariant spread in January 2022.</p>
<p>Dr. David Dowdy is an infectious disease expert at Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health. He said it is increasing a little, but it is not something to be overly concerned about.</p>
<p>It is likely that infections are rising too, but data is lacking. Federal officials ended the public health emergency in May. That means that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and many states no longer follow the number of <strong>positive</strong> test results.</p>
<p>Since early June, about 500 to 600 people have died each week. The number of deaths appears to be unchanging this summer. But past increases in deaths usually follow behind hospitalizations.</p>
<p><strong>How are we following the virus?</strong></p>
<p>The amount of the COVID-19 virus in wastewater has been rising since late June across the U.S. In the coming weeks, health officials say they will look closely at wastewater levels. People will be returning from summer travel and students will be going back to school then.</p>
<p>Cristin Young is an infectious disease expert at Biobot Analytics. The CDC uses Biobot Analytics to study wastewater. She said researchers are finding higher levels of COVID-19 in wastewater in the Northeast and South.</p>
<p>"It's important to remember right now the <strong>concentrations</strong> are still fairly low," Young said. She noted that it is about 2.5 times lower than last summer.</p>
<p>There is not one kind of variant that appears much more than others. But there is a higher number of cases from one kind of Omicron variant – EG.5. Some are calling this variant "eris" but scientists are not using that name.</p>
<p>"There are a couple that we're watching, but we're not seeing anything like Delta or Omicron," Young said, talking about former variants that caused high increases in COVID cases. And genetic changes to the virus that happen naturally do not necessarily make it more dangerous.</p>
<p>"Just because we have a new subvariant doesn't mean that we are <strong>destined </strong>to have an increase in bad outcomes," Dowdy said.</p>
<p><strong>When is the new vaccine coming?</strong></p>
<p>This autumn, officials expect to see updated COVID-19 vaccines that contain the Omicron variant XBB.1.5. It is an important change from today's combination shots. They mix the <strong>original</strong> coronavirus with last year's most common Omicron variants.</p>
<p>It is not clear when people can expect what officials hope is a yearly COVID-19 vaccine in autumn. Drug makers Pfizer, Moderna and Novavax are all creating vaccines with the XBB update. But the Food and Drug Administration will have to approve the shots. And the CDC must then issue suggestions on their use.</p>
<p>Dr. Mandy Cohen is the new CDC director. She said she expects people will get their COVID-19 vaccines where they get their vaccines for another infectious disease, the flu. She expects people will get vaccines at places like work or drug stores, rather than places that were set up just for COVID-19 vaccinations. Those places were set up early in the pandemic as part of the emergency measure.</p>
<p>"This is going to be our first <strong>fall</strong> and winter season coming out of the public health emergency, and I think we are all recognizing that we are living with COVID, flu, and RSV," Cohen told The Associated Press last week. Respiratory Syncytial Virus, or RSV, is another infectious disease. "But the good news is we have more tools than ever before."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>update </strong>– <em>v.</em> to make (something) more modern</p>
<p><strong>admission </strong>– <em>n.</em> the act or process of accepting a patient in a hospital for treatment</p>
<p><strong>positive </strong>– <em>adj.</em> showing the presence of a particular germ, condition, or substance</p>
<p><strong>concentration </strong>– <em>n.</em> the amount of an ingredient in a mixture</p>
<p><strong>destined </strong>– <em>adj.</em> certain to do or to be something</p>
<p><strong>original </strong>– <em>adj.</em> happening or existing first or at the beginning</p>
<p><strong>fall </strong>– <em>n.</em> autumn</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Recent Record-breaking Mountain Climber Sets New Goal  (2023/8/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/recent-record-breaking-mountain-climber-sets-new-goal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dominic Varela</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A mountain guide who recently climbed the world's 14 tallest mountains in record time has set a new goal for himself. Tenjen Sherpa of Nepal says he now wants to become the youngest person to climb all the peaks twice.</p>
<p>Last month, the 35-year-old Tenjen and 37–year-old Norwegian Kristin Harila, broke the record for the fastest climb of the mountains. All of the peaks are above 8,000 meters. The two reached the final mountaintop, K2, in 92 days. It was very speedy. The record they broke was set at 189 days.</p>
<p>Now, Tenjen is preparing for his new goal. He said he hopes to start by climbing Mount Shishapangma in China in the next two months. "I have already done (it) once and I want to double it," he told the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Nepali climbing guide Tenjen Sherpa, 35, poses during an interview with the Associated Press in Kathmandu, Nepal, Wednesday, August 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8d2fdb52-0de8-4241-89b5-2327bac617a9_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Nepali climbing guide Tenjen Sherpa, 35, poses during an interview with the Associated Press in Kathmandu, Nepal, Wednesday, August 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)</span></div>
<p>Only person has climbed all 14 peaks twice. Forty-eight-year-old Sanu Sherpa completed his second climb of the mountains last year.</p>
<p>Tenjen has already climbed seven of the mountains twice. He hopes to climb the remaining seven by next spring.</p>
<p>Tenjen climbed the first of these mountains in 2016, when he reached the top of Mount Dhaulagiri in Nepal. He has since made several similar climbs every year, including four trips to Mount Everest.</p>
<p>He and his three brothers set a record as the most <strong>siblings</strong> to have climbed Mount Kanchenjunga. Kanchenjunga is the world's third-tallest mountain, behind Mount Everest and K2.</p>
<p>Tenjen started working as a mountain guide to support his family. However, in April, the Kathmandu company Seven Summits Treks hired Tenjen to join Harila's trip to Mount Shishapangma. Harila and Tenjen then climbed the rest of the mountains together.</p>
<p>"It was my good luck and (I) was <strong>fortunate</strong> to be with her in the team," Tenjen said to the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>Tenjen plans to climb Shishapangma for the second time later this fall. He plans on carrying with him pictures of a brother who died. Shishapangma was the only one of the 14 tallest mountains that this brother had not climbed. Tenjen says he will bury the images on the mountaintop.</p>
<p>Tenjen told the <em>AP</em> that Sherpas do not get enough government recognition for their hard work.</p>
<p>"It is not possible to just continue climbing mountains as you grow older, so what else is there than to think of migrating <strong>abroad</strong>," Tenjen pointed out.</p>
<p>Tenjen never attended school growing up. He has difficulty reading and writing. But, living in Kathmandu, Nepal's capital, his children are able to get an education. Tenjen thinks, though, that since more children will be growing up in cities in the future, they will not have the skills to become Sherpas.</p>
<p>I'm Dominic Varela.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Dominic Varela adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sibling </strong><em>– n. </em>one of two or more individuals having one common parent</p>
<p><strong>fortunate </strong><em>– adj. </em>lucky</p>
<p><strong>abroad </strong><em>– adv. </em><strong> </strong>beyond the borders of one's country</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Death Total Grows as Hawaii Works to Recover from Wildfires  (2023/8/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/death-total-grows-as-hawaii-works-to-recover-from-wildfires.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hawaii's Governor Joshua Green told U.S. broadcaster CBS that the number of dead from wildfires on the island of Maui will continue to grow over the next week.</p>
<p>Green said the search for bodies and survivors will take at least 10 days and it is "impossible" to guess how many people died. He said he expects crews will find 10 to 20 bodies each day.</p>
<p>"We are prepared for many tragic stories," Green said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Two people examine a burned house after an inferno destroyed much of the historic Maui resort town of Lahaina, Hawaii, Aug. 13, 2023. (Sandy Hooper/USA Today Network via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d5df-08db9cf009df_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Two people examine a burned house after an inferno destroyed much of the historic Maui resort town of Lahaina, Hawaii, Aug. 13, 2023. (Sandy Hooper/USA Today Network via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>At least 96 people died when a fire spread through the town of Lahaina on Maui last Tuesday. Officials said the fires moved nearly two kilometers per minute.</p>
<p><strong>Searching for bodies</strong></p>
<p>It is the deadliest natural disaster in Hawaii since a huge ocean wave killed 61 people in 1960. It will be the costliest disaster since a hurricane in 1992. Green estimated the damage to be $5.6 billion.</p>
<p>The National Fire Protection Association said the fires on Maui caused the most deaths from a wildfire in the U.S. since 1918 when over 450 died in Minnesota and Wisconsin.</p>
<p>Firefighters were still trying to contain small fires over the weekend. Dogs trained to look for human remains helped people search the burned Lahaina area. The town was home to about 13,000 people.</p>
<p>"They're going street by street, <strong>block</strong> by block," said Jeff Hickman, of the Hawaii Department of Defense.</p>
<p>Officials have said the area might be unsafe for some time. The fire might have released dangerous gases and made water undrinkable. People who cannot return home, or those whose homes have burned, will live in hotels and <strong>rental</strong> homes.</p>
<p><strong>Searching for a cause </strong></p>
<p>Green said officials are investigating the cause of the fire. They also want to know why safety officials failed to activate some emergency signals.</p>
<p>Green said dry weather and winds from a hurricane caused the fire to move quickly.</p>
<p>Those in the area said they had little warning about the danger. They said the fire surrounded their homes in minutes. Some people jumped into the ocean to escape.</p>
<p>The fire damaged power lines and reduced mobile phone service, so some people did not get messages that the fire was getting close. Warning <strong>sirens</strong> placed around the island that are supposed to turn on in case of a disaster did not turn on.</p>
<p>‘We'll know soon whether or not they did enough to get those sirens going," Green told the broadcaster MSNBC.</p>
<p>
<strong>Searching for comfort</strong></p>
<p>Some people went to a Catholic church or attended other religious services over the weekend.</p>
<p>Akanesi Vaa was at a church. She said she and her family left their car and climbed a fence to get to a safe place.</p>
<p>"I think a lot of us needed to hear today's message," she said. "All these ashes are going to turn into beauty. I know Lahaina will come back ten times stronger."</p>
<p>Scott Landis is a Christian church leader in Makena. He said about 100 people attended his services – twice the usual number.</p>
<p>"You could tell people were here, looking for a word of hope," he said. Many, he added, did not know the <strong>location</strong> of friends and family.</p>
<p><strong>Asking for help</strong></p>
<p>Some people sent messages on social media services such as Instagram asking people to look for relatives.</p>
<p>"People are being found alive and severely <strong>disoriented</strong> due to what they have gone through," wrote Heather Baylosis on Saturday. She was looking for the parents of her partner.</p>
<p>Famous television star Oprah Winfrey lives <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_gugQsn3v">on</a> Maui part of the year. She brought supplies such as towels, water and personal washing products to those who were staying in a shelter. She warned that, in time, the people documenting the disaster will leave and the story will no longer be in newspapers and on television.</p>
<p>"But we're all still going to be here trying to <strong>figure out</strong> what is the best way to rebuild," Winfrey said.</p>
<p>J.P. Mayoga is helping, too. He works as a cook at a large hotel. Now, he is making meals for 200 hotel employees and their family members who have been living there since Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said it is good that the co-workers can be together.</p>
<p>"Everybody has their story, and everybody has lost something...And they understand what's going on in each other's lives."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters and the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>block </strong><em>–n.</em> an area of land in a city that is bordered by streets</p>
<p><strong>rental </strong><em>–adj.</em> property, such as a home, that is offered for use for a temporary period for a cost called rent</p>
<p><strong>siren </strong><em>–n.</em> a device that makes a very loud noise that is meant to warn people of danger</p>
<p><strong>location </strong><em>–n.</em> the place where something is</p>
<p><strong>disoriented </strong><em>–adj.</em> to become unable to understand what is happening around you</p>
<p><strong>figure out </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to come to understand or to find something out by thinking</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. How do you feel about the people in Maui now that you know more about what happened last week?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Work to Save Florida Reefs  (2023/8/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/scientists-work-to-save-florida-reefs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Several organizations are racing to save the <strong>reef</strong> that runs along the Florida Keys.</p>
<p>A summer heat wave has already led to historic coral <strong>bleaching</strong>. Coral bleaching is the process by which coral becomes white because of high water temperatures or pollution.</p>
<p>Up and down the islands that form the Florida Keys, coral rescue groups, universities and the government are working to save the coral. Experts say the bleaching event threatens the health of the third-largest reef area<strong> </strong>in the world. They have been working long days for many weeks to get as much coral as they can onto land.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Grad student Berfin Sagir, left, and Research associate Catherine Lachnit collect coral fragments to be transplanted, Friday, Aug. 4, 2023, near Key Biscayne, Fla. (AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ff46-08db9a89781e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Grad student Berfin Sagir, left, and Research associate Catherine Lachnit collect coral fragments to be transplanted, Friday, Aug. 4, 2023, near Key Biscayne, Fla. (AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee)</span></div>
<p>In mid-July, water surface temperatures averaged 33 degrees Celsius off the lower Florida Keys. That is well above the average of 29.5 degrees, says the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or NOAA.</p>
<p>The hot water resulted in nearly 100 percent bleaching along some parts of the reef. The bleaching caused the corals to lose their zooxanthellae. That is the algae that gives them color and nutrition. If they do not recover their zooxanthellae, they will die.</p>
<p>"We're already seeing not just bleaching, but actual coral death out on the reef because the temperatures were so hot," said Cynthia Lewis. She is director of the Keys Marine Lab, a research institute on the island of Long Key, about 160 kilometers south of Miami.</p>
<p>In Miami, rescue groups have already brought more than 1,500 pieces of coral.</p>
<p>Coral bleaching happens naturally when waters warm greatly. It happened in 2016 in the Florida Keys. But Lewis said the current situation is urgent for coral, which is very important to Florida's economy, coastal protection and marine life.</p>
<p>Recent cloudy and rainy days helped lower water temperatures slightly. But it will likely be late October or November before the coral samples can be returned to the reef, Lewis said.</p>
<p>The Florida Coral Reef stretches about 563 kilometers from the Dry Tortugas in the Gulf of Mexico to St. Lucie Inlet, about 185 kilometers north of Miami.</p>
<p>The reef is a first line of defense against coastal <strong>erosion</strong> and flooding from storms, Lewis said. It helps support fishing and the <strong>tourism</strong> industry. Coral also contains "such an amazing amount of <strong>diversity</strong> and life" in the ocean around them, Lewis added.</p>
<p>Reef Renewal is a group that has worked to move endangered coral into land-based centers. More recently, the group has worked to save coral in several of their own underwater <strong>facilities</strong> in shallower water by moving them to deeper, cooler water.</p>
<p>Reef Renewal founder Ken Nedimyer called the coral bleaching "hard to watch and hard to experience." He said his group knew that coral <strong>stress</strong> would increase under climate change. But he and others did not think it would happen so soon.</p>
<p>Back at the Keys Marine Lab on Long Key, the collected pieces of coral are put in cooling containers that hold between 40 and 400 gallons of seawater. The 29-degree water makes for "much happier coral," said marine biologist Emily Becker.</p>
<p>The work goes beyond saving the coral. Becker and others are studying different kinds of coral to see which ones survive temperature stress and disease better. They hope to "build a better reef with more <strong>resilient</strong> corals," she said.</p>
<p>Scientists from the University of Miami have created a research site off of Key Biscayne to do such work.</p>
<p>Jamison Gove is the co-writer of a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06394-w">new article in Nature</a> about how Hawaii coral reefs survived a 2015 ocean heat wave.</p>
<p>The oceanographer said reefs that returned best after Hawaii's heat wave were those that had both the most fish and the least <strong>sewage</strong>. But he said local efforts will not save reefs if people do not reduce greenhouse gas <strong>emissions</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>bleach </strong><em>— n. </em>whiten by exposure to sunlight or by a chemical process.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>erosion </strong><em>— n. </em>the gradual destruction of something by natural forces</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tourism </strong><em>— n. </em>the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diversity </strong><em>— n. </em>the quality or state of having many different forms, types, ideas, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>facility </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is built for a specific purpose</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stress </strong><em>— n. </em>a state of mental tension and worry caused by problems in your life, work, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resilient </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to become strong, healthy, or successful again after something bad happens</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sewage </strong><em>— n. </em>waste material that is carried away from homes and other buildings in a system of pipes</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sea Reptile Fossils Suggest It Was a Filter-feeder  (2023/8/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/sea-reptile-fossils-suggest-it-was-a-filter-feeder.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Baleen whales, such as the blue whale, are huge sea animals. Baleen describes a <strong>filter</strong>-feeding system in their mouths through which they can eat huge amounts of very small ocean animals.</p>
<p>But, it appears now that whales were not the first sea animals to filter-feed.</p>
<p>Scientists recently reported their findings from a study of ancient remains of a sea reptile called Hupehsuchus nanchangensis. The fossils were unearthed in China's Hubei area. The study appeared in the publication <em>BMC Ecology and Evolution</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Artist's reconstruction shows the Triassic Period marine reptile Hupehsuchus nanchangensis, based on fossils unearthed in China's Hubei Province. (Shi Shunyi and Long Cheng/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/996090ea-2b0e-486e-82ce-4100e8a160fe_cx5_cy0_cw91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Artist's reconstruction shows the Triassic Period marine reptile Hupehsuchus nanchangensis, based on fossils unearthed in China's Hubei Province. (Shi Shunyi and Long Cheng/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>Hupehsuchus lived 248 million years ago, during the Triassic Period. Scientists say its fossil presents evidence of a filter-feed system similar to baleen whales.</p>
<p>The sea reptile lived during a time of intense biological changes following Earth's worst mass <strong>extinction</strong>. Powerful volcanic bursts led to severe warming, destroying many kinds of life.</p>
<p>Unlike blue whales, Hupehsuchus was not large. The animal measured about one meter long, fossils show. Its mouth was narrow and toothless. It had a large tail that moved from side to side for swimming forward, and had front and back <strong>limbs</strong> to help it turn.</p>
<p>Its lower<strong> jaw</strong> was only loosely connected to the rest of the head bone. This permitted the animal to open its mouth widely to take in a large amount of water and the animals, zooplankton, it carried.</p>
<p>The baleen structure is made up of keratin, a soft organic material. The baleen traps little sea animals but lets the seawater flow out.</p>
<p>The researchers found evidence along the jaws suggesting the presence of soft tissues that could have served as baleen.</p>
<p><strong>Paleontologist</strong> Mike Benton was a study writer.</p>
<p>"Altogether, this points to a soft <strong>pouch </strong>made of skin around the mouth and throat, as in modern baleen whales, and some kind of filtering device hanging from the jaws, like baleen," Benton said.</p>
<p>But, he added, the baleen and skin was not fossilized.</p>
<p>Paleontologist Long Cheng of the Wuhan Center of China Geological is the study's lead writer. He said Hupehsuchus would have continuously filter-fed at slow swimming speeds. He also said the animal would have fed in areas with a dense amount of zooplankton.</p>
<p>Long said Hupehsuchus took in water and the animals together into its mouth, "filtered out the water" and then swallowed the food.</p>
<p>Researchers first described Hupehsuchus fossils in the 1970s but lacked any good remains of the head. The new study involves two new fossils with well-kept head bones, or skulls.</p>
<p>Many sea creatures use some form of filter-feeding.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>filter </strong>– <em>n.</em> a device that is used to remove something unwanted from a liquid or gas that passes through it</p>
<p><strong>extinction </strong>– <em>n.</em> the state or situation that results when something (such as a plant or animal species) has died out completely</p>
<p><strong>limb </strong>– <em>n.</em> a leg or arm</p>
<p><strong>paleontology </strong>– <em>n.</em> the science that deals with the fossils of animals and plants that lived very long ago especially in the time of dinosaurs</p>
<p><strong>pouch </strong>– <em>n.</em> a pocket of skin inside the mouths of some animals (such as squirrels and hamsters) that is used to carry food</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ancient Whale May Be Heaviest Animal Ever Found  (2023/8/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/ancient-whale-may-be-heaviest-animal-ever-found.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have discovered <strong>fossils</strong> that might have belonged to the heaviest animal in Earth's history.</p>
<p>The blue whale holds the current record as the largest creature to live on Earth. But a collection of bones found in Peru might break that record.</p>
<p>Researchers recently introduced the whale <strong>species</strong> in a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06381-1">study</a> in the publication <em>Nature</em>. It is called Perucetus colossus, or "the <strong>colossal</strong> whale from Peru." Each back bone, or vertebra,<strong> </strong>weighs more than 100 kilograms. The animal's ribs measure nearly 1.4 meters long.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this 2023 artist illustration by Alberto Gennari, Perucetus colossus is reconstructed in its coastal habitat. (Alberto Gennari/Nature via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d3b1-08db9773afab_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this 2023 artist illustration by Alberto Gennari, Perucetus colossus is reconstructed in its coastal habitat. (Alberto Gennari/Nature via AP)</span></div>
<p>Mario Urbina discovered the bones in 2012. He is with the University of San Marcos' Natural History Museum in Lima. An international team spent years digging them out from the side of a rocky hill in the Ica desert.</p>
<p>The area was once underwater and is known for its rich collection of ocean fossils. The find resulted in 13 backbone vertebrae, four ribs and a hip bone. The large fossils date back to around 39 million years ago.</p>
<p>Alberto Collareta is a <strong>paleontologist</strong> at Italy's University of Pisa. He was a lead writer of the study. He told The Associated Press the fossils were "unlike anything I've ever seen."</p>
<p>Hans Thewissen is a paleontologist at Northeast Ohio Medical University who did not take part in the research. He said, "It's just exciting to see such a <strong>giant </strong>animal that's so different from anything we know."</p>
<p>After the digging operation, the researchers used 3D <strong>scanners</strong> to study the surface of the bones and also looked inside. The researchers used the huge but incomplete skeleton to estimate the whale's size and weight, said Eli Amson. He is a paleontologist at the State Museum of Natural History in Stuttgart, Germany.</p>
<p>The team estimates the ancient creature weighed somewhere between 85 and 340 metric tons. The biggest blue whales found have been within that range, at about 180 metric tons.</p>
<p>The body of Perucetus colossus stretched about 20 meters long. Blue whales can be longer, with some growing to more than 30 meters. This means the newly discovered whale was "possibly the heaviest animal ever," said the University of Pisa's Collareta. But, he added, "it was most likely not the longest animal ever."</p>
<p>The research team said one reason the animal weighs more is because its bones are much denser and heavier than a blue whale's bones. Those super-dense bones suggest the whale may have spent its time in less deep, coastal waters, the scientists said. Other animals that stay close to the coast, like manatees, have heavy bones to help them stay close to the seafloor.</p>
<p>Amson, from the State Museum of Natural History in Germany, said that without the skull, it is hard to know what the whale was eating to support such a huge body. It is possible that the large creature sought food along the seafloor, the researchers said. Or it could have eaten up tons of smaller sea life in the ocean.</p>
<p>Thewissen added that he would not be surprised "if this thing actually fed in a totally different way that we would never imagine."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Nature reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>– n. </em>something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) from a plant or animal that lived in ancient times and that you can see in old rocks</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>colossal </strong><em>– adj. </em>very large</p>
<p><strong>paleontologist </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who studies fossil animals and plants</p>
<p><strong>giant </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely big</p>
<p><strong>scanner </strong><em>– n. </em>a device that images things to see what is inside</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Launches AI Competition to Protect Computer Systems  (2023/8/14) | 美国发起人工智能竞赛保护计算机系统</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-launches-ai-competition-to-protect-computer-systems.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>The United States has launched a competition for developing artificial intelligence (AI) to find and fix security issues in U.S. government infrastructure.<br/>
美国发起了一场开发人工智能的竞赛，以发现并解决美国政府基础设施中的安全问题。</p>
<p>Anne Neuberger is the U.S. government's deputy national security advisor for cyber and emerging technology.<br/>
安妮·纽伯格是美国政府负责网络和新兴技术的副国家安全顾问。</p>
<p>She told Reuters news agency, "Cybersecurity is a race between offense and defense." She said bad actors are already using AI to identify weaknesses in systems and to build malicious software.<br/>
她对路透社表示，“网络安全是一场进攻和防御之间的竞赛。”她说，恶意行为者已经在使用人工智能来识别系统漏洞，并构建恶意软件。</p>
<p>A number of U.S. organizations, in healthcare, manufacturing and government, have been targets of hacking in recent years. Officials have warned about such threats, especially from foreign actors.<br/>
近年来，在医疗保健、制造业和政府部门方面的一些美国机构一直是黑客攻击的目标。官员们对此类威胁发出了警告，尤其是来自外国势力的威胁。</p>
<p>Canada's cybersecurity chief Sami Khoury made similar comments last month. He said his agency had seen AI being used for everything from creating phishing emails and writing malicious computer code to spreading disinformation.<br/>
加拿大网络安全负责人萨米·库利上个月也发表了类似言论。他说，他领导的机构已经发现人工智能被用于从创建钓鱼电子邮件、编写恶意计算机代码到传播虚假信息的方方面面。</p>
<p>The White House said the two-year competition includes around $20 million in awards. The Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) will lead the competition. DARPA is the U.S. government body in charge of creating technologies for national security.<br/>
白宫表示，这项为期两年的竞赛包括约2000万美元的奖金。美国国防高级研究计划局将领导这场竞赛。美国国防高级研究计划局是美国政府负责国家安全技术的机构。</p>
<p>The technology companies Google, Anthropic, Microsoft, and OpenAI will make their systems available for the competition, the government said.<br/>
美国政府表示，科技公司谷歌、Anthropic、微软和OpenAI将为这场竞赛提供他们的系统。</p>
<p>The event signals official attempts to deal with an emerging threat that experts are still trying to fully understand. In the past year, U.S. businesses have launched a number of generative AI tools such as ChatGPT. These tools permit users to create videos, images, texts, and computer code. Chinese companies have launched similar tools.<br/>
该活动标志着官方试图应对一种专家们仍在努力充分了解的新兴威胁。在过去的一年里，美国企业推出了许多生成类人工智能工具，如ChatGPT。这些工具允许用户创建视频、图像、文本和计算机代码。中国企业也推出了类似的工具。</p>
<p>Experts say such tools could make it far easier to carry out large hacking campaigns or create false identities on social media to spread lies and propaganda.<br/>
专家表示，这些工具可能会使大规模黑客活动或在社交媒体上创建虚假身份散步谎言和进行宣传变得容易得多。</p>
<p>Neuberger said the goal of the DARPA AI competition is to build a larger community of cyber defenders who use AI to help increase America's cyber defenses.<br/>
纽伯格表示，美国国防高级研究计划局人工智能竞赛的目标是建立一个更大的网络防御者社区，他们使用人工智能来帮助加强美国的网络防御。</p>
<p>The Open Source Security Foundation, a group of experts trying to improve open source software security, will also be involved in the competition. It will make sure the "winning software code is put to use right away," the U.S. government said.<br/>
开源安全基金会作为一家致力于提高开源软件安全性的专家小组也将参与到这项竞赛。美国政府表示，该基金会将负责确保获胜的软件代码立即投入使用。</p><p>
I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sea Ice in Antarctica Falls to Record Lows  (2023/8/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/sea-ice-in-antarctica-falls-to-record-lows.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Sea ice in the Antarctic area fell to a record low this year. The drop is a result of rising temperatures worldwide. And there is no quick fix to make up for the damage, scientists said recently in a new study.</p>
<p>Antarctica's minimum summer ice cover, which last year dropped below 2 million square kilometers for the first time since satellite <strong>monitoring</strong> began in 1978, fell further to a new low in February.</p>
<p>The scientists' findings appeared in the publication Frontiers in Environmental Science.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Penguins are seen on an iceberg as scientists investigate the impact of climate change on Antarctica's penguin colonies, on the northern side of the Antarctic peninsula, Antarctica January 15, 2022. (REUTERS/Natalie Thomas)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4f93ba83-600a-47a5-bce7-2ee2aea78392_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Penguins are seen on an iceberg as scientists investigate the impact of climate change on Antarctica's penguin colonies, on the northern side of the Antarctic peninsula, Antarctica January 15, 2022. (REUTERS/Natalie Thomas)</span></div>
<p>Anna Hogg of the University of Leeds in Britain was one of the study's co-writers. When speaking about the melting icebergs and <strong>shelves</strong>, she said "It's going to take <strong>decades</strong> if not centuries for these things to recover. There's no quick fix to replacing this ice."</p>
<p>She told a group of reporters, "It will certainly take a long time, even if it's possible."</p>
<p>This year's sea ice minimum is 20 percent lower than the average over the last 40 years. The sea ice loss represents an area nearly 10 times that of New Zealand, said Tim Naish of the Antarctic Research Center at New Zealand's Victoria University of Wellington. Naish was not part of the study.</p>
<p>Naish added that in some cases we are getting close to important large changes that could lead to serious <strong>consequences</strong> for future generations.</p>
<p>The warming of Earth's surface driven by the burning of <strong>fossil</strong> fuels has made Antarctica more likely to suffer from extreme events. And the effect is almost "<strong>certain</strong>" to get worse, the study said.</p>
<p>Climate change will "lead to increases in the size and <strong>frequency</strong>" of heatwaves, ice shelf collapses and declines in sea ice, it said.</p>
<p>The study drew on recent evidence from scientific studies of the Antarctic Ocean, atmosphere, cryosphere and biosphere.</p>
<p>The exact effects of climate change on Antarctica and the surrounding ocean have been uncertain. Scientists have had problems measuring how much the Earth's warming is affecting the thickness of Antarctic ice.</p>
<p>But from events such as the fast decline in sea ice, it is "scientifically reasonable" to assume that extreme events are going to become worse as temperatures rise worldwide, said Martin Siegert of the University of Exeter, another study co-writer.</p>
<p>Last year, an "atmospheric river" coming from Australia pushed heat and moisture into Antarctica. The result was temperatures up to 38.5 Celsius above normal, the largest <strong>variance</strong> from the norm the world has ever experienced.</p>
<p>Siegert described the temperature increase as "absolutely <strong>astonishing</strong>." Siegert added that if the event had happened during the Antarctic summer, instead of winter, it would have caused melting on the surface of the East Antarctic ice sheet, which has so far been saved from melting.</p>
<p>Siegert used the term fragile, meaning easily broken or damaged, to describe Antarctica.</p>
<p>"Antarctica is fragile as an environment, but extreme events test that fragility," he said. "What we're deeply concerned about is the increase in intensity and frequency of extreme events and the .... influences that they have in other areas."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>David Stanway reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>-- v. </em>to watch or observe for a special purpose over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>shelf </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>a flat area of rock, sand, etc., especially underwater</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong><em>– n.</em> a period of 10 years</p>
<p><strong>consequence </strong><em>-- n. </em> something that happens as a result of an action</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>a fuel (such as coal or oil) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>certain</strong> <em>– adj. </em>used to say that something will definitely happen</p>
<p><strong>frequency </strong>–<em> n.</em> the number of times that something happens during a particular period</p>
<p><strong>variance</strong> <em>– n.</em> an amount of difference or change</p>
<p><strong>astonishing</strong> <em>– adj.</em> causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More US Minority Teachers Are Quitting  (2023/8/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/more-us-minority-teachers-are-quitting.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>States are reporting that teachers are leaving their jobs in growing numbers.</p>
<p>In some cases, retirement is highest among teachers from minority groups. One reason is <strong>stress</strong> from <strong>burnout</strong> during the COVID-19 pandemic. Another reason, teachers say, is low pay. And another reason teachers give is what they call the introduction of politics in the classroom. But the stress can be worse in schools serving poor communities that have a lot of minority teachers.</p>
<p>Rhonda Hicks is leaving her teaching job in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She said she loved teaching and loved her students. As a Black woman, she took pride in being a <strong>role model </strong>for minority children.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Philadelphia school district teacher Rhonda Hicks poses for a portrait at her home in Philadelphia, Thursday, July 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Perez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b26b-08db98dde43b_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Philadelphia school district teacher Rhonda Hicks poses for a portrait at her home in Philadelphia, Thursday, July 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Perez)</span></div>
<p>But growing demands from administrators over what and how to teach made it harder for her to work. When she retires, she will join a <strong>disproportionate</strong> number of Black and Hispanic teachers in her state who are quitting.</p>
<p>"I enjoy actually teaching, that part I've always enjoyed," said 59-year-old Hicks. "But it's the higher-ups: ‘Do it this way or don't do it at all.'" That, she said, was stressful.</p>
<p>Philadelphia has one of the highest percentages of Blacks in any major U.S. city. But the number of Black teachers has been falling. Twenty years ago, about one-third of teachers were Black. Last fall, that percentage fell to below 23 percent.</p>
<p>The Associated Press reports that about 80 percent of American public school teachers are white. White students, however, are not a majority in public schools. Having teachers who are the race of their students is important, researchers say. The idea is that teachers can provide students with role models who share their culture and life experience.</p>
<p>Retirements could affect recent efforts to bring more Black and Hispanic teachers into public schools. New, inexperienced teachers are more likely to quit. Researchers say minority teachers often are affected disproportionately by <strong>layoffs</strong>.</p>
<p>Ed Fuller is an education <strong>professor</strong> at Pennsylvania State University. In a report, he wrote that Black teachers in Pennsylvania were over two times more likely to leave their jobs than white teachers after the 2021-22 school year. The numbers for Hispanic teachers were similar.</p>
<p>"They're in more <strong>precarious</strong> teaching positions, meaning you're in a position with less resources and worse working conditions, so you're more likely to quit no matter who you are," Fuller said.</p>
<p>States are reporting different rates of retirement for minority teachers. But Travis Bristol said minority retirement rates have been higher than rates for whites for 20 years. Bristol is an education professor at the University of California-Berkeley. He blamed federal policies from around 20 years ago that began leading to the closure of schools where students repeatedly had low test scores.</p>
<p>In poor schools with large populations of Black and Hispanic children, teachers say they have more responsibilities. They also say they have fewer resources and more children who are troubled by poverty and violence.</p>
<p>Chantle Simpson is a 36-year-old teacher in Texas who quit teaching after 11 years this spring.</p>
<p>She said other minority teachers are leaving because of growing expectations from administrators.</p>
<p>"They believe we can handle more," Simpson said. "So, we get fitted with the children who are more <strong>challenging</strong> or have more requirements. It's crazy."</p>
<p>That leaves teachers who deal with difficult children less time for the rest of their students who behave better, Simpson said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stress </strong>–n. a state of mental tension</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>burnout </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>when a person becomes physically and emotionally tired from doing a difficult job for a long time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>role model </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who children look up to and who they try to imitate</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>disproportionate </strong><em>— adj. </em>showing a difference that is not in proportion to another set of numbers which causes people to wonder what the cause of the imbalance is</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>layoff </strong><em>— n. </em>when workers' employment is ended for reasons beyond their control</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>professor</strong><em>— n. </em>a teacher of high rank at a college or university</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>precarious </strong><em>— adj. </em>not safe, strong or sure</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>challenging </strong><em>— adj. </em>difficult</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Learn When to Wear 'Kid Gloves'  (2023/8/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/learn-when-to-wear-kid-gloves.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, notes on usage, and use them in conversations.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a piece of clothing – gloves.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kid gloves used to be worn by some servants to protect handling costly objects. (Adobe Stock Footage)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5a0f-08db99f6c875_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kid gloves used to be worn by some servants to protect handling costly objects. (Adobe Stock Footage)</span></div>
<p>We wear gloves to protect our hands. When the weather is cold, we wear gloves to keep our hands warm. When we do difficult outdoor work, we might wear work gloves. And when we clean indoors, we might wear <strong>rubber </strong>gloves to protect our hands from chemicals.</p>
<p>But when do we wear "kid gloves"?</p>
<p>Kid gloves are made from the skin of a young goat, also called a kid. Kid leather is very soft. So, kid gloves are perfect for holding objects such as silverware and art without leaving fingerprints. Years ago, many servants would wear kid gloves.</p>
<p>But today, we use the expression <u>kid gloves</u> to describe a way of dealing with certain people or situations. People who are <strong>sensitive</strong> require kid gloves. And situations that are complex and <strong>delicate</strong> often need the<u> kid-glove treatment</u>.</p>
<p>However, when we use kid gloves to talk about people, it is a little different than when we talk about situations.</p>
<p><u>To treat something with kid gloves</u> is to handle a situation carefully and with <strong>tact</strong>. When we do something tactfully, we do it in a thoughtful way. Tactful people deal with people and situations very well. They are diplomatic.</p>
<p>Handling a situation with kid gloves is the opposite of <u>being a bull in a china shop</u>. If you are<u> a bull in a china shop,</u> you handle a situation very carelessly. (<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/are-you-a-bull-in-a-china-shop-/7059316.html" target="_blank">We talked about this idiom</a> on another <em>Words and Their Stories.</em>)</p>
<p>Kid-glove treatment shows special skill and sensitivity. People who need kid-glove treatment might be very sensitive, meaning their feelings are easily hurt. Or they might be<strong> fussy </strong>and demanding. For example, really famous actors or pop stars might need the kid-glove treatment.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear the idiom used in a conversation between two friends.</p>
<p><em>A: What are you doing this weekend?</em></p>
<p><em>B: An old friend is visiting me. We were best friends all through middle school and high school. </em></p>
<p><em>A: That sounds fun!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, I hope it will be. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Why do say ‘hope'?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, she just went through a very <strong>nasty</strong> divorce from her high school sweetheart. She's still very sensitive about it. So I have to handle her with kid gloves and not talk about our high school days.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Sounds like a little kid-glove treatment is just what she needs. And you can talk about the future instead. </em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rubber </strong><em>–n.</em> n elastic substance obtained from the milky juice of various tropical plants</p>
<p><strong>sensitive</strong> <em>–adj.</em> easily hurt or damaged <em>especially</em> :<strong> </strong>easily hurt emotionally</p>
<p><strong>delicate </strong><em>–adj.</em> easily unsettled or upset : resulting from or requiring skill or careful treatment</p>
<p><strong>tact</strong> <em>–n.</em> the ability to deal with others without upsetting them :<strong> tactfully </strong>–adv.</p>
<p><strong>fussy </strong><em>–adj.</em> easily upset : hard to please</p>
<p><strong>nasty </strong><em>–adj.</em> morally disgusting or degrading</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>William McKinley: Imperial  (2023/8/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/americas-presidents-william-mckinley.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about William McKinley. He took office in 1897 and was re-elected in 1900. He led the United States into the 20<sup>th</sup> century.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - William McKinley" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/25fb1fdf-86f1-46b4-a09d-153acde1b822_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - William McKinley</span></div>
<p>One way to think of McKinley is as a <strong>transition </strong>president. In the 1800s, lawmakers were mostly concerned with how the country was growing in North America.</p>
<p>But during McKinley's government, the U.S. looked beyond its borders. Congress declared war on Spain, the first time the U.S. had fought a European power since the War of 1812 against Britain.</p>
<p>The U.S. also took control of overseas territories, <strong>annexed</strong> Hawaii, and<a class="wsw__a" href="https://history.state.gov/milestones/1899-1913/hay-and-china"> tried to <strong>regulate</strong> the world's trade with China</a>.</p>
<p>Some historians say President McKinley himself wanted the U.S. to increase its international influence. Others argue that he was just answering the country's <strong>mood</strong> at the time.</p>
<p>Either way, his presidency is often defined by the country's rise as an <strong>imperial </strong>power.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>McKinley was the sixth president to come from the state of Ohio. He was the seventh of eight children. Historians describe his childhood as loving and fun.</p>
<p>His father owned a small iron factory. His mother raised her children to be honest and polite.</p>
<p>McKinley was a hard-working student. He briefly attended Allegheny College in Pennsylvania, but he did not have the money to finish his education there.</p>
<p>A few years after leaving that school, he volunteered for the Army on the side of the Union in the Civil War. He served under a man who would later become president himself, Rutherford B. Hayes. The two stayed close throughout their lives.</p>
<p>After the war ended, McKinley studied law, became involved in Republican Party politics, married, and had two daughters.</p>
<p>His wife, Ida, was an energetic, well-educated young woman from a wealthy family. For a while, she had worked in her father's bank.</p>
<p>But Ida McKinley's health began to suffer. She was struck by seizures. Then her mother died. A few months later, her younger daughter died while still an infant. Ida McKinley <strong>clung</strong> to her older daughter, but the little girl soon developed a fever disease, and she died, too.</p>
<p>William and Ida McKinley were never the same. Ida McKinley remained sick her entire life. She spent most of her hours in a small rocking chair sewing.</p>
<p>William McKinley paid great attention to her. He organized his schedule to spend time near her, even as his political success grew.</p>
<p>In time, McKinley served in Congress and as the governor of Ohio. He was known as a likable person and a skilled politician.</p>
<p>His Republican Party nominated him on the first ballot at their convention. A few months later, voters elected McKinley into office in a <strong>landslide</strong>. He became the country's 25<sup>th</sup> president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When McKinley took office, the U.S. was just coming out of a severe economic depression.</p>
<p>His government quickly approved a high protective tariff to help struggling workers. In general, his administration also permitted the growth of big business.</p>
<p>But most of McKinley's attention as president was devoted to foreign policy. The main issue was Cuba.</p>
<p>At that time, Spain controlled the island. Cubans revolted, and Spanish forces used violence and detainments to crush the rebellion.</p>
<p>In the U.S., many Americans denounced the events in Cuba. They wanted McKinley and his government to intervene.</p>
<p>At first, President McKinley was unwilling. He tried to use diplomacy. He even ordered a U.S. ship into Spanish waters near Havana to show his continued support of Spain.</p>
<p>But the ship, called the Maine, exploded. Americans believed the Spanish were responsible. Relations between the two countries worsened fast. Spain declared war. The U.S. Congress answered <strong>in kind</strong>.</p>
<p>For 100 days, U.S. and Spanish forces fought in Cuba and other areas under Spanish control.</p>
<p>The war quickly turned in the Americans' favor. When the Spanish-American War ended with the Treaty of Paris in 1898, the U.S. took control of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Philippines from Spain. Cuba was made independent; however, the U.S. continued to occupy the island for several more years.</p>
<p>Not everyone approved of the actions of McKinley's government. Even some members of Congress warned against the U.S. becoming an imperial power.</p>
<p>But a majority of voters approved of McKinley as a victorious commander-in-chief. They also noted that the U.S. economy was getting stronger. In 1900, McKinley won re-election.</p>
<p><strong>Assassination</strong></p>
<p>As it turned out, McKinley's second term in office was short.</p>
<p>In September, only six months after his swearing-in, the president was receiving visitors at a fair in the city of Buffalo, New York.</p>
<p>One of the visitors in line was a 28-year-old man named Leon Czolgosz. His family was from Poland, but he lived in the city of Detroit, Michigan. He had worked in a factory, but at the time was unemployed. He supported the idea of <strong>anarchy</strong> – no government at all.</p>
<p>When McKinley reached to shake the young man's hand, Czolgosz shot the president twice in the stomach.</p>
<p>Although injured, McKinley spoke to his guards. He told them not to hurt the shooter. And, he expressed concern about how his wife would feel when she learned he had been shot.</p>
<p>Quickly, McKinley was taken to a hospital. Doctors predicted that he would survive. And, for a few days, McKinley seemed to improve.</p>
<p>But the wound became infected, and eight days after the attack McKinley died.</p>
<p>The president's murderer did not say he was sorry for his act. He defended it, saying McKinley was an enemy of working people.</p>
<p>Within a few weeks of the shooting, Czolgosz was tried, found guilty, and executed.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Both the nation and the world mourned when McKinley died. He had been one of the country's most popular presidents in many years.</p>
<p>He left behind the beginning of what some called an American <strong>empire</strong>. He also marked a change in the U.S. presidency.</p>
<p>When he first took office in the 19<sup>th</sup> century, most presidents acted primarily as administrators.</p>
<p>But President McKinley began to act in ways that are more like a modern president. He prepared remarks to give to the media. He traveled across the country speaking to voters. He used the power of his office to direct the armed forces.</p>
<p>McKinley laid the groundwork, but he did not completely change the presidency. He left that to the even more famous man who followed him into the White House.</p>
<p>After McKinley's death, his vice president, Theodore Roosevelt, took office and truly brought the country into modern times.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Caty Weaver was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>________________________________________________________</em><em style="font-size: 9pt;">___________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p>
<br/>
<strong>transition</strong> - <em>n.</em> a change from one state or condition to another</p>
<p><strong>annex</strong> - <em>v.</em> to add an area to a country : to take control of a place</p>
<p><strong>mood</strong> - <em>n. </em>an attitude or feeling shared by many people</p>
<p><strong>imperial</strong> - <em>adj. </em> of or relating to an empire or an emperor</p>
<p><strong>clung</strong> -<em> v. </em>tried very hard to keep something that you are in danger of losing</p>
<p><strong>landslide</strong> - <em>n. </em>election in which the winner gets a much greater number of votes than the loser</p>
<p><strong>in kind </strong>- <em>adj.</em> in a way that is equal or very similar to what someone else has done to or for you</p>
<p><strong>anarchy</strong> - <em>n. </em>a situation in which the people in a country are not controlled by rules or laws</p>
<p><strong>empire</strong> - <em>n.</em> a group of countries or regions that are controlled by one ruler or one government</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hip-hop Culture Carries the Spirit of Protest  (2023/8/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/hip-hop-culture-carries-the-spirit-of-protest.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The signs of hip-hop's influence are everywhere. American rapper and music producer Pharrell Williams recently became a creative director for the French <strong>fashion</strong> company Louis Vuitton. Other hip hop stars, including Dr. Dre, Diddy and Jay-Z, started billion-dollar fashion, lifestyle and music companies.</p>
<p>But it did not start out that way.</p>
<p>Hip-hop started 50 years ago as an escape from the poverty and violence in the Bronx area of New York City. The music and style appealed to Black and Latino <strong>teenagers</strong>. As hip-hop spread throughout New York, so did the culture.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Breakdancer Victor Montalvo, 27, of Kissimmee, Fla., performs in New York City on June 22, 2021. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-93b6-08db9a7553d9_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Breakdancer Victor Montalvo, 27, of Kissimmee, Fla., performs in New York City on June 22, 2021. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)</span></div>
<p>People often mix up hip-hop with rap. Rap is a musical style that combines quick <strong>recitation</strong> of <strong>rhymes</strong> with musical beats. But hip-hop is more than just music. It is a culture, and rap music is one part of it. Hip-hop also includes other activities, like breakdancing, <strong>disc</strong>-<strong>jockeying</strong> and <strong>graffiti</strong> art.</p>
<p>In his 1993 song <em>Hip Hop vs. Rap</em>, KRS-One <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YRkoHiOiPcc">said</a>: "Rap is something you do. Hip hop is something you live."</p>
<p>In the early days of hip-hop, playing music on the streets or turning a basketball court into a dance floor may have seemed like a simple invitation to have fun and party. But it actually was an answer to social and economic injustice in poor neighborhoods. It was a way to show joy and imagination even without resources and wealth.</p>
<p>As hip-hop and rap music grew into a force in American culture, entertainers used it to speak to their personal realities. In 1982, in the song <em>The Message</em>, Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five denounced poverty and a lack of investment in Black communities. Several years later, Tupac Shakur railed against police violence in the song <em>Changes</em>.</p>
<p>Today, hip-hop's influence on music and other industries is so widespread that experts say it becomes difficult to measure. Writer Zack O'Malley Greenburg estimates that hip-hop's five wealthiest artists were collectively worth nearly $4 billion in 2022.</p>
<p>There is also hip-hop's influence on protest, resistance and political dissent around the world. From the Arab Spring and the Palestinian freedom fight to feminism and class struggles, rap music is a popular expression for calls to action. Music videos produced by artists in Africa, Europe, Asia and South America often include breakdancers, graffiti and other elements of hip-hop.</p>
<p>In 2016, former U.S. President Barack Obama answered questions about human rights and free expression during a visit to Vietnam. One question came from Suboi, a female rapper known as Vietnam's "Queen of Hip-Hop." She said she struggled against the Vietnamese stereotype that rap and hip-hop music are not a good form of expression for Asian women.</p>
<p>"Let's be honest, sometimes art is dangerous and that's why governments sometimes get nervous about art," Obama said. "But one of the things that I truly believe is that if you try to suppress the arts, then I think you're suppressing the deepest dreams and aspirations of a people."</p>
<p>American civil rights leader Rev. Al Sharpton was 18 years old when hip-hop took off in his native New York. He said rap music fueled the movement that has shaped much of his public life. Now 68 years old, Sharpton said he believes hip-hop culture was part of what made it possible for the United States to elect its first Black president in 2008.</p>
<p>"Hip-hop took the <strong>chains</strong> off us and said, ‘No, we're gonna say it our way, " Sharpton said, "It was that freedom. It was that raw, non-watered down kind of expression."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English based on reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fashion</strong> - n. the business of creating and selling new styles of clothes</p>
<p><strong>teenager</strong> - n. someone between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p><strong>recitation</strong> - n. the act of describing or listing many things in a series</p>
<p><strong>rhyme</strong> - n. words or phrases that end in the same sound</p>
<p><strong>disc jockey</strong> - n. a person who plays recorded music on radio, at a party or a night club</p>
<p><strong>graffiti</strong> - n. pictures or words drawn on a wall</p>
<p><strong>chain</strong> - n. metal links or rings usually used to attach to a prisoner</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hawaii Wildfires Kill at Least 55, Recovery to Take Years  (2023/8/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/hawaii-wildfires-kill-at-least-55-recovery-to-take-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Wildfires on Hawaii's island of Maui have killed at least 55 people and destroyed a historic town, officials said.</p>
<p>The number of deaths is expected to rise even higher. Officials said it will take years to rebuild Lahaina, the one-time capital of the former kingdom of Hawaii.</p>
<p>Governor Josh Green said the fire was the worst natural disaster in the state's history, making thousands of people homeless and burning as many as 1,000 buildings. In 1960, a <strong>tsunami</strong> killed 61 people in the state.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An aerial image taken on August 10, 2023 shows destroyed homes and buildings on the waterfront burned to the ground in Lahaina in the aftermath of wildfires in western Maui, Hawaii. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a0496a8e-c3d8-4afd-99fd-1d5bcda8801a_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An aerial image taken on August 10, 2023 shows destroyed homes and buildings on the waterfront burned to the ground in Lahaina in the aftermath of wildfires in western Maui, Hawaii. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)</span></div>
<p>"It's going to take many years to rebuild Lahaina," Green said at a Thursday news conference.</p>
<p>Lahaina was once the home of King Kamehameha, who united Hawaii under a single kingdom. Kings and queens are buried on the grounds of the 200-year-old stone Waiola Church, one of burned sites.</p>
<p>Lahaina draws 2 million visitors each year, or about 80 percent of the island's visitors.</p>
<p>Fueled by a dry summer and strong winds from a passing hurricane, at least three wildfires burned on Maui this week.</p>
<p>Maui Fire Department Chief Brad Ventura said one fire moved so fast that it was impossible to warn people of the emergency. "What we experienced was such a fast-moving fire ... they were basically self-evacuating with fairly little notice," Ventura told the <em>Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>Thousands of visitors and locals were <strong>evacuated</strong> from the western side of Maui, which has a year-round population of about 166,000. Locals sheltered on the island or the neighboring island of Oahu. And visitors gathered in Kahului Airport, waiting for flights back home.</p>
<p>Some people fled the immediate danger by jumping into the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>Among them was Vixay Phonxaylinkham, a visitor from Fresno, California. He said his family was trapped in a car as the fires neared, forcing the family to jump in the water. They held onto pieces of wood to stay above water.</p>
<p>"We floated around for four hours," the man told <em>Reuters</em> from an emergency shelter. "It was a vacation that turned into a <strong>nightmare</strong>. I heard explosions everywhere, I heard <strong>screaming</strong>, and some people didn't make it. I feel so sad," he said.</p>
<p>Many survivors suffered burns and other injuries.</p>
<p>"It was so hot all around me, I felt like my shirt was about to catch fire," said Nicoangelo Knickerbocker, a 21-year-old from Lahaina. Knickerbocker heard cars and a gas station explode. He fled from the town with his father and the family dog. "It sounded like a war was going on," he said.</p>
<p>Officials said Thursday that they have contained about 80 percent of the Lahaina fire. There was no immediate estimate for others. However, experts say the fires are likely to change Hawaii in unwanted ways. They include a threat to coral reefs, drinking water, and its soil.</p>
<p>Wildfires, often caused by record-setting heat, have become more common around the world this summer. They forced the evacuation of tens of thousands of people in Greece, Spain, Portugal and other parts of Europe. In western Canada, several unusually severe fires sent clouds of smoke over a large part of the United States, polluting the air.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English based on reporting from Reuters and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tsunami</strong> - n. a very large, high wave in the ocean usually caused by an earthquake under the sea</p>
<p><strong>evacuate</strong> - v. to remove people from a dangerous place</p>
<p><strong>nightmare</strong> - n. a very bad and frightening situation</p>
<p><strong>scream</strong> - v. to suddenly cry out because of pain and fear</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Does the Song, ‘This Is Me’ Mean?  (2023/8/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/what-does-the-song-this-is-me-mean.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dr. Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello. This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will explain parts of a song for a listener.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>I have a song I want you to explain. It is <em>This Is Me</em> from the <em>Greatest Showman.</em></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ad6e-08db945b5327_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Masafumi, Japan</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Dear Masfumi,</p>
<p>Thanks for writing to us. The song you asked about is from a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CjxugyZCfuw" target="_self">2017 movie about P.T. Barnum</a>. He started his circus, a traveling show featuring unusual animals and people, in 1870. He gathered performers of all kinds for the show. One was a very small man. Another was a very tall woman. A woman named Josephine Clofullia had a beard; her face was covered with long hair. In her act people called her a "bearded lady."</p>
<p>In the movie, Hugh Jackman plays the part of P.T. Barnum. One of his lines in the movie expresses his view of the unusual people he employs: "Every one of us is special, and nobody is like anyone else. That's the point of my show."</p>
<p>The actor who sings the song <em>This Is Me</em> in the movie is Keala Settle. She plays the character Lettie Lutz, a bearded lady, in <em>The Greatest Showman.</em></p>
<p><strong>Song meaning</strong></p>
<p>Now that you know about where the song appears and who sings it, let us look at its meaning. The song is about strength in the face of criticism. The singer confirms her individuality and self-acceptance.</p>
<p>Here are the words of the song showing its basic meaning. First, the criticism:</p>
<p><em>Hide away, they say<br/>
'Cause we don't want your broken parts<br/>
I've learned to be ashamed of all my scars<br/>
Run away, they say<br/>
No one will love you as you are</em></p>
<p>Next, her resistance to it and self-acceptance:</p>
<p><em>When the sharpest words wanna cut me down<br/>
I'm gonna send a flood, gonna drown them out<br/>
I am brave, I am <strong>bruised</strong><br/>
I am who I'm meant to be, this is me</em></p>
<p>To be "bruised" can mean to have marks on one's skin from a blow. But it can also mean a person received an emotional injury. Another image we can draw from the song's words is the person who hears a "different drummer" and marches, or moves forward, to that beat.</p>
<p><em>Look out 'cause here I come<br/>
And I'm marching on to the beat I drum<br/>
I'm not scared to be seen<br/>
I make no apologies, this is me</em></p>
<p>The song uses a common expression about a person who does not follow the expected path. That person is "marching to the beat of a different drummer."</p>
<p>In one part of the song, the singer uses "we" to include all of the unusual performers in the show.</p>
<p><em>We are bursting through the <strong>barricades</strong><br/>
And reaching for the sun (we are warriors)<br/>
Yeah, that's what we've become</em></p>
<p><strong>Connection to social issues</strong></p>
<p>I hope this answers your question, Masafumi. You may also find it interesting to know that Barnum was against the practice of slavery before it became illegal in this country. And the ideas presented in the movie <em>The</em> <em>Greatest Showman </em>are being debated today.</p>
<p>Do you have a question for us? Write to us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a> and we will try to answer you in another <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>And I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Dr. Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bruised </strong><em>– adj.</em> injured in a way that causes discoloration to the skin</p>
<p><strong>barricade</strong> – <em>n. </em>a line of vehicles or other objects placed across a road or open space to stop people from getting past, for example, during street fighting or as a protest</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Economists Wonder If Few or Many Will Benefit from AI  (2023/8/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/economists-wonder-if-few-or-many-will-benefit-from-ai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Throughout history, technological progress has brought new wealth but has not always improved people's lives. Economists now say it is not clear whether artificial intelligence (AI) will help or hurt society.</p>
<p>Simon Johnson teaches economics at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology near Boston. He said AI has a lot of possibilities. But he added, "We are at a fork in the road." A fork in the road is an expression used to describe a situation where the <strong>outcome</strong> is uncertain.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An AI (Artificial Intelligence) sign is seen at the World Artificial Intelligence Conference (WAIC) in Shanghai, China July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/aa9b225a-fb1a-48ca-84e5-f493a15b741f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An AI (Artificial Intelligence) sign is seen at the World Artificial Intelligence Conference (WAIC) in Shanghai, China July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo)</span></div>
<p><strong>Wealth, jobs and productivity</strong></p>
<p>McKinsey is a business <strong>consulting</strong> company. It said AI could add between $14 trillion and $22 trillion of value to the world's economy.</p>
<p>Supporters say the technology will create wealth and improve living <strong>standards</strong>. Some go as far as saying AI will increase people's free time and help them be more creative.</p>
<p>But others are worried the technology will lead to lost jobs. They point to Hollywood writers and actors who are worried that they will be replaced by technology.</p>
<p>The internet arrived with a similar promise of more productivity, wealth and jobs. Last month, the French bank Natixis noted in its research that most of the wealth has gone to a few billionaires. And many of the jobs do not require highly paid, skilled workers.</p>
<p>The bank warned in its report, "We should be <strong>cautious</strong> when estimating the effects of artificial intelligence on labor productivity."</p>
<p>In July, the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development released its opinion research of 5,300 workers about AI. Some workers hope the technology will increase pay and job satisfaction. But they are also concerned that the technology could push people to work too hard.</p>
<p><strong>Lessons from history</strong></p>
<p>Such concerns are not unfounded. History has shown the economic impact of technological progress is generally uncertain, unequal and even harmful.</p>
<p>Johnson recently published a book, <em>Power and Progress,</em> with Daron Acemoglu, another economist from MIT. They studied technological progress over the last 1,000 years including clothing production, train travel, and even food shopping.</p>
<p>The two economists looked at an invention called the spinning jenny that made it easier to turn cotton and wool into <strong>yarn</strong>. They said the device helped clothing production and created wealth for many people in the late 1700s. However, it also increased the demand for cotton and led to longer hours for workers. The demand also led to the growth of slavery in the southern United States.</p>
<p>Johnson noted that it is easier to create something new than to make sure it works for everyone. His book shows how the arrival of rail travel improved the lives of many people in England in the 1800s. People were able to travel longer distances and eat fresh food because it could move faster from farms to cities.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Johnson said <strong>self-checkout</strong> technology at food stores does not lower the cost or make life easier for people. All it does is reduce the number of workers and help businesses lower labor costs.</p>
<p>As for AI technology, Johnson wonders if it will make existing inequalities worse, or "could it help us get back to something fairer?"</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>outcome</strong> <em>–n. </em>the result of an event or choice</p>
<p><strong>consulting</strong> <em>–n. </em>a business based on doing research and providing suggestions to another company about how to be more successful</p>
<p><strong>standards</strong> <em>–n. </em>a level of quality</p>
<p><strong>cautious</strong> <em>–n. </em>careful</p>
<p><strong>yarn</strong> <em>–n. </em>fibers of plants or animal hair that a refined and used to make clothing, fabrics or floor coverings</p>
<p><strong>self-checkout</strong> <em>–n. </em>a machine or system at a food store that permits customers to pay for items without help from anyone else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Schools Lost Track of Homeless Kids during Pandemic  (2023/8/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/schools-lost-track-of-homeless-kids-during-pandemic.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>During the coronavirus pandemic, many schools struggled to keep a count of students whose families struggled with homelessness.</p>
<p>The number of children identified as homeless by schools nationwide dropped by 21 percent from the 2018-2019 school year to the 2020-2021 school year, federal data found. That decrease represented more than 288,000 students.</p>
<p>But it is likely there were many students whose schools did not know they were homeless.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Aaliyah Ibarra and fellow students work on their computers during the last week of classes at Frye Elementary School in Chandler, Ariz., Tuesday, May 23, 2023. (AP Photo/Darryl Webb)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-79fa-08db98dfa18b_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Aaliyah Ibarra and fellow students work on their computers during the last week of classes at Frye Elementary School in Chandler, Ariz., Tuesday, May 23, 2023. (AP Photo/Darryl Webb)</span></div>
<p>By the time Aaliyah Ibarra started second grade, her family had moved five times in four years in search of housing. As she was about to start a new school, her mother, Bridget Ibarra, saw how much it was affecting Aaliyah's education.</p>
<p>At 8 years old, Aaliyah did not know the alphabet. Her family's struggles came during the COVID-19 pandemic, which forced Aaliyah to begin school online.</p>
<p>Online school was especially hard for Aaliyah because she was homeless. And, like thousands of other students across the country, her school did not know.</p>
<p>By not being identified as homeless, such students lose out on important support like transportation, clothes-cleaning services and other help.</p>
<p>Two years later, the effects have worsened. Students nationwide have struggled to make up for missed learning. And educators have lost important time identifying who needs the most help.</p>
<p>Schools are offering services like <strong>tutoring</strong> and counseling. But schools now have limited time left to spend federal pandemic assistance money for homeless students, said Barbara Duffield. She is director of SchoolHouse Connection, a national homelessness organization.</p>
<p>Many education leaders, Duffield said, do not even know about federal money meant to support homeless students. The federal support ends next year.</p>
<p>In Bridget Ibarra's case, she chose not to tell the school her children were homeless. She said that teachers never asked. She was worried if officials knew the family was staying in a shelter, the family would face pressure to attend a different school that was closer to the shelter.</p>
<p>The <strong>stigma</strong> that comes with homelessness also can lead families not to tell anyone they do not have housing, Duffield said.</p>
<p>If schools cannot identify homeless children, "we can't <strong>ensure</strong> that they have everything they need to be successful in school and even go to school," Duffield added.</p>
<p>Aaliyah's school is in Phoenix, Arizona. It continued with online learning for her whole <strong>kindergarten</strong> year. Aaliyah and her older brother spent most of their school days on computers in a temporary classroom at the shelter.</p>
<p>While the shelter helped the family meet their basic needs, Ibarra said she often asked the school for extra help for her daughter. She felt the school was giving all its attention to Aaliyah's older brother because he is a special education student. That means he has been identified as needing extra educational support.</p>
<p>The school's principal, Sean Hannafin, said school officials met often with the children's mom. He said they offered the support they had available. But he said it was hard to know online which students required more help.</p>
<p>There is a federal law aimed at making sure homeless students have equal <strong>access</strong> to education. The law provides rights and services to children without a "fixed, regular and <strong>adequate</strong> nighttime <strong>residence</strong>."</p>
<p>Many students are not identified as homeless when they sign up for school. At school, teachers or other school workers often notice students who may be dealing with difficulties at home. But with children learning online, teachers often could not see signs of problems.</p>
<p>Overall, the drop in the student homelessness count began before the pandemic. But it became greater when the pandemic began.</p>
<p>The percentage of enrolled students identified as homeless in the U.S. dropped from 2.7 percent in 2018-2019 to 2.2 percent in 2020-2021. Over that time, Arizona had one of the biggest drops in the number of students identified as homeless.</p>
<p>Eventually, Bridget Ibarra had to send Aaliyah to a different school after moving to find new housing. At Aaliyah's new school, Frye Elementary, Principal Alexis Cruz Freeman saw how hard it was to communicate with families when children were not in classrooms.</p>
<p>Aaliyah has improved at her new school, Cruz Freeman said. She still has trouble saying and reading some words. But by the end of the school year, she was able to read a <strong>text</strong> and write four sentences based on its meaning. She is also performing at her grade level in math.</p>
<p>Cruz Freeman considers Aaliyah a success story in part because of her mother's support. "She was an <strong>advocate</strong> for her children, which is all that we can ever ask for," Cruz Freeman said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor </strong><em>— n. </em>a teacher who works with one student</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stigma </strong><em>— n. </em> a set of negative and often unfair beliefs that a society or group of people have about something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>kindergarten </strong><em>— n. </em>a school or class for very young children</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adequate </strong><em>— adj. </em>enough for some need or requirement</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>text </strong><em>— n. </em>the original words of a piece of writing or a speech</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>residence </strong><em>— n. </em> the state of living in a particular place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ensure </strong><em>— n. </em>to make sure, certain, or safe</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access </strong><em>— adj. </em>a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>advocate </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who argues for or supports a cause or policy</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>DNA of Enslaved Iron Workers Gives Light to African American History  (2023/8/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/dna-of-enslaved-iron-workers-gives-light-to-african-american-history.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Not far from Camp David, a U.S. presidential base in Maryland, lie the remains of an iron workshop called Catoctin Furnace. The workshop dates back to the late 18th century. It is an important place for understanding the start of the Industrial Revolution in early U.S. history.</p>
<p>The site is also providing researchers with a greater understanding of African American history. A new study examined <strong>DNA</strong> from the remains of 27 individuals found in a burial place at Catoctin Furnace for enslaved people.</p>
<p>The study <strong>revealed</strong> the ancestry of some of the enslaved people who were forced to work there in the years after the nation's founding. It also identified thousands of living relatives. Many of the relatives still live in Maryland.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="A view of the site of the Catoctin Furnace, an iron forge where enslaved people of African descent once worked, in Cunningham Falls State Park in Maryland, U.S., in this undated photograph. (Aneta Kaluzna/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8f4d511e-bb79-4a6e-b5a6-1487c35dabf1_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">A view of the site of the Catoctin Furnace, an iron forge where enslaved people of African descent once worked, in Cunningham Falls State Park in Maryland, U.S., in this undated photograph. (Aneta Kaluzna/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The burial site was used from 1774 to 1850. The remains were removed from the site in the 1970s so that a road could be built. Since then, the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C. has kept the remains. They include 16 males and 11 females. Some are very young children, while others are older adults.</p>
<p>Researchers found that the 27 individuals <strong>descended from</strong> just a few African populations, mainly West Africa's Wolof and Mandinka peoples and Central Africa's Kongo people. And they have strong genetic connections to present-day populations in Senegal, Gambia, Angola and the Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>Millions of people were forcibly taken from Africa to the Americas from the 16th to 19th century in the transatlantic slave trade. A lack of documentation about these people has left descendants with little information about their own family history.</p>
<p>Kari Bruwelheide is a researcher with the Smithsonian's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, D.C. She helped write the study, which appeared last week in the publication <em>Science. </em></p>
<p>Bruwelheide said, "This knowledge was <strong>severed</strong> by slavery – a truth that has implications for African Americans far beyond the community of Catoctin Furnace."</p>
<p>She added that the study shows the power of genetic research to rebuild some of what was destroyed by a lack of record-keeping.</p>
<p>Enslaved people of African descent were forced to work in agricultural, industrial, and home settings in parts of the United States. Slavery ended with the U.S. Civil War, which was fought from 1861 to 1865.</p>
<p>Catoctin Furnace is a few kilometers from Camp David in Cunningham Falls State Park. It grew into a village area, with industrial buildings and housing.</p>
<p>Workers mined iron, kept fires burning to melt the iron and made different kinds of goods. The goods they made included stoves, pots and even cannon balls. Enslaved people were the main part of the work force until paying European immigrants to work there became less costly by the mid-19th century.</p>
<p>For the study, the researchers examined historical DNA alongside genetic testing company 23andMe's personal ancestry database. Through their efforts, they identified 41,799 Americans related to the 27 individuals.</p>
<p>Eadaoin Harney was the lead study writer. She is also a 23andMe population geneticist. She said, "Enslaved African Americans are largely excluded from the historical record, and in documents where they are <strong>mentioned</strong>, they are often treated as property, not as people."</p>
<p>The study found some European ancestry in most of the 27 individuals. That finding supports records of sexual abuse of enslaved people by their enslavers and others. It found that some of the 27 had possible genes for genetic conditions like sickle cell anemia and G6PD <strong>deficiency</strong>. Genetic conditions involving red blood cell problems are still common among African Americans.</p>
<p>Kathryn Barca is a Smithsonian researcher and a writer of the study. She said, "The experiences of African Americans within the early industrial complex of the United States are not completely understood and their labors in this system have not been <strong>thoroughly</strong> explored or acknowledged."</p>
<p>Barca added, "We hope this paper gives voice to these 27 individuals..."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>DNA </strong>– <em>n.</em> a substance that carries genetic information in the cells of plants and animals</p>
<p><strong>reveal </strong>– <em>v.</em> to make (something) known</p>
<p><strong>descend from </strong>– <em>phr. v.</em> to have (something or someone in the past) as an origin or source</p>
<p><strong>sever </strong>– <em>v.</em> to end (a relationship or connection) completely</p>
<p><strong>mention </strong>– <em>v.</em> to talk about, write about, or refer to (something or someone) especially in a brief way</p>
<p><strong>deficiency </strong>– <em>n.</em> a lack of something that is needed</p>
<p><strong>thorough </strong>– <em>adj.</em> including every possible part or detail</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Cleaning  (2023/8/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/grammar-and-cleaning.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Whether you enjoy it or not, cleaning is an activity that all of us have to do from time to time.</p>
<p>As a result, we should explore how to talk about it.</p>
<p>In this <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, you will learn about different kinds of verbs we use to talk about cleaning.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0037-08db99bfc675_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar</span></div>
<p><strong>Group of verbs </strong></p>
<p>Let's start with the verb "clean."</p>
<p>We can think of "clean" as a kind of general term for many activities. For example, a person might say:</p>
<p><em>"I am cleaning my house."</em></p>
<p>Aside from "clean," we can use a number of more exact verbs. For example, we have "sweep," "vacuum," "wash," and "dust."</p>
<p>Let's explore each of these in turn.</p>
<p>We use the verb "sweep" when we remove dust or dirt with a <strong>broom</strong>.<br/>
We use "vacuum" when we clean something with a special device known as a vacuum cleaner.</p>
<p>We use "wash" when we clean something with water and soap.</p>
<p>We use "dust" when we make something clean by wiping the surface, often with cloth.</p>
<p>So, we have a group of verbs. "Clean" is the widest in meaning; the others describe more exact activities - "sweep," "vacuum," "dust," and so on.</p>
<p><strong>Important </strong></p>
<p>You might be asking yourself how this discussion connects with grammar.</p>
<p>The question leads us to an important point. We have a group of verbs. These verbs are interesting because all of them can be used in a transitive or an intransitive sense.</p>
<p>Transitive means to take a direct object. Intransitive means to not take a direct object.</p>
<p>What this means is that the verbs we have explored – clean, sweep, dust, and so on - have some sense of flexibility in how they can be used.</p>
<p>Let's clarify.</p>
<p>Think back to the sentence you heard earlier:</p>
<p><em>"I am cleaning my house."</em></p>
<p>In the example, we have the subject, "I," the present progressive form "am cleaning," and the object, "my house." In this sentence, we can say that the verb "clean" is followed by an object.</p>
<p>But we could also say:</p>
<p><em>"I am cleaning."</em></p>
<p>In this example, we do not have an object.</p>
<p>Now, let us take some of the other verbs we explored earlier. They all follow the same general idea.</p>
<p>The verb "sweep" might be used with an object, as in:</p>
<p><em>"She swept the floor."</em></p>
<p>Or without an object, as in:</p>
<p><em>"She swept."</em></p>
<p>The same idea is true of "vacuum," where a person might say:</p>
<p><em>"I vacuumed the living room."</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>"I vacuumed."</em></p>
<p>The main difference between the statements is in the amount of shared information. If the speaker and listener both know what is being discussed, then the object is not necessary. If the listener does not know what is being discussed, then the speaker might need to include the object.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas.</p>
<p>Make a sentence using the present progressive form of the verb "dust." Be sure to use the object, "the <strong>bookshelf</strong>."</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here is one answer:</p>
<p><em>"I am dusting the bookshelf."</em></p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>Today, you learned a few basic ideas that are important for talking about cleaning. You learned some related verbs and how to use them with or without an object. The next step will be to develop more complex sentences that involve adverbs and prepositions. But that will have to be the subject of a future report.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>_________________________________</strong></h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in The Story</h2>
<p><strong>broom </strong><em>– n.</em> a brush that has a long handle and that is used for sweeping floors</p>
<p><strong>bookshelf</strong><em> – n.</em> a shelf that is used for books</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Game Maker Bans Use of AI in Artwork Design  (2023/8/10) | 游戏公司禁止设计师使用人工智能设计插图</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/game-maker-bans-use-of-ai-in-artwork-design.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A major American game maker has banned designers from using artificial intelligence (AI) tools to create artwork for its games.<br/>
美国一家大型游戏制造商禁止设计师使用人工智能工具为其游戏创作插图。</p>
<p>The company, Wizards of the Coast, owns the product collection for the popular game Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D). The role-playing game, set in an imaginary world, was first launched in 1974.<br/>
这家名为“海岸奇才”的公司拥有热门游戏《龙与地下城》的产品系列。这款角色扮演游戏设定在一个虚构的世界，于1974年首次推出。</p>
<p>Toy manufacturer Hasbro is the parent company of Wizards of the Coast and the related company D&amp;D Beyond. Officials at D&amp;D Beyond said they did not find out until recently that one of its artists used AI to create artwork for an upcoming book. The company said in a statement it had talked to the artist involved.<br/>
玩具制造商孩之宝公司是海岸奇才公司和关联公司D&amp;D Beyond的母公司。D&amp;D Beyond公司的官员表示，他们直到最近才发现，该公司的一位艺术家使用人工智能为一本即将出版的书籍创作了插图。该公司在声明中称已与相关艺术家进行了交谈。</p>
<p>D&amp;D Beyond said the artist – who had worked for the company for more than 10 years – had agreed to no longer use AI tools for artistic designs. The company said it is also examining its current AI rules.<br/>
D&amp;D Beyond公司表示，这位在该公司工作了10多年的艺术家已同意不再使用人工智能工具进行艺术设计。该公司称其也在审查目前的人工智能规则。</p>
<p>Some D&amp;D fans discovered the AI-developed art in the series.<br/>
一些D&amp;D爱好者在该系列中发现了人工智能开发的插图。</p>
<p>Hasbro bought D&amp;D Beyond for $146.3 million last year. The Rhode Island-based toy company has owned Wizards of the Coast for more than 20 years.<br/>
去年，孩之宝公司以1.463亿美元收购了D&amp;D Beyond公司。这家总部位于罗德岛州的玩具公司拥有海岸奇才公司已经20多年了。</p>
<p>The AI artwork in question was part of a soon-to-be-released book of creature descriptions and lore called Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants. The digital and physical versions of the game are set for release August 15.<br/>
存在问题的人工智能插图是即将出版的一本名为《Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants》的生物描述和传说书籍的一部分。该游戏的数字版和实体版定于8月15日发布。</p>
<p>The use of AI tools to assist with creative work has raised copyright and labor concerns across a number of industries. The issue is part of what is fueling the current Hollywood strike. It also led the music industry organization, the Recording Academy, to change the rules of its Grammy Awards process.<br/>
使用人工智能工具协助创造性工作引起了许多行业对版权和人工的担忧。这个问题是助长当前好莱坞罢工的部分原因。它还导致音乐产业组织“唱片学院”改变了格莱美颁奖程序的规则。</p>
<p>Some artists have brought legal action against AI companies for using their work without permission.<br/>
一些艺术家对人工智能公司未经许可使用其作品提起法律诉讼。</p>
<p>The Associated Press reported that Hasbro competitor Mattel had used AI-created images to help come up with ideas for a new Hot Wheels toy car. The news agency noted, however, that Mattel has not said exactly how it is using AI in product development.<br/>
美联社报道称，孩之宝公司的竞争对手美泰公司使用人工智能创建的图像来帮助想出设计新的风火轮玩具车的构思。然而，该通讯社指出，美泰没有确切说明它在产品开发中如何使用人工智能。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>World Cup Money Is Life-changing for Some Players  (2023/8/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/world-cup-money-is-life-changing-for-some-players.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The players who reached the <strong>knockout</strong> round of the Women's World Cup received larger individual <strong>bonuses</strong> than those of the past. The increased earnings can be life-changing for many of the players.</p>
<p>FIFA, the world's soccer organizing body, pays $30,000 for the 732 players among 32 teams in the 2023 World Cup. The amount rises to $60,000 for players on the 16 teams that <strong>advance</strong> out of group play.</p>
<p>The amount grows to $90,000 for players in the <strong>quarterfinals</strong>. That is a major payday, especially for the many players who have had pay disputes with their soccer organizations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Jamaican players celebrate at the end of the Women's World Cup soccer match between Panama and Jamaica in Perth, Australia, Saturday, July 29, 2023. Jamaica won 1-0. (AP Photo/Gary Day)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-84e9-08db9080e5ed_cx6_cy1_cw80_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Jamaican players celebrate at the end of the Women's World Cup soccer match between Panama and Jamaica in Perth, Australia, Saturday, July 29, 2023. Jamaica won 1-0. (AP Photo/Gary Day)</span></div>
<p>Hildah Magaia is on South Africa's team, and was a big part of its advance out of group play into the knockout round. The team calls Magaia "Breadwinner." The term is often used to describe someone who earns the money needed to support their family.</p>
<p>The South African players doubled their payout. Magaia says she plans to use the money to care for her mother.</p>
<p>"I'll be able to do everything for my mother because I'm the one who's taking care of her," she said. "I'm the breadwinner, so I'll be doing everything for my mom."</p>
<p>Deneisha Blackwood plays for Jamaica. It lost to Colombia in the knockouts. She said the <strong>minimum</strong> pay was a good start for her team, which has had serious financial difficulties.</p>
<p>"A lot of us have bills to pay and family to take care of," Blackwood said, "and I think for the younger generation, especially, football doesn't make you a lot of money. So for (girls) to see us doing what we love and realize that you can make a living off it — it's <strong>motivational</strong>."</p>
<p>In June, FIFA said it would provide $110 million in prize money for players of the Women's World Cup. FIFA President Gianni Infantino said the money would be sent to soccer's governing bodies, called federations. They would be responsible for awarding it. Infantino said he could not guarantee that the money would reach the players.</p>
<p>FIFPRO is an organization that represents international players. The organization said late Tuesday that it was assisting Nigeria's national team players in a dispute with their federation concerning earnings dating back as far as 2021.</p>
<p>"The team is extremely <strong>frustrated</strong> that they've had to <strong>pursue</strong> the Nigeria Football Federation for these payments before and during the <strong>tournament</strong>," FIFPRO said. "It is regrettable that players needed to <strong>challenge</strong> their own federation at such an important time in their careers."</p>
<p>Before the World Cup, South African players boycotted a game against Botswana because bonuses were not included in their contracts. Patrice Motsepe, president of the African Football Confederation, agreed to give $320,000 to the players to be divided equally. The dispute was settled.</p>
<p>Nigerian player Uchenna Kanu said the money was not the team's main goal --- playing well was.</p>
<p>"But of course, if we get paid that much money, of course, it'll have a huge<strong> impact</strong> on our lives," Kanu said. "We have families, we have things to take care of with money. That's important for us as well."</p>
<p>The total prize money at this Women's World Cup is more than three times the $30 million that was paid out at the 2019 Women's World Cup in France. But it is still far less than the $440 million in prize money for the Men's World Cup in Qatar last year.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Anne Peterson reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>knockout</strong> - n. in soccer, a team is out of the tournament after a loss in the knockout round</p>
<p><strong>bonus</strong> - n. extra amount of money</p>
<p><strong>advance</strong> - v. to move forward</p>
<p><strong>quarterfinal</strong> - n. a round in a competition with four teams left</p>
<p><strong>minimum</strong> - n. the lowest number</p>
<p><strong>motivational</strong> - adj. causing someone to do something</p>
<p><strong>frustrated</strong> - adj. discouraged or upset</p>
<p><strong>pursue</strong> - v. try to get to</p>
<p><strong>tournament</strong> - n. a sports competition</p>
<p><strong>challenge</strong> - v. dispute</p>
<p><strong>impact</strong> - n. major influence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Asian, African Nations Join Amazon Meeting to Preserve Rainforests  (2023/8/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/asian-african-nations-join-amazon-meeting-to-preserve-rainforests.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Representatives of nations with rainforests in Asia and Africa joined leaders from eight Amazon-area countries for a meeting in Brazil on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The nations will produce a statement called "United for our Forests" to be presented at COP 28 in November. COP 28 is the United Nations climate change conference and it will be held in the Middle Eastern city of Dubai.</p>
<p>The eight South American countries, known as the Amazon Cooperation Treaty Organization (ACTO), opened the meeting on Tuesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Leaders pose for a group photo during the Amazon Summit at the Hangar Convention Center in Belem, Brazil, Wednesday, Aug. 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/65164352-e4ad-40fc-a268-94f9ab9f9755_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Leaders pose for a group photo during the Amazon Summit at the Hangar Convention Center in Belem, Brazil, Wednesday, Aug. 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres)</span></div>
<p>The ACTO includes Brazil, Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador, Guyana, Peru, Suriname and Venezuela. The nations agreed to work on developing their economies without harming the rainforest to a "point of no return."</p>
<p>Representatives also came from the Republic of Congo, the Democratic Republic of Congo, Indonesia and the French territory of Guiana. The president of Norway, a contributor to the Amazon fund for <strong>sustainable</strong> development, also joined.</p>
<p>Scientists say when 20 to 25 percent of the Amazon rainforest is destroyed, it will reduce rainfall and change the environment. The land will get drier and many kinds of plants and animals will die out.</p>
<p>Some environmental activists, however, criticized Tuesday's event, saying the countries did not create a plan with clear goals and <strong>deadlines</strong>.</p>
<p>Brazil's president is Luiz Inacio "Lula" da Silva. In his third term as leader, he is working to save the Amazon. A study last month showed his efforts caused a 42 percent drop in <strong>deforestation</strong> in only seven months.</p>
<p>The Amazon stretches across an area twice the size of India. Two-thirds of it lies in Brazil, with seven other countries and French Guiana sharing the remaining third.</p>
<p>Until recently, critics say South American governments saw the rainforest as a resource for materials they could use to grow their economies. Trees were cleared for cattle, companies drilled for oil and mined the land for minerals and metals, and cities and roads were built through the forest. <strong>Indigenous</strong> people lost their land and plants and animals became <strong>endangered</strong>.</p>
<p>All the Amazon nations signed the 2015 Paris climate agreement to reduce pollution. But experts say the countries have had problems working together. They say the latest agreement should require all nations to end deforestation by 2030. So far, only Brazil and Colombia agreed on that deadline.</p>
<p>The nations are also divided on oil drilling in the Amazon. Colombian leader Gustavo Petro called for an end to oil exploration but other nations are not sure they want to follow.</p>
<p>The ACTO meeting, however, did receive support from one Indigenous leader, Fany Kuiru of Colombia. Kuiru praised the group for recognizing the rights of native people to traditional lands and opening a way for indigenous people to participate.</p>
<p>In a discussion on Tuesday, da Silva said the Amazon is a "passport to a new relationship with the world" where its resources can be "valued and put in the service of everyone."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong>–<em>adj</em>. able to continue for a long time without harming the environment</p>
<p><strong>deadline </strong><em>–n.</em><em> </em>a time that a project must be completed by<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>deforestation</strong> <em>–n. </em>the act of removing trees for a forest so the land can be used for something else, or the trees can be used for lumber</p>
<p><strong>indigenous</strong> <em>–n. </em>people who originally lived in a land</p>
<p><strong>endangered</strong> <em>–adj. </em>at risk of dying out</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Health Care Is One of America’s Most Violent Fields  (2023/8/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/health-care-is-one-of-america-s-most-violent-fields.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A wave of violence is increasingly affecting American hospitals and medical centers.</p>
<p>Recent attacks at such places make health care one of the nation's most violent industries. Data shows American health care workers experience more non-deadly injuries from workplace violence than workers in any other profession -- including law enforcement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Northside Hospital Midtown where a man killed one and wounded four on May 3, 2023. (Arvin Temkar/Atlanta Journal-Constitution via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4f3a-08db98487e0e_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Northside Hospital Midtown where a man killed one and wounded four on May 3, 2023. (Arvin Temkar/Atlanta Journal-Constitution via AP)</span></div>
<p>Michael D'Angelo is a former police officer. He now works as a security adviser in Florida. His work centers on health care and workplace violence. He said, "health care workers don't even think about" risks to their safety when they decide to become a nurse or doctor.</p>
<p>But, he added, "health care is four or five times more dangerous than any other profession."</p>
<p>Several mass shootings have taken place in hospitals across the country.</p>
<p>In June of last year, a gunman killed his doctor and three other people at a medical office in Tulsa, Oklahoma. The gunman said he blamed the doctor for his continuing pain after an operation.</p>
<p>In October of last year, a man killed two workers at a hospital in Dallas, Texas, while he was there for his child's birth.</p>
<p>This past May, a man opened fire in a medical center waiting room in Atlanta, Georgia. One woman died and four other people were wounded.</p>
<p>And late last month, a gunman shot and killed a security guard at Legacy Good Samaritan Medical Center in Portland, Oregon. Police later shot and killed the suspect, who was at the hospital for his child's birth.</p>
<p>Hospitals and medical centers are trying to create a safer environment for workers.</p>
<p>Legacy Health said it plans to add more metal detectors at all of its medical centers. It also plans to require bag searches at every hospital and send patients and visitors to controlled entrances. Legacy Health also said it will provide more officers with <strong>stun</strong> <strong>guns</strong> and will add protective measures from bullets to some glass at main entrances.</p>
<p>The American Nurses Association says around 40 states have passed laws creating or increasing punishment for violence against health care workers. And some states, including Indiana, Ohio, and Georgia, let hospitals create their own police forces.</p>
<p>Critics say private hospital police can worsen the health care and policing inequalities already experienced by Black people. They also say private police forces often do not have to release information such as how often they use force or if they detain members of a minority group more often.</p>
<p>Deborah Burger is a registered nurse and president of National Nurses United. She said security teams cannot change the reasons leading to violence. Many of the reasons exist because of the country's problematic health care system, she said.</p>
<p>Patients and families are often <strong>frustrated</strong> by high medical bills, limited treatment choices and long wait times.</p>
<p>"Hospitals don't really have a <strong>complaints</strong> department, so the only real target they have is the nurse or <strong>staff</strong> that are standing right in front of them," she said.</p>
<p>Worker shortages mean nurses are forced to care for more patients. That means less time to examine each one for behavior problems. Burger said efforts to calm an aggressive patient are not as effective if nurses have not been able to spend enough time to build a relationship with patients.</p>
<p>Some hospitals tell their staff to try to make peace with aggressive visitors and patients. Hospital leaders want to avoid getting bad <strong>reviews</strong> from patients, Burger said. That is because the Affordable Care Act has tied part of federal repayment rates to patient <strong>satisfaction</strong> <strong>survey</strong> results. Low satisfaction means less money for the hospitals.</p>
<p>D'Angelo, the former police officer, said, "The results of those surveys should never take <strong>priority</strong> over staff safety."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Rebecca Boone reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stun gun </strong>– <em>n.</em> a gun that produces an electric shock which makes someone unconscious or stops someone from moving</p>
<p><strong>frustrated </strong>– <em>adj.</em> very angry, discouraged, or upset because of being unable to do or complete something</p>
<p><strong>complaint </strong>– <em>n.</em> a statement that you are unhappy or not satisfied with something</p>
<p><strong>staff </strong>– <em>n.</em> a group of people who work for an organization or business</p>
<p><strong>review </strong>– <em>n.</em> a report that gives someone's opinion about the quality of a book, performance, or product</p>
<p><strong>satisfaction </strong>– <em>n.</em> a result that deals with a problem or complaint in an acceptable way</p>
<p><strong>survey </strong>– <em>n.</em> an activity in which many people are asked a question or a series of questions in order to gather information about what most people do or think about something</p>
<p><strong>priority </strong>– <em>n.</em> the condition of being more important than something or someone else and therefore coming or being dealt with first</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Niger Rejects Diplomatic Efforts To Bring Order  (2023/8/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/niger-rejects-diplomatic-efforts-to-bring-order.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Niger's military rulers have rejected the latest diplomatic attempt to return to power the country's ousted president.</p>
<p>The <strong>coup</strong> leaders refused to meet with a delegation of West African, African Union and United Nations representatives. In a letter Tuesday, the new rulers said a "climate of threatened aggression" made it impossible to hold talks on ending the constitutional crisis in Niger.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mohamed Toumba, one of the soldiers who ousted Nigerian President Mohamed Bazoum, addresses supporters of Niger's ruling junta in Niamey, Niger, Sunday, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Sam Mednick)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2a9e-08db983a2ff1_cx0_cy12_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mohamed Toumba, one of the soldiers who ousted Nigerian President Mohamed Bazoum, addresses supporters of Niger's ruling junta in Niamey, Niger, Sunday, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Sam Mednick)</span></div>
<p>The crisis began on July 26, when members of the presidential guard seized control of the government. They detained and continue to hold the democratically-elected leader of Niger, President Mohamed Bazoum and his family.</p>
<p>The West African political and economic organization, ECOWAS, threatened military intervention in Niger unless Bazoum was returned to power by August 6. ECOWAS stands for Economic Community of West African States.</p>
<p>Earlier, a top U.S diplomatic official visited Niger to urge the military rulers to restore the democratically elected Bazoum to power.</p>
<p>U.S. Undersecretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland said she traveled to the capital Niamey "to express <strong>grave</strong> concern at the undemocratic attempts to seize power and urged a return to constitutional order." She made the comment on the social media site X, formerly Twitter.</p>
<p>Nuland told reporters in a conference call Monday that she met with Niger's self-appointed ruler Brigadier General Moussa Salaou Barmou and three other military officials during her visit. She described the talks as "extremely <strong>frank</strong> and at times, quite difficult."</p>
<p>She said the military officials are "quite firm" on how they plan to move forward and those plans do not "<strong>comport</strong> with the constitution of Niger." She said the officials refused her request to meet directly with ousted President Bazoum and his family, as well as coup leader General Abdourahamane Tchiani.</p>
<p>ECOWAS leaders are preparing for a meeting Thursday to discuss their situation with Niger's ruling military.</p>
<p>Niger is the world's seventh-biggest producer of uranium. Uranium is the most widely used fuel for nuclear energy, adding to its importance.</p>
<p>"There's no doubt that diplomacy is the best way to resolve this situation," American Secretary of State Antony Blinken told French radio station RFI.</p>
<p>He said the United States was backing ECOWAS efforts to bring order. He declined to comment on the future of about 1,100 U.S. troops in Niger. French, German and Italian troops are also present in the country.</p>
<p>Blinken later told the BBC he was worried that Russia's Wagner mercenaries were using the instability in Niger to strengthen their presence in the Sahel.</p>
<p>ECOWAS has ordered <strong>sanctions</strong> on Niger and Western allies have suspended aid.</p>
<p><strong>Residents</strong> of Niamey who spoke to <em>Reuters</em> were strongly supportive of the overthrow.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coup </strong><em>— n. </em> a sudden attempt by a small group of people to take over the government usually through violence</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grave </strong><em>— adj. </em>requiring or causing serious thought or concern</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>frank </strong><em>— adj. </em>used to say that someone is speaking or writing in a very direct and honest way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sanction </strong><em>— n. </em>an action that is taken or an order that is given to force a country to obey international laws by limiting or stopping trade with that country, by not allowing economic aid for that country, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>comport </strong><em>— v. </em>to behave in a certain way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>someone who lives in a particular place</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Letter-sound Connection (Phonics)  (2023/8/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-literacy-letter-sound-connection-(phonics).mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Phonics is where written language meets spoken language.</p>
<p>Phonics teaches students the relationship between the letters of written language and the sounds of spoken language. The goal of phonics is to help students learn how to use the alphabet to read and write words. It also helps them understand writing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Letter-sound Connection (Phonics) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-90dc-08db825b5fcb_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Letter-sound Connection (Phonics) </span></div>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for phonics</strong></p>
<p><u>Effective phonics instruction should:</u></p>
<ul style="margin-left:40px">
<li>include letter shapes and names</li>
<li>work with each separate sound in a word</li>
<li>include all major letter-sound relationships</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Teach phonics in a clear and direct way with a plan. </u></p>
<p>When you teach letter-sound relationships tell your students the goal of the lesson. Explain the learning strategies you plan to use. After you teach something such as words or spelling patterns, plan to use them often with your students. Use them in sentences, songs, or poems. Play games with them. Read texts and stories using words or letters. Practice writing them.</p>
<p><u>Teach the ABCs.</u></p>
<p>Singing the ABC Song is a great place to start. As you say each letter, point to it. This will help teach the connection between letters and sounds. Have them write letters early and often.</p>
<p><u>However, do not teach the alphabet in order from A to Z. </u></p>
<p>It is fine to say or sing the full alphabet in order. However, when you begin teaching individual letters, experts advise against teaching them in order. Teachers often start with this group of letters — s, a, t, i, p, n. They make more three-letter words than any other six letters. Have them write letters early and often.</p>
<p><u>Teach commonly confused letters or sounds separately. </u></p>
<p>Some English language learners confuse some letters. If that is the case with your students, teach them separately. Let the students master one letter sound before moving to a similar one. Some commonly confused letters are:</p>
<p>- b, d, p</p>
<p>- e, i</p>
<p>- m, n</p>
<p>- t, d</p>
<p>If a sound is written more than one way, teach the different spellings one at a time. For example, the long /a/ sound can be spelled several different ways. Try teaching its forms in order:</p>
<ul style="margin-left:40px">
<li>First, -ai as in "train;"</li>
<li>Next, -a_e as in "gate;"</li>
<li>Then, -ay as in "day;"</li>
<li>Finally, use them together in a game or activity.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Teach short vowel sounds first.</u> Words with short vowel sounds are usually easier to say and spell. At this stage, teach single-beat (<strong>syllable</strong>) words with short vowel sounds, like "sat" and "pat." However, short vowel sounds can be confusing. So, teach them separately.</p>
<p><u>Teach easy and common consonant letter sounds first.</u></p>
<p>Some consonants are easier than others. Usually, consonants that you can stretch out are easier to say – letters like m, s, and f.</p>
<p>With some consonant combinations you can hear each letter, such as fl, sp, tr, and st. (These are called <strong>blends</strong>. In the video for this article, you can hear them all.) Teach these with short vowel sounds, for example "flap," "spin," "trim," "step."</p>
<p>With some consonant combinations, the consonants become one sound, such as the /sh/ in "sheep." (These are called <strong>digraphs</strong>.) Teach common consonant combinations like ch, sh, and th. But keep in mind, some students may have a hard time with these.</p>
<p>For all of these suggestions, teachers must decide which sounds are easiest for their students.</p>
<p><strong>Learning strategies for teaching phonics</strong></p>
<p><u>Learning Strategy: Use all the senses.</u></p>
<p>Let the students see your face and mouth make the sounds. Use a mirror so the students can see their own mouths make sounds.</p>
<p>Have students touch their throats and say letter sounds. Some letters move the throat. Some letters do not move the throat.</p>
<p>Put a tissue in front of your face and show how some sounds make the tissue move while others do not.</p>
<p>Have students draw letters with their fingers while saying them. Students can draw letters in materials like sand or paint.</p>
<p>Students can also build letters with their bodies. Put students in groups. Give them a letter or they can pick a letter. Then they make the letter with their bodies.</p>
<p><u>Learning Strategy: Alphabet Matching</u></p>
<p>Young learners are just beginning to understand that there are relationships between written letters and spoken sounds. They are also learning that these relationships follow rules. They are learning the <strong>alphabetic principle</strong>.</p>
<p>Teachers can help students develop this understanding with fun activities that play with alphabet letters and sounds — for example, games that match lowercase and uppercase letters.</p>
<p><strong>Assessment for phonics</strong></p>
<p>Ask students questions about lesson material. Some assessments will be spoken, and some will be written.</p>
<p>Sample questions:</p>
<ul style="margin-left:40px">
<li>What sound do the letters "s" and "h" make when you put them together?</li>
<li>How do you spell the /sh/ sound?</li>
<li>How can I turn the word "bit" into "bite?"</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Ask students to pick out the following in a text:</u></p>
<ul style="margin-left:40px">
<li>uppercase and lowercase letters</li>
<li>consonant sounds and letters</li>
<li>long vowel sounds and letters</li>
<li>short vowel sounds and letters</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Read short vowel sounds in consonant-vowel-consonant words:</u></p>
<p>mat, cat, bag, bat</p>
<p><u>Read consonant combinations with short vowels:</u></p>
<p>flag, trim, brag</p>
<p><u>Read long vowel spellings:</u></p>
<p>- long /a/ sound spelled ai, ay, a_e</p>
<p>- long /e/ sound spelled ee</p>
<p><u>Read words with many syllables:</u></p>
<p>- treehouse</p>
<p>- rainbow</p>
<p>- bookbag</p>
<p>- syllable</p>
<p>Use these tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve you and your learners. Change them to fit your students and teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this article for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>syllable <em>–</em></strong><em>n.</em> <strong> </strong>a natural division of a word based on sound; a sound unit that makes up a word</p>
<p><strong>blend </strong><em>–n.</em> A blend is two consonants together that each make a sound. In the word "stop" the /s/ and the /t/ each make a sound.</p>
<p><strong>digraph </strong><em>–n.</em> A digraph has two letters but only one sound. In the word "shop" the /sh/ makes only one sound.</p>
<p><strong>alphabetic principle </strong><em>–n</em> the idea that there are systematic and predictable relationships between letters and the sounds they represent</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Data Shows Ocean Waves Getting Bigger, Stronger  (2023/8/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/new-data-shows-ocean-waves-getting-bigger-stronger.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>An ocean researcher at the University of California, San Diego says waves are getting bigger and stronger since 1970. There are also more "big wave events" than ever before.</p>
<p>A big wave is about four meters tall or more.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Large waves crash into a seawall in Pacifica, Calif., on Jan. 6, 2023. New data permits researchers to follow the growth of big waves over 90 years. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b550885e-485d-47ac-9f42-2d7415c902ac_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Large waves crash into a seawall in Pacifica, Calif., on Jan. 6, 2023. New data permits researchers to follow the growth of big waves over 90 years. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)</span></div>
<p>Peter Bromirski at the university's Scripps Institution of Oceanography looked at <strong>seismic</strong> records going back to 1931 in his research.</p>
<p>Seismic information is often used to measure the power of earthquakes. But Bromirski said large waves create enough energy to be measured by seismographs, also.</p>
<p>When large waves reach the shore, they bounce back and run into new waves. The crash sends energy through the ocean floor where it can be measured by seismographs.</p>
<p>Those measurements permitted Bromirski to judge the strength and size of waves over a period of 90 years.</p>
<p>Bromirski said he "<strong>stumbled upon</strong>" the seismographic information. Before the discovery, he said, "it was almost impossible" to compare waves from the past with those from the present.</p>
<p>It took a lot of work to put the data together. Much of the information was on paper. Bromirski and his team of student researchers had to put the information into a computer so they could examine the data. The slow process took years.</p>
<p>They found that the height of most waves in the winter along the California coast have grown by about 30 centimeters since 1970. Starting that year, waves of over 4 meters happened more often, as well. Between 1996 and 2016, the large waves happened twice as often as they did from 1949 to 1969.</p>
<p>Bromirski and his team published their research recently in the <em>Journal of Geophysical Research: Oceans.</em></p>
<p>1970 is the year scientists believe the warming of the planet began to speed up. Bromirski says the new data shows that climate change is making ocean waves taller and stronger. That means they are more likely to damage the coast, roads and structures, such as <strong>piers</strong> and houses.</p>
<p>Bromirski said his research may be a warning that bigger and stronger waves are ahead. With more warming, sea levels will rise and waves will get stronger, causing flooding and more damage to land. The California coast has already been damaged by big waves in recent years.</p>
<p>Gary Griggs is an ocean researcher at the University of California, Santa Cruz. He did not work on the study. He said a 30 centimeter increase in wave height over 50 years is not that large. However, the findings of the study support what scientists already know: waves are becoming stronger and causing more damage along coasts.</p>
<p>He said Bromirski's project adds to the data showing the world is warming fast and sea levels are rising.</p>
<p>"The <strong>challenge</strong>," he said, "is sort of how to really <strong>respond </strong>to that."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>seismic</strong> <em>–adj. </em>having to do with an earthquake or energy created by the shifting of the earth's surface</p>
<p><strong>stumble upon</strong> <em>–phr v. </em>a surprise discovery or unexpected encounter</p>
<p><strong>pier</strong> <em>–n. </em>a long structure built in water that connects the shore to where boats dock and allows people to walk</p>
<p><strong>challenge</strong> <em>–n. </em>a difficult task that takes hard work to complete</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Health Agency Targets Effects of ‘Long COVID’  (2023/8/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-health-agency-targets-effects-of-long-covid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By </span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. National Institutes of Health (NIH) is beginning a group of studies aimed at treatments for the condition called long COVID.</p>
<p>Reports say millions of Americans are affected by long-lasting effects from COVID-19 infections.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This undated, colorized electron microscope image made available by the U.S. National Institutes of Health in February 2020 shows the Novel Coronavirus SARS-CoV-2. (NIAID-RML via AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1675-08db9516dbd1_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This undated, colorized electron microscope image made available by the U.S. National Institutes of Health in February 2020 shows the Novel Coronavirus SARS-CoV-2. (NIAID-RML via AP, File)</span></div>
<p>The NIH is using $1.15 billion provided through the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 to study how people recover from COVID-19. The project is called RECOVER. The goal is to pay for studies examining the health problems that COVID patients suffer long after their infection has ended.</p>
<p>Dr. Ziyad Al-Aly is with Washington University in St. Louis, Missouri. He is not involved in the NIH project. But his own research on American veterans has brought attention to long COVID. Speaking about the NIH's project, he said: "This is a year or two late and smaller in <strong>scope</strong> than one would hope but nevertheless it is a step in the right direction."</p>
<p>Al-Aly said getting answers is important because there are so many people pushing unproven <strong>therapies</strong>.</p>
<p>The term "long COVID" is used to describe about 200 symptoms. It is estimated that between 10 and 30 percent of people experience some form of long COVID after an infection.</p>
<p>However, even federal health officials cannot agree on what long COVID truly means. U.S. Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra has said, "If I get 10 people, I get 10 answers of what long COVID really is."</p>
<p>The RECOVER effort has followed 24,000 patients in what are called observational studies. The goal is to define the most common symptoms. The findings will help shape future tests for treatments of the symptoms.</p>
<p>Current tests are already taking place. They include a trial of Pfizer's antiviral drug Paxlovid. Researchers want to find out if Paxlovid can ease long COVID symptoms. The idea behind the study is that some coronaviruses remain in some patients and the treatment will help them.</p>
<p>Researchers are also studying treatments for "<strong>brain fog</strong>" and other thinking problems. Posit Science Corp. has a treatment program called BrianHQ. PASC-Cognitive Recovery is from New York City's Mount Sinai Health System. And Soterix Medical has a device that <strong>stimulates</strong> brain connections.</p>
<p>The two additional studies will begin in the coming months. One will test treatments for sleep problems in people with long COVID. Another will target breathing and heartbeat problems. People's bodies perform breathing and heartbeat unconsciously. The problems include the disorder POTS, which results from unusual blood flow to the heart.</p>
<p>One planned trial that is the subject of some disagreement involves intolerance to exercise and tiredness, or fatigue. It is not a normal experiment. It is known as a "platform study." This lets the NIH add new therapies at any time.</p>
<p>"We can rapidly <strong>pivot</strong>," said Dr. Amy Patterson, who is with the NIH. She said a failing treatment can be dropped without ending the trial. She added that the study can quickly include a treatment "if something promising comes on the <strong>horizon</strong>."</p>
<p>Dr. Anthony Komaroff said it is important to be flexible. He is a researcher from Harvard University. He is not involved in NIH's RECOVER program. But he said studying the effects of Paxlovid on long COVID patients "makes all sorts of sense." But he said researchers should consider extending the treatment for longer than 25 days if there is little sign of improvement.</p>
<p>Komaroff said he understands that people get upset over the long wait for treatment trials. He believes, however, that NIH has waited the right amount of time. Waiting, he said, permits enough time for problems to be identified.</p>
<p>"You've got to have targets," Komaroff said.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Lauran Neergaard reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scope </strong><em>–n.</em> the areas that is included or dealt with</p>
<p><strong>therapy</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a treatment of physical or mental sickness that might or might not involve medicines</p>
<p><strong>brain fog</strong> <em>–n.</em> the inability to think clearly</p>
<p><strong>stimulate </strong>–v. to make something active from a less active or quiet state</p>
<p><strong>pivot </strong><em>–v.</em> to turn around a central point</p>
<p><strong>horizon </strong><em>–n. (figurative)</em> the future; a future time</p>
<p><strong>clue </strong>–n. something that helps a person understand or find something out that was hidden</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Barbie’ Is Changing the Clothes People Wear  (2023/8/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/barbie-is-changing-the-clothes-people-wear.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>If you walk into a clothing store, you are likely to be hit with an explosion of the color pink.</p>
<p>The pink wave has been fueled by the release last month of the wildly successful film<em> Barbie</em>. The movie is based on the popular doll of the same name, made by the toy company Mattel.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image released by Warner Bros. Pictures shows Ryan Gosling, left, and Margot Robbie in a scene from Barbie. (Warner Brothers via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c5e9-08db91450ab6_cx9_cy0_cw83_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image released by Warner Bros. Pictures shows Ryan Gosling, left, and Margot Robbie in a scene from "Barbie." (Warner Brothers via AP)</span></div>
<p>Barbie dolls are known for their bright pink color. And clothes based on what the toy wears have become hugely popular. People are calling them Barbiecore <strong>outfits</strong>.</p>
<p>Barbie clothing items include shoes, backpacks, swimsuits and even special clothes for dogs.</p>
<p>"There is not a corner of the <strong>globe</strong> that hasn't turned pink," said Richard Dickson, Mattel's president and chief operating officer.</p>
<p>The pink wave actually began last year, but Barbie strengthened it. High-end designer Valentino kicked off the pink wave by dressing models in head-to-toe in a pink color called fuchsia for a runway show in March of 2022.</p>
<p>A few months later, photos showed <em>Barbie</em> movie star Margot Robbie on set in a hot pink Western outfit. The look got a lot of attention online, said Madeline Hirsh. She is news director for the fashion magazine InStyle.</p>
<p>Around the same time, more and more people were returning to their workplaces and doing more social things as COVID-19 restrictions eased.</p>
<p>Hirsch said, "People were <strong>craving</strong> joy, color and new clothes to wear out again..."</p>
<p>The style took off. Fashion magazines published pictures of famous stars, including Kim Kardashian and Harry Styles, in bright Barbie-<strong>inspired</strong> clothes.</p>
<p><strong>Barbie stylized items</strong></p>
<p>Barbie is one of Mattel's top three <strong>brands</strong>. The toymaker <strong>trademarked</strong> the word Barbiecore in 2022. It also partnered with companies such as high-end French designer Balmain, Kendra Scott, and Barefoot Dreams.</p>
<p>Those efforts went into full force in 2023, with more than 100 partnerships tied to the movie. Mattel has also worked on many products outside of fashion, such as an Instagram-perfect pool float from Funboy and a pink Microsoft X-box gaming device in a Barbie Dreamhouse.</p>
<p>There are even Barbie-centric foods. They include an ice cream flavor and a Barbie Burger with pink sauce sold at Burger King fast food restaurants in Brazil.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Lisa Richwine reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>outfit </strong>– <em>n.</em> a popular way of dressing during a particular time or among a particular group of people</p>
<p><strong>globe </strong>– <em>n.</em> the earth</p>
<p><strong>crave </strong>– <em>v.</em> to have a very strong desire for (something)</p>
<p><strong>inspired </strong>– <em>adj.</em> having a particular cause or influence</p>
<p><strong>brand </strong>– <em>n.</em> a category of products that are all made by a particular company and all have a particular name</p>
<p><strong>trademarked </strong>– <em>n.</em> something (such as a word) that identifies a particular company's product and cannot be used by another company without permission</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>China Plans New Limits on Children’s Smartphone Use  (2023/8/8) | 中国拟严管青少年使用智能手机</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/china-plans-new-limits-on-children-s-smartphone-use.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>China has released an early form of new rules that aim to reduce the amount of time children spend on their smartphones.<br/>
中国发布了一项旨在减少儿童使用智能手机时间的规定草案。</p>
<p>The move affects companies such as Tencent and ByteDance, which run social media platforms and online games.<br/>
此举影响到腾讯和字节跳动等运营社交媒体平台和网络游戏的公司。</p>
<p>The Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC) published an early version of the rules on its website recently. The rules say that young people would not be permitted to use most internet services on mobile devices from 10 p.m. to 6 a.m. The rules also say that children between the ages of 16 and 18 would only be able to use the internet for two hours a day.<br/>
中国网信办最近在其网站上发布了该规定的草案。规定称，青少年在晚上10点到早上6点之间将不被允许在移动设备上使用大多数互联网服务。规定还称，16岁到18岁的青少年每天只能上网两个小时。</p>
<p>Children between the ages of 8 and 15 would be permitted only an hour a day while those under 8 could spend only 40 minutes.<br/>
8岁至15岁的儿童每天只能上网一小时，而8岁以下的儿童只能上网40分钟。</p>
<p>Some services, such as apps or websites that are good for the physical and mental development of young people, will not be subject to the rules.<br/>
一些有利于年轻人身心发展的应用程序或网站将不受规定约束。</p>
<p>The proposed restrictions are Beijing's latest efforts to attempt to limit internet addiction, a problem it views as widespread among its youth.<br/>
这项规定草案是中国政府试图限制网络成瘾的最新举措，政府认为这个问题在青少年中普遍存在。</p>
<p>In 2019, the Chinese government limited children's daily online game time to 90 minutes a day. Officials then tightened those restrictions in 2021. Children could only spend an hour a day playing online games on Fridays, weekends and public holidays.<br/>
2019年，中国政府将儿童每天的网络游戏时间限制在90分钟以内。官员们随后在2021年收紧了这些规定。孩子们只能在周五、周末和公共假日每天玩一个小时的网络游戏。</p>
<p>Short-video and online video websites like Douyin, Bilibili and Kuaishou have offered youth modes that restrict the type of content shown to young people and the length of time they can use the service. Officials are also pushing for children to see more educational material, such as science experiments.<br/>
抖音、哔哩哔哩和快手等短视频和在线视频网站提供了青少年模式，该模式限制了向年轻人展示的内容类型和他们使用该服务的时长。有关官员也在推动孩子们看更多的教育材料，比如科学实验。</p>
<p>The latest restrictions would affect Tencent, China's largest online game company, and ByteDance, which runs popular short-video platform Douyin. The government pressures companies in China to enforce rules.<br/>
这项最新规定将影响中国最大的网络游戏公司腾讯和运营热门短视频平台抖音的字节跳动。政府向中国企业施压，要求它们执行相关规定。</p>
<p>"To…strengthen the online protection of minors, the CAC has in recent years pushed for the establishment of a youth mode on internet platforms," the CAC said.<br/>
中国网信办表示：“为了强化未成年人网络保护，中国网信办近年来推动在互联网平台上建立青少年模式。”</p>
<p>"Since the mode was launched, there has been a positive impact in reducing youth internet and the impact of undesirable information," it added.<br/>
网信办还表示：“自该模式推出以来，在减少互联网和不良信息对青少年影响方面发挥了积极作用。”</p>
<p>The CAC said the rules can be commented on by the public until September 2. It did not say when the new rules would take effect.<br/>
网信办表示，公众可以在9月2日之前对这些规定发表评论。它没有说明新规定将于何时生效。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI System Finds First Possibly Dangerous Asteroid  (2023/8/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/ai-system-finds-first-possibly-dangerous-asteroid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new artificial intelligence (AI) method has been used to identify an <strong>asteroid</strong> that could one day present a threat to Earth.</p>
<p>Scientists made the discovery using a computer processing method called an algorithm. The algorithm searches through data collected by four different Earth-based telescopes. The goal is to identify asteroids that might present a risk of crashing into Earth.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image shows the orbit of 2022 SF289 (green) at its closest approach to Earth (orbit in blue). Orbits of Venus and Mars are shown in orange and red, respectively. (Image Credit: Joachim Moeyens/University of Washington/OpenSpace)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2200-08db9503fb2f_cx4_cy2_cw95_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image shows the orbit of 2022 SF289 (green) at its closest approach to Earth (orbit in blue). Orbits of Venus and Mars are shown in orange and red, respectively. (Image Credit: Joachim Moeyens/University of Washington/OpenSpace)</span></div>
<p>The asteroid search effort is financed by the American space agency NASA. It is operated by a team at the University of Hawaii's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.ifa.hawaii.edu/">Institute for Astronomy</a>.</p>
<p>The system is called ATLAS. It involves four different telescopes. Two of the telescopes are based in Hawaii. Another operates in Chile and the other sits in South Africa. ATLAS is designed to search the whole sky several times each night looking for moving objects, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://atlas.fallingstar.com/">explains</a>.</p>
<p>NASA and its international partners continuously search the skies for what scientists call <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/did-you-know">near-Earth objects</a> (NEOs). Such objects include asteroids and <strong>comets</strong> that come within 50 million kilometers of Earth's orbit. The effort aims to identify and follow NEOs that could one day strike Earth.</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/did-you-know">says</a> a large majority of the NEOs that enter Earth's atmosphere burn up before reaching the planet's surface. But the space agency is concerned about larger NEOs up to 50 meters in size. NASA says such objects could cause widespread damage to areas they hit.</p>
<p>The space agency considers NEOs that come within 7.5 million kilometers of Earth's orbit and that are bigger than 140 meters "potentially <strong>hazardous</strong> objects."</p>
<p>Researchers from the University of Washington created the algorithm and led the latest discovery operation. The team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.washington.edu/news/2023/07/31/heliolinc3d/">announced</a> in a statement it had identified a 182-meter-long asteroid named 2022 SF289. The find came during testing of the new algorithm, which the researchers called HelioLinc3D.</p>
<p>The researchers said the newly discovered asteroid met the description of a <strong>potentially</strong> hazardous asteroid (PHA). However, the scientists said asteroid 2022 SF289 will likely present no threat to Earth in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>The newly discovered asteroid was the first PHA to be identified with the HelioLinc3D algorithm. Scientists plan to use the new algorithm together with the Vera C. Rubin Observatory, which is still being developed on top of a mountain in Chile.</p>
<p>Rubin is expected to start operating in early 2025. University of Washington researchers have said the observatory should greatly improve the discovery rate of PHAs. This is because the telescope was built with a very powerful new camera and a huge mirror.</p>
<p>Some NEOs are difficult to identify with existing telescopes because they can be blocked by bright areas of space. For example, other equipment missed asteroid 2022 SF289 because of rich star fields that exist in our Milky Way galaxy. Rubin's instruments are expected to provide more detailed images and data to improve the identification process for NEOs.</p>
<p>Ari Heinze is a researcher at the University of Washington and a main developer of the HelioLinc3D algorithm. He said in a statement, "By demonstrating the real-world effectiveness of the software that Rubin will use to look for thousands of yet-unknown potentially hazardous asteroids, the discovery of 2022 SF289 makes us all safer."</p>
<p>The University of Washington researchers say more than 2,350 have so far been discovered. They say with the new algorithm, scientists hope to identify thousands more. Astronomers using ATLAS say discoveries of PHAs are made when they identify "a point of light moving <strong>unambiguously</strong> in a straight line over the image series."</p>
<p>The HelioLinc3D algorithm was developed specifically to be used by the Vera C. Rubin Observatory. But Heinze and other researchers said they wanted to see if it could discover a new asteroid using existing telescope data.</p>
<p>After Rubin's team set HelioLinc3D to search through Rubin data, it identified its first PHA on July 18. The asteroid was 20 million kilometers from Earth.</p>
<p>ATLAS astronomer Larry Denneau was a leader of the discovery team. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.washington.edu/news/2023/07/31/heliolinc3d/">said</a> the algorithm shows "it is possible to recover these <strong>faint</strong> objects as long as they are visible over several nights." Denneau added, "This in effect gives us a bigger, better telescope."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on the University of Washington, the University of Hawaii and NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>a rocky object that goes around the sun like a planet</p>
<p><strong>comet </strong><em>– n. </em>an object in space that leaves a bright line behind it in the sky</p>
<p><strong>hazardous </strong><em>– adj. </em>dangerous</p>
<p><strong>unambiguous </strong><em>– adj. </em>expressed in a way that makes it completely what is meant</p>
<p><strong>faint </strong><em>– adj. </em>not clear or strong</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Railway Tests a System to Help Visitors  (2023/8/7) | 日本铁路测试游客求助系统</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/japanese-railway-tests-a-system-to-help-visitors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Japanese railway operator, Seibu, is testing a special help desk for foreigners at one of the company's busiest train stations.<br/>
日本铁路运营商西武正在该公司其中一个最繁忙的火车站测试一种面向外国人的特殊服务台。</p>
<p>Visitors who need help at the Seibu-Shinjuku station in Tokyo can go to an information window and ask questions. About 135,000 people per day pass through the Seibu-Shinjuku station.<br/>
在东京西武新宿站需要帮助的游客可以到一个信息窗口提问。每天约有13.5万人通过西武新宿站。</p>
<p>To get help, a person just speaks into a microphone. A system called VoiceBiz listens to their words and displays them on the window in Japanese. The railway worker can see the question and reply in Japanese. Then VoiceBiz translates the answer into a language the person who needs help can understand. The system works with Japanese and 11 other languages.<br/>
有人要寻求帮助，只用对着麦克风说话。VoiceBiz系统会听他们说话，并用日语显示在窗口上。铁路员工可以看到问题，并用日文回答。然后VoiceBiz将答复翻译成需要帮助的人士所能理解的语言。该系统可适用于日语和其他11种语言。</p>
<p>Rail stations throughout Japan are very busy this summer. More than 2 million people visited Japan in June, the most since before 2020. COVID-19 restrictions barred most foreign travelers for a long time.<br/>
日本各地的火车站今年夏天都很繁忙。6月份访问日本的人数超过200万，为2020年前以来最多。新冠肺炎限制措施长期禁止大多数外国游客入境。</p>
<p>Kevin Khani was visiting Japan from Germany. He tried out the VoiceBiz system recently after getting confused in Seibu's Shinjuku station.<br/>
凯文·卡尼从德国到访日本。最近，他在西武新宿车站搞晕头后，试用了VoiceBiz系统。</p>
<p>He said the translations were "spot on," which means they were exactly right. He also said it is nice to see that there is a human working at the window.<br/>
他说这些翻译“准确无误”，这意味着它们完全正确。他还说，很高兴看到有人在窗口工作。</p>
<p>"So, you take your time to explain what you need, and you will know that they will understand what you need," he said.<br/>
他说：“所以，你慢慢来说出你需要什么，你就会知道，他们会搞懂你需要什么。”</p>
<p>The Seibu railway has been testing the VoiceBiz system for three months. After that time, the company will consider using it in additional stations.<br/>
西武铁路已经测试VoiceBiz系统三个月了。之后，该公司将考虑在其他车站使用该系统。</p>
<p>Ayano Yajima is a sales and marketing official for Seibu. Yajima said looking at each other adds to the "smoothness of communication."<br/>
八州绫野是西武的销售和营销官员。八州绫野说，看着彼此会增加“沟通的顺畅性”。</p>
<p>Toppan is the company that makes VoiceBiz. It tested the window at Kansai International Airport near Osaka earlier this year. It hopes to sell the windows to businesses and government offices in Japan so they can communicate with travelers and immigrants.<br/>
凸版公司制造了VoiceBiz系统。今年早些时候，该公司在大阪附近的关西国际机场测试了这个窗口。它希望将这些窗口出售给日本的企业和政府办公室，以便他们能够与游客和移民交流。</p>
<p>The company believes the Shinjuku area is a good testing place. The busiest railway station in the world is nearby – 3.6 million people use the Japan Railway station in Shinjuku. Many people use the Seibu train to get to other trains and subways and go to other places in Tokyo or the rest of Japan. As a result, there is a high chance that someone gets lost or needs help.<br/>
该公司认为新宿地区是一个很好的测试场所。世界上最繁忙的火车站就在附近——360万人使用新宿的日本火车站。许多人乘坐西武列车，搭乘其他火车和地铁，前往东京或日本其他地方。因此，很有可能有人会迷路或需要帮助。</p>
<p>French visitors Isabelle and Marc Rigaud used the help window to find their way from the Seibu station to the Japan Railway station. They had just gotten off an airplane at 1 in the morning, local time.<br/>
法国游客伊莎贝尔和马克·里戈使用该求助窗口找到了从西武站到日本火车站的路线。他们于当地时间凌晨1点刚下飞机。</p>
<p>"It's very Japan," Isabelle said of the technology.<br/>
伊莎贝尔在谈到这项技术时说：“这很日本。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·费利德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More Companies Seek to Recycle Solar Panels  (2023/8/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/more-companies-seek-to-recycle-solar-panels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many plans designed to deal with climate change depend on the use of clean energy from the sun, or solar power. But the equipment necessary for solar power sometimes gets damaged or wears out. These solar <strong>panels</strong> often end up as waste in <strong>landfills</strong>.</p>
<p>A business based in Yuma, Arizona, is trying to deal with what its founders call a tsunami of solar waste. The company is called We <strong>Recycle</strong> Solar.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Dwight Clark inspects a used solar panel at We Recycle Solar on Tuesday, June 6, 2023, in Yuma, Ariz. (AP Photo/Gregory Bull)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c30b2cc8-d090-47e6-a863-be9e1f4174ef_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Dwight Clark inspects a used solar panel at We Recycle Solar on Tuesday, June 6, 2023, in Yuma, Ariz. (AP Photo/Gregory Bull)</span></div>
<p><strong>Large amounts of waste </strong></p>
<p>Workers move large numbers of solar panels with special machines, then lift each out by hand to begin separating by maker and model. Some panels only have a few cracks in their glass.</p>
<p>These panels can be reused, said company chief Adam Saghei.</p>
<p>The panels that do not go to testing and resale instead go to a special area where glass, metals, and other materials with value are separated.</p>
<p>Solar panels are built to survive many years of bad weather, so it is difficult to take them apart.</p>
<p>Separating the glass without it breaking, for example, is difficult. But We Recycle Solar uses special robotic devices that can do the work successfully.</p>
<p>Some of the highest value materials in solar panels are copper, silver, aluminum, glass, and crystalline silicon.</p>
<p>For Saghei, the idea for the company came in 2017. He was working in the computer electronic waste sector. He saw solar panels spread across roofs and wondered where the panels would go in the future. He said he realized that green technology does not stay green once it is no longer being used.</p>
<p>Copper is one metal the recycling process produces, said Dwight Clark, director of recycling technology at We Recycle Solar. Clark said there is not a lot of copper in each solar panel. But when the company recycles around 4500 kilograms of solar panels in an hour, the company can get over a hundred kilograms of copper.</p>
<p><strong>The future </strong></p>
<p>By 2050, solar panel waste will total some 78 million tons worldwide, said Mool Gupta of the University of Virginia. The reason recycling and recovery is not very strong yet, Gupta said, is that companies do not want to pay the $30 per panel cost when it costs only $1 to send it to a landfill.</p>
<p>Garvin Heath is a renewable energy expert at the U.S. Department of Energy. He said the cost to recycle should not be more than the cost to put solar panels in landfills. He said consumers should not have to pay anything and recycling businesses should not suffer financial losses.</p>
<p>Other companies are starting to get into the business.</p>
<p>Solarcycle, a new company based in Odessa, Texas, raised $30 million earlier this year. And Solarpanelrecycling.com is connected to electronics recycler PowerHouse Recycling.</p>
<p>The European Union has rules that require recycling of electronic waste under its Waste Electrical and Electronic Waste Directive (WEEE).</p>
<p>Market researcher Visiongain estimates the global market for solar panel recycling at $138 million for last year and growing fast.</p>
<p>Jack Groppo of the University of Kentucky says people have to stop sending solar panels to the landfill as soon as possible. "Once the solar panels go into the landfill, they're gone unless we go back and mine the landfill," he said.</p>
<p>Groppo estimates that in 20 years people will mine landfills to get valuable materials in the solar panels. But he said it makes more sense to separate the panels at their retirement instead.</p>
<p>The Yuma facility can process 7,500 panels in a single day. As of early June, it estimates more than 650,000 tons of carbon dioxide waste production have been avoided. It is reusing about 60 percent of the panels that come in.</p>
<p>The company plans to open another recycling center next to a large solar manufacturer in the southeastern part of the country.</p>
<p>For now, solar recycling companies are still looking for a way to make money. But Gupta said these profitability issues are temporary. Researchers are hard at work on solving them, he said.</p>
<p>He added, "Too many lives are lost to pollution and solar is one of the top solutions."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p>
<em>Isabella O'Malley reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>panel </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
<p><strong>recycle</strong> <em>– v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
<p><strong>landfill</strong> <em>– n.</em> a system in which waste materials are buried under the ground</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>To Cut Food Waste, Switzerland Tries Public Refrigerators  (2023/8/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/in-effort-to-cut-food-waste-switzerland-tries-public-refrigerators.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A nonprofit group in Geneva, Switzerland is making <strong>refrigerators</strong> available so restaurant owners and cooks can make food available to the public before it goes bad.</p>
<p>The refrigerators are being placed along streets for anyone to use. The project is part of a continuing effort by people in Switzerland and other European countries to cut down on food waste.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Free Food Fridge Albany sidewalk refrigerator is stocked with produce and other food, June 25, 2021, in Albany, N.Y. The nonprofit Free-Go has put refrigerators and food storage centers in Geneva, Switzerland so people can get food. (AP Photo/Hans Pennink)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a643-08db941f2950_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Free Food Fridge Albany sidewalk refrigerator is stocked with produce and other food, June 25, 2021, in Albany, N.Y. The nonprofit Free-Go has put refrigerators and food storage centers in Geneva, Switzerland so people can get food. (AP Photo/Hans Pennink)</span></div>
<p>The nonprofit Free-Go has put refrigerators and food storage centers in Geneva so people can get fruit, vegetables, breads and other foods at no cost. Free-Go is a smart play on the word "frigo," which is an informal French word for refrigerator.</p>
<p>The program costs about $40,000 to run each year. It receives support from private groups and the city government. Free-Go launched a year ago with a single refrigerator outside a community center in western Geneva. There are now four refrigerators around the city. The group plans a fifth before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Marine Delevaux is the project's director. She said the food left in its refrigerators is usually taken within an hour of being left. For health and legal reasons, no frozen foods, open food containers, prepared meals, or alcohol are permitted in the refrigerators.</p>
<p>Free-Go also lets people who use the service plan when they will get their food. The idea is to make it easier for people who live in <strong>apartment buildings</strong> to join the program. There is also a telephone line, or "hotline," that restaurants can use to call for someone to <strong>pick up</strong> unused food.</p>
<p>"Generally, when the food collected from <strong>shops</strong> and restaurants arrives in the morning, people are already waiting to help themselves," Delevaux said.</p>
<p>She added that the first Geneva refrigerator helped save 3.2 tons of food from going to waste last year. Of the food donated, only about three percent had to be thrown away because nobody wanted it.</p>
<p>Free-Go said those who give food from private businesses, like restaurants or food sellers, must promise to make sure the donated food is safe to eat. Swiss law says food past the "recommended use-by" date can be eaten for up to a year afterwards, Delevaux said.</p>
<p>The Swiss government estimates that nearly one-third of all food products are wasted or thrown away. That amounts to about 330 kilograms of food waste per person each year. Of that, about 100 kilograms are waste from households.</p>
<p>Free-Go says about 1 billion tons of food go to waste every year around the world. The group says the waste uses up energy and other resources in the farming and transportation process.</p>
<p>"Wasting food is not only an ethical and economic issue but it also <strong>depletes</strong> the environment of limited natural resources," the European Union's Commission said.</p>
<p>Similar food-sharing campaigns are in place in the Swiss capital, Bern, and in the town of Neuchatel. The idea was first imported from Germany.</p>
<p>Foodsharing.de is a community group in Germany that started more than 10 years ago. It said that more than half a million people in Germany, Switzerland and Austria have made "the food-sharing <strong>initiative</strong> an international movement." The group said it has helped save 83 million tons of food from going to waste.</p>
<p>Because the food is free, and the donations can change, it is not always clear what will appear in the refrigerators. Some people receiving food might not get what they want or need.</p>
<p>Outside a community center in Geneva recently, Shala Moradi said she was looking for some bread and there was none. She is 65 years old and came from Iran. She has lived in Geneva for 10 years. She said she <strong>appreciates</strong> the initiative.</p>
<p>"It's very good. I can take strawberries, cherries, things like that," she said, talking about the different food that is available. Of the no cost food, she said, "I like that too."</p>
<p>Severine Cuendet is a 54-year-old teacher. Just after leaving some vegetables that she grew, she said, "We have too much" and praised the initiative "because this neighborhood has a lot of need."</p>
<p>She added, "And it happens to all of us to buy too much."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Jamey Keaten reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>refrigerator </strong>– <em>n.</em> a device or room that is used to keep food cold</p>
<p><strong>apartment building </strong><em>–n.</em> a building that holds many places to live which could have one or several rooms</p>
<p><strong>pick up </strong><em>–v.</em> to go to get something and take it back to where it is needed</p>
<p><strong>shop </strong>– <em>n.</em> a building or room where goods and services are sold</p>
<p><strong>deplete </strong>– <em>v.</em> to use most or all of (something important): to greatly reduce the amount of (something)</p>
<p><strong>initiative </strong>– <em>n.</em> a plan or program that is intended to solve a problem</p>
<p><strong>appreciate </strong>– <em>v.</em> to understand the worth or importance of (something or someone): to admire and value (something or someone)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Rules Aim to Protect Valuable Horseshoe Crabs  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/new-rules-aim-to-protect-valuable-horseshoe-crabs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>New rules aim to protect horseshoe crabs, which are used in medical research, and also to support an endangered bird <strong>species</strong>.</p>
<p>Blue blood from horseshoe crabs is used by researchers to test for dangerous substances in vaccines, medicines and medical devices. The animals are also used by fisherman as <strong>bait</strong> to catch eels and sea snails.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Horseshoe crabs spawn at Reeds Beach in Cape May Court House, N.J., Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-8df0-08db920c47ff_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Horseshoe crabs spawn at Reeds Beach in Cape May Court House, N.J., Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke)</span></div>
<p>In addition, the eggs of horseshoe crabs are an important food for an endangered bird called the red knot.</p>
<p>Scientists say horseshoe crabs have been living in ocean environments for more than 400 million years. But they are different from other crabs. They are more closely related to spiders and scorpions. The animals have been decreasing in numbers in areas they live in, called habitats, along the U.S. East Coast.</p>
<p>The blue blood is taken from the animals for medical research. The process returns the crabs to the environment. But many die from the blood harvesting process.</p>
<p>Blood from the crabs can be manufactured into limulus amebocyte lysate, or LAL, a substance used to identify dangerous substances in some medications and vaccines.</p>
<p>Fishermen collect the crabs by hand or with special equipment on boats for use by biomedical companies. The blood – which contains immune cells sensitive to bacteria – is then separated and proteins are processed. It takes many crabs to produce enough blood to fill a single glass tube, which contains cells that are sensitive to bacteria.</p>
<p>New guidelines for dealing with horseshoe crabs were approved in May by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. Industry officials said those changes should keep more crabs alive. But, in recent years, environmentalists brought attention to the issue of the horseshoe crabs, including their relationship to the red knot.</p>
<p>Red knots are birds that travel about 30,500 kilometers back and forth from South America to Canada. During their long trip, the birds must stop to eat along the way and horseshoe crabs are an important food.</p>
<p>Bethany Kraft is a coastal <strong>conservation</strong> specialist with the environmental organization the Audubon Society. Kraft told The Associated Press (AP) that red knots need horseshoe crab eggs to give them enough fuel to complete their long flights. "There's very clear linkage between horseshoe crabs and the survival of the red knot in the coming <strong>decades</strong>," she added.</p>
<p>Kraft said horseshoe crabs currently need stronger protection to survive. She and other wildlife conservationists have noted the new guidelines are currently only voluntary. This, they say, still leaves the red knot at risk. They say the bird needs stronger legal protection.</p>
<p>The new guidelines urge best practices for the biomedical industry's harvesting and processing of the crabs. They include measures aimed at limiting <strong>exposure</strong> to sunlight and keeping crabs cool and wet.</p>
<p>Caitlin Starks is a fishery specialist with the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. She told the AP the goal of the guidelines "is to give the crabs that are bled a better chance of surviving."</p>
<p>That is exactly what the new guidelines will do, said Nora Blair, an operations official with Charles River Laboratories. The company manufactures LAL from horseshoe crab blood. Blair was a member of a working group that created the new guidelines along with other industry groups.</p>
<p>Blair said the industry is working to find <strong>synthetic</strong> materials that could be used for biomedical research. Conservationists have been pushing for years for such a solution. Lonza, a Switzerland-based company that manufactures LAL, offers an animal-free testing solution.</p>
<p>But Blair said that, for now, the wild harvest of horseshoe crabs remains extremely important for drug safety. The animals play an important part in supplying and testing drugs and the coastal environment makes their conservation "<strong>imperative</strong>," she added.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>bait </strong>–n. a piece of foot that is used to catch fish or other animals</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong><em>– n. </em>a period of ten years<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>expose </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove what is covering something so that it can be seen</p>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong><em>– adj. </em>a group of products made from artificial substances, often copying a natural product</p>
<p><strong>imperative </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely important or necessary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Colleges Ask for More Writing after Affirmative Action Ban  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-colleges-ask-for-more-writing-after-affirmative-action-ban.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>August 1 is the start of the new college <strong>admissions</strong> season in the United States. It is the day students can start to complete the Common Application for college admission in 2024.</p>
<p>The Common Application is accepted by over 1,000 colleges and universities. The service permits students to <strong>apply</strong> to many schools by submitting their information only one time.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sign points the way to the Harvard College Admissions Visitors Center at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, U.S., July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/13cb9c21-c17c-4e4c-ac4b-e322b40519e0_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sign points the way to the Harvard College Admissions Visitors Center at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, U.S., July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)</span></div>
<p>However, some colleges and universities that accept the Common Application are asking students to send in an extra piece of writing. They are using the extra "<strong>prompt</strong>" to give students a chance to discuss their background.</p>
<p>The reason for this new writing prompt is the U.S. Supreme Court's recent decision to end affirmative action in college decisions.</p>
<p>The court said <strong>selective</strong> colleges and universities, such as Harvard University or the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, can no longer use race as a way to decide between two qualified students.</p>
<p>But the court did say schools can consider "an applicant's discussion of how race affected his or her life..."</p>
<p>That is why some schools are re-writing their prompts.</p>
<p>At Yale University, students who apply with the Common Application must also answer one of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://admissions.yale.edu/essay-topics" target="_blank">three questions</a>.</p>
<p>The first question permits students to write about a time they discussed an important issue with someone holding an opposing view.</p>
<p>Another question asks students to discuss a meaningful community to which they are connected.</p>
<p>But a third question is new, compared to past years. It asks students to talk about part of their "personal experience that you feel will <strong>enrich</strong> your college."</p>
<p>That question permits a student to state their race and discuss how they would add something special to the group of students at Yale.</p>
<p>At Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, a new prompt asks students to "tell about a community that you have been part of where your <strong>participation</strong> helped to change or shape the community for the better."</p>
<p>Timothy Fields is a top admissions official at Emory. He said the new questions "are going to be much more targeted."</p>
<p>At Sarah Lawrence College outside of New York City, a new question asks students how the Supreme Court decision on affirmative action might affect their lives.</p>
<p>Kevin McKenna is a vice president at the college. He said the new question gives students a chance to discuss the decision "that could <strong>impact</strong> the student bodies of the colleges to which they are applying."</p>
<p><strong>An acceptance campaign</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the new questions, many colleges and universities are thinking about how to connect with Black and Latino students. The school leaders worry that those students may think they are no longer welcome at selective universities after the Supreme Court decision.</p>
<p>Amin Abdul-Malik Gonzalez is the top admissions official at Wesleyan University in Connecticut. He and his team are planning extra time at high schools and more meetings at college information events to tell minority students they are still welcome.</p>
<p>He also will offer more training to his admissions officers so they can work to build a <strong>diverse</strong> group of students without going against the Supreme Court's decision.</p>
<p>Visits such as those by the Wesleyan team are important, said Angel Perez. He is head of the National Association for College Admission Counseling. Perez said some college counselors for high school students are uncertain how their students should address their race in applications.</p>
<p>"The general feeling with school counselors right now is mostly <strong>anxiety</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>But those who work with students, like private admissions counselor Shereem Herndon-Brown, say students should not overstate how race affects their lives.</p>
<p>Herndon-Brown wrote a book with Fields, the admissions leader at Emory. He said students need to write "<strong>authentically</strong>" about how they think and have developed as a result of their background.</p>
<p>He gave an example of a Black student from New York who recently visited relatives in the southern part of the U.S. Herndon-Brown encouraged the student to write about that experience although it was not in the student's original plan.</p>
<p>That he said, is a better idea than declaring their race or overstating their disadvantage.</p>
<p>"There is no way to trick an admissions officer or a school into believing you're something that you're not," he says.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>admissions </strong>–<em>n</em>. the act or process of accepting a student into a college or university study program</p>
<p><strong>apply </strong><em>–v.</em><em> </em>to submit information to an organization such as a college for the right to be admitted as a student</p>
<p><strong>prompt</strong> <em>–n. </em>a suggestion for a conversation or piece of writing</p>
<p><strong>selective</strong> <em>–adj. </em>choosy; interested in picking something of higher quality</p>
<p><strong>enrich</strong> <em>–v. </em>to add something memorable to an experience</p>
<p><strong>participation</strong> <em>–n. </em>the act of being involved in something</p>
<p><strong>impact</strong> <em>–v. </em>to make an impression or have an effect on something</p>
<p><strong>diverse</strong> <em>–adj. </em>used to describe a group made of people or things that are different from each other</p>
<p><strong>anxiety</strong> <em>–n. </em>an emotional state of being worried or very concerned</p>
<p><strong>authentic</strong> <em>–adj. </em>something true or real</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Run Something Up the Flagpole' to Test an Idea  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/run-something-up-the-flagpole-to-test-an-idea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Great ideas can be the <strong>lifeblood </strong>of any project. That means they can bring a project to life or even back from the dead. From redesigning a home to creating an educational product, <strong>bold</strong>, creative ideas are valuable.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Flags of member nations at NATO headquarters." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e62f-08db343e7c1a_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Flags of member nations at NATO headquarters.</span></div>
<p>But often even a great idea needs a little work. It may need <strong>tweaking</strong>,<strong> </strong>meaning you need to make<strong> </strong>small changes. So, before sharing an idea with a large group, we may want to share it with a smaller group. We can test it out first, before putting the idea into action.</p>
<p>But first, let's talk about getting that big idea.</p>
<p>You may have heard of brainstorming. This is an idea-creating activity. When we brainstorm, we say ideas as quickly as we think of them.</p>
<p>In informal situations, we can call this <u>throwing spaghetti at the wall</u>. Why, you may ask? Well, cooked spaghetti is sticky. If spaghetti is cooked enough, it will stick when you throw it against the wall. If it is not cooked enough, it might not stick.</p>
<p>Good ideas stick too. In brainstorming, we often say we throw ideas around. And the good ones stay or stick. But as we said earlier, even if an idea sticks, we may want to test it out before sharing it with a large group of people.</p>
<p>That is when we can <u>run it up the flagpole</u>. Running an idea, plan, or proposal up the flagpole is a way to test interest or get <strong>feedback</strong>. The full phrase is "run it up the flagpole and see if anyone salutes." Military members <strong>salute</strong> when our flag is present and when they hear the first note of the national anthem.</p>
<p>Let's listen to an example: If you are the leader of a project, you could say to your team, "I like that plan. But it is risky. Let's run it up the flagpole before <strong>pitching</strong> it to the boss." In other words, you want to get more opinions before making the plan official.</p>
<p>Here is another example: When writing these stories, I often run my ideas up a flagpole. I respect the opinions of my co-workers and often take their suggestions <u>on board</u> – meaning I take them into consideration. So, I like bouncing ideas off them.</p>
<p>And that is a more common way to express this idea. <u>Bouncing something off someone</u> is a way to know their thoughts. You are asking their opinion and are looking to see their reaction. Bouncing ideas around is a good way to <strong><u>gauge</u></strong><u> interest</u> – to find out what people think.</p>
<p>So, the next time you have an idea, and you are unsure about it, run it up the flagpole! Bounce it off some friends! With the right people, you will soon know if it is good, bad, or needs work.</p>
<p>And that is all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lifeblood </strong><em>–n</em>. the most important part of something</p>
<p><strong>bold </strong><em>–adj.</em> strong, clear and without fear</p>
<p><strong>tweak </strong><em>–v. </em>to change something a little to improve it</p>
<p><strong>feedback </strong>–n. advice or criticism given to a person or group providing a product or service</p>
<p><strong>salute </strong><em>–v. </em>to honor (a person, a nation, an event, etc.) by a conventional military or naval ceremony</p>
<p><strong>pitch in </strong><em>–v. </em>to contribute to a common task</p>
<p><strong>gauge </strong>–v. to judge the qualities of someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Benjamin Harrison: Grandson  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/americas-presidents-benjamin-harrison.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Benjamin Harrison.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Benjamin Harrison" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fbc85745-b2a6-494e-be5a-05b8b04f862a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Benjamin Harrison</span></div>
<p>His family name may sound familiar. That is because he was the grandson of President <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-william-henry-harrison/3806092.html" target="_blank">William Henry Harrison</a>. That situation is unique in U.S. history so far.</p>
<p>Harrison played an unusually active <strong>role</strong> as president at a time when most chief executives saw themselves as simply administrators. As a result, American writer and intellectual Henry Adams said Harrison was the best president since Lincoln.</p>
<p>But most Americans remember little about him, except his connection to the previous President Harrison, who himself died after only a month in office.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Benjamin Harrison grew up on a farm in the Midwestern state of Ohio as one of eight children.</p>
<p>His grandfather was not the only famous political Harrison.</p>
<p>His great-grandfather signed the Declaration of Independence. And his father had been a congressman.</p>
<p>Young Benjamin Harrison respected these men and believed he had a role to play in history, too. He received a good education, and even outside of school he read many books.</p>
<p>His hard work and intelligence carried him to Miami University in Ohio, and then to a career as a lawyer.</p>
<p>Along the way, he married a woman he had known since he was a teenager, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/carolineharrison" target="_blank">Caroline Lavinia Scott</a>. The couple settled in another Midwestern city, Indianapolis, Indiana, and had a son and daughter.</p>
<p>Over time, Harrison steadily built a career as a public official. But his political path was <strong>interrupted</strong> by the American Civil War.</p>
<p>Harrison rose to the rank of general in the Union Army. He fought under General William T. Sherman, and was one of the first soldiers to enter Atlanta, Georgia after the city surrendered.</p>
<p>After the war, he returned home to Indiana and continued his legal and political career. In 1881, he was elected to the U.S. Senate. But six years later he lost his seat when Democrats came to power in his state.Reports say that Harrison was an excellent soldier. But he did not enjoy fighting or find war <strong>romantic</strong>.</p>
<p>Harrison's loss of his Senate seat soon turned to a victory. The Republican Party nominated him as their candidate to run against Grover Cleveland in the 1888 presidential election.</p>
<p>Cleveland's economic policies had become unpopular, and Republicans worked hard to support their candidate. They succeeded. Although Cleveland won the popular vote, Harrison won the Electoral College.</p>
<p>In 1889, he followed his grandfather's footsteps all the way to the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency </strong></p>
<p>Harrison's election was a major victory for his Republican Party. In addition to winning the White House, Republicans gained seats in the House of Representatives, held a majority in the Senate, and appointed several Republican justices to the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Harrison and other Republican lawmakers used their power to take action on issues at home and internationally.</p>
<p>One act was to preserve forests. Harrison identified 17 protected natural areas, and helped create Yosemite National Park in California.</p>
<p>His government also established Ellis Island in New York to make immigration to the U.S. a more orderly process.</p>
<p>Internationally, Harrison's administration sought to build ties with Latin American countries. His government established what would, in time, become the Organization of American States.</p>
<p>His administration also increased the United States' global trade – as well as the country's navy.</p>
<p>But, for the most part, the most pressing issues of the day were economic. The federal government at that time had an unusually large surplus. Some argued that the surplus was hurting business. In answer, Harrison's government placed a high protective tariff on imported goods. The legislation was known as the McKinley Tariff of 1890.</p>
<p>Officials also aimed to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.britannica.com/event/Sherman-Antitrust-Act">limit the power of large corporations</a> to control important markets in the U.S.</p>
<p>Finally, they agreed to require the government to buy silver to use as currency.</p>
<p>These actions pleased some of his supporters. But, they <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.historylink.org/File/2030">may have contributed</a> to the severe economic depression that followed Harrison's term.</p>
<p>And in general, voters disapproved of the amount of money Republican lawmakers were spending. Although the country was at peace, the 51<sup>st</sup> Congress <strong>appropriated</strong> $1 billion. At the midterm elections, many lawmakers paid for all the spending with their seats.</p>
<p>Two years later, voters turned Harrison out of the White House, too. They returned Grover Cleveland to the presidency.</p>
<p>Harrison did not express much disappointment. He had worked hard to become president like his grandfather. But he found he did not like being the chief executive. He said when he left the White House, it was like being released from prison.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Among U.S. presidents, Harrison does not have one of the most dramatic biographies. The facts of his life show an intelligent, disciplined man who tried to live by his beliefs.</p>
<p>But he was not considered <strong>passionate </strong>about many things, except perhaps his enjoyment of nature. And he did not have an easy way with people. Even his staff called him "the human iceberg" because he could be <strong>aloof</strong> and act coldly toward people.</p>
<p>Yet Harrison's family brought some warmth to his administration. His wife, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/carolineharrison">Caroline</a>, was known to be a lively, social person. She was the first to install a Christmas tree in the White House.</p>
<p>Some of Harrison's grandchildren also lived in the White House. Harrison permitted them to play on the grounds with their pet animals. During Harrison's term, the family kept a goat, which the children called "Old Whiskers."</p>
<p>Harrison's time in the White House saw sorrow, too. Toward the end of her husband's term, the first lady became seriously ill with tuberculosis. For months, Benjamin Harrison divided his attention between his wife and his job, and yet in the end lost both.</p>
<p>After his term as president ended, Benjamin Harrison returned to his home in Indianapolis. He did some work as a teacher and lawyer, and kept a good public image in his community.</p>
<p>He also re-married. His second wife was a widow herself, as well as his first wife's niece.</p>
<p>He and Mary Scott Lord Dimmick Harrison had a daughter together. The child was only four when Harrison died from pneumonia at age 67.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Mario Ritter was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>____________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Check your understanding by taking a listening quiz. Play each video, then choose the best answer.</p>
<p>____________________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>role </strong>- <em>n.</em> a part that someone or something has in a particular activity or situation</p>
<p><strong>interrupt</strong> -<em> v.</em> to cause (something) to stop happening for a time</p>
<p><strong>romantic</strong> - <em>adj.</em> not realistic or practical : not based on what is real</p>
<p><strong>appropriate</strong> - <em>v. </em> to get or save (money) for a specific use or purpose</p>
<p><strong>passionate</strong> - <em>adj.</em> having, showing, or expressing strong emotions or beliefs</p>
<p><strong>aloof</strong> - <em>adj.</em> not involved with or friendly toward other people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
