<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>US Insurance Group Rates Most Driver Assistance Systems ‘Poor’  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-insurance-group-rates-most-driver-assistance-systems-poor.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>An American <strong>insurance</strong> industry group has given most driver assistance systems "poor" ratings after a series of safety tests.</p>
<p>The Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (IIHS) carried out the tests. The group released a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iihs.org/news/detail/first-partial-driving-automation-safeguard-ratings-show-industry-has-work-to-do">report</a> this week describing its findings.</p>
<p>The tests involved 14 different driver assistance tools. Such tools offer partial driving <strong>automation</strong> as a way to improve safety and reduce accidents. The systems are equipped to assist drivers with things like staying inside road lines and automatically slowing or stopping the car when possible dangers are identified.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Tesla Model 3 vehicle drives on autopilot along the 405 highway in Westminster, California, U.S., March 16, 2022. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b708-08dc436a400c_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Tesla Model 3 vehicle drives on autopilot along the 405 highway in Westminster, California, U.S., March 16, 2022. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)</span></div>
<p>The IIHS is a nonprofit organization financed by America's insurance industry. The group carries out numerous crash tests each year as it seeks to persuade automakers to design safer vehicles. Automakers follow safety ratings issued by the group and often make changes to products based on them.</p>
<p>The IIHS noted there is a lack of effective tools to <strong>monitor</strong> drivers and provide warnings when they need to pay better attention or take immediate corrective action.</p>
<p>David Harkey is president of the IIHS. He told the Associated Press his group aims to set guidelines for manufacturers to make up for a lack of <strong>regulation</strong> over the systems by the U.S. National Highway Safety Administration.</p>
<p>Harkey noted that most current driver assist systems do not have effective measures "to prevent misuse and keep drivers from losing <strong>focus</strong> on what's happening on the road."</p>
<p>All automakers advise drivers using assistance tools not to fully depend on vehicle technologies to keep them safe. The companies say the tools are meant to improve, or enhance, overall safety, rather than take over certain driving duties.</p>
<p>The IIHS said it tested 14 different driver assist systems. Of those, 11 received an overall rating of "poor." Two other systems were rated "<strong>marginal</strong>," while one was considered "acceptable." Harkey said the 14 systems are among the highest quality technologies currently on the market.</p>
<p>The driver assist system used in the Lexus LS model earned the acceptable rating. The marginal declarations were given to systems in General Motors' GMC Sierra and Nissan's Ariya electric vehicle. Other systems from Nissan, Tesla, BMW, Ford, Genesis, Mercedes-Benz, and Volvo received ratings of "poor."</p>
<p>Harkey said the high-level of technology <strong>sophistication</strong> in today's driver assist systems provides a lot more automation possibilities. But these tools can cause drivers not to pay attention for longer periods, presenting new, dangerous risks. "That's why the focus is on how do we make sure that the driver remains focused on the driving...," he added.</p>
<p>The IIHS has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-many-drivers-treat-driving-assist-tools-as-fully-self-driving/6789001.html">warned</a> that manufacturers advertise their vehicles in a way that gives drivers the false idea that they are fully automated, or autonomous. "The one thing we do not want is for drivers to <strong>misinterpret</strong> what these things can or cannot do," Harkey said.</p>
<p>The IIHS is calling for automakers to build additional tools into their systems. These would be designed to observe whether or not a driver's eyes are directed at the road and whether their hands are on the wheel or ready to immediately take control.</p>
<p>The institute suggested the systems should have built-in tools that send warnings to drivers within 10 seconds if their eyes and hands are not in the right positions. At 20 seconds, the IIHS said the system should add another warning or start an automatic emergency process to slow down the vehicle.</p>
<p>Toyota, which makes Lexus vehicles, said it considers IIHS reports when it creates safety guidelines, while General Motors called the ratings important. Nissan said it will work with the institute on proposed changes.</p>
<p>Mercedes said it takes the findings seriously, while Hyundai Genesis said it was quickly improving its system, including plans to put a camera inside vehicles.</p>
<p>BMW said while it respects IIHS's efforts, it differs on the use of technology to monitor drivers inside the vehicle. Ford said its driver assist system monitors drivers and sends repeated warnings. While Ford said it disagrees with the institute's findings, it will consider the suggestions in future development.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>insurance </strong><em>– n. </em>an agreement in which you pay a company regularly, and it pays some of your costs if you have an accident or injury</p>
<p><strong>automate </strong><em>– v. </em>to control something using machines and not people</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>– v. </em>to watch closely</p>
<p><strong>regulation </strong><em>– n. </em>an official rule that controls how something is done</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>– n.</em> the person or thing that is getting the most attention</p>
<p><strong>marginal</strong><em> – adj. </em>small and not important</p>
<p><strong>sophisticated</strong><em> – adj. </em>very advanced in development</p>
<p><strong>misinterpret</strong><em> – v. </em>to understand something in the wrong way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Stone Tools Might Be Earliest Evidence of Human Ancestors in Europe  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/stone-tools-might-be-earliest-evidence-of-human-ancestors-in-europe.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say they have identified stone tools that might represent the oldest-known evidence of humans in Europe.</p>
<p>The recent research suggests that the human ancestors started settling Europe 1.4 million years ago. That is hundreds of thousands of years earlier than previously thought.</p>
<p>The stone tools were first discovered in the 1970s near the town of Korolevo, close to Ukraine's borders with Hungary and Romania. But the tools' age had remained unclear.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A view of the Korolevo quarry in western Ukraine, surrounded by archaeological sites, August 12, 2021. (Roman Garba/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fa7c2f72-937d-4a87-afc3-ba7a5c55e18a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A view of the Korolevo quarry in western Ukraine, surrounded by archaeological sites, August 12, 2021. (Roman Garba/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The place of the find is important for understanding how humans first spread into Europe. They moved into the area during warm periods, called interglacial periods. Those were times, in between Ice Ages, when huge amounts of ice covered Europe.</p>
<p>The scientists used a method for estimating the age that identifies the effects of <strong>cosmic rays </strong>on some kinds of minerals. The new method placed the age of the <strong>sediment</strong> layer containing the stone tools at around 1.4 million years.</p>
<p>The researchers believe that the maker of the tools was likely a human ancestor called Homo erectus. That early human <strong>species</strong> appeared around 2 million years ago and spread across Africa, Asia and Europe before disappearing perhaps 110,000 years ago.</p>
<p>"No bones were found at Korolevo, only stone tools. But the age suggests that Homo erectus was the only possible human species at the time. We know very little about our earliest ancestors. They used stone tools for <strong>butchery</strong> and probably used fire," said Roman Garba of the Czech Academy of Sciences. Garba was the lead writer of the research published in Nature.</p>
<p>Homo erectus was the first member of our evolutionary <strong>lineage</strong>. Homo erectus had body <strong>proportions</strong> like our species, Homo sapiens, though with a smaller brain.</p>
<p>The tools, made of volcanic rock, were made in a way that is called Oldowan. While simple, they represent the beginning of human technology.</p>
<p>Until now, the oldest-known evidence of humans in Europe was from about 1.2 million years ago from a place called Atapuerca in Spain.</p>
<p>The Korolevo findings suggest how the first humans might have moved into Europe. Homo erectus<strong> fossils</strong> from 1.8 million years ago are known from a place in the Caucasus Mountains in Georgia called Dmanisi. Garba said the evidence from Korolevo and Dmanisi suggests Homo erectus entered Europe from the east or southeast, moving along the Danube River.</p>
<p>It has been difficult to identify the age of places like Korolevo. The study dated the tools, left by their makers on a riverbed, by estimating when the layer holding the objects was buried under sediment.</p>
<p>Mads Knudsen of Aarhus University in Denmark described how scientists were able to date the prehistoric tools.</p>
<p>He said cosmic rays from outer space are always passing through the Earth's atmosphere. When they do, they create particles that are smaller than atoms, such as neutrons and muons. These particles are so small that they pass through all sorts of materials.</p>
<p>These particles react with minerals in rocks to produce radioactive nuclides, a class of atoms. The sediment was dated based on the <strong>ratio </strong>of two nuclides. This is possible because the two nuclides break down at different rates, through the process of radioactive decay.</p>
<p>Europe was later colonized by other human ancestor species including Homo heidelbergensis and Neanderthals. Scientists say Homo sapiens evolved in Africa about 300,000 years ago. They arrived in large numbers in Europe around 40,000 to 45,000 years ago.</p>
<p>The researchers suspect evidence of human occupation in Europe that is even older than Korolevo will be found.</p>
<p>"The question is not 'if' but 'when' we will find a site of similar or older age somewhere else in Ukraine, Romania, Bulgaria or Serbia," Garba said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cosmic rays </strong><em>– n.</em> particles of atomic or smaller size that pass into the Earth's atmosphere from space at extremely high energy levels</p>
<p><strong>sediment </strong><em>– n. </em>material (such as stones and sand) that sinks to the bottom of a body of water forming a layer that solidifies into rock over long periods of time</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>–n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young</p>
<p><strong>butchery </strong>–<em> n.</em> the job or act of preparing meat for eating</p>
<p><strong>lineage </strong><em>– n.</em> the people who were in someone's family in past times</p>
<p><strong>proportion </strong><em>– n.</em> the relationship between the size, shape, and position of the different parts of something</p>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as a bone or footprint) that is from a plant or animal that lived in ancient times</p>
<p><strong>ratio</strong> <em>–n.</em> a numerical relationship between two values</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Greek Grandmother Makes Scarves for Children in Need  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/greek-grandmother-makes-scarves-for-children-in-need.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In her small home in the capital of Greece, Athens, 93-year-old Ioanna Matsouka has <strong>knit</strong> thousands of brightly colored <strong>scarves </strong>for children in need from Greece to Bosnia to Ukraine. She has no plans to stop just yet.</p>
<p>"Until I die, I will be knitting," Matsouka told Reuters. Her knitting tools called needles made noises through her expert fingers, her nails painted red. "It brings me <strong>joy</strong> to share them," she said.</p>
<p>Since she took up knitting in the 1990s, Matsouka has easily made over 3,000 scarves, her daughters estimate.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ioanna Matsouka, 93, knits scarves in her house in Athens, Greece, March 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Karolina Tagaris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b19fcd92-bde9-41a5-bd04-1a392e8ad925_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ioanna Matsouka, 93, knits scarves in her house in Athens, Greece, March 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Karolina Tagaris)</span></div>
<p>By the door to her home, bags filled with her latest creations await their new owners. A knitted <strong>blanket</strong> is thrown over a large chair where she spends her days.</p>
<p>In the beginning, the scarves were gifted to friends. As the number of scarves grew, they were donated to children's homes across Greece. Then, through people she knew, they reached children in Bosnia and Ukraine. The latest 70 scarves went to a refugee camp near Athens this winter, via the United Nations refugee agency UNHCR.</p>
<p>"The fact that we give them away gives her strength," said her daughter Angeliki.</p>
<p>She recounted simple artwork and mail her mother received over the years: "Thank you, be well, keep going. You gave joy to children; you gave joy to people... That's her only <strong>reward</strong>: a letter, a few words."</p>
<p>Matsouka knits one scarf a day now. Her eyesight suffers and she sometimes has severe facial pain, a condition known as trigeminal neuralgia.</p>
<p>Angeliki says her mother is an example of strength and hope.</p>
<p>Matsouka wakes up every morning, drinks a glass of milk, puts on her jewelry and gets to work. She takes a break for lunch and a short sleep, then knits into the night.</p>
<p>She may have even found the secret to a long life in it, she says. "It's the happiness I get from giving," she said, sitting beside a big blue bag filled with the knitting materials.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Karolina Tagaris reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>knit </strong><em>– v. </em>to make (a piece of clothing) from yarn or thread by using long needles or a special machine</p>
<p><strong>scarf </strong><em>– n. </em>a long piece of cloth that is worn on your shoulders, around your neck, or over your head</p>
<p><strong>joy </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling of great happiness</p>
<p><strong>blanket </strong><em>– n</em>. a covering made of cloth that is used especially on a bed to keep you warm</p>
<p><strong>reward </strong><em>– n</em>. money or another kind of payment that is given or received for something that has been done or that is offered for something that might be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Filipino Man Makes Library in His Home  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/filipino-man-makes-library-in-his-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>"A good book is easy to find." That is the message on a sign at Hernando Guanlao's home in the Makati area of Manila, the capital of the Philippines.</p>
<p>Guanlao has turned his home into a free public library. Visitors can borrow the books inside for free.</p>
<p>Guanlao says he hopes his library will<strong> inspire</strong> people to read, especially the young. The 72-year-old told reporters that his library includes books that all students can enjoy – from young children in Kindergarten to older students in grade 12.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Hernando Guanlao, 72, sits in front of his home library in Makati, a metro area of Manila, Philippines, Feb. 7, 2024. (REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a80b-08dc3f8dc6b2_cx2_cy0_cw97_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Hernando Guanlao, 72, sits in front of his home library in Makati, a metro area of Manila, Philippines, Feb. 7, 2024. (REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez)</span></div>
<p>Guanlao says his library has books for readers of all interests. He spoke to reporters at his home, which is filled with thousands of available books.</p>
<p>He calls his library Reading Club 2000. It contains many different kinds of books, or genres.</p>
<p>Genre is a group of artistic, musical, or literary works that share a particular style, form, or content. Some genres in <strong>literature</strong> are poetry, non-fiction (or real stories), and fiction (or imaginary stories). Then there are "sub-genres" such as cookbooks, science fiction, and mystery, to name just a few.</p>
<p>Guanlao added, "There are also spiritual books for those who are looking for religious knowledge, hardbound and softbound books, autobiographies, and many different<strong> </strong>genres that one can enjoy, all for free."</p>
<p>He started his library more than 20 years ago when he set 50 books on the walkway in front of his home. Guanlao's collection has grown greatly over the years -- thanks to a continuous supply of books from donors.</p>
<p>Speaking of donors, he said, "They just leave boxes of books outside my house." He has also started donating books himself. He sends reading materials to public schools in far-away communities.</p>
<p>Guanlao's efforts come at a time when reading ability among students in the Philippines remains low. The Program for International Student Assessment reports that reading scores in the Philippines are among the lowest in the world. The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development runs that program.</p>
<p>Students in the Philippines are also facing learning delays in math and science.</p>
<p>Guanlao is firm about his goals: "My <strong>mission</strong> is to give away used and donated books to others at no cost," he said, "and to <strong>promote</strong> education through literature."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Adrian Portugal and Karen Lema reported this story for Reuters News Agency. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><strong><em>– v.</em></strong><strong> </strong><strong> </strong>to stimulate to greater or higher activity <strong>: </strong>make spirited</p>
<p><strong>literature </strong><strong><em>– n.</em></strong><strong> </strong>written works having excellence of form or expression and ideas of lasting and widespread interest</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><strong><em>– n. </em></strong>a preestablished and often self-imposed objective or purpose</p>
<p><strong>promote </strong><strong><em>– v.</em></strong><strong> </strong>to help (something) grow or develop<strong> </strong></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Agency Warns: Mass Coral Bleaching Expected in Near Future  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-agency-warns-mass-coral-bleaching-expected-in-near-future.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American agency that follows the risk of coral bleaching around the world says "the worst bleaching event in the history of the planet may come soon."</p>
<p>Those are the words of Derek Manzello, head of NOAA's Coral Reef Watch.</p>
<p>NOAA is the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A photo of threatened coral off the southern edge of Florida. (REUTERS/Maria Alejandra Cardona/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ad1c2456-02cd-438d-82bb-045e728f364a_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A photo of threatened coral off the southern edge of Florida. (REUTERS/Maria Alejandra Cardona/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Manzello said the "<strong>entirety</strong>" of the Southern Hemisphere is "probably going to bleach this year." The Southern Hemisphere is currently in summer and suffering from record-breaking water temperatures.</p>
<p>Experts say climate change and the El Nino weather pattern are to blame for the warmer water.</p>
<p><strong>Sensitive organisms</strong></p>
<p>Corals are small marine organisms that attach to mineral <strong>deposits</strong> in the ocean. Collections of the animals form ocean structures that support many kinds of sea life.</p>
<p>Bleaching is the term used by experts who see the once colorful coral turn white when water temperatures rise. It is a sign the animals are dying.</p>
<p>If corals die or go <strong>dormant</strong>, they can hurt fishing and tourism industries.</p>
<p>The last large coral bleaching event around the world took place from 2014 to 2017. At the time, the Great Barrier Reef off Australia lost nearly one-third of its coral. Overall, the world lost 15 percent of its coral.</p>
<p>Corals get their color from small plants called algae that live inside them. The high temperatures stress the coral and cause them to <strong>expel</strong> the algae. When that happens, the corals lose their color. The algae help the coral stay healthy and without it, the corals face increasing risk of disease.</p>
<p>Observers are concerned that 2024's bleaching will be even worse than the last time. Scientists reported the worst coral bleaching on record in the Caribbean late last year.</p>
<p>Manzello said there is coral bleaching "all over the place" in the Southern Hemisphere. He said all of the Great Barrier Reef is bleaching as are reefs in the territory of American Samoa.</p>
<p>The El Nino weather pattern always brings warmer ocean temperatures. However, the world just experienced one of the warmest 12-month periods on record. In 2023, temperatures were 1.5 degrees Celsius higher than during pre-industrial times. Scientists say a longer period of high temperatures could cause the deaths of 90 percent of the world's coral.</p>
<p>Manzello noted that scientists must look at coral in all three major oceans – Atlantic, Pacific and Indian – to call a bleaching event "global."</p>
<p>Scientists use sea surface temperature data and examine satellite imagery of reefs to measure for bleaching. Based on studies so far, Manzello said the world is "already there."</p>
<p>A similar study of Indian Ocean coral is continuing.</p>
<p>Joanne Manning is a spokesperson for the Australian Institute of Marine Science. Manning said the organization has documented extensive bleaching in the Keppels area and Capricorn-Bunker groups. She said the group's research continues.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>entirety </strong>–adj. everything, or the full amount</p>
<p><strong>deposit </strong>–n. a substance left behind, or created during a chemical reaction</p>
<p><strong>dormant </strong>–adj. not actively growing but still alive, such as when grass turns brown in the winter</p>
<p><strong>expel </strong>–v. to push something out</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Looks at How 15-year-olds Learn English  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/study-looks-at-how-15-year-olds-learn-english.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Today's English students have a lot of <strong>exposure</strong> to the language outside of the classroom. By using the internet, social media, and other <strong>digital</strong> technologies, they can watch videos, hear music, and play video games in English.</p>
<p>But teachers are not so sure that digital exposure results in better English-speaking abilities. That is the finding of a new study on how teenagers learn English. The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, or OECD, a group that studies economic activities in large economies, supported the study.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/a3fcacd5-en/1/3/8/index.html?itemId=/content/publication/a3fcacd5-en&amp;_csp_=699fa32b3d47245b9d0bc15535a1d6cf&amp;itemIGO=oecd&amp;itemContentType=book">study</a> is called "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/education/how-15-year-olds-learn-english_f30ed0a4-en">How 15-Year-Olds Learn English.</a>" It provides case studies of teaching teenagers English from five countries: Finland, Greece, Israel, the Netherlands and Portugal. The researchers gathered information by visiting schools and observing English lessons in each country. They also <strong>interviewed</strong> teachers, students and school administrators.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - ESL (English-as-a-second-language) teacher Xavier Chavez, standing, teaches a summer history class at Benson High School in Portland, Ore.,Wednesday, Aug. 6, 2008. (AP Photo/Don Ryan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/D453CE0D-CF25-4D78-912C-54154923EB59_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - ESL (English-as-a-second-language) teacher Xavier Chavez, standing, teaches a summer history class at Benson High School in Portland, Ore.,Wednesday, Aug. 6, 2008. (AP Photo/Don Ryan)</span></div>
<p>The study findings will be used to support the OECD's 2025 Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA), said Catalina Covacevich. She was one of the study's main researchers. PISA studies the school systems of about 90 countries by measuring the performance of 15-year-olds in reading, writing and math. In 2025, PISA will aim to measure 22 of those countries' English language skills for the first time.</p>
<p>"It's an <strong>obvious</strong> statement that English <strong>transcends</strong> classroom walls," Christa Rawkins told VOA. She was another one of the researchers for the study.</p>
<p>Teens spoke "about the ways they used English with people on those sorts of social networking sites and other media. But it was rarer that they were talking about sitting down to learn English via those <strong>platforms</strong>."</p>
<p>Some students in Greece said it is easier to search for English-language information on the internet because more of it is available. In the Netherlands, 15-year-olds described watching English YouTube videos. In a written opinion study, half of students in the Netherlands reported always using English when using digital tools.</p>
<p>Teachers however are unsure whether digital tools are improving students' English knowledge. While teachers said using English platforms might increase students' motivation to learn and help them get used to the language, the platforms "are not necessarily teaching them English," Rawkins said.</p>
<p>One teacher in Finland, for example, said students might get the false idea that they do not need to study English because of how often they use English outside of school.</p>
<p>"They think they know it better than I do because they use it in computer games and it's present in their lives all the time," the teacher said. "They think they don't have to listen to me in English classes, I feel that is a <strong>challenge</strong>.</p>
<p>Rawkins said there is a "slight disconnect" between the kind of English students are learning outside of school "and the kind of English they're being asked to learn and study in classrooms." Students might feel that "studying English at school is just about studying <strong>grammar</strong> whereas outside (of) school they can communicate and interact in the language," the report said.</p>
<p>A large part of OECD's work with PISA, the researchers said, is examining <strong>inequities</strong> in education. Rawkins said there can be large inequities that arise from the kinds of out-of-school exposure kids get to English. Kids from wealthy families are able to travel to English-speaking countries or attend summer camps where they can speak English to international friends, for example. Some students can pay for private lessons.</p>
<p>"Kids living in cities were more likely to be using English out and about in their daily lives compared to their counterparts in more rural areas," Rawkins added.</p>
<p>There has been a big change in how students are exposed to English outside of school. But within the classroom, things "hadn't really changed." The report noted how digital technologies are used within the classroom, but traditional teaching methods, like textbooks, were still used in every school observed.</p>
<p>Teachers in all five countries said their students struggled the most with writing and speaking English rather than in reading and listening. Researchers noted that students might feel a lack of self-confidence when it comes to speaking. They might also be less likely to speak and write English outside of school.</p>
<p>"Outside school they're doing a lot of reading and listening to English because that's what the majority of their exposure is, particularly when it comes to digital technologies," Rawkins said. "They're not doing so much speaking or writing."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exposure </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of experiencing or meeting something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>digital </strong>–adj. related to computers and computing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>interview </strong>–v. to talk to someone to get information and learn about something they know about</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>obvious </strong><em>— adj. </em>something everyone knows<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transcend </strong><em>— v. </em>to go beyond or above something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>platform </strong>–n. a service or network that distributes information or messages</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>challenge </strong>–n. something that is done that must be overcome or dealt with using effort</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grammar </strong>–n. the rules of language use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inequity </strong><em>— n.(social) </em>the state of being unequal or unbalanced especially when talking about how people feel about social relationships between groups<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Haiti's Leader to Resign amid Gang Violence  (2024/3/13) | 海地总理辞职</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/haiti-s-leader-to-resign-amid-gang-violence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Haitian Prime Minister Ariel Henry announced early Tuesday that he would resign once a transitional council is created. The move followed international pressure to save the country from violent criminal groups.<br/>
海地总理阿里埃尔·亨利周二早些时候宣布，一旦过渡委员会成立，他将辞职。此举是在国际社会施加压力，要求将该国从暴力犯罪集团手中拯救出来之后做出的。</p>
<p>Henry announced the decision hours after meeting with leaders of neighboring Caribbean nations and American Secretary of State Antony Blinken. The group met in Jamaica to discuss a solution to Haiti's crisis. They agreed to a joint proposal to establish a transitional council.<br/>
亨利在与加勒比邻国领导人和美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯会晤数小时后宣布了这一决定。该群体在牙买加举行会议，讨论海地危机的解决方案。他们同意了建立一个过渡委员会的联合提议。</p>
<p>"The government that I'm running cannot remain insensitive in front of this situation. There is no sacrifice that is too big for our country," Henry said in a videotaped statement. "The government I'm running will remove itself immediately after the installation of the council."<br/>
亨利在一份录像声明中说：“我所领导的政府在这种情况面前不能麻木不仁。对我们的国家来说，没有太大的牺牲。我所领导的政府将在委员会成立后立即解散。”</p>
<p>After the announcement, Haitians celebrated in the streets in the capital Port-au-Prince, dancing and playing music, Reuters news agency reported, based on videos posted on Haitian social media.<br/>
据路透社报道，根据海地社交媒体上发布的视频，该消息宣布后，海地人在首都太子港街头载歌载舞地庆祝。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Haiti under Henry<br/>
亨利统治下的海地</span></p>
<p>Henry took power in 2021 following the murder of President Jovenel Moise. Under his administration, armed criminal groups, called gangs, grew in wealth and power.<br/>
亨利于2021年在总统约维尼尔·莫伊兹被谋杀后掌权。在他的领导下，被称为帮派的武装犯罪集团的财富和权力不断增加。</p>
<p>In late February, Henry traveled to Kenya to secure its support for a United Nations-backed security mission to help Haitian police. However, the violence greatly increased in his absence. It led to the closing of the country's main international airports.<br/>
2月下旬，亨利前往肯尼亚，以确保其对联合国支持的一项帮助海地警察的安全任务的支持。然而，在他缺席期间，暴力事件大大增加。这导致该国主要国际机场关闭。</p>
<p>Armed gangs have burned police stations and raided two of the country's biggest prisons. The raids resulted in the release of more than 4,000 prisoners.<br/>
武装团伙烧毁了警察局，并突袭了该国两所最大的监狱。突袭行动导致了4000多名囚犯被释放。</p>
<p>Many Haitians have been killed and more than 15,000 are homeless after fleeing neighborhoods raided by gangs. Stores are running out of goods. Food and water are lacking. The main port in the capital city is closed, keeping supplies away.<br/>
许多海地人被杀害，还有15000多人在逃离被帮派袭击的社区后无家可归。商店里的商品眼看要销售一空。食物和水缺乏。首都的主要港口已经关闭，物资供应中断。</p>
<p>Henry arrived in Puerto Rico a week ago, after being barred from landing in the Dominican Republic, Haiti's neighbor. Dominican officials also closed the airspace to flights to and from Haiti.<br/>
亨利一周前抵达波多黎各，此前他被禁止在海地的邻国多米尼加共和国降落。多米尼加官员还对进出海地的航班关闭了领空。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">International force<br/>
国际力量</span></p>
<p>On Monday, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said the new council would be responsible for meeting the "immediate needs" of Haitians. They include the deployment of an international security mission to help police fight armed criminals.<br/>
周一，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示，新的委员会将负责满足海地人的“迫切需求”。其中包括部署一个国际安全特派团，帮助警察打击武装罪犯。</p>
<p>The U.S. would also provide an additional $100 million to this mission and $33 million in humanitarian aid, bringing the U.S. total promise to $300 million.<br/>
美国还将向这项任务额外提供1亿美元和3300万美元的人道主义援助，使美国的承诺总额达到3亿美元。</p>
<p>A U.N. spokesperson said that, as of Monday, less than $11 million had been provided to the U.N.'s account for the mission. No financial contributions have arrived since Haiti declared its state of emergency on March 3.<br/>
联合国发言人表示，截至周一，联合国负责该任务的账户收到的援助不足1100万美元。自3月3日海地宣布进入紧急状态以来，没有收到任何财政捐款。</p>
<p>As Haiti prepares for new leadership, some experts question the role of armed gangs that control 80 percent of Port-au-Prince.<br/>
在海地筹备新领导层之际，一些专家质疑控制太子港80%地区的武装组织的作用。</p>
<p>"Even if you have a different kind of government, the reality is that you need to talk to the gangs," said Robert Fatton, a Haitian politics expert at the University of Virginia.<br/>
弗吉尼亚大学海地政治专家罗伯特·法顿说：“即使有了一个不同类型的政府，现实是你需要与帮派对话。”</p>
<p>Fatton said officials will still have to deal with the armed groups and try to convince them to give up their weapons, "but what would be their concessions?"<br/>
法顿说，官员们仍将不得不与武装组织打交道，并试图说服他们放弃武器，“但他们会做出什么让步？”</p>
<p>The United Nations estimates over 362,000 people have been internally displaced in Haiti. The organization says thousands have been killed in the conflict overall, with widespread reports of rape, torture and kidnappings since 2021.<br/>
联合国估计，海地境内有362000多人流离失所。该机构表示，自2021年以来，已有数千人在冲突中丧生，同时有大量关于强奸、酷刑和绑架的报道。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Shevchenko Garden: A Peaceful Oasis in Kharkiv  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/shevchenko-garden-a-peaceful-oasis-in-kharkiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/z/7773" target="_blank">Teach Us about Ukraine</a>" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>My name is Oksana Chelombitko. I teach at Chuhuiv Lyceum No. 1. This is my essay.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Taras Shevchenko Park is opposite the university in Kharkiv. (Adobe Stock Photo by Oleh Rode)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1ca4-08dc3c880932_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Taras Shevchenko Park is opposite the university in Kharkiv. (Adobe Stock Photo by Oleh Rode)</span></div>
<p>Shevchenko Garden, located in the heart of Kharkiv, is a significant public park named after the renowned Ukrainian poet Taras Shevchenko. Established in 1907, the garden has a rich history, beginning as a botanical garden showcasing Ukraine's diverse flora. Over the years, it has transformed into a beloved recreational space, hosting various events, art exhibitions and concerts, making it an integral part of Kharkiv's cultural scene.</p>
<p>In addition to its cultural significance, Shevchenko Garden plays a crucial role in preserving biodiversity. The park is home to a wide range of plant and animal species, some of which are rare and endangered. You can freely visit the modern and renovated Kharkiv Zoo, which is located in Shevchenko Garden. Efforts are made by the park's caretakers to maintain the ecological balance, ensuring the conservation of these species for future generations.</p>
<p>The garden's allure is not only in its natural beauty but also in its ability to bring people together. Families gather for picnics, children enjoy outdoor activities, and artists find inspiration amidst the serene surroundings. There are small, cozy cafes and ice cream stalls, restaurants, and coffee shops, a concert hall, and an opera house. Lots of people spend their time in this peaceful and tranquil place. Shevchenko Garden serves as a symbol of unity in Kharkiv, welcoming people from diverse backgrounds and fostering a sense of community. This is very important nowadays during the war; people in Kharkiv are courageous and resilient. They adore the city and make it better every single day.</p>
<p>Today, Shevchenko Garden stands as a testament to the city's cultural richness and the harmonious existence of nature and humanity. It continues to be a peaceful oasis where visitors can experience the beauty of nature and the spirit of Kharkiv in a peaceful setting.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the Writer</h2>
<p>Oksana Chelombitko was born and still lives in Chuhuiv, a city in eastern Ukraine. She graduated from Skovoroda Kharkiv National Pedagogical University and has worked as a teacher for 11 years. They have been learning online only since September 2022, and she misses her students in person. Despite the war in their country, they are working hard for a better future.</p>
<p><em>What do you think of this story? Let us know in the Comments.</em></p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pacific’s Gray Whale Found off Atlantic Coast  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/pacific-s-gray-whale-found-off-atlantic-coast.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have confirmed the presence of a gray whale off New England in North America recently.</p>
<p>The large sea animal disappeared from the Atlantic Ocean two centuries ago. The scientists are <strong>thrilled</strong> with the discovery but they say it shows the effects of climate change on sea life.</p>
<p>Researchers with the New England Aquarium in Boston found the gray whale on March 1. At the time, they were flying about 48 kilometers south of Nantucket, an island off the coast of Massachusetts in the Atlantic. The whale, which can weigh over 27,000 kilograms, usually lives in the northern Pacific Ocean.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo by Orla O'Brien shows a gray whale south of Nantucket, Massachusetts, on March 1, 2024. (Orla O'Brien/New England Aquarium via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4df06435-4a5a-48fe-9f23-5371a5704f55_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo by Orla O'Brien shows a gray whale south of Nantucket, Massachusetts, on March 1, 2024. (Orla O'Brien/New England Aquarium via AP)</span></div>
<p>The gray whale disappeared from the Atlantic Ocean by the 18th century. But there have been five observations of the animal in the Atlantic and Mediterranean waters in the last 15 years, the aquarium said in a statement. The whale found this month was likely the same animal observed off the coast of Florida late last year, the aquarium said.</p>
<p>The researchers who found the animal off Massachusetts said they were not sure at first. But after circling the area for 45 minutes, they were able to take photographs that confirmed it was a gray whale.</p>
<p>"I didn't want to say out loud what it was, because it seemed <strong>crazy</strong>," said Orla O'Brien. She is a research scientist with the Anderson Cabot Center for Ocean Life at the New England Aquarium.</p>
<p>Scientists said they were thrilled to see the animal, but its presence probably has to do with the warming of the planet. The Northwest Passage, which connects the Atlantic and Pacific oceans through the Arctic Ocean in Canada, has lacked ice in the summertime in recent years, they said.</p>
<p>That means gray whales can travel through the passage in the summer when normally they would have been blocked, the scientists said. O'Brien said the animal's arrival off New England serves "as a reminder of how quickly <strong>marine species</strong> respond to climate change, given the chance."</p>
<p>Gray whales were almost completely killed off by hunting during the years of <strong>commercial</strong> whaling. Today, the whales have recovered to the point that they are considered a species of "least concern" by the International Union for Conservation of Nature. The organization, however, considers the western population of whales that live off the coast of Asia to be endangered.</p>
<p>They can be identified by the lack of a part of a body often seen on other whales: a dorsal fin. Also, they can be identified by their <strong>blotchy</strong> appearance which is different from the humpback and minke whales seen off New England. Gray whales can also be identified by the unusual sounds they make.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Patrick Whittle reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>thrill </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling of great excitement or happiness</p>
<p><strong>crazy </strong><em>– adj. </em>very strange or unusual</p>
<p><strong>marine </strong><em>– adj. </em>of or relating to the sea or the plants and animals that live in the sea</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong><em>– adj. </em>concerned with earning money</p>
<p><strong>blotchy </strong><em>– n. </em>a usually dark-colored spot especially on the skin</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Grow Mini-organs in Cells from Pregnancy Fluid  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/scientists-grow-mini-organs-in-cells-from-pregnancy-fluid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health and Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>British researchers say they have grown small human organs using cells removed from fluid that protects developing fetuses.</p>
<p>These organs are known as mini-organs, or organoids. They are extremely small, simple structures. They could be used in testing of new medical treatments or to study the workings of full-size organs.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This microscope image provided by researchers in March 2024 shows a lung organoid created from cells collected from amniotic fluid. (Giuseppe Cal&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;224;, Paolo De Coppi, Mattia Gerli via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4d2a-08dc3eb3e96f_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This microscope image provided by researchers in March 2024 shows a lung organoid created from cells collected from amniotic fluid. (Giuseppe Cal<i>&amp;#</i>224;, Paolo De Coppi, Mattia Gerli via AP)</span></div>
<p>The University College London carried out the study. Researchers collected the cells from fluid removed from 12 pregnant women during routine medical examinations at Great Ormond Street Hospital in London.</p>
<p>The cells then were grown into organoids in a laboratory. The researchers said it was the first time such mini-organs had been produced from cells collected during an active pregnancy.</p>
<p>The scientists said they hope their method will lead to future methods for treating conditions present before birth.</p>
<p>Mattia Gerli of University College London was a lead writer of the study. He told the<em> </em>Associated Press (AP) that he and his team were "really excited" about how their research might result in important new treatment possibilities.</p>
<p>The findings were reported <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-024-02807-z">in a study</a> that recently appeared in the publication <em>Nature Medicine.</em></p>
<p>Scientists have so far produced organoids that look like some human organs, including the brain, kidney, lung, stomach and liver. Lab-grown mini-organs are generally used to study how organs work without the need to experiment on real ones.</p>
<p>The scientists looked for which tissues the stem cells came from and then identified cells from three organs: lungs, kidneys and intestines.</p>
<p>In the past, organoids could only be created from adult stem cells or tissues collected after an abortion. An abortion is a medical operation to end a pregnancy.</p>
<p>The current method does not violate rules that govern direct removal of stem cells from fetal tissue. The amniotic fluid method permits scientists to get cells from fetuses during the <strong>latter</strong> parts of pregnancy.</p>
<p>Governments around the world have different <strong>regulations</strong> covering abortions. In Britain, the legal limit for ending a pregnancy is generally 22 weeks after <strong>conception</strong>. This rule prevents British researchers from studying some parts of normal human development or diseases that are present past 22 weeks.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>In the United States, abortion restrictions differ by state. Most states ban the use of fetal tissue for research, said Alta Charo. She is a retired professor of law and bioethics at the University of Wisconsin at Madison. Charo was not part of the latest study.</p>
<p>Fetal tissue is <a class="wsw__a" href="https://grants.nih.gov/grants/policy/nihgps/html5/section_4/4.1.14_human_fetal_tissue_research.htm#:~:text=Human%20fetal%20tissue%20is%20defined,or%20induced%20abortion%20or%20stillbirth.">defined</a> by the National Institutes of Health as material coming from a dead human embryo or fetus. The tissue could come from a fetus that was aborted or did not survive because of medical problems with the pregnancy. The use of tissue from an abortion has long been <strong>controversial</strong>.</p>
<p>Charo said the new method does not raise the same <strong>ethical </strong>concerns. And taking amniotic fluid during a woman's pregnancy "does not appear to add any physical risks to either fetus or pregnant woman," Charo said in an email to the AP.</p>
<p>As part of the experiments, the researchers worked with scientists in Belgium to study the development of babies with a condition called congenital diaphragmatic hernia. This can result in organs such as the liver and intestines getting displaced into the chest. About 30 percent of fetuses with this disease die because the lungs cannot fully develop. If doctors could identify the condition before birth, they could operate on a fetus to fix it.</p>
<p>In the experiments, researchers grew lung organoids from the cells of fetuses with the hernia condition before and after treatment. When comparing those organoids to organoids from healthy fetuses, the team was able to use the lab method to identify the affected child's condition before birth.</p>
<p>The scientists said this ability to study working, pre-birth mini-organs is the first step toward establishing more detailed <strong>prognosis</strong> information and improving treatment methods.</p>
<p>And that's the Health and Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conception </strong><em>– n. </em>the moment when a woman or animal becomes pregnant</p>
<p><strong>controversial </strong><em>– adj. </em>causing a lot of disagreement or argument</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to what is right or wrong</p>
<p><strong>latter</strong> - <em>adj</em>. coming or happening near the end of a process, activity, series, life, etc</p>
<p><strong>regulation</strong> - <em>n</em>. an official rule or law that says how something should be done</p>
<p><strong>prognosis </strong><em>– n. </em>a judgement<em> </em>a doctor makes about a sick person's change of becoming healthy</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>War and Peace at the Oscars  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/war-and-peace-at-the-oscars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>American film <em>Oppenheimer</em> was the big winner at the Academy Awards Sunday in Los Angeles, California. The Academy honored the film about a creator of the atomic bomb with seven Oscars.</p>
<p>The televised event presented a usual mix of moods and messages. There was a reminder of the recent death in a Russian prison of opposition leader Alexei Navalny. Demonstrators called for a cease-fire in Gaza at a protest outside the Dolby Theatre where the event took place. And there was a bit of election-year politics from ceremony host Jimmy Kimmel.</p>
<p>But there was also joyful<strong> </strong>fun, as when actor Ryan Gosling performed <em>I'm</em> <em>Just Ken</em>, a nominated song from the film <em>Barbie</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Oppenheimer British film producer Emma Thomas (C) accepts the award for Best Picture onstage during the 96th Annual Academy Awards at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, California on March 10, 2024. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/bb27ae2e-5806-472f-ba71-e44ac495bcd1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">"Oppenheimer" British film producer Emma Thomas (C) accepts the award for Best Picture onstage during the 96th Annual Academy Awards at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, California on March 10, 2024. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The night, though, belonged not to <em>Barbie</em> but to its partner in the cultural event known as "Barbenheimer."</p>
<p><em>Oppenheimer's</em> seven wins include the top prize of best picture. Director Christopher Nolan also took home the Oscar for directing while the film's star Cillian Murphy received the best actor award. And <em>Oppenheimer's</em> Robert Downey Jr won the Oscar for best supporting actor. It is his first Academy Award.</p>
<p>Many of those wins were expected, but the Oscars did hold some surprises. The race for the best actress was considered very close this year. And, Emma Stone looked shocked when her name was called for her performance in the movie, <em>Poor Things</em>.</p>
<p>Stone won her first Oscar, also for best actress, in 2017 for <em>La La Land</em>.</p>
<p>Here are some more of the night's notable moments:</p>
<p>Jimmy Kimmel was hosting the Academy Awards for a fourth time. Late in the show he presented a social media post about the ceremony from former president Donald Trump.</p>
<p>"Thank you for watching," Kimmel said, adding, "isn't it past your jail time?"</p>
<p><strong>A call for peace In Ukraine...</strong></p>
<p><em>Associated Press</em> reporter Mstyslav Chernov, was one of the filmmakers accepting the best documentary Oscar for <em>20 Days in Mariupol</em>. He noted that it was the first Oscar in the history of his country, Ukraine. He said he was honored – but then added: "Probably I will be the first director on this stage to say I wish I'd never made this film." The film is an account of the early days of Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</p>
<p>Chernov called on Russia to end the war in Ukraine. "We can make sure that the history record is set straight ... and those who have given their lives, will never be forgotten," he said.</p>
<p><strong>And in Gaza</strong></p>
<p>Jonathan Glazer's <em>The Zone of Interest</em> takes place during World War II. It is about the family of a Nazi commandant living next to the Auschwitz death camp. But it was a current war that the writer-director spoke about when accepting his Oscar for best international film.</p>
<p>"Our film shows where dehumanization leads at its worst," Glazer said, before speaking about the conflict in Gaza. "Right now we stand here as men who <strong>refute</strong> their Jewishness and the Holocaust being hijacked by an occupation which has led to conflict for so many innocent people," he said. "Whether the victims of October the 7th in Israel or the ongoing attack on Gaza, all the victims of this dehumanization, how do we resist?"</p>
<p><strong>A sad reminder</strong></p>
<p>"If they decide to kill me, it means that we are incredibly strong." Those words from Navalny, the Russian opposition leader, began the memorial to industry members who died over the year. He was the subject of last year's winning documentary, <em>Navalny</em>. His wife stood on the Oscar stage that night and spoke directly to him: "Alexei, I am dreaming of the day when you will be free and our country will be free," Yulia Navalnaya said.</p>
<p><strong>Nolan's ‘incredible journey'</strong></p>
<p>Winning his first directing Oscar, the 53-year-old Nolan noted that <strong>cinema</strong> is just over 100 years old. "Imagine being there 100 years into painting or theater. We don't know where this <strong>incredible journey</strong> is going from here. But to know that you think that I'm a meaningful part of it means the world to me."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>refute </strong><em>— v. </em>to say that something is not true</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cinema </strong><em>— n. </em>the film industry</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>incredible </strong><em>— adj. </em> difficult or impossible to believe</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>journey </strong><em>— n. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Britain’s Princess Kate Apologizes for ‘Confusion’ over Official Photo  (2024/3/12) | 凯特王妃为P图造成混乱道歉</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/britain-s-princess-kate-apologizes-for-confusion-over-official-photo.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Kate, Britain's Princess of Wales, apologized Monday for "any confusion" caused by a photo released over the weekend. The official photo was the first image of the princess since she had a medical operation nearly two months ago.<br/>
英国威尔士王妃凯特周一为周末发布的一张照片造成的“任何混乱”道歉。这张官方照片是凯特王妃近两个月前接受医疗手术后的第一张照片。</p>
<p>Kensington Palace released the photograph on social media on Sunday. It showed the 42-year-old Kate looking healthy and sitting and smiling in a chair surrounded by her three children. The photo was credited to Kate's husband, Prince William, and was said to have been taken earlier in the week in Windsor.<br/>
肯辛顿宫周日在社交媒体上发布了这张照片。照片显示，42岁的凯特看起来很健康，她坐在椅子上面带微笑，身边环绕着她的三个孩子。这张照片被当成凯特王妃的丈夫威廉王子的作品，据说是本周早些时候在温莎城堡拍摄的。</p>
<p>In a message on X, Kate wrote, "Thank you for your kind wishes and continued support over the last two months." Her message also wished people a "Happy Mother's Day," as Britain celebrated the holiday on Sunday.<br/>
凯特在X网站上的一条消息中写道：“感谢你们过去两个月里的善意祝福和持续支持。”在英国周日庆祝母亲节之际，凯特还祝人们“母亲节快乐”。</p>
<p>But shortly after the photo was published, some royal observers online began raising questions about whether the picture had been changed in some ways with image editing tools.<br/>
但在照片发布后不久，网络上的一些王室观察人员开始质疑这张照片是否经过了图像编辑工具的某种修改。</p>
<p>
After close examination, several major news organizations withdrew the photo, saying it did in fact appear to have been edited in some way. Because of these changes, the picture did not meet the requirements set by those news organizations.<br/>
经过仔细检查，几家主要新闻机构撤回了这张照片，称其实际上似乎经过了某种编辑。由于这些改动，图片不符合这些新闻机构设定的要求。</p>
<p>After the questions about the image were raised, Kate issued another message on X. She wrote, "Like many amateur photographers, I do occasionally experiment with editing. I wanted to express my apologies for any confusion the family photograph we shared yesterday caused."<br/>
在人们对这张照片提出质疑后，凯特在X上发布了另一条消息。她写道：“和许多业余摄影师一样，我偶尔也会尝试修图。我想对我们昨天分享的全家福造成的任何混乱表示歉意。”</p>
<p>Among the news agencies withdrawing the photo were The Associated Press, Reuters, the French news agency AFP, Getty Images, and Britain's Press Association.<br/>
撤回这张照片的新闻机构包括美联社、路透社、法国法新社、盖蒂图片社和英国新闻协会。</p>
<p>Photo editors for Reuters said their examinations of the image showed the left arm of Kate's daughter, Princess Charlotte, did not seem to line up naturally with her body in the picture. This suggested that editing changes had been made to the photo.<br/>
路透社的图片编辑表示，他们对照片的检查显示，凯特王妃的女儿夏洛特公主的左臂似乎与照片中的身体对不上。这表明对照片进行了编辑更改。</p>
<p>Different news agencies have different policies regarding how much an image can be changed before being released. Both Reuters and the AP said the changes violated their editorial rules. Most news organizations generally only permit minor photo editing, such as cropping and making light and color changes.<br/>
各家新闻机构对图片在发布前可以有多大调整有着不同的政策。路透社和美联社都表示，这些调整违反了他们的编辑规则。大多数新闻机构通常只允许对照片进行小的编辑，如裁剪、调整光线和颜色。</p>
<p>The picture had already drawn widespread media attention online. This is because it was the first official image of Kate since she spent two weeks in the hospital after undergoing an abdominal operation in January. Her exact condition was not identified.<br/>
这张照片已经在网上引起了媒体的广泛关注。这是凯特一月份接受腹部手术并住院两周后的第一张官方照片。她的确切情况尚未确定。</p>
<p>Kate's office had said during her absence that she was recovering well and was not expected to return to her public duties until after Easter, which is March 31.<br/>
凯特办公室在她缺席期间表示，她恢复得很好，预计要到3月31日复活节后才能重返公职。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Data Suggests Jupiter’s Moon Europa Has Less Oxygen than Expected  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/new-data-suggests-jupiter-s-moon-europa-has-less-oxygen-than-expected.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests Jupiter's icy moon Europa produces much less oxygen than previously thought.</p>
<p>The study was based on data collected by the American space agency NASA's Juno spacecraft. Juno is an orbiter that has been studying Jupiter since July 2016.</p>
<p>The study involved Juno's instruments measuring levels of oxygen and hydrogen molecules coming from Europa's atmosphere. The data showed the icy moon produces about 1,000 tons of oxygen every 24 hours. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/juno/nasas-juno-mission-measures-oxygen-production-at-europa/">said</a> that amount would be enough "to keep a million humans breathing for a day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image made available by NASA in 2014 shows Jupiter's icy moon Europa in a reprocessed color view, made from images captured by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/SETI Institute via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-cfbd-08dc3f79ca56_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image made available by NASA in 2014 shows Jupiter's icy moon Europa in a reprocessed color view, made from images captured by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/SETI Institute via AP)</span></div>
<p>However, the space agency noted those oxygen level estimates were "<strong>substantially</strong> less" than those measured in earlier studies about the moon.</p>
<p>Europa is a little smaller than Earth's moon. But it is still one of the largest in our solar system. NASA observations have suggested an ocean exists beneath a thick layer of ice on Europa's surface. Scientists estimate the moon's ocean may contain twice the amount of water as Earth's oceans.</p>
<p>The new study is based on data Juno collected in 2022 during a particularly close flyby of Europa. The flyby is believed to have brought the spacecraft within 350 kilometers of the moon.</p>
<p>The research was led by teams from Princeton University in New Jersey and Maryland's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/">Southwest Research Institute</a>. The scientists estimated Europa is producing around 12 kilograms of oxygen per second. Earlier predictions suggested the moon was releasing up to 1,000 kilograms per second.</p>
<p>Since Europa is believed to have a large ocean under its surface, researchers in the past identified it <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/ocean-on-jupiter-moon-europa-may-have-supported-life/5481557.html">as a good candidate</a> to hold the right conditions to support some form of life. That data came mainly from telescope observations of oxygen levels existing in the moon's icy surface.</p>
<p>The new, lower oxygen estimates do not support the earlier observations. The team involved in the study said more research will be needed to confirm the latest findings.</p>
<p>Scott Bolton is a Juno investigator at the Southwest Research Institute and a co-writer of the study. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/press-release/juno-spacecraft-measures-oxygen-production-jupiter-s-moon-europa">said</a> in a statement that the team's new findings have a direct effect on the possibility that Europa could be <strong>habitable</strong>. While the oxygen amounts measured were much lower, the latest study gives scientists "a narrow range that could support habitability," Bolton said.</p>
<p>Princeton University researcher Jamey Szalay was the study's lead writer. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/press-release/juno-spacecraft-measures-oxygen-production-jupiter-s-moon-europa">said</a>, "The findings <strong>unambiguously</strong> demonstrate oxygen is continuously produced at the surface, just a good bit lower than we expected."</p>
<p>Szalay added that Juno's flyby of Europa marked the first time a spacecraft was able to directly measure the moon's atmosphere. "We couldn't wait to <strong>peek behind the curtain</strong> of its complex environment," he wrote to The Associated Press in an email.</p>
<p>The researchers said the new measurements can help scientists gain a better understanding of Europa and its environment, and "open the door for newer, more <strong>precise</strong> models."</p>
<p>Robert Ebert is a researcher at the Southwest Research Institute and a co-writer of the study. He said that even with the new results, he believes further investigations should take place to search for signs of life on Europa. "Water is important for the existence of life... Europa is a good place to search for water within our solar system."</p>
<p>NASA hopes to launch its Europa Clipper mission in October. This orbiter is designed to carry out close examinations of Europa. It will look for signs it might hold the right conditions to support life.</p>
<p>NASA says the orbiter plans to fly in orbit around Jupiter and "perform repeated close flybys of the ice moon."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, NASA, Nature Astronomy and the Southwest Research Institute. </em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>substantial </strong><em>– n. </em>large in amount</p>
<p><strong>habitable </strong><em>– adj. </em>able to support life</p>
<p><strong>unambiguous </strong><em>– n. </em>expressed in a very clear way</p>
<p><strong>peek behind the curtain </strong><em>– n. </em>get a look at something not normally seen</p>
<p><strong>precise</strong><em> – adj. </em>very clear or exact<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Garden Expert Tries New Fruits, Vegetables  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/garden-expert-tries-new-fruits-vegetables.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Jessica Damiano says crops like tomatoes, garlic, chives, basil, parsley, thyme, and sage have been permanent plants in her <strong>garden</strong> for ages. Damiano, a gardening expert who writes for The Associated Press, says every year, she experiments with new – or new to her – crops.</p>
<p>Many do not stay in her garden for long, like the Voyager tomatoes that lack taste or the goji berries she could not seem to eat. But others, like 8-ball zucchini, rainbow Swiss chard, and golden beets have earned permanent homes in her raised beds.</p>
<p>This year's new introductions are available in seed <strong>catalogs</strong> in the U.S.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co. shows Lila Lu Sang carrots, which are deep purple on the outside and bright orange on the inside. (Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co./rareseeds.com via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/673143a3-5d61-4aac-8711-ae45eb5d8372_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co. shows Lila Lu Sang carrots, which are deep purple on the outside and bright orange on the inside. (Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co./rareseeds.com via AP)</span></div>
<p>Four small apple trees from Plants Nouveau called Blushing Delight, Golden Treat, Tangy Green, and Tasty Red, work well for people like Damiano who have limited garden space. The trees grow to 2.5 to 3 meters tall and just a meter wide. And they will even grow in containers. You can plant two different kinds for cross-<strong>pollination</strong> and fruit production.</p>
<p>Another crop, Love Gourmansun beefsteak tomatoes from Burpee, is available in two different kinds that each produce 28-gram, heart-shaped fruits. Choose between Red and a yellow-red fruit called Sunrise. They grow in similar ways and taste similar, but have different disease resistance.</p>
<p>Damiano said she tested another crop from Burpee called Prism Sweet Peppers last summer. She said the sweet, bell-shaped fruits grew well in her garden. The productive plants also added beauty to her garden, as the crop turned from light green to orange and then red as the fruit aged. The result was many different colors of fruits on the plants at any one time.</p>
<p>The crop Quick Snack cucumbers are the newest addition to PanAm Seed's Kitchen Minis collection. They are small enough to be grown in a hanging basket or even indoors since they do not require pollination. The small cucumbers are <strong>crisp</strong> and sweet.</p>
<p>The Pastel Duo baby turnip seed mix, introduced from Japan by Renee's Garden, grows small, round roots in colors like pink and white. Both colors have a <strong>mild</strong>, sweet taste and thin skin that does not need to be removed.</p>
<p>Damiano says her Genovese basil plants often get the disease downy mildew more often than not. She said she is looking forward to growing Noga Prospera Active DMR <strong>organic </strong>basil, produced by Genesis Seeds. The plants are sold as "highly resistant" to the disease. But they are also slow to flower, which she says is another problem she often deals with in the height of the summer's heat.</p>
<p>Finally, the crop Lila Lu Sang carrots offered by Baker Seeds are just about as eye-catching as vegetables can get. They have a deep purple color on the outside and a bright orange color on the inside. But they are more than what one sees: they contain the gains of both purple and orange carrots. They are sweet, tasty and full of nutrients.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong><em>– n. </em>an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>catalog </strong><em>– n. </em>a book containing a list of things that you can buy or use and often pictures</p>
<p><strong>pollinate </strong><em>– v.</em> to give (a plant) pollen from another plant of the same kind so that seeds will be produced</p>
<p><strong>crisp </strong><em>– adj.</em> pleasantly firm and making a sharp sound when chewed or crushed</p>
<p><strong>mild </strong><em>– adj. </em>not strong or harsh in taste</p>
<p><strong>organic </strong><em>– adj.</em> grown or made without the use of artificial chemicals</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France's 'Invader' Could Surprise Olympic Games Visitors  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/france-s-invader-could-surprise-olympic-games-visitors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>When visitors come to Paris for the Olympic Games starting in July, they will be entering the territory of France's most famous street artist: "Invader." It will be one invasion coming face-to-face with another.</p>
<p>Like Banksy, the British street artist he is sometimes compared to, Invader does not want his identity to be publicly known.</p>
<p>Sometimes working close to the edge of illegality, Invader comes, does his art, and disappears into the night. He leaves behind <strong>mosaics</strong> made mostly with small ceramic and glass <strong>tiles</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A mosaic by French artist Invader floats in the International Space Station in 2015. (Samantha Cristoforetti/ESA-NASA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8cd7e268-24be-4394-9b03-65b5e669f695_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A mosaic by French artist Invader floats in the International Space Station in 2015. (Samantha Cristoforetti/ESA-NASA via AP)</span></div>
<p>Many of the mosaics look like the aliens from the Space Invaders video game. Others are very complex <strong>portrayals</strong> of fruit or, in New York, of Lou Reed and Andy Warhol.</p>
<p>Some of his artworks come from popular culture, including Spiderman, Star Wars, Bugs Bunny, Ninja Turtles, pizza and others. Some artworks suggest deep research, including a portrait of guitarist Django Reinhardt facing the house where he lived, south of Paris in Samois-sur-Seine.</p>
<p>Since the first recorded mosaic of a blue Space Invader went up on a Paris street in 1998, numbered PA_01, Invader has taken over the world. There are now more than 4,000 of his mosaics in cities and towns on all continents except Antarctica.</p>
<p>London, Tokyo, Los Angeles and other cities were invaded in 1999; New York and Geneva and more in 2000; Hong Kong in 2001; Berlin, Bangkok, Melbourne. On and on.</p>
<p>The 4,000th mosaic was <strong>glued</strong> to a brick wall in Potosi, 4,000 meters up in the Bolivian Andes, in 2021. The European Space Agency installed Invader's Space2 mosaic aboard the International Space Station in 2015.</p>
<p>"‘Anytime, Anywhere' is the philosophy," Invader says on his website.</p>
<p>In Paris — by far his most invaded area — the artist's footprint is larger than ever as the Olympics draw closer.</p>
<p>A new public showing in a multi-story building has one of his works on its roof, visible via satellite on Google Maps. With a telescope, the show's visitors can also look across Paris to Invader's 1,500th mosaic in the city and surrounding areas.</p>
<p>Announced in February, PA_1500 is glued outside a chimney of the Pompidou Center. Unlike many of his other artworks, Invader got the center's permission to put the red-and-white Space Invader alien into place.</p>
<p>"It's a <strong>symbol</strong>. It's number 1,500. It's Paris," said Alexandre Aumis, the building's security director. He added, "It's got to be here."</p>
<p>Some of those who know Invader say they are expecting him to spring more surprises for the Olympics, perhaps installing new mosaics related to the Games.</p>
<p>Fabrice Bousteau is the <strong>editor</strong> of Beaux Arts Magazine. He said, "The invasion is the 15 million people who are going to arrive in Paris for the Olympic Games. It's a lot. Obviously, there will be Invader fans among them."</p>
<p>Bousteau, who also directed Invader's latest public showing, added, "So there will be this meeting between two cultures...He will doubtless invade the Games in a different way. I am almost certain."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Leicester reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mosaic<em> </em></strong><em>– n. </em> a kind of art made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material</p>
<p><strong>tile </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat piece of material that is used for covering walls, floors, etc.</p>
<p><strong>portrayal </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong> the act of showing someone or something especially in a painting</p>
<p><strong>glue </strong><em>-- v. </em>to make (something) stick to something else by using glue</p>
<p><strong>chimney<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the part of a building that sticks up above the roof</p>
<p><strong>symbol </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>an object that expresses or represents a particular idea</p>
<p><strong>editor </strong><em>-- n. </em> a person whose job is to edit something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dovbush Rocks: Secrets of the Stone Giants  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/dovbush-rocks-secrets-of-the-stone-giants.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>Hello everyone. My name is Natalia Lavryk. I am an English teacher from Ukraine. I would like to introduce you to my country—its beautiful nature and very hard-working and friendly people, who most of all want peace, freedom, and independence.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Dovbush rocks, a group of rocks, natural and man-made caves carved into stone. Photo taken on Oct. 22, 2020. (Adobe Stock Photo by Iryna_l)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5ed2-08dc3d5b737b_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Dovbush rocks, a group of rocks, natural and man-made caves carved into stone. Photo taken on Oct. 22, 2020. (Adobe Stock Photo by Iryna_l)</span></div>
<p>As the world watches Ukraine's fight for freedom, its soldiers have become a symbol of unbreakable resistance. For Ukrainians, nothing represents that spirit more than the giant stones in the Carpathian Mountains called Dovbush Rocks.</p>
<p>Located on the border of Ivano-Frankivsk and Lviv areas, Dovbush Rocks covers about 100 hectares. The website <a class="wsw__a" href="https://vidviday.ua/blog/en/dovbush-rocks-carpathian-mountains/">vidviday.ua</a> says the volcanic giant stones once rested at the bottom of the ancient sea. They are now surrounded by green forests. Named a national monument in 1981, they are seen as a "place of power" and are popular with visitors seeking a mystical experience.</p>
<p>The rocks are named after Oleksa Dovbush, a Robin Hood-like figure, who used them as a hideout in the 18th century. As a leader of a group of rebels, he fought against the oppressive forces that ruled the area. The rocky terrain, with its numerous caves and narrow passages, provided the perfect refuge for Dovbush and his followers.</p>
<p>Ancient storytellers said that Oleksa was killed by the husband of his former lover Dzvinka, who turned into a rock for her betrayal. And Oleksa's body was dismembered and spread throughout the mountains.</p>
<p><strong>Visiting Dovbush Rocks</strong></p>
<p>Last summer I visited this mysterious place with my students from the Lyceum of Otyniia, a school for students ages six to 17. The energy of this place is impossible to forget. We felt there was a special force that inspired us to do great things and build our inner strength.</p>
<p>The path through the cave is so narrow that, at times, it may seem that there is no way out. In some places, the distance between the rocks is very narrow, only 20 to 30 centimeters wide. In the caves between the rocks, it gets darker and you can hear the rustling of bats' wings and the echo of dripping water.</p>
<p>Above the cave is an unusual rock in the image of a lion. Visitors can climb on top of the lion to see the beautiful view of Prykarpattia and look for their hopes and dreams on a "wishing stone."</p>
<p>According to folk legend, the lion is there to guard Dovbush's buried treasure which no one has been able to find yet. It is said that after Dovbush's death, his fellow rebels hid gold taken from tavern keepers and merchants in the Odynets cave. The entry to the cave is covered by a rotating stone. One needs to say a magic word to turn the stone and open a passage to the cave. The person who knew that magic word died long ago. So the gold has been lying under the rock for more than a hundred years.</p>
<p>Another mysterious place is Devil's Gorge. Only 20 centimeters wide, the gorge is difficult to get through. People put a lot of effort into getting through this narrow gap because, as legend has it, they could be set free of sin.</p>
<p>For Ukrainians, Dovbush Rocks represents both the power of nature and the resilience of the human spirit. The rock formation inspires us to rethink our place in nature, and our culture and history. It is a beautiful place where everyone should experience all its magic for themselves.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Europe’s Digital Act Forces Tech Companies to Change  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/europe-s-digital-act-forces-tech-companies-to-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Europeans can now choose what online services, including <strong>browsers</strong> and search engines, to use for their mobile phones and computers. They can also choose where to download iPhone <strong>apps</strong> and how their personal online data is used.</p>
<p>They are part of changes required under the Digital Markets Act (DMA). The DMA is a set of European Union laws that six large technology companies had to start following recently. Those companies include Amazon, Apple, Microsoft, Google parent Alphabet, Facebook owner Meta, and TikTok owner ByteDance.</p>
<p>The DMA is the latest in a series of laws that Europe has passed as a world leader in controlling large tech companies. The companies have followed by changing long-held ways of doing business. For example, Apple will permit people to download smartphone apps outside of its App Store.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Google's first datacenter in Germany is pictured during its inauguration in Hanau near Frankfurt, Germany, Oct. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Probst, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/397c0153-2ef3-41fe-9ff6-b68ff64c19bb_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Google's first datacenter in Germany is pictured during its inauguration in Hanau near Frankfurt, Germany, Oct. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Probst, File)</span></div>
<p>Here's a look at how the Digital Markets Act will work:</p>
<p><strong>What companies have to follow the rules?</strong></p>
<p>Some 22 services, from operating systems to messenger apps and social media companies, fall under the DMA.</p>
<p>They include Google services like Maps, YouTube, the Chrome browser and the Android operating system. Others are the online store Amazon's Marketplace and Apple's Safari browser and operating system iOS.</p>
<p>Meta's social media and messaging sites Facebook, Instagram, and WhatsApp are included as well as Microsoft's operating system Windows and social media site LinkedIn.</p>
<p>The companies face the threat of large fines of up to 20 percent of their yearly worldwide income for repeated violations. That could amount to billions of dollars. And they also face the threat of a breakup for major violations.</p>
<p><strong>What effect will the rules have around the world?</strong></p>
<p>Zach Meyers is an assistant director at the Center for European Reform, a research organization. He said, "If it works, many Western countries will probably try to follow the DMA..."</p>
<p>Already, countries like Japan, Britain, Mexico, South Korea, Australia, Brazil, and India are writing their own versions of DMA-like rules. The aim is to prevent tech companies from having too much control over online markets.</p>
<p><strong>How will downloading apps change?</strong></p>
<p>In one of the biggest changes, Apple has said it will let European iPhone users download apps outside its App Store, which comes with its devices.</p>
<p>Apple has long opposed such a move. A large part of its income comes from the 30 percent charge it demands for payments made through iOS apps. Apple has warned that downloading apps outside of its store will come with added security risks.</p>
<p>Now, Apple is cutting those charges for developers in Europe that choose to stay with its payment-processing system. But Apple is adding a 55-cent fee for each iOS app downloaded through outside app stores. Critics say that will persuade existing free apps to not use outside stores.</p>
<p>Avery Gardiner is a director at the music company Spotify. She said those outside app stores will never grow because they will be missing many apps that would need to be there for people to want to use those stores.</p>
<p><strong>How will people get more choices online?</strong></p>
<p>Users of mobile devices will have more choices online.</p>
<p>They will not be forced to use certain services like Apple's Safari browser or Google search engine. Android users can choose which search engine to use, and iPhone users will get to choose which browser will be their main one. Microsoft, meanwhile, will stop forcing people to use its Edge browser.</p>
<p>Some Google search results will show up differently because the DMA bans companies from giving <strong>preference</strong> to their own services. So, for example, searches for hotels will now show a list of <strong>booking</strong> sites like Expedia.</p>
<p>Users can also stop companies from using their online data to target them with advertising.</p>
<p>The DMA also requires messaging systems to be able to work with each other.</p>
<p>Meta owns two messaging apps that fall under the rules. So it is expected to come up with a proposal on how Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp users can send messages, videos, and images to each other.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of software that you can download to a device such as a smartphone or tablet, for example to look up information or to play a game</p>
<p><strong>browser </strong><em>– n. </em>a computer program that lets you look at or read documents on the World Wide Web</p>
<p><strong>preference </strong><em>– n. </em>a greater interest in or desire for somebody/something than somebody/something else</p>
<p><strong>booking </strong><em>– n</em>. an arrangement to have something (such as a room) held for your use at a later time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Uncover ‘Secrets’ of African Sand Dune  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/researchers-uncover-secrets-of-african-sand-dune.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers have used radar and other technologies to study a large "star" sand <strong>dune</strong> in eastern Morocco. The team said it was able to capture detailed data on how these dunes form and develop.</p>
<p>A star dune is named after its shape because it can look like a star when seen from above. These structures are very large and have a hill, or peak, at the top. They have large masses, called arms, spreading out from the peak. Star dunes are shaped by wind and other conditions in the environment.</p>
<p>Star dunes are common in deserts and can be found in Africa, the Middle East, China and North America. But scientists say, although there are a lot of star dunes, the formations have not been studied very much so far.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A view of the Lala Lallia star dune of the Sahara Desert, in Erg Chebbi, Morocco, as seen in an undated handout image from 2008 and obtained by Reuters on March 1, 2024. (Charlie Bristow/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b857-08dc3d6095ab_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A view of the Lala Lallia star dune of the Sahara Desert, in Erg Chebbi, Morocco, as seen in an undated handout image from 2008 and obtained by Reuters on March 1, 2024. (Charlie Bristow/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The new study – believed to be the first of its kind – was led by two British researchers. It examines a large star dune in the Sahara Desert's Erg Chebbi sand sea in Morocco. The research results recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53485-3">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Scientific Reports</em>.</p>
<p>The scientists said the star dune rises 100 meters above surrounding dunes and is 700 meters wide. The structure contains an estimated five-and-a-half metric tons of sand.</p>
<p>The researchers used radar that can "see" underground to look at different elements within the star dune. The science instruments that were used are designed to map all layers within the dunes. They also used a method called <strong>luminescence</strong> dating to study the age of the dune. This method uses minerals in the sand to estimate when they last received sunlight in an attempt to guess the age of the dune.</p>
<p>Geoff Duller is a professor of geography and earth sciences at Britain's Aberystwyth University. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.aber.ac.uk/en/news/archive/2024/03/title-269226-en.html">said</a> in a statement the new technology had finally made it possible to study these large dunes. "It's only because of new technology that we can start to uncover their secrets," Duller said.</p>
<p>The researchers estimated the oldest parts of the base of the star dune are about 13,000 years old. And the dune is moving across the desert at a rate of about 50 centimeters a year. The team noted the star dune experienced the most growth during the past 1,000 years.</p>
<p>Star dunes make up just 10 percent of all dunes in Earth's deserts. They have also been observed on Mars and on Saturn's moon Titan.</p>
<p>Earth's largest star dunes are found in western China's Badain Jaran desert. Star dunes also are found in places including the Namib Sand Sea in Namibia, large sand seas in Algeria and Rub' al Khali in Saudi Arabia. In North America, Great Sand Dunes National Park in Colorado contains a series of them.</p>
<p>"I first encountered star dunes in Namibia 20 years ago," Duller told Reuters news agency. He added that he still has clear memories of being surprised at the size and beauty of the first sand dunes he saw. "I have a <strong>vivid</strong> memory of the long climb to the top, struggling up very loose sand in the heat of the day."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters, </em><em>Aberystwyth University </em><em>and Scientific Reports reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dune </strong><em>– n. </em>a hill of sand in a desert</p>
<p><strong>luminescence </strong><em>– n. </em>the giving out of light by a substance</p>
<p><strong>vivid </strong><em>– adj. </em>clear or strong</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Student-athletes Considered College Employees?  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/are-student-athletes-considered-college-employees.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Dartmouth College men's basketball team voted to join a labor organization, called a union, this week.</p>
<p>The move means that the student-athletes on the team could have the right to negotiate a working contract like other university employees.</p>
<p>In an election held by the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), the team members voted 13-2 to join Service Employees International Union Local 560. The same union also represents some workers at Dartmouth.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A student walks near the Alumni Gymnasium on the campus of Dartmouth College, Tuesday, March 5, 2024, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/dd226cf9-e035-4344-9bf4-8bdce29beaf2_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A student walks near the Alumni Gymnasium on the campus of Dartmouth College, Tuesday, March 5, 2024, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)</span></div>
<p>Cade Haskins and Romeo Myrthil are Dartmouth basketball players. The student-athletes said of the vote, "... we, as students, can also be both <strong>campus</strong> workers and union members. Dartmouth seems to be stuck in the past. It's time for the age of <strong>amateurism</strong> to end."</p>
<p>However, the school in Hanover, New Hampshire has already appealed the local NLRB decision. In a statement, Dartmouth said, "<strong>Classifying</strong> these students as employees simply because they play basketball is as <strong>unprecedented</strong> as it is inaccurate."</p>
<p>The school also warned the students that unionizing could get the team removed from athletic competition.</p>
<p>Both sides have until March 12 to file objections with the NLRB. The case could also end up in federal court, which would likely delay the outcome for some time.</p>
<p>The Dartmouth vote is the latest effort by student-athletes to unionize and gain money and other rights in exchange for many hours spent practicing and playing sports.</p>
<p>In 2015, a local NLRB blocked an attempt by students on the football team at Northwestern University in Illinois to form a union. But the decision did not directly answer the question of whether student-athletes are employees.</p>
<p><strong>Growth of college sports</strong></p>
<p>The history of college students playing sports for their school goes back over 100 years.</p>
<p>The National Collegiate Athletic Association, or NCAA, is the governing body for college sports. The organization has long said that its players are "student-athletes" who go to school mainly to study.</p>
<p>At first, students were not paid to play sports and were considered "amateurs." Gradually, student-athletes from large universities started receiving money for housing, food and <strong>tuition</strong>.</p>
<p>In recent years, American television networks have spent more money to broadcast college sports around the country and the world. The Big Ten, an athletic organization with college teams from the New York area to Los Angeles, reached an agreement in 2022 to broadcast its football and basketball games for $7 billion.</p>
<p>As college sports became popular, teams from large universities now regularly play in front of large crowds of up to 100,000 people. And some student-athletes have become even better known than professional athletes.</p>
<p>In 2021, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the NCAA could not prevent college athletes from getting paid by outside groups in return for the use of their name or image.</p>
<p>That opened the door for some college athletes to make lots of money. This year, one top student-athlete is Caitlin Clark, a basketball player at the University of Iowa. She set college scoring records and reportedly earns nearly $1 million a year for the use of her name and image.</p>
<p>The Dartmouth basketball players will never be famous enough to make that kind of money. One student-athlete said what he really wants from the union push is to get access to better healthcare so he can heal his basketball injuries.</p>
<p><strong>What about Dartmouth?</strong></p>
<p>Tony Clark is the head of the Major League Baseball Players Association. He said the vote gives the Dartmouth basketball players "a seat at the table and powerful voice."</p>
<p>One basketball coach whose team is very well known – Dan Hurley of the University of Connecticut – said some kind of union or players' organization is the future of college sports.</p>
<p>"These players are putting in <strong>incredible</strong> work days, work weeks for five, six months," he said. "I think there's so much there that's going to have to be settled."</p>
<p>A 2015 legal case suggested athletes like the basketball players can spend up to 40 hours per week involved in their sports activities, leaving little time for study or work.</p>
<p>Haskins said he loves playing basketball. But he has had serious injuries to his ankle, hip and shoulder while playing. "It is definitely a <strong>burden</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Union interest among younger workers is growing, says the Economic Policy Institute. Workers under 45 joined unions at <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.epi.org/publication/union-membership-data/" target="_blank">the highest rate in 2023</a>.</p>
<p>Myrthil said he will talk about the union with new students who are coming next year. "We'll introduce them to the idea and what it means," he said. "And then hopefully it gets passed on."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>campus </strong>– <em>n</em>. the grounds or land upon which a school is built</p>
<p><strong>amateurism </strong>– <em>adj</em>. participating in something, such as a sporting event, without being paid</p>
<p><strong>classify </strong>– <em>v</em>. to consider something as part of a group with other similar items</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not existing or having been done before</p>
<p><strong>tuition </strong>– <em>n</em>. the money paid to attend school</p>
<p><strong>incredible </strong>– <em>adj</em>. hard to believe, not believable</p>
<p><strong>burden </strong>– <em>n</em>. a heavy weight, used both literally and figuratively</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Dip Your Toes' or 'Take the Plunge'?  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/dip-your-toes-or-take-the-plunge.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about trying something new or something you are unsure about.</p>
<p>People can react differently to these kinds of situations. Some people may want to <u>jump right in feet first</u>. They may want to <u>take the plunge! </u></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Triathletes dive into The Seine river with the Eiffel Tower in the background during the men's 2023 World Triathlon Olympic Games Test Event in Paris. (Photo by Bertrand GUAY / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-116f-08dba014e0b4_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Triathletes dive into The Seine river with the Eiffel Tower in the background during the men's 2023 World Triathlon Olympic Games Test Event in Paris. (Photo by Bertrand GUAY / AFP)</span></div>
<p>And some people may want <u>to test the waters</u>. They may want to <u>dip their toes in </u>first.</p>
<p>Which kind of person are you? Well, imagine you are standing on the edge of a lake or swimming pool. You want to get into the water, but you don't know the water's temperature.</p>
<p>Do you jump right in? If you do, you may be more bold and adventurous.</p>
<p>Or do you want to dip a toe into the water before you decide? If so, you may be more <strong>cautious </strong>and careful.</p>
<p>If you dip your toes into something, you start doing it slowly and carefully. You are not sure if you will like it. You want to test the waters before beginning something, or before taking the plunge.</p>
<p>Testing the waters means you get a feel for something before committing to it. For example, if you want to move to a new city, you probably want to test the waters first by going there for a short stay.</p>
<p>Taking the plunge is the opposite of dipping your toes. When you take the plunge, you jump right into something. You do not wait or <strong>hesitate.</strong></p>
<p>We use the expression <u>dip your toes in </u>for many situations. You may want to try an activity briefly to find out if you like it first. It can also mean you start something very carefully before becoming involved in something that you are not experienced at.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear some of these expressions used in a non-water related situation.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, I'm going ballroom dancing this Saturday. Do you want to join me?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Ballroom dancing? I know nothing about ballroom dancing. </em></p>
<p><em>A: That's fine! This place I found is perfect for you. Before the dance starts, they give a free class to beginners.</em></p>
<p><em>B: Yeah, I don't know. Maybe I'll just go and watch. You know ... dip my toes in. I like to know what I'm getting into first.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Sure. But I promise you ... after the first 5 minutes you are going to want to jump in feet first!</em></p>
<p>That is all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>If you are new to VOA Learning English, there's no need to dip your toes in first. Just take the plunge! Visit our website to find more stories.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>careful about avoiding danger or risk</p>
<p><strong>hesitate </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to hold back in doubt or indecision</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russia, China Aim to Put a Nuclear Plant on the Moon  (2024/3/9) | 俄罗斯计划在月球建造核电站</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/russia-and-china-aim-to-put-a-nuclear-plant-on-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Russia and China are considering putting a nuclear power station on the moon in about 10 years.<br/>
俄罗斯和中国正在考虑在大约10年后将核电站送上月球。</p>
<p>The head of Russia's space agency Roscosmos, Yuri Borisov, made the statement recently. He added that such a project could support the building of moon settlements one day.<br/>
俄罗斯航天局局长尤里·鲍里索夫最近发表了上述声明。他补充说，这种项目有一天可以支持月球基地的建设。</p>
<p>Borisov said that Russia and China had been working on a moon program together. The former deputy defense minister explained that Russia was able to help with its expertise in "nuclear space energy."<br/>
鲍里索夫说，俄罗斯和中国一直在共同致力于月球计划。这位前国防部副部长解释说，俄罗斯能够利用其在“太空核能”方面的专业知识提供帮助。</p>
<p>"Today we are seriously considering a project - somewhere at the turn of 2033-2035 - to deliver and install a power unit on the lunar surface together with our Chinese colleagues," Borisov said.<br/>
鲍里索夫说：“今天，我们正在认真考虑一个项目——在2033至2035年左右——与中国同行一起在月球表面交付和安装发电机组。”</p>
<p>Solar panels would not be able to provide enough electricity to power future moon settlements, he said, while nuclear power could.<br/>
他说，太阳能电池板无法为未来的月球基地提供足够电力，而核电可以。</p>
<p>He said the possible plan should be done "without the presence of humans."<br/>
他说，这项可能的计划应该在“无人在场的情况下”完成。</p>
<p>Borisov also spoke about Russian plans to build a nuclear-powered spaceship to carry cargo. He said all the technical questions concerning the project had been solved, except for finding out how to cool the nuclear reactor.<br/>
鲍里索夫还谈到了俄罗斯建造核动力飞船运载货物的计划。他说，除了找出如何冷却核反应堆的办法之外，有关该项目的所有技术问题都已解决。</p>
<p>He said the ship would be a large "structure that would be able, thanks to a nuclear reactor and ... high-power turbines...to transport large cargoes from one orbit to another." He added that such a ship could collect objects for many other projects.<br/>
他说，这艘飞船将是一个大型“结构，由于有核反应堆和大功率涡轮机，将能够将大型货物从一个轨道运输到另一个轨道。”他补充说，这艘飞船可以为许多其他项目收集物体。</p>
<p>Russian officials have spoken before about plans to mine minerals on the moon. But the Russian space program has suffered a series of problems in recent years.<br/>
俄罗斯官员此前曾谈到在月球上开采矿产的计划。但近年来，俄罗斯的太空计划遇到了一系列问题。</p>
<p>Its first moon mission in 47 years failed last year after Russia's Luna-25 spacecraft lost control and crashed.<br/>
去年，在俄罗斯的月球-25号宇宙飞船失控坠毁后，其47年来的首次月球任务失败了。</p>
<p>Russian officials have said they will launch further lunar missions and then explore the possibility of a joint Russian-China crewed mission and even a lunar base.<br/>
俄罗斯官员表示，他们将进一步发动月球任务，然后探索俄中联合载人任务甚至月球基地的可能性。</p>
<p>Last month, China said it aimed to put the first Chinese astronaut on the moon before 2030.<br/>
中国上月表示计划在2030年前将首位中国宇航员送上月球。</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin last month said a warning by the United States that Russia planned to put nuclear weapons in space was false. Putin said the warning was part of a plan to force Russia into arms negotiations on the West's terms.<br/>
俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京上个月表示，美国警告俄罗斯计划在太空部署核武器是虚假的。普京表示，这一警告是迫使俄罗斯按照西方条件进行武器谈判计划的一部分。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>An Italian Shop in Rome Is Behind 17 Academy Awards  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/an-italian-shop-in-rome-is-behind-17-academy-awards.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In many movies, the clothing the actors wear is an important part of the story. In Rome, there is a workshop that has been a big part of Italian and international film history for 60 years.</p>
<p>Tirelli Costumes in Rome's Prati neighborhood is an <strong>atelier</strong>, a business that makes special clothing and costumes. It has earned the <strong>nickname</strong> the "Oscar tailor's shop" for its work in film costume design. An "Oscar" is another name for an award from the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.</p>
<p>Umberto Tirelli started the shop in November 1964. It has been behind 17 Academy Awards for best costume design. Most recently, its workers helped create the costumes for Ridley Scott's movie <em>Napoleon</em>. The film's costume designers were nominated for an Oscar that will be decided at the Academy Awards in Hollywood this weekend.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Amadeus dress by Milos Forman is displayed at the Tirelli Atelier in Rome, Tuesday, March 5, 2024. (AP Photo/Gregorio Borgia) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ad63-08dc3e0cba8e_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Amadeus dress by Milos Forman is displayed at the Tirelli Atelier in Rome, Tuesday, March 5, 2024. (AP Photo/Gregorio Borgia) </span></div>
<p>"Maybe it will win! Let's add another medal to the medal collection," the shop's current head, Dino Trappetti, told <em>The Associated Press</em>. "Of course, the Oscar is not won by the tailor's shop, the Oscar is won by the costume designer. But the tailor's shop has the <strong>merit</strong> and the honor of having participated to make it win."</p>
<p>The beginning of the atelier started with Tirelli's passion for collecting old clothes. He searched for clothing in houses of <strong>nobility</strong> and <strong>flea markets</strong> worldwide. He slowly built a collection that now has more than 15,000 real pieces of clothing that date from 1750 to 1980.</p>
<p>At the start, the shop had "a <strong>sewing</strong> machine, two cutters and two other <strong>seamstresses</strong>," Trappetti said.</p>
<p>Today, the headquarters of Tirelli Costumes has <strong>mannequins</strong> wearing some of the atelier's most famous creations: A pink flowered outfit that actor Tom Hulce wore as Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart in <em>Amadeus</em>, and the red outfit Michelle Pfeiffer wore in <em>The Age of Innocence</em>. The designers of each of those pieces of clothing won Oscars.</p>
<p>After the 1984 costume design Oscar for <em>Amadeus</em>, Tirelli could have accepted many international projects "because the market was immediately interested," Trappetti said. But Tirelli, who died in 1990, was not sure.</p>
<p>Trappetti remembered him saying: "I'm not going to America. If America wants, America will come looking for me."</p>
<p>Over 60 years, the tailor's shop has created more than 300,000 costumes that are now stored near Rome. Costume designers come for ideas and historical information. They also come for hand-cut, hand-sewn creations by the team of Tirelli workers.</p>
<p>"You can't make those costumes in a factory. In a factory you can make films with robots, futuristic or <strong>fantasy</strong>," Trappetti said. "But these things have to be made by hand."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>atelier </strong><em>— n. </em>a room or space where artists work; a small shop where skilled workers make things like clothing to order</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nickname </strong><em>— n. </em>an informal name for a person or something that is short and easy to use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nobility </strong><em>— n. </em>people who receive their position or rank from a king, queen or royal house</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>flea market </strong><em>— n. </em>an informal market that contains many sellers who informally gather in a place for a day to offer household objects and homemade art for sale</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sew </strong>–v. to make clothes our of cloth with thread</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>seamstress </strong><em>— n. </em>a woman who sews clothes as a job</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mannequin </strong><em>— n. </em>a form shaped like a human body that is used for making and showing clothes</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fantasy </strong>–n. a story or idea of pure imagination that is not based in reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Open Boat by Stephen Crane, Part Two  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/open-boat-stephen-crane-part-two-american-stories.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>
<em>We continue the story of "The Open Boat" by Stephen Crane. As we told you last week, the story is based on true events. In eighteen ninety-six, Crane was traveling to Cuba as a news reporter. On his way there, his ship sank in the Atlantic Ocean. Crane climbed into the last remaining lifeboat.</em></p>
<p><em>Three men got into the boat with him. They were the ship's captain, the cook and a sailor named Billie. For three days, the men steered the small boat through high waves along the coast of Florida. At last, they saw land. Here is Shep O'Neal with the final part of the story.</em></p>
<p>A long stretch of coast lay before the eyes of the men. Slowly, the land rose up out of the mountainous sea. The men could see a small house against the sky. To the south, they could see a lighthouse. Tide, wind and waves were pushing the lifeboat northward. The men thought someone on land would have seen the boat by now.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Open Boat Part Two" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0334B585-D474-47D2-A875-420BF2D17277_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Open Boat Part Two</span></div>
<p>"Well," said the captain, "I suppose we'll have to attempt to reach the shore ourselves. If we stay out here too long, none of us will have the strength left to swim after the boat sinks."</p>
<p>So Billie the sailor turned the boat straight for the shore.</p>
<p>"If we don't all get ashore," said the captain, "I suppose you fellows know where to send news of my death?"</p>
<p>The men then exchanged some information. There was a great deal of anger in them. They thought: "If I am going to be drowned, why, in the name of the seven mad gods who rule the sea, was I permitted to come this far and think about sand and trees?"</p>
<p>The waves grew stronger. They seemed always just about to break and roll over the little boat. The coast was still far away. The sailor said: "Boys, the boat won't live three minutes more, and we're too far out to swim. Shall I take her to sea again, captain?"</p>
<p>"Yes! Go ahead!" said the captain. The sailor turned the boat and took her safely out to sea again.</p>
<p>"It's funny those life-saving people haven't seen us," one of the men said.</p>
<p>"Maybe they think we're out here for sport! Maybe they think we're fishing. Maybe they think we're fools."</p>
<p>Once more, the sailor <strong>rowed</strong> the boat and then the reporter rowed. Suddenly, they saw a man walking along the shore.</p>
<p>The man stopped walking. He moved his hand in the air to wave at them. He saw them! Now he was running to the house.</p>
<p>The captain tied a cloth to a stick and waved it. Now there was another man on the shore. The two men waved their hands in the air, as if they were saying hello to the men in the boat.</p>
<p>Now, what was that moving on the shore? It was a bus – a hotel bus. A man stood on the steps of the bus and waved his coat over his head. The men in the boat wondered what he wanted to say. Was he attempting to tell them something? Should they wait for help? Should they go north? Should they go south?</p>
<p>The men waited and waited but nothing happened. The sun began to go down. It got dark and cold. They could no longer see anyone on the beach.</p>
<p>The sailor rowed, and then the reporter rowed, and then the sailor rowed again. They rowed and rowed through the long night. The land had disappeared but they could hear the low sound of the waves hitting the shore. This was surely a quiet night.</p>
<p>The cook finally spoke: "Billie, what kind of pie do you like best?"</p>
<p>"Pie," said the sailor and the reporter angrily. "Don't talk about those things!"</p>
<p>"Well," said the cook, "I was just thinking about ham sandwiches, and ..."</p>
<p>A night on the sea in an open boat is a long night. The sailor continued to row until his head fell forward and sleep overpowered him. Then he asked the reporter to row for a while. They exchanged places so the sailor could sleep in the bottom of the boat with the cook and the captain.</p>
<p>The reporter thought that he was the one man <strong>afloat</strong> on all the oceans in the world. The wind had a sad voice as it came over the waves.</p>
<p>Suddenly, there was a long, loud swishing sound behind the boat and a shining trail of silvery blue. It might have been made by a huge knife. Then there was another swish and another long flash of bluish light, this time alongside the boat. The reporter saw a huge fin speed like a shadow through the water, leaving a long glowing trail. The thing kept swimming near the boat. He noted its speed and power. The reporter wished the men would wake up. He did not want to be alone with the <strong>shark</strong>.</p>
<p>The reporter thought as he rowed. He was angry that they had come so close to land and yet might still die at sea. Then he remembered a poem that he had learned as a child. It was a poem about a soldier of the French Foreign Legion. The soldier lay dying in Algiers. Just before he died, he cried out: "I shall never see my own, my native land." And now, many years after he had learned this poem, the reporter for the first time understood the sadness of the dying soldier.</p>
<p>Hours passed. The reporter asked the sailor to take the oars so that he could rest. It seemed like only a brief period, but it was more than an hour later, when the sailor returned the oars to the reporter. They both knew that only they could keep the boat from sinking. And so they rowed, hour after hour, through the night.</p>
<p>When day came, the four men saw land again. But there were no people on the shore. A conference was held on the boat.</p>
<p>"Well," said the captain, "if no help is coming, we might better try to reach the shore right away. If we stay out here much longer, we will be too weak to do anything for ourselves at all."</p>
<p>The others agreed. They began to turn the boat toward the beach. The captain told them to be careful – that when the boat came near the beach, the waves would sink it. Then everyone should jump out of the boat and swim to the shore.</p>
<p>As the boat came closer to land, the waves got bigger and more violent. At last, a large wave climbed into the air and fell on the small boat with great force.</p>
<p>The boat turned over as the men jumped into the sea. The water was like ice. The reporter was tired. But he swam toward the beach. He looked for his friends.</p>
<p>He saw Billie, the sailor, in front of him, swimming strongly and quickly. The cook was near him. Behind, the captain held on to the overturned boat with his one good hand. Soon, the reporter could swim no longer. A current was carrying him back out to sea. He thought: "Am I going to drown? Can it be possible?"</p>
<p>But the current suddenly changed and he was able to swim toward the shore. The captain called to him to swim to the boat and hold on. The reporter started to swim toward the boat. Then he saw a man running along the shore. He was quickly taking off his shoes and clothes.</p>
<p>As the reporter got close to the boat, a large wave hit him and threw him into the air over the boat and far from it. When he tried to get up, he found that the water was not over his head, only half way up his body. But he was so tired that he could not stand up. Each wave threw him down, and the current kept pulling him back to sea.</p>
<p>Then he saw the man again, jumping into the water. The man pulled the cook to the shore. Then he ran back into the water for the captain. But the captain waved him away and sent him to the reporter. The man seized the reporter's hand and pulled him to the beach. Then the man pointed to the water and cried: "What's that?"</p>
<p>In the shallow water, face down, lay Billie, the sailor.</p>
<p>The reporter did not know all that happened after that. He fell on the sand as if dropped from a housetop. It seems that immediately the beach was filled with men with blankets, clothes and whiskey. Women brought hot coffee. The people welcomed the men from the sea to the land.</p>
<p>But a still and dripping shape was carried slowly up the beach. And the land's welcome for the sailor's body could only be its final resting place. When night came, the white waves moved in the moonlight. The wind brought the sound of the great sea's voice to the men on the shore.</p>
<p></p><p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>afloat</strong> - <em>adj</em>. floating on water</p>
<p><strong>shark</strong> - <em>n. </em>a large and often dangerous sea fish with very sharp teeth</p>
<p><strong>row </strong>- <em>v. </em>to move a boat through water using oars</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Yet'  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/yet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Al.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Hi, hello</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="'Yet'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8c17-08dc3d3702a9_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">'Yet'</span></div>
<p>My name is Al from Indonesia. I am still not sure how to use the word "yet" in a sentence, <strong>positive</strong> or <strong>negative</strong>.</p>
<p>Would you like to inform us more about that?</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Al.</p>
<p>We have talked about how to use the word "yet" in comparison to "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/already-or-yet-/6878196.html" target="_blank">already</a>" and "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/still-and-yet-/6818661.html" target="_blank">still</a>" in earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em> articles. Now, let's talk about "yet" by itself.</p>
<p>"Yet" is almost always used as an adverb of time. It means from some time in the past until now. "Yet" is used in both positive and negative sentences.</p>
<p><strong>Yes-No Questions</strong></p>
<p>In spoken English, "yet" is often used in both yes or no questions. For example,</p>
<p><em>Have you heard from your boss <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p><em>Did you finish your homework <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p>We can ask these questions without "yet". Why use it then?</p>
<p>When we add "yet" to a question, we not only want to know if it happened, but we expect it to happen. And, we want it to happen.</p>
<p>We can use yet with negative questions, too. For example,</p>
<p><em>Have you not heard from your boss <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p><em>Have you not finished your homework <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p>Using a negative question expresses an even stronger expectation or desire, almost disbelief that something has not happened "yet!"</p>
<p><strong>Statements</strong></p>
<p>Most statements with "yet" are negative, especially in informal spoken language.</p>
<p><em>But you don't have to make a decision <u>yet</u>.</em></p>
<p><em>We are not there <u>yet</u>.</em></p>
<p>In these negative statements, "yet" expresses an expectation that it will happen at some point in the future.</p>
<p>We hope this explanation has helped you, Al.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>positive</strong>—<em>adj</em>. in grammar, a positive sentence does not have any negative words</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong>—<em>adj</em>. in grammar, a negative sentence shows that something cannot be the case, is not true or not happening</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Miami Beach Adding More Security Measures for Spring Break  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/miami-beach-adding-more-security-measures-for-spring-break.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American city of Miami Beach, Florida is a popular destination for travelers during school break periods in spring. But, in the last three years, the area has dealt with high levels of violent crime during spring break.</p>
<p>So, city officials are putting in place new security measures.</p>
<p>The measures include parking restrictions for non-<strong>residents</strong> and closings of outdoor restaurants on busy weekends. The city has warned visitors to expect curfews, personal property searches at the beach, early beach closures, road security checkpoints, and arrests for drug possession and violence.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Miami Beach park rangers watch over crowds Tuesday, Feb. 27, 2024, in Miami Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-715d-08dc3dfbb98b_cx0_cy10_cw99_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Miami Beach park rangers watch over crowds Tuesday, Feb. 27, 2024, in Miami Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)</span></div>
<p>Civil rights activists say the restrictions are an overreaction to large crowds of Black people. And, business owners in the city's famous South Beach neighborhood argue that the new measures will cause them financial loss during one of the busiest times of the year.</p>
<p>Miami Beach has ordered such measures before, so the restrictions are not unfamiliar to the area. But, this is the first time the rules have been established ahead of the season.</p>
<p>Steven Meiner is the mayor of Miami Beach. "The <strong>status quo</strong> and what we've seen in the last few years is just not acceptable," he said.</p>
<p>Meiner said spring break crowds get out of control even with a strong police presence. He said the island city can only hold so many people. And the amount of people has often gone beyond what is safe.</p>
<p>Local business owner, David Wallack, opposes the measures. He said the city has always been a place of celebration. And he argued that limits on the numbers of visitors will turn the city into a retirement community.</p>
<p>Wallack and others have proposed holding a music <strong>festival</strong> during the third week of spring break, the season's busiest time. Supporters say such an event would help prevent the gathering of mobs.</p>
<p>But, Meiner said the city has spent millions of dollars on musical performances and similar events in the past. He said such offerings did not prevent violence well. He said businesses suffer when violent crowds gather and force them to close. And, he said the people causing most of the problems are not spending money in the city anyway.</p>
<p>Some civil rights supporters, however, believe the restrictions are racist.</p>
<p>South Beach became popular among Black tourists about 20 years ago because of an event called Urban Beach Week. It takes place in late May during the Memorial Day holiday. Many locals have protested about violence and other crime connected to the event. Officials increased police presence during Memorial Day as a result.</p>
<p>Stephen Hunter Johnson is an attorney and member of Miami-Dade's Black Affairs Advisory Board. He said city officials are only cracking down so hard because many of the visitors are Black.</p>
<p>"Everybody loves this idea that they are free from the government <strong>intruding</strong> on them," Johnson said. "But amazingly, if the government intrudes on Black people, everyone's fine with it."</p>
<p>But Meiner rejects the idea that the city's actions have anything to do with race.</p>
<p>"I have a moral <strong>obligation</strong> to keep people safe, and right now, it is not safe," the mayor said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>one who lives in a place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>festival </strong><em>— n. </em>an often regularly occurring program of events or entertainment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>status quo </strong><em>— n. </em>the way things are now</p>
<p><strong>intrude </strong><em>— v. </em>to bring or force in unasked</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>— n. </em>something (as a promise or contract) that requires one to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boy Wounded in Gaza Travels to New York for a New Arm  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/boy-wounded-in-gaza-travels-to-new-york-for-a-new-arm.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Four-year-old Omar Abu Kuwaik is from the Gaza Strip, but in the last several weeks, he has spent time in Egypt, New York City, and Philadelphia before returning to Egypt.</p>
<p>Why did he travel so far from home?</p>
<p>He came for medical operations on his skin and to receive a <strong>prosthetic</strong> arm.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Omar Abu Kuwaik throws snow shortly after arriving from Gaza at the residence of the Global Medical Relief Fund as Khaolah Obahi of Rahma Worldwide looks on, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Peter K. Afriyie)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/29cfdf30-b88a-4fbb-8832-7c8191ea6a79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Omar Abu Kuwaik throws snow shortly after arriving from Gaza at the residence of the Global Medical Relief Fund as Khaolah Obahi of Rahma Worldwide looks on, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Peter K. Afriyie)</span></div>
<p>He is one of the few Gazans to have made it out of the war <strong>zone</strong>. But his family was not so lucky.</p>
<p>Omar was wounded during an Israeli airstrike in December that also killed a number of his family members, including his parents and a sister.</p>
<p><strong>‘Anywhere is better'</strong></p>
<p>A <strong>charity</strong> group called the Global Medical Relief Fund found out about Omar and provided for his medical care in the U.S. Elissa Montanti started the organization. She has spent 25 years getting hundreds of children free medical care after they lost arms and legs to wars or disasters, including wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Montanti said she knew she would have to help the Gazan children when the conflict started between Hamas and Israel last October. But, she wondered, "How? How will I ever get these kids out when they can't even get out of Gaza?'"</p>
<p>Another group, Rahma Worldwide, a U.S.-based charity, learned about Omar's injuries. The group got him and his aunt into Egypt, provided them with new passports and airplane tickets to the United States in January.</p>
<p>Omar was getting only simple medical care in Gaza.</p>
<p>Adib Chouiki is vice president of Rahma Worldwide. Chouiki knew his group needed to get the boy to a place where he could get help.</p>
<p>"Our view was, anywhere is better for him than being in Gaza," Chouiki said.</p>
<p>The United Nations says there are many more men, women and children like Omar waiting for medical care. About 4,000 wounded people and their families – such as Omar's aunt – have been permitted to leave Gaza to get medical help. But the U.N. refugee agency says there are still 8,000 people on a medical waiting list.</p>
<p>Gaza's health ministry, which is controlled by the territory's Hamas rulers, said 30,000 people have been killed in Gaza, and 70,000 wounded. The ministry said about two-thirds of those killed have been women and children.</p>
<p><strong>To the United States</strong></p>
<p>Omar went with his aunt, Maha on a flight from Egypt to New York City. Maha left her husband and children behind in Gaza.</p>
<p>Along the way, Omar saw the airline pilots getting ready to start the flight and he said, "When I grow up, I want to be a pilot, so I can bring people places."</p>
<p>Once in the U.S., the Global Medical Relief Fund sent Omar to Shriners Children's Hospital in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, for treatment. He received pieces of new skin, called grafts, to repair the burns on his leg. Medical workers also fitted him for a prosthetic arm.</p>
<p>As he recovered, he learned how to use his new arm. He stayed in a home owned by the Global Medical Relief Fund in the Staten Island area of New York City.</p>
<p>His arm was cut off just below the elbow. As he received treatment, he could see his new arm. He looked forward to learning how to use it. One day, he reached out to touch it. "My arm is nice," he said.</p>
<p>Montanti said getting a prosthetic <strong>limb</strong> is important for children who have been wounded in a war. Even if they will never be the same, "The kids, they feel whole," she said, "<strong>Psychologically</strong>, it means so much."</p>
<p>The hospital in Philadelphia is currently treating two children who have been removed from Gaza. One is an American, who was trapped when the war started. Another child, a two-year-old boy, is supposed to come soon.</p>
<p>One day after Omar got his arm, he and his aunt got on a plane to return to Egypt. Maha said she was concerned about what would happen to Omar and the rest of her family when they arrived. Their relatives are living in tents.</p>
<p>After coming back to Egypt, Omar and his aunt's futures are unclear; they might remain in exile.</p>
<p>For Maha Abu Kuwaik and Omar, there might never be a home to return to.</p>
<p>She said she could not imagine going back to Gaza. "What would his life be? Where is his future?" she wondered.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>prosthetic </strong>–n. a device meant to take the place of a part of the body that is missing or injured</p>
<p><strong>zone </strong>–n. a place that is set apart and subject to special rules or restrictions</p>
<p><strong>charity </strong>–n. an organization that takes donations and usually uses that donations for a cause that is meant to help people</p>
<p><strong>limb </strong>–n. an arm or leg</p>
<p><strong>psychologically </strong>–adv. relating to the mind, how it works and how people think about things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Congo, Drilling Leads to Worry over Pollution  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/in-congo-drilling-leads-to-worry-over-pollution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Democratic Republic of Congo (D.R.C.) is looking to expand operations to dig, or <strong>drill</strong>, for oil. The central African country is known for its mineral riches. Currently, drilling is limited to just a small area along the Atlantic Ocean and out in the water. But that is expected to change if the government carries out its plan to sell 30 pieces of land for oil and gas exploration across the country.</p>
<p>Leaders say the plan will grow the economy. They say such growth is necessary for the poor people of Congo. But communities, rights groups, and environmentalist groups warn that expanded drilling will harm the environment and human health.</p>
<p>In the Moanda area of the D.R.C., locals say pollution has worsened since a French company began drilling there in 2000. They say spills and leaks from operations are destroying the soil. The work includes "flaring" --- the burning of natural gas near drilling sites. Locals report that the flaring is dirtying the air they breathe. Flaring is also wasteful as the energy goes unused.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Children sit inside a fishing boat outside a mangrove in Kimpozia village, one of the areas auctioned for oil drilling, in Moanda, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Monday, Dec. 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Mosa'ab Elshamy)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5881-08dc3c7e2147_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Children sit inside a fishing boat outside a mangrove in Kimpozia village, one of the areas auctioned for oil drilling, in Moanda, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Monday, Dec. 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Mosa'ab Elshamy)</span></div>
<p>And, critics say, the Congolese government does not supervise the oil drilling operations well enough.</p>
<p>The company, Perenco, says it follows accepted international measures in its <strong>extraction</strong> methods. It said its operation does not create health risks and that any pollution it causes is low-level. The company also said it offered to support a power plant that would make use of the natural gas and reduce flaring that way.</p>
<p>The government did not respond to questions about the proposed plant.</p>
<p>Congo's minister overseeing oil and gas, Didier Budimbu, said the government plans to protect the environment.</p>
<p>Natural areas in Congo, including the Congo Basin rainforest, capture large amounts of carbon dioxide – about 1.5 billion tons a year, or about 3 percent of what the world produces each year. More than 12 of the extraction areas for sale include land in government-protected wild areas.</p>
<p>The government said the 27 properties for sale hold an estimated 22 billion <strong>barrels </strong>of oil. Environmental groups say that selling more land to drill would have harmful effects in the D.R.C. and in other countries.</p>
<p>"Any new oil and gas project, anywhere in the world, is fueling the climate and nature crisis that we're in," said Mbong Akiy Fokwa Tsafak, program director for Greenpeace Africa. She said Perenco's operations have done nothing in respect to the poor and instead harm the environment and the lives of communities.</p>
<p>Environmentalists say Congo has a strong possibility to instead develop renewable energy.</p>
<p>Budimbu said now is not the time to move away from <strong>fossil fuels</strong> when the country still depends on them. He said the D.R.C. will move away from fossil fuel dependency over the long term.</p>
<p>Perenco has faced criticism for years. Local researchers, aid groups, and Congo's Senate have made multiple reports of pollution dating back more than ten years. Two organizations, Sherpa and Friends of the Earth France, opened a legal action against the company in 2022, accusing Perenco of polluting.</p>
<p>Adore Ngaka's lives in the village of Tshiende. Oil drills can be seen up the road from his home. Ngaka says they remind him every day of all that he has lost. The extraction processes have polluted the soil, hurt his crops, and forced the family to use all their savings to survive, he said.</p>
<p>He pointed to an ear of corn he grew. The 27-year-old farmer said the vegetable is about half the size of those that grew before the drilling began ten years ago.</p>
<p>He said, "It's bringing us to poverty."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Sam Mednick reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drill </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to get oil or water by digging through land or sea bed</p>
<p><strong>extract </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove or obtain a substance from something, for example by using an industrial or a chemical process</p>
<p><strong>barrel </strong><em>– n.</em> the contents of or the amount contained in a barrel; a unit of measurement in the oil industry equal to between 120 and 159 litres</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>– n.</em> fuel such as coal or oil that was formed over millions of years from parts of dead animals or plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Learn Indefinite Pronouns with 'Fast Car'  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/learn-indefinite-pronouns-with-fast-car.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dr. Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>On today's <em>Everyday Grammar,</em> we are going to look at things that are different from each other: in other words, contrasts.</p>
<p>Let's start:</p>
<p>At the 2024 Grammy awards, one performance got the attention of many different sorts of music fans. It was the country music singer Luke Combs singing with singer and songwriter Tracy Chapman.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-75a2-08dc3dd8ab34_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Together, they sang "Fast Car," a song that had helped Chapman win a Grammy Award in 1989 for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance. You can listen to the song <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.grammy.com/videos/tracy-chapman-luke-combs-fast-car-2024-grammys-performance-66th-annual-grammy-awards?streamUrl=https://nomad-content.grammy.com/pmc/2f/6d/c5/2f6dc584-337d-4a9e-8b03-916f21017e49/tra-apple-hls-acc/0312-cbsperf2-gmypgmbug-tp.m3u8&amp;title=Tracy%20Chapman%20and%20Luke%20Combs%20Perform%20%E2%80%9CFast%20Car%E2%80%9D%20%7C%202024%20GRAMMYs">on the Grammys website</a>.</p>
<p>The song won the Country Music Association Awards prize for Country Song of the Year in 2023. Chapman is the first Black songwriter to win this award. Luke Combs recorded the song in 2023. He invited Chapman to sing it with him at the Grammy awards show in February.</p>
<p><strong>The American Dream</strong></p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will look at some of the words in the song and explore how they tell the story of two people. The two tried to find the American Dream: good jobs, a nice home, and children.</p>
<p>We will especially learn about the meanings of some <strong>indefinite</strong> pronouns and how they can be used to make contrasts.</p>
<p>In the beginning of the song, Chapman sings about going someplace in a fast car:</p>
<p><em>You got a fast car<br/>
I want a ticket to anywhere<br/>
Maybe we make a deal<br/>
Maybe together we can get somewhere<br/>
Anyplace is better<br/>
Starting from zero got nothing to lose<br/>
Maybe we'll make something<br/>
But me myself I got nothing to prove</em></p>
<p><strong>Somewhere and anywhere</strong></p>
<p>In this part, we hear <strong>pairs</strong> of contrasting words. The first pair is "anywhere" and "somewhere." She says she wants a "ticket to anywhere," which means there is no exact place she wants to go. A similar word appears in the line, "Anyplace is better." Then, she says that together, she and her friend with the fast car "can get somewhere." "To get somewhere" means to succeed or reach a goal.</p>
<p><strong>Nothing and something</strong></p>
<p>The next pair of contrasting words is "nothing" and "something." The first expression is that she has "nothing to lose." That means she will not suffer if what she tries to do fails. Again, speaking of what the young <strong>couple</strong> can do together, she sings, "Maybe we'll make something." When we use "something" as an indefinite pronoun, it can mean a thing that is quite good, as in the expression:</p>
<p>That's really something!</p>
<p>Moving on to the next part of the song, we find the singer is working at a low-paying job and wants to escape.</p>
<p><em>You got a fast car<br/>
And I got a plan to get us out of here<br/>
I been working at the <strong>convenience</strong> store<br/>
Managed to save just a little bit of money<br/>
We won't have to drive too far<br/>
Just ‘cross the border and into the city<br/>
You and I can both get jobs<br/>
And finally see what it means to be living</em></p>
<p><strong>Dreams and reality</strong></p>
<p>Tracy Chapman has said she wrote the song about the lives of her parents. As a young couple, they struggled to create the kinds of lives they dreamed of. Listen for the words in the next part that contrast their dream with the reality of living in a shelter – a place for people without a home in which to live:</p>
<p><em>I know things will get better<br/>
You'll find work and I'll get promoted<br/>
We'll move out of the shelter<br/>
Buy a big house and live in the suburbs</em></p>
<p>Finally, we learn through Chapman's song that the young woman did not finish her education because she stayed home to take care of her sick father. The couple seems to continue to struggle in the last part of the song, but they have good memories of their younger years. Listen for the indefinite pronoun "someone" here. To "be someone" means to be an important person.</p>
<p><em>I remember we were driving driving in your car<br/>
The speed so fast I felt like I was drunk<br/>
City lights lay out before us<br/>
And your arm felt nice wrapped 'round my shoulder<br/>
And I had a feeling that I belonged<br/>
And I had a feeling I could be someone, be someone, be someone</em></p>
<p>Listening to Tracy Chapman's song, we find that indefinite pronouns can help express two ideas related to the American Dream: to "make something" and to "be someone."</p>
<p>How do you express your own dreams for the future? Email us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a> or write to us in the comments.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dr. Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>Official Music video for Tracy Chapman - "Fast Car" from 'Tracy Chapman' (1988)</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>indefinite</strong> – <em>adj.</em> (<em>grammar) </em>not limiting or specifying; not referring to a specific or previously identified person or thing</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>–n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>couple</strong> <em>– n.</em> two people who are married, living together, or in a romantic relationship</p>
<p><strong>convenience (store)</strong> – <em>n. </em>a small market with a limited choice of foods and everyday items</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Don’t Put Your Wet Phone in Bag of Rice  (2024/3/7) | 手机掉水里怎么办？</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/don-t-put-your-wet-phone-in-bag-of-rice.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Anyone with a mobile phone has likely dropped it in water or been caught in a rainstorm. And many seem to think that putting a wet phone in a bag of uncooked rice will rescue it.<br/>
人们都有可能会把手机掉进水里或者是淋了暴雨。许多人似乎认为，把弄湿的手机放进一袋米里能够挽救它。</p>
<p>However, Apple recently warned against doing just that. The technology company said it is a bad idea because small particles of rice can get into the phone and cause damage.<br/>
然而，苹果公司最近警告不要这样做。这家科技公司表示，这并非良策，因为碎米会进到手机里并造成损坏。</p>
<p>So what should you do instead?<br/>
那么你应该怎么做呢？</p>
<p>If the phone is dropped in water, dry it with a clean cloth, even a shirt will do. Turn the phone off if you can. Remove its SIM card. Remove the phone's cover. Remove the battery, if possible. And let everything dry at room temperature, perhaps with a fan running.<br/>
如果手机掉在水里，用干净的布擦干，用衣服擦也行。如果可以的话，关掉手机。取出SIM卡。卸下手机外壳。如果可能的话，取下电池。让所有东西在室温下干燥，也许可以打开风扇（加速空气流动）。</p>
<p>Since you cannot take an iPhone apart, Apple says to tap the phone against your hand with the connecting ports facing down so water can flow out.<br/>
苹果公司说，由于你不能拆开iPhone，用手轻轻拍打手机，连接端口朝下，这样水就可以流出。</p>
<p>Samsung, the biggest maker of Android phones, suggests using a cotton swab to get water out of the ports. Apple, however, advises against putting one inside iPhone openings.<br/>
最大的安卓手机制造商三星公司建议用棉签将水从端口中吸出。然而，苹果公司建议不要把棉签插入iPhone手机的端口。</p>
<p>If your phone is dropped in seawater, treated water, or a drink, Samsung advises to keep it in clean water for a few minutes. Doing that will remove any salt or substances that could hurt the phone.<br/>
如果你的手机掉在海水、经过处理的水或饮料中，三星公司建议把手机放在干净的水中泡几分钟。这样做可以去除任何有损手机的盐分或物质。</p>
<p>Both Apple and Samsung say to leave the phone out in an open area to dry. More importantly, do not use a hair dryer or put the phone in a freezer.<br/>
苹果和三星都表示要把手机放在开阔的地方晾干。更重要的是，不要用吹风机吹或将手机放在冰箱里。</p>
<p>Most newer phones are not waterproof but they are water-resistant. It means they can get wet for a short time.<br/>
大多数新手机都不防水，但是能抗水。这意味着它们可能会在短时间内浸湿。</p>
<p>Apple says its newest phones can survive 30 minutes in up to 6 meters of water. Samsung's phones can last for the same amount of time in about 5 meters. But Google advises that all phones lose some water resistance over time.<br/>
苹果公司表示，其最新款手机可以在6米深的水中坚持30分钟。三星的手机可以在大约5米的水中坚持相同的时间。但谷歌建议，随着时间的推移，所有手机都会失去一些抗水性能。</p>
<p>Another way to dry your phone is by using silica gel, a drying agent. Packs of silica gel are usually included with products including food and shoes to keep them dry. These packs can help dry your phone in a sealed container.<br/>
另一种干燥手机的方法是使用硅胶干燥剂。袋装硅胶通常放在食品和鞋子等产品里，以保持其干燥。这些袋装硅胶可以帮助你在密封容器中烘干手机。</p>
<p>The phone manufacturers say it is hard to know when phones are completely dry. But it will likely take a few days. Samsung says it is still a good idea to bring the phone in for service even if you can turn it back on again.<br/>
手机制造商表示，人们很难知道手机什么时候彻底干燥了。但这可能需要几天时间。三星公司表示，即使可以再次开机，最好还是将手机送去维修。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Virtual Fences for Cows Show Benefits  (2024/3/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/virtual-fences-for-cows-show-benefits.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In the American state of Florida, <strong>rancher</strong> Jim Strickland can see his cows at any time, day or night. To do this, all he needs is his phone.</p>
<p>Strickland uses virtual fencing to watch and control the movements of his animals. The system, based on Global Positioning Satellite (GPS) technology, can help Strickland and researchers improve <strong>grazing</strong> lands, <strong>preserve</strong> wildlife and save time and labor for workers. It can also help improve animal health.</p>
<p>Strickland has been using the system for about six months. He told VOA Learning English he has already seen many good results with the new technology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Cattle wear Vence GPS tracking collars connected to a virtual fence system. (Courtesy photo Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e466-08dc3b075f76_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Cattle wear Vence GPS tracking collars connected to a virtual fence system. (Courtesy photo Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</span></div>
<p>"It has exceeded by far my expectations."</p>
<p><strong>How it works</strong></p>
<p>Virtual fencing uses radio signals to make an <strong>invisible</strong> fence. This means you cannot see the fence.</p>
<p>This keeps animals within, or outside of, certain areas. The signals come from nearby mobile phone towers. The signals can also come from base stations that can be moved using a small truck.</p>
<p>Each animal wears a <strong>collar</strong> around its neck. The collar has a radio signal receiver and a <strong>GPS</strong> device that shows the animal's location.</p>
<p>Ranchers train livestock to connect a sound with a small electric shock. When an animal gets close to a virtual fence, its collar makes a warning sound. If the animal moves even closer to the fence, it receives a shock. In this way, livestock quickly learn to stay away from the fence.</p>
<p>Ranchers can change the virtual fence boundaries quickly by using a phone App or computer. And livestock quickly learn the new boundaries.</p>
<p>Strickland and his coworkers can use their phones even while on horseback to move cattle from one area to another. All they need to do is change the virtual fence lines.</p>
<p>"And every 30 minutes, that line will move down; it will literally drive those cows down."</p>
<p><strong>Benefits of virtual fencing </strong></p>
<p>Physical fences take time, labor and money to build. It can be difficult to put them in areas such as rocky and hilly land, wet areas, or places with thick vegetation. Over time, fences need to be fixed or new ones need to be built.</p>
<p>When hurricane Ian hit Florida last year, it destroyed four houses and 45 kilometers of physical fence on the land where Strickland works. But the cell towers for the virtual fence system kept working.</p>
<p>Physical fences can also harm wild animals by making it difficult for them to move within and to areas they need for survival.</p>
<p>The Nature Conservancy (TNC) is a U.S-based environmental non-profit organization. It has partnered with cattle ranches in the states of Kansas, New Mexico and Colorado to research the effects of virtual fencing.</p>
<p>William Burnidge is Deputy Director of TNC's North America Regenerative Grazing Lands Strategy. He said that by changing fence boundaries, the systems prevent animals from eating too much vegetation within one area. This helps plants regenerate, or grow again.</p>
<p>He added that virtual fences could help protect rare plants and areas near rivers and streams. They could also support conservation of wild animals, improve the health of animals and help ranch workers have a better quality of life.</p>
<p>Strickland works with partners at Florida Conservation Group and the University of Florida. With virtual fences, they can carefully control grazing. This helps them research the effects of grazing patterns on the growth of young cows, birth rates, and even the effects on nesting birds.</p>
<p>They also plan to research how grazing can affect the release of carbon dioxide gas into the atmosphere. In Florida and other places, fields are sometimes burned to prepare them for future grazing. The burning releases carbon. Virtual fences may help reduce burning by better controlling where and how long cattle graze.</p>
<p>Both Strickland and Burnidge note that, unlike physical fences, livestock cannot not get injured by a virtual fence.</p>
<p>The GPS collars also let ranchers watch for animals that may be having problems. For example, if the system shows that a cow has not moved for many hours, it may be sick or injured.</p>
<p><strong>Other research and developing countries</strong></p>
<p>In the northwestern state of Oregon, researchers from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and Oregon State University studied how virtual fencing can prevent cows from grazing on recently burned land. Cattle can easily damage burned areas and the young plants that grow there.</p>
<p>The Oregon study showed that cows without virtual fence collars ate nearly 70 percent of the plants available to them in a burned area. However, cows with collars spent very little time in the burned area and ate less than three percent of the plants available to them.</p>
<p><strong>Reducing costs</strong></p>
<p>Although virtual fencing systems have benefits, they can be costly. A collar for just one animal can cost around $50 each year or more. And <strong>portable</strong> base stations cost $10,000 or more.</p>
<p>Researchers are looking for ways to lower costs and bring the technology to developing countries.</p>
<p>Last year, the Bezos Earth Fund awarded $9.9 million to Cornell University's College of Agriculture and Life Sciences to develop low-cost virtual fencing. The university plans to test new systems in Kenya, Mongolia, Argentina, Brazil and Colombia.</p>
<p>But in some areas, virtual fencing may not be the best solution, Burnidge said. When Burnidge visited Kenya, he saw many workers who closely follow and take care of livestock. Virtual fences could cause some of these workers to lose their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>Great interest in the new technology</strong></p>
<p>Still, Burnidge said, many people want to learn more about the technology. "The amount of interest in the ranching community, I've never seen anything comparable," he said.</p>
<p>And Strickland said they are already working on more ways virtual fencing can be used.</p>
<p>"Now we're seeing so many things. Once you start down the road of new technology, then it starts expanding . . . It's like, what can we do next?" he said.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rancher </strong><em>-n.</em> a person who owns or manages a large farm, especially one with animals such as cows, sheep, and goats</p>
<p><strong>graze </strong><em>-v.</em> the eating of grass or other plants in fields by animals</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong><em>-v.</em> to keep something safe for future use</p>
<p><strong>invisible </strong><em>-adj.</em> unable to be seen, not visible</p>
<p><strong>collar </strong><em>-n.</em> a ring worn around the neck of an animal</p>
<p><strong>GPS </strong><em>-n.</em> <em>(acronym </em><strong>Global Positioning Satellite</strong><em>) </em>a system for finding and tracking locations on earth using satellite technology</p>
<p><strong>portable </strong><em>-adj.</em> able to be moved or carried from one place to another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report Estimates 1 Billion People Worldwide Are Obese  (2024/3/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/report-estimates-1-billion-people-worldwide-are-obese.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study estimates more than 1 billion people worldwide are currently living with <strong>obesity</strong>. People with obesity are considered <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/obesity-and-overweight#:~:text=Worldwide%20adult%20obesity%20has%20more,16%25%20were%20living%20with%20obesity.">medically overweight</a>.</p>
<p>The study, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(23)02750-2/fulltext">published</a> in the medical publication <em>The Lancet</em>, said that one in eight people are obese. Researchers said around 43 percent of adults were overweight in 2022.</p>
<p>Worldwide, obesity among adults has more than doubled since 1990, the study found. Among young people aged five to 19, the obesity rate increased by four times during the same period.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man walks past the New York Stock Exchange after the close of trading hours in New York City on August 17, 2009. (REUTERS/Lucas Jackson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-196d-08dc3c61cd43_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man walks past the New York Stock Exchange after the close of trading hours in New York City on August 17, 2009. (REUTERS/Lucas Jackson)</span></div>
<p>"A <strong>staggering</strong> number of people are living with obesity," declared the lead writer of the study, Majid Ezzati. He is a professor at Imperial College London.</p>
<p>Severe obesity is strongly linked to a long list of health problems and an early death.</p>
<p>Researchers used data from more than 3,600 population studies involving 222 million people, <em>The Lancet</em> reported. The study "measured height and weight in representative <strong>samples</strong> of the general population," the researchers said.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.who.int/news/item/01-03-2024-one-in-eight-people-are-now-living-with-obesity">said</a> in a statement that it shared data with other international researchers and helped to create the report.</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said the study identifies the "importance of preventing and <strong>managing</strong> obesity from early life to adulthood."</p>
<p>The WHO <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.who.int/news/item/01-03-2024-one-in-eight-people-are-now-living-with-obesity" target="_blank">noted</a> that at the World Health Assembly in 2022, member states agreed to an agency plan to fight obesity. So far, 31 governments "are now leading the way" to reduce obesity by carrying out goals of the plan.</p>
<p>These include government measures to enact new rules on "harmful" marketing of unhealthy food and drinks to children. In addition, governments are aiming to improve school and nutrition policies. They are also seeking price reductions for healthy foods, to increase public awareness about healthy diets and exercise and to strengthen requirements for physical activity in schools.</p>
<p>Imperial College's Ezzati said that obesity rates are not rising in many wealthier nations. But they are quickly increasing in other countries. He noted that some countries have many underweight people, meaning the nations are facing what he called a "double burden" of nutrition problems.</p>
<p>Francesco Branca is head of nutrition at the WHO. He told reporters, "In the past, we have been thinking of obesity as a problem of the rich. Obesity is a problem of the world."</p>
<p>The research represented the first major report on the issue since 2017, with more than 1,500 scientists taking part. That report estimated around 774 million people above the age of five were living with obesity.</p>
<p>Branca and Ezzati suggested that powerful new obesity drugs – such as Ozempic and Wegovy – could be helpful tools in reducing obesity. But they noted that the cost and availability of the drugs might increase inequality.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and the World Health Organization reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>obesity </strong><em>– n. </em>a medical problem of having too much body fat. It increases the risk of many other diseases and health problems</p>
<p><strong>staggering </strong><em>– adj. </em>very shocking and surprising</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>manage </strong><em>– v.</em> to deal with something successfully</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Last Member of 1st Team to Top Everest Says Mountain Crowded, Dirty  (2024/3/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/last-member-of-1st-team-to-top-everest-says-mountain-crowded-dirty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The only living member of the team to first climb to the top of Mount Everest says the mountain is too crowded and polluted.</p>
<p>Ninety-one-year-old Kanchha Sherpa was part of the team that helped New Zealander Edmund Hillary and Nepali Sherpa Tenzing Norgay reach the<strong> peak</strong> of the world's tallest mountain on May 29, 1953.</p>
<p>Kanchha recently spoke with the<em> Associated Press</em>, saying the 8,849-meter tall mountain must be respected. "They should not be dirtying the mountain. It is our biggest god and they should not be dirtying the gods," he said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kanchha Sherpa speaks to Associated Press during an interview at his home in Kathmandu, Nepal, Saturday, March 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2de955e1-d4bb-4485-a7a7-736b3b87af03_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kanchha Sherpa speaks to Associated Press during an interview at his home in Kathmandu, Nepal, Saturday, March 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)</span></div>
<p>Since 1953, the mountain has been climbed thousands of times, and it gets more crowded every year.</p>
<p>During the spring climbing season in 2023, 667 climbers got to the top, or summit. And that brought thousands of support workers to Everest base camp between March and May.</p>
<p>"It would be better for the mountain to reduce the number of climbers," Kanchha said. "Right now there is always a big crowd of people at the summit."</p>
<p>There have been concerns for years about the number of people living on the mountain for several months and leaving <strong>trash</strong> behind. But officials have no plans to cut down on the number of permits they issue to climbers.</p>
<p>The rules require climbers to bring down their own trash, equipment and everything they carry to the mountain. But <strong>monitoring</strong> of the climbers has not been very effective.</p>
<p>"It is very dirty now. People throw <strong>tins</strong> and <strong>wrappings</strong> after eating food. Who is going to pick them up now?" Kanchha said.</p>
<p>Some climbers just drop their trash in deep openings in the earth on the mountain, he said, noting that the trash is hidden at first. But, he said, in time the trash "will flow down to base camp as the snow melts and carries them downward."</p>
<p>For the Sherpas, Everest is Qomolangma or goddess mother of the world. The mountain is highly honored. And Sherpas generally perform religious services before climbing it.</p>
<p>Kanchha was just a young man when he joined the Hillary-Tenzing climb. He was among the three Sherpas to set up the climb's last camp for Hillary and Tenzing to use.</p>
<p>They heard by radio message that Hillary and Norgay reached the top. Later, the summiteers reunited with the Sherpas at Camp 2.</p>
<p>"We all gathered at Camp 2 but there was no alcohol so we celebrated with tea and <strong>snacks,"</strong> Kanchha said. "We then collected whatever we could and carried it to base camp."</p>
<p>The path they opened up from the base camp to the summit is still used by current climbers.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>peak </strong><em>– n. </em>mountain top</p>
<p><strong>trash </strong><em>– n. </em>things that are no longer useful or wanted and that have been thrown away</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>– v. </em>to watch, keep track of, or check usually for a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>tins </strong><em>– n. </em>metal containers</p>
<p><strong>wrapping </strong><em>– n. </em>paper or soft material used to cover or enclose something.</p>
<p><strong>snack </strong><em>– n. </em>a light meal;<strong> </strong>food eaten between usual mealtimes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Educators Increasingly Urge Total Phone Bans in Schools  (2024/3/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-educators-increasingly-urge-total-phone-bans-in-schools.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>American educators and lawmakers are calling for complete bans on smartphone use by students in schools.</p>
<p>Most U.S. schools already have rules restricting phone use in class. But administrators and teachers say the measures are difficult to enforce.</p>
<p>Educators across the United States say students are using their phones to do many things that can <strong>distract</strong> their attention during class. These include sending messages, gaming, listening to music, watching videos, checking social media and shopping.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A ninth grader places her cellphone into a phone holder as she enters class at Delta High School, Friday, Feb. 23, 2024, in Delta, Utah. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1ffe-08dc3931db45_cx0_cy14_cw80_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A ninth grader places her cellphone into a phone holder as she enters class at Delta High School, Friday, Feb. 23, 2024, in Delta, Utah. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)</span></div>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-number-of-kids-watching-online-videos-doubled-in-4-years/5147205.html">Studies</a> in recent years have confirmed high smartphone usage by young people in America. But an increasing number of educators and experts are now beginning to agree that total bans are necessary to solve the problem.</p>
<p>Leaders and lawmakers in a growing number of states have also called for complete phone bans or suggested new ways to limit their use in class.</p>
<p>James Granger is a science teacher at a Los Angeles, California high school. He recently told <em>The Associated Press</em> (AP), "Students used to have an understanding that you aren't supposed to be on your phone in class. Those days are gone."</p>
<p>Granger requires students attending his class to place their phones in a special container. "The only solution that works is to physically remove the cellphone from the student," Granger said.</p>
<p>The latest state intervention on phones in schools came last month in Utah. Governor Spencer Cox, a Republican, urged all school districts and the Board of Education to remove cellphones from classrooms. He explained that studies had repeatedly shown students do better in school when their phones are not available.</p>
<p>The studies, Cox noted, found that learning improves, distractions are decreased, and students are more likely to talk to each other if their phones are taken away.</p>
<p>"We just need a space for six or seven hours a day where kids are not <strong>tethered</strong> to these devices," Cox told reporters. He said his urging, which does not have the force of law, is part of a larger legislative push to protect children from social media harms.</p>
<p>Patrick Truman is a high school teacher in Maryland who bans student phone use during class. "Cellphone use is out of control," he told the AP. "By that, I mean that I cannot control it, even in my own classroom."</p>
<p>Truman bought a container that can hold 36 phones. But he says that still, every day, students find ways to hide their phones so they can still use them.</p>
<p>Last year, Florida became the first state to strongly restrict phones in schools. A law took effect in July that requires all public schools in the state to ban student cellphone use and block social media services during class. Some school districts went a step further and banned phones for the whole school day.</p>
<p>Oklahoma, Vermont and Kansas also recently introduced what is becoming known as "phone-free schools" legislation.</p>
<p>Two U.S. senators – Tom Cotton, an Arkansas Republican, and Tim Kaine, a Virginia Democrat – introduced federal legislation in December. The legislation would require a government study on how phone use by students affects their mental health and school progress.</p>
<p>The National Center for Education Statistics reports that nationally, 77 percent of U.S. schools say they currently ban phones for non-school use. Education experts, however, say that number is misleading. That is because it does not mean students are actually following the rules or that all the schools are enforcing them.</p>
<p>Many educators and experts say that, for a school phone ban to work, school administrators must be the ones to enforce it.</p>
<p>Some students say such policies take away their <strong>autonomy</strong> and cut off their main method of communication with family and friends. Opposition has also come from parents who fear they could be cut off from their children if there is a school emergency.</p>
<p>Kim Whitman is a leader of the Phone-Free Schools Movement, a group that advises schools. She told the AP she urges educators to make exceptions for students with special educational and medical needs.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>distract </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone stop giving their attention to something</p>
<p><strong>tether </strong><em>– v. </em>to tie something to an object so that it cannot be removed</p>
<p><strong>autonomy </strong><em>– n. </em>the right to be independent of have the right to self-govern</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Vietnamese Woman Accused of $12.5 Billion Fraud  (2024/3/6) | 越南前女首富被控欺诈125亿美元</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/vietnamese-woman-accused-of-12-5-billion-fraud.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>A major property investor in Vietnam, Truong My Lan, is on trial over an accusation of fraud amounting to $12.5 billion. That is nearly 3 percent of the country's 2022 total economic production and the largest financial fraud case on record.<br/>
越南主要房地产投资商张美兰因涉嫌欺诈125亿美元而受审。这几乎占该国2022年经济总量的3%，也是有记录以来最大的金融欺诈案件。</p>
<p>Lan is the 66-year-old head of the property company Van Thinh Phat. The company was one of Vietnam's biggest property companies and its projects include homes, offices, hotels, and business centers.<br/>
现年66岁的张美兰是越南万盛发房地产公司的负责人。该公司是越南最大的房地产公司之一，其项目包括住宅、办公室、酒店和商业中心。</p>
<p>A government document says she reportedly used "thousands of ghost companies," paid bribes to government officials, and broke banking laws. She is accused of illegally controlling the Saigon Joint Stock Commercial Bank from 2012 to 2022 and using it to steal $12.5 billion, the document adds.<br/>
一份政府文件称，据报道她利用了“数千家幽灵公司”，向政府官员行贿，并违反了银行法。文件补充道，她被指控在2012年至2022年非法控制西贡商业股份银行，并利用该银行窃取125亿美元。</p>
<p>Another 85 people are being charged in the case, including a former State Bank of Vietnam official accused of accepting $5.2 million in bribes. Lan was arrested in October 2022 and could be executed if found guilty.<br/>
另有85人在此案中受到指控，其中包括一名前越南国家银行官员，他被控受贿520万美元。张美兰于2022年10月被捕，如果罪名成立，她可能会被处决。</p>
<p>Officials brought Lan to a Ho Chi Minh City courtroom on Tuesday morning. Her husband Eric Chu Nap-kee, who works in property investment in Hong Kong, was also asked to appear in the case, VN Express reported.<br/>
周二上午，官员将张美兰带上胡志明市法庭。据《越南快讯》报道，她的丈夫Eric Chu Nap-kee（在香港从事房地产投资）也被要求出庭。</p>
<p>Lan's arrest is part of an ongoing anti-corruption drive that brought thousands of officials and business leaders under investigation. In January 2023, then-President Nguyen Xuan Phuc and two top officials resigned for "political responsibility" of corruption dealings during the pandemic.<br/>
张美兰的被捕是正在进行的反腐运动的一部分，该运动使数千名官员和商界领袖受到调查。2023年1月，时任总统阮春福和两名高级官员因对疫情期间的腐败交易负有“政治责任”而辞职。</p>
<p>But observers said the anti-corruption drive has also worsened Vietnam's economic outlook and concerned foreign investors. It came at a time when the Southeast Asian nation has been trying to get businesses to move from China.<br/>
但观察人士表示，反腐运动也恶化了越南的经济前景，并让外国投资者感到担忧。当此之际，这个东南亚国家正试图让企业从中国搬过来。</p>
<p>Linh Nguyen is the lead researcher for Washington D.C.-based Control Risks. She said it is the size of Lan's alleged fraud that has been surprising.<br/>
阮灵是总部位于华盛顿特区的“控制风险组织”的首席研究员。她说，张美兰涉嫌欺诈的规模令人吃惊。</p>
<p>"More than 3 percent of the GDP is very large," Nguyen said. GDP, or gross domestic product, is how much a country produces in one year. She added that it also raised questions about whether other banks and businesses had "done the done the same (and) just haven't been discovered."<br/>
阮灵表示：“超过3%的国内生产总值是非常大的数额。”国内生产总值是一个国家一年的生产量。她补充说，这也引发了人们的疑问，即其他银行和企业是否“也做了同样的事情，只是还没有被发现。”</p>
<p>The anti-corruption drive has also resulted in Vietnam's government slowing down. A report from Singapore's ISEAS-Yusof Ishak Institute says that public officials are concerned about being investigated and are avoiding their responsibilities.<br/>
反腐运动也导致越南政府的行动放缓。新加坡尤索夫·伊萨东南亚研究所的一份报告称，公职人员担心被调查，并在逃避责任。</p>
<p>And Nguyen said that investors in banking, finance, and property investment are also taking a "wait and see" position at the moment.<br/>
阮灵表示，银行、金融和房地产投资的投资者目前也持“观望”态度。</p>
<p>Last year, local media reported that 1,300 property companies withdrew from the market and developers have been offering price reductions and gold to bring in buyers.<br/>
当地媒体去年报道称，有1300家房地产公司退出了市场，开发商一直在提供降价和黄金来吸引买家。</p>
<p>But Communist Party General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong, Vietnam's top politician, said in November that the anti-corruption fight would "continue for the long term."<br/>但是，越共总书记、越南最高政治家阮富仲在11月说，越南反腐败斗争将“长期持续”。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Popasna - A Town Which Doesn't Exist  (2024/3/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/popasna---a-town-which-doesn-t-exist.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>My name is Kateryna Bezruk and I teach online in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Someone once said that you should appreciate and enjoy everything that surrounds you.</p>
<p><strong>Poposna before 2022</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Popasna, Ukraine, Town Center in 2018. (Courtesy photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c787-08dc39e23a01_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Popasna, Ukraine, Town Center in 2018. (Courtesy photo)</span></div>
<p>Until the spring of 2022, I did not take these words seriously. It seemed that our cozy and developing town Popasna in the Luhansk region would exist forever. The newly refurbished school, called Lyceum 25, would teach our children and grandchildren. The "Unity of Hearts" bridge would always be there for lovers. And there would be walks in the forest and swims in the pond.</p>
<p>But the war came to our town, a small village with a large railway junction between Luhansk and Donetsk. There was a train repair workshop, a locomotive depot, and a bread factory in town. With its fertile black soil, the area was also home to several agricultural businesses.</p>
<p>Why do I use the words ‘was' and ‘were'? Because everything in Popasna is now gone. And the soil is now black with the residue of bombs and artillery shells.</p>
<p><strong>Erased from maps</strong></p>
<p>Russian troops attacked Popasna in February and occupied the town on May 8, 2022. The fighting destroyed much of the town. And Russian officials said they would not rebuild Popasna and simply erased it from maps.</p>
<p>It was not the first time that Popasna had been occupied. The town suffered under Soviet rule in 1932-1933. That was the time the former Soviet Union government's policy led to the deaths of 416 people in Popasna.</p>
<p><strong>Damage of another war</strong></p>
<p>During World War II, the Nazis operated a prison during their occupation of Popasna. The town was heavily damaged but was rebuilt after the war. Returning businesses included a bakery, food plant, sewing factory and a dairy. The 1955 rebuilding also brought rail and transport services, a glass factory, nine schools, five libraries and a stadium. By 1974, Popasna's population was more than 30,000.</p>
<p>Having such experience with rebuilding, I believe that our town will rise again, and "nothing shall burn the living record of our memory."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the Writer</h2>
<p>Kateryna Bezruk, 28 years old, once lived and worked in Popasna, Luhansk region. Now the town is temporarily occupied by the Russian Federation and destroyed, so she lives in the Dnipropetrovsk region of Ukraine and teaches online. She holds a specialist diploma from the Horlivka Institute for Foreign Languages and has taught in primary and secondary school for six years.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Is Elon Musk Bringing Legal Action Against OpenAI?  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/why-is-elon-musk-bringing-legal-action-against-openai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Business leader Elon Musk is bringing a legal case against artificial intelligence (AI) company OpenAI and its chief Sam Altman.</p>
<p>Musk is chief of carmaker Tesla and SpaceX and also leads the social media service X. He said OpenAI is <strong>betraying</strong> its founder's aims by seeking to increase profits rather than helping the world.</p>
<p>Musk brought the legal action in San Francisco Superior Court. He said that, at first, he financially supported OpenAI, the maker of the AI tool ChatGPT. He said he had an agreement with Altman and Greg Brockman, the president. That agreement was to keep the artificial intelligence company as a nonprofit organization. Musk said the goal was to develop technology that would help the public.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Elon Musk addresses the European Jewish Association's conference, in Krakow, Poland, Monday, Jan. 22, 2024. Musk is suing OpenAI and its CEO Sam Altman over what he says is a betrayal of the ChatGPT maker's founding aims. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/46837636-89ef-493b-8889-928c9e067b1b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Elon Musk addresses the European Jewish Association's conference, in Krakow, Poland, Monday, Jan. 22, 2024. Musk is suing OpenAI and its CEO Sam Altman over what he says is a betrayal of the ChatGPT maker's founding aims. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski, File)</span></div>
<p>Under its founding agreement, OpenAI would also make its <strong>code</strong> open to the public instead of making it the company's private property, the <strong>lawsuit</strong> says. Musk claims in the lawsuit that OpenAI went against the agreement by having a close relationship with Microsoft.</p>
<p>OpenAI did not comment on the lawsuit last week.</p>
<p>Musk's lawsuit says OpenAI broke a contract, failed in its financial responsibility, and used unfair business methods. Musk also wants to prevent anyone, including Microsoft, from profiting from OpenAI's technology.</p>
<p><strong>Musk was early supporter of OpenAI</strong></p>
<p>Anupam Chander is a law professor at Georgetown University in Washington, D.C. He said Musk's claims are unlikely to succeed in court. However, he said that might not be the point for Musk, who is getting his personal story on the record.</p>
<p>Chander said Musk claims he named OpenAI, employed an important scientist, and that he was the main financial supporter in its early years. He said, "In some sense, it's a lawsuit that tries to establish his own place in the history of <strong>generative</strong> AI."</p>
<p>Musk was an early investor in OpenAI when it was founded in 2015. He was a leader in the company alongside Altman. In the lawsuit, he said he invested "tens of millions" of dollars in the nonprofit research laboratory.</p>
<p>Musk left the company in early 2018 in a move that OpenAI said at the time would prevent conflicts of interest. Musk's Tesla car company was looking for people in AI to help develop self-driving car technology.</p>
<p>Musk has since said he disagreed with the company's direction but continued to give money to the nonprofit.</p>
<p>Later, OpenAI created a for-profit arm and began moving most of its workforce to that business. But it kept its nonprofit board of directors that oversaw the company.</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft investment</strong></p>
<p>Microsoft made its first $1 billion investment in the company in 2019. The next year Microsoft signed an agreement with OpenAI giving Microsoft the rights to OpenAI's AI models. That agreement is supposed to end once OpenAI has created artificial general intelligence (AGI), the company has said.</p>
<p>AGI is a sort of artificial intelligence that can perform just as well or even better than humans in different kinds of work.</p>
<p>The nonprofit board of directors fired Altman as chief executive officer late last year. But Microsoft helped bring Altman back and pushed most of the old board of directors to leave.</p>
<p>Musk's lawsuit claims that those changes caused the balance of power protecting the nonprofit aim of the company to "collapse overnight." One of Musk's claims is that the directors of the nonprofit have failed in their duty to support its nonprofit aim.</p>
<p>Dana Brakman Reiser is a professor at Brooklyn Law School. She questions whether Musk has standing, or a connection to the case, that a court would uphold.</p>
<p>She said it would be a problem if every person who cared about or gave money to a nonprofit group could bring a lawsuit against its leaders and officers. She said only other directors, or a government legal official could bring that sort of lawsuit.</p>
<p>Musk now has his own AI company. But his legal case against Altman could inform the public about private talks and decision-making that took place at OpenAI. The company's lawyers will likely fight to keep some of those documents from being released.</p>
<p>Investor Chamath Palihapitiya wrote on X, Musk's social media service: "The discovery will be <strong>epic</strong>." Discovery is the process by which lawyers request documents related to a legal case. Musk answered in his only public comments on the case so far: "Yes."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan, Thalia Beaty, and Matt O'Brien reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>betray </strong><em>– v. </em>to ignore your principles or beliefs in order to achieve something or gain an advantage for yourself</p>
<p><strong>lawsuit </strong><em>– n. </em>a claim or complaint against somebody that a person or an organization can make in court</p>
<p><strong>code </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of computer programming instructions</p>
<p><strong>generate </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce or create something</p>
<p><strong>epic </strong><em>– adj.</em> very great or large and usually difficult or impressive</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Electrical Device in Brain Might Help with Depression  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/electrical-device-in-brain-might-help-with-depression.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Deep brain stimulation, or DBS, is an experimental treatment that involves having an electrical device placed in the brain.</p>
<p>The treatment gives patients' brains targeted electrical <strong>impulses</strong>.</p>
<p>Researchers say DBS could help some of the nearly 3 million Americans with depression that resists other treatments. It is approved for conditions like Parkinson's disease and epilepsy. Many doctors and patients hope it will become more widely available for depression.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Emily Hollenbeck stands for a portrait at the American Museum of Natural History's Rose Center in New York on Jan. 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Mary Conlon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/79c7f011-4328-4f7b-b8c9-ba767241aa2d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Emily Hollenbeck stands for a portrait at the American Museum of Natural History's Rose Center in New York on Jan. 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Mary Conlon)</span></div>
<p>Recent research suggests gains are possible and more research is planned. However, two earlier studies showed no gains using DBS for depression. Those results have slowed the treatment that involves a brain operation. Some scientists continue to raise concerns about DBS.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has agreed to speed up its study of Abbott Laboratories' request to use its DBS devices for treatment-resistant depression.</p>
<p><strong>"Nothing else was working"</strong></p>
<p>Emily Hollenbeck lived with severe depression. She compared it to a black hole. She felt as though her arms and legs could barely move. She knew both of her parents had taken their lives and that her condition was dangerous.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck, who grew up poor and sometimes homeless, suffered from signs of depression as a child. In college, after her father's suicide in 2009, she had her first period of major depression. Another happened while she was working. She was concerned she would lose her teaching job and become poor again. She went to the hospital.</p>
<p>"I ended up having sort of an on-and-off <strong>pattern</strong>," she said. Medication helped her for a while.</p>
<p>She was able to earn a doctoral degree in <strong>psychology</strong> although she lost her mom in her final year of graduate school. But the depression stayed with her. At times, she said, she thought about ending her life.</p>
<p>She was willing to try something extreme.</p>
<p>Her doctor then told her about DBS three years ago.</p>
<p>"Nothing else was working," she said.</p>
<p>She became one of a few hundred people to have her depression treated with DBS.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck is part of ongoing research at Mount Sinai West medical center in New York City. Her brain operation took place while she was <strong>sedated</strong> but still awake. Dr. Brian Kopell directs Mount Sinai's Center for Neuromodulation. He placed thin metal <strong>electrodes</strong> in the part of her brain believed to control emotional behavior and is thought to be involved in feelings of sadness.</p>
<p>The thin metal electrodes are connected by wires to a device placed under the skin of her <strong>chest</strong>. The device controls the electrical impulses sending current to her brain.</p>
<p>Doctors involved in DBS say the impulses help because the brain uses electricity to send signals.</p>
<p>In normal brains, Kopell said, electrical activity spreads through the brain unblocked to all areas. In depression, he said, the brain's emotional signals get blocked. He compared the problem to dancing. He said DBS seems to "unstick the circuit," permitting the brain to do what it normally would. A circuit is the path unblocked electrical current takes.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck said the effect on her was almost immediate.</p>
<p>"The first day after surgery, she started feeling a lifting of that <strong>negative</strong> mood, of the heaviness," said her <strong>psychiatrist</strong>, Dr. Martijn Figee.</p>
<p>For Hollenbeck, the biggest change was finding pleasure in music again.</p>
<p>She wishes her treatment had been available for her parents.</p>
<p><strong>The treatment's history</strong></p>
<p>DBS research has continued for at least 20 years. Brain expert Dr. Helen Mayberg led early research that was called promising. But large studies launched more than 12 years ago saw no difference in treated and untreated groups.</p>
<p>Dr. Katherine Scangos is a <strong>psychiatrist</strong> at the University of California, San Francisco. She is also researching DBS and depression. She said there could be two reasons for the major studies showing no effect.</p>
<p>She said one reason was that the treatment was not "personalized" for each individual in the two studies. The second was that researchers looked at outcomes over just a few weeks.</p>
<p>Recent research has shown more promising results for depression. A 2022 study said that on average 60 percent of depression patients showed improvement with DBS. A study from 2023 said that after six months of targeted DBS treatment, 90 percent of subjects showed improvements. Seventy percent were no longer considered medically depressed.</p>
<p>Treatments being tested by teams today target individual patients more closely. The team at Mount Sinai, for example, is using brain imaging to find the right place to put electrodes in the brain.</p>
<p>Mayberg is also with Mount Sinai. She said, "Everybody's brain is a little different, just like people's eyes are a little further apart or a nose is a little bigger or smaller."</p>
<p><strong>Looking ahead</strong></p>
<p>Medical devices manufacturer Abbott Laboratories is launching a large <strong>clinical trial </strong>on patients this year, ahead of a possible decision by the FDA.</p>
<p>Scangos said: "I'm hoping we will have approval within a short time."</p>
<p>But some doctors have concerns. They point to possible dangers of having a brain operation, which include bleeding, stroke and infection.</p>
<p>Dr. Stanley Caroff is a professor of psychiatry at the University of Pennsylvania. He said scientists do not know the exact pathways or systems in the brain that produce depression. That makes it difficult to send the impulses to the right place.</p>
<p>"I believe from a psychiatric point of view, the science is not there," he said of DBS for depression.</p>
<p><strong>Moving forward</strong></p>
<p>Hollenbeck said DBS has not cured her. She still takes medicines for depression and needs ongoing care.</p>
<p>She recently visited Mayberg of Mount Sinai in her office and discussed recovery. "It's not about being happy all the time," Mayberg told her. "It's about making progress."</p>
<p>Researchers are studying the progress patients make. Recent research by Mayberg and others published in <em>Nature</em> said scientists can study brain activity to see how someone is doing at any given time.</p>
<p>Study subjects can provide data from their homes about how they feel. Subjects answer questions and send data from their devices to researchers. They also send videos where researchers can observe speech and facial movements.</p>
<p>Additionally, patients go to Mount Sinai so researchers can collect more information about their body movements. Hollenbeck, for example, is showing faster movements as her condition improves.</p>
<p>The data gained, combined with other information like life events, records how she is doing. This helps guide doctors' decisions about treatment, like increasing the amount of electricity used — which they did once.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck showed AP the scars on her chest and head where doctors had placed the DBS devices. To her, they were signs of how far she had come.</p>
<p>She added, "...I'm able to see and remember, even on a bodily level, that I'm going to be OK."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impulse </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of energy that moves from one area to another</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong><em>– n. </em>the regular and repeated way in which something happens or is done</p>
<p><strong>psychology </strong><em>– n.</em> the science or study of the mind and behavior</p>
<p><strong>sedate </strong><em>– v.</em> to give (a person or animal) drugs that cause relaxation or sleep</p>
<p><strong>electrode </strong><em>– n.</em> one of the two points through which electricity flows into or out of a battery or other device</p>
<p><strong>chest </strong><em>– n. </em>the front part of the body between the neck and the stomach</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. harmful or bad: not wanted</p>
<p><strong>psychiatry </strong><em>– n.</em> a branch of medicine that deals with mental or emotional disorders</p>
<p><strong>clinical trial </strong><em>– n.</em> a research study in which a medical treatment is carefully tested on people to find out how safe and effective it is</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Locals Worried about Olympic Surfing Event in Tahiti  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/locals-worried-about-olympic-surfing-event-in-tahiti.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Summer Olympic Games this year are in Paris, France.</p>
<p>Paris does not have an ocean. So, how do organizers plan to present competition in the sport of surfing?</p>
<p>They are taking that Olympic event halfway around the world to the South Pacific country of French Polynesia. The athletes will compete on the island of Tahiti, in a small coastal village called Teahupo'o. The area is rural. It did not even have a road until the 1970s.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Tahitian-born surfer Kauli Vaast rides a wave in Teahupo'o, Tahiti, French Polynesia, Sunday, Jan. 13, 2024. (AP Photo/Daniel Cole)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e6989c0a-6001-447b-8bb5-ce80206c7faa_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Tahitian-born surfer Kauli Vaast rides a wave in Teahupo'o, Tahiti, French Polynesia, Sunday, Jan. 13, 2024. (AP Photo/Daniel Cole)
</span></div>
<p>Hundreds of people are expected to visit Teahupo'o to watch the sport, as the surfers go out onto the famous waves from July 27 to August 4.</p>
<p>Peva Levy is a Tahitian surfer. He said the Teahupo'o beach was a "secret spot" when he first rode the waves there more than fifty years ago. But, he added, it did not stay secret. Teahupo'o gained fame among surfers around the world in the years since.</p>
<p>Levy said the place has a special energy, a feeling known as "mana" in the local language.</p>
<p>And the people who live there want that special quality protected. There are concerns that a week of Olympic competition in Teahupo'o could destroy the "mana" and harm the environment that surrounds it.</p>
<p>Proposed preparations for the event included building temporary housing, roads, and even a large structure out on the water. The work called for drilling into a <strong>coral reef</strong>. Opposition to the plans quickly grew.</p>
<p>Environmentalists, locals and surfers joined forces to protect Teahupo'o's culture, its corals and other sea life.</p>
<p>"It was too much for us, a big change," said Levy, who also serves on a local environmental organization Vai Ara o Teahupo'o.</p>
<p>The group told the Olympic organizers they did not want new buildings or roads. And organizers are adjusting their plans as a result.</p>
<p>For example, they will not be building any Olympic housing. Instead, athletes will stay on a nearby boat. Homes of locals will serve other Olympic housing needs.</p>
<p>Organizers also shrunk the size of the planned structure, a platform, they will build in the ocean. Judges will watch the competition from the platform.</p>
<p>Some people worry that the <strong>drilling</strong> into the reef will disrupt the ecosystem and attract a dangerous <strong>algae</strong>. If fish eat the algae, people who eat the fish can become sick.</p>
<p>Twenty-two-year-old Mormon Maitei is concerned about the fish in the area. Maitei is a spearfisher who catches fish to feed his family. He sells what they do not need. The water is "where we get our dinner," he said.</p>
<p>Tahitians also worry that changing the reef could also change the shape of the famous waves.</p>
<p>Levy said if the reef cracks and breaks off "there will be no more wave over here, it will be finished for us."</p>
<p>In December, the worries of the locals were confirmed when a boat working on some Olympic construction hit a piece of the reef and broke it.</p>
<p>Cindy Otcenasek, the president of Via Ara o Teahupo'o, called the destruction deeply hurtful.</p>
<p>She said in Polynesian culture, people believe gods and spirits are everywhere, "in the coral, in the ocean. The ocean is considered to be our most sacred temple," she said.</p>
<p>Otcenasek said the fish live in and around the corals, "so if we break a coral, we break a home."</p>
<p>Barbara Martins-Nio is a senior event manager for the Paris 2024 Olympic and Paralympic Games Organization Committee. She called the accident "<strong>awful</strong>." She said Tahitians have a "special relationship with nature ... and it was like a bomb for us."</p>
<p>Since the incident, Martins-Nio said, the relationship between the organizers and locals has improved. The Olympic group is moving slowly and asking for more input from the local groups.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>coral reef </strong><em>–n.</em> a long section of material formed on the bottom of the sea by the skeletons of small creatures that is home to sea life and living coral</p>
<p><strong>drill </strong><em>–v.</em> to make a hole in something with a powerful tool</p>
<p><strong>algae </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind plant life that grows in water</p>
<p><strong>awful </strong><em>–adj.</em> something very bad or upsetting</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Supreme Court Rules Trump Can Stay on Ballots  (2024/3/5) | 美国最高法院裁定川普可参加大选</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-supreme-court-rules-trump-can-stay-on-ballots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The United States Supreme Court ruled on Monday that former President Donald Trump can stay on 2024 presidential primary ballots.<br/>
美国最高法院周一裁定，前总统川普可以继续参加2024年的总统初选。</p>
<p>All nine justices ruled that individual states cannot use the 14th Amendment to prevent presidential candidates from appearing on ballots. They said that power "rests with Congress and not the states."<br/>
所有九名大法官都裁定，个别州不能利用第十四修正案阻止总统候选人出现在选票上。他们说，这项权力“归于国会而非各州”。</p>
<p>The ruling ended efforts in several states, including Colorado, Maine and Illinois, to remove Trump from ballots for presidential primary elections run by state governments.<br/>
这项裁决终止了几个州将川普从州政府举行的总统初选选票中除名的努力，这些州包括科罗拉多州、缅因州和伊利诺伊州。</p>
<p>Those state governments wanted to remove Trump, the leading candidate for the Republican Party nomination, from ballots because of his activities related to the 2020 presidential election. Trump is accused of trying to overturn his loss to Democrat Joe Biden. He is also accused of involvement in activities that led to the January 6 attack on the U.S. Capitol.<br/>
这些州政府希望将共和党提名的主要候选人川普从选票中除名，原因是他在2020年总统大选中的相关举动。川普被指控试图推翻他输给民主党人拜登的事实。他还被指控参与了导致1月6日美国国会大厦骚乱的活动。</p>
<p>Colorado's highest state court decided that Trump incited the January 6 attack. It also ruled that Section 3 of the 14th Amendment, which was passed shortly after the American Civil War, could be applied to Trump. The amendment aimed to prevent former officeholders of the U.S. who "have engaged in insurrection" or "given aid or comfort" to such activity from holding such office again.<br/>
科罗拉多州最高法院裁定川普煽动了1月6日的袭击。它还裁定，美国内战后不久通过的第14修正案第3条可以适用于川普。该修正案旨在防止“参与叛乱”或“为此类活动提供帮助或配合”的前美国官员再次担任此类职务。</p>
<p>In Monday's ruling, the U.S. Supreme Court did not deal with the issue of insurrection. All nine justices agreed that Trump should be on the ballot. But they offered different opinions on the ruling.<br/>
在周一的裁决中，美国最高法院没有处置暴动问题。所有九位大法官都同意川普应该被名列选票上。但他们对裁决提出了不同意见。</p>
<p>A five-justice conservative majority wrote, "The Constitution makes Congress, rather than the states, responsible for enforcing Section 3 against federal officeholders and candidates."<br/>
五名占多数优势的保守派法官写道：“宪法规定由国会，而不是由各州负责对联邦官员和候选人执行第3条。”</p>
<p>Three liberal justices, Sonia Sotomayor, Elena Kagan, and Ketanji Brown Jackson, jointly wrote, "Today, the majority goes beyond the necessities of this case to limit how Section 3 can bar an oathbreaking insurrectionist from becoming President."<br/>
三位自由派大法官索尼娅·索托马约尔、埃琳娜·卡根和凯坦吉·布朗·杰克逊共同写道：“今天，多数派超越了本案的必要性，限制了第3条如何禁止一名宣誓叛乱者成为总统。”</p>
<p>And Justice Amy Coney Barrett added that the majority should not have dealt with the "question whether federal legislation is the exclusive vehicle through which Section 3 can be enforced."<br/>
大法官艾米·科尼·巴雷特补充道，多数派不应该处理“联邦立法是否是执行第3条的唯一途径的问题”。</p>
<p>Trump posted on his social media network shortly after the decision was released: "BIG WIN FOR AMERICA!!!"<br/>
裁决发布后不久，川普在其社交媒体网络上发帖称：“美国的重大胜利！！！”</p>
<p>The case is the Supreme Court's latest direct involvement in a presidential election since Bush v. Gore. In that case, the court stopped the recount of votes in the state of Florida that effectively handed the 2000 election to Republican George W. Bush.<br/>
这是自小布什诉戈尔案以来，最高法院最新一次直接卷入总统选举。在那起案件中，最高法院阻止了佛罗里达州重新计票，这实际上将2000年的选举胜利交给了共和党人小布什。</p>
<p>The Supreme Court has an even more important case ahead that involves Trump directly on the week of April 22.<br/>
最高法院还有一起更重要的案件，将于4月22日这一周直接涉及川普。</p>
<p>A three-judge federal appeals court had ruled earlier that Trump could be put on trial for trying to undo the 2020 elections and actions leading to the January 6 attack. But the nation's highest court agreed last week to hear whether Trump could face criminal prosecution for actions taken while in office as president.<br/>
一家由三名法官组成的联邦上诉法院早些时候裁定，川普可能因试图撤销2020年的选举和导致1月6日国会袭击的行为而受审。但美国最高法院上周同意审理川普是否会因担任总统期间的行为而面临刑事起诉。</p>
<p>The decision effectively put on hold several federal cases against Trump and raised questions about whether Trump will be tried before the November election.<br/>
这一决定实际上搁置了几起针对川普的联邦案件，并引发了人们对川普是否会在11月大选前受审的质疑。</p>
<p>Recently, a jury in New York City found Trump guilty of defaming writer E. Jean Carroll. It ordered him to pay her $83 million. Last month, a New York judge presiding over Trump's civil fraud trial set a penalty and interest of $450 million and barred Trump from running a business in the state for three years. Later in March, Trump will face a trial for charges related to payments made to adult movie performer Stormy Daniels.<br/>
最近，纽约市的一个陪审团裁定川普诽谤作家简·卡罗尔罪名成立。陪审团命令川普赔付给她8300万美元。上个月，主持川普民事欺诈案审判的纽约法官设定了4.5亿美元的罚款和利息，并禁止川普在三年内在该州经营企业。3月晚些时候，川普将因向成人电影演员斯托米·丹尼尔斯付款而面临审判。</p>
<p>In addition to those ongoing cases, the former president is facing charges brought by the state of Georgia over his actions related to the 2020 presidential election. And the federal government has brought a case against Trump in the state of Florida for holding classified documents after leaving office.<br/>
除了这些正在进行的案件外，这位前总统还因其与2020年总统选举有关的行为而面临佐治亚州的指控。同时联邦政府已在佛罗里达州对川普提起诉讼，指控他在离任后持有机密文件。</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.<br/>
我是安娜·马泰奥。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: NASA Space Strike Might Have Reshaped an Asteroid  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/study-nasa-space-strike-might-have-reshaped-an-asteroid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests that an <strong>asteroid</strong> strike by an American spacecraft likely changed the shape of the targeted object.</p>
<p>NASA crashed the DART spacecraft into the asteroid Dimorphos in 2022. The asteroid strike happened about 11 million kilometers from Earth.</p>
<p>The experiment tested a method for changing the orbit of some asteroids to prevent them from possibly crashing into our planet in the future.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This artist's illustration depicts NASA's DART spacecraft, which will be launched to crash into an asteroid to see how the crash affects the space object's path. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C27B36A6-BC02-4175-9B42-68C44C0D9969_cx6_cy3_cw93_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This artist's illustration depicts NASA's DART spacecraft, which will be launched to crash into an asteroid to see how the crash affects the space object's path. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL)</span></div>
<p>NASA has said its studies of the crash showed it was successful because the force of the strike changed the asteroid's orbit around a larger asteroid Didymos. NASA's measurements also found the strike reduced the orbital period of Dimorphos by 33 minutes.</p>
<p>Such a major crash would normally create a large <strong>crater</strong> in the targeted object. But a new study presents evidence that the crash made more than a hole – it likely changed the shape of the whole asteroid.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Astronomers at the University of Bern, in Switzerland carried out the research. A <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-024-02200-3">study</a> detailing the findings recently appeared in the publication <em>Nature Astronomy</em>.</p>
<p>The team used a computer<strong> simulation</strong> system to study the changes to Dimorphos that resulted from the crash. The system aimed to recreate the breakup of space objects that have been hit.</p>
<p>The researchers said their simulation method has been used in the past to recreate space objects crashing into each other. For example, the team said it confirmed the results of a Japanese spacecraft collecting a sample from the Ryugu asteroid in 2019.</p>
<p>Sabina Raducan is with the Physics Institute of the University of Bern. She helped lead the project. Raducan <a class="wsw__a" href="https://mediarelations.unibe.ch/media_releases/2024/media_releases_2024/impact_of_the_dart_space_probe_could_have_deformed_an_asteroid/index_eng.html">described</a> the simulation process in a statement as "computationally intensive." In total, she said 250 simulations were completed, which reproduced the first two hours after the asteroid strike.</p>
<p>The researchers used all available information about NASA's operation. These included the predicted shape of Dimorphos, data on the strike itself, as well as the size of the cloud the crash left behind. In addition, the team aimed to estimate unknown details about the asteroid and the surrounding area.</p>
<p>"Then what we did is <strong>check</strong> which of the simulation run outcomes most closely match observed reality," Raducan said.</p>
<p>She added that results of the research provided clear evidence that the crash turned Dimorphos into a relatively weak "<strong>rubble pile</strong>" asteroid. Raducan explained this meant that the object is currently being held together "by the asteroid's extremely weak gravity" rather than a solid and strong mass.</p>
<p>The researchers noted that the results of the simulation and the team's examinations partly explain why the crash was so effective in changing the path of the asteroid.</p>
<p>Raducan said the results also persuaded the team that "the likelihood is that the crater grew to <strong>encompass</strong> the entire body itself, so that Dimorphos ended up being completely reshaped." It is therefore unlikely that a crater still exists after the crash.</p>
<p>The researchers said the existence of a crater can be investigated further by a European Space Agency (ESA) spacecraft. The spacecraft, called Hera, is preparing for a possible launch in October.</p>
<p>ESA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Space_Safety/Hera">says</a> Hera's cameras and instruments will carry out detailed studies of Dimorphos and the asteroid it orbits, Didymos. During the operation, the spacecraft will aim to collect the most data yet on such an asteroid system.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from the University of Bern, the European Space Agency, NASA and Nature Astronomy.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>a rocky object that goes around the sun like a planet</p>
<p><strong>crater </strong><em>– n. </em>a big hole left in the ground or an object by a force of impact</p>
<p><strong>simulate </strong><em>– v. </em>to do or make something that behaves or looks like something real but is not</p>
<p><strong>check </strong>–v. to look for something of interest or something that might be a mistake</p>
<p><strong>rubble </strong><em>– n. </em>pieces of broken bricks from a destroyed structure</p>
<p><strong>pile </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of substance in the shape of a small hill or a number of objects laying on top of each other</p>
<p><strong>encompass </strong><em>– v. </em>to include a lot of things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Life Inside Russia’s Prisons  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/life-inside-russia-s-prisons.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Vladimir Kara-Murza is a <strong>critic</strong> of the Russian government.</p>
<p>He was sentenced to 25 years in prison last year on charges of treason for speaking against Russia's war with Ukraine.</p>
<p>He is in Penal Colony Number 6, south of Moscow and not far from Kazakhstan.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A replica of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny's jail cell from last year that was installed on a square near the Louvre Museum in Paris is pictured on March 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a8cf-08dc39435397_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A replica of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny's jail cell from last year that was installed on a square near the Louvre Museum in Paris is pictured on March 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla, File)</span></div>
<p>Kara-Murza's wife, Yevgenia, spoke with <em>The Associated Press</em> about her husband's experiences.</p>
<p>She said her husband lives in a small cell with a <strong>cot</strong>, a sink, a stool and toilet. The only things he owns are a drinking cup and a toothbrush.</p>
<p>People are interested in what life is like inside of the prisons because another critic of President Vladimir Putin's government died at a prison in Russia's far north, close to the Arctic Circle. Alexei Navalny died February 16. He was the leader of a political group that campaigned against Putin. Forty-seven-year-old Navalny was sentenced to 19 years in prison in early 2021.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press </em>called life in Russia's prisons "<strong>grim</strong>" and noted the prisoners suffer from a lack of food, sleep, and healthcare. They also must deal with rules that change all the time.</p>
<p>Grigory Vaypan is a lawyer with Memorial, a group that started during the period of the Soviet Union. Memorial received the Nobel Prize in 2022. The group studies the experiences of political prisoners, and how Russia uses the threat of prison to quiet critics.</p>
<p>Vaypan said there are 680 political prisoners in Russia. He also said no one in the Russian prison system is safe, but the situation is worse for government critics.</p>
<p>"The state aims to additionally punish them, or additionally <strong>isolate</strong> them from the world, or do everything to break their spirit," Vaypan said.</p>
<p>Kara-Murza's sentence of 25 years is the longest in modern Russia. He is one of a growing number of critics held in prison for expressing their anti-Putin opinions.</p>
<p>Historians say the Russian prison system developed from the Soviet Union's "gulags." The prisons of that time were known for their bad conditions. Nobel Prize-winning writer Alexander Solzhenitsyn documented the prisons in his books <em>One Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich </em>and <em>The Gulag Archipelago</em>.</p>
<p>Yevgenia Kara-Murza, the wife of Vladimir Kara-Murza, described Russian prison life:</p>
<p><strong>Meals</strong></p>
<p>Meals are simple and not very satisfying. The first meal of the day is porridge, a liquid made from grains. The midday meal is soup with very little meat, along with mashed potatoes and a piece of meat or fish. For dinner, the meal is almost the same. Prisoners are permitted to eat two eggs per week. They can buy fruits and vegetables at small prison stores but not much is available.</p>
<p>Friends and family can send packages with other foods. But those in <strong>solitary cells</strong> are not permitted to receive packages.</p>
<p><strong>How do people spend their time?</strong></p>
<p>Some prisoners are told to spend most of their days doing tasks such as cleaning their rooms. Other times they are told to only "stand at attention." They sometimes must listen to recordings of prison rules for hours.</p>
<p>Others are told to work. There are not enough jobs for all the men in the prison. In women's prisons, the jobs often include <strong>sewing</strong> uniforms for the military, police and other workers. There are 30 to 40 women's prisons in Russia.</p>
<p>One woman, Nadya Tolokonnikova, was in prison for nearly 22 months. She was a member of the rock band Pussy Riot. Her prison time was from 2012 to 2013. She said she worked on uniforms for 16 to 18 hours at a time.</p>
<p>"It's a system of slavery and it is truly horrible," she said.</p>
<p>Inmates — another word for prisoners — are supposed to be paid at least minimum wage. That is about $200 per month. But experts say it is usually much less. Sasha Graf is an activist for better prison conditions. Graf said prisoners' pay can be as low as $3.20 per month. That is only enough to buy cigarettes at the prison store.</p>
<p><strong>Intimidation</strong></p>
<p>Tolokonnikova said, when she arrived at Penal Colony No. 14 in Mordovia, the head of the prison described himself as a "Stalinist."</p>
<p>She said he told her: "You may be a somebody outside of this colony, have a voice, people who support you and care for you, but here, you are completely in my power, and you need to understand this."</p>
<p>Zoya Svetova, a reporter and prisoner rights activist, said that in the past, prisons were overseen by commissions that were supposed to make sure the prisoners were treated with respect. However, she said, most of the people have been replaced with those loyal to Putin's government. The government uses the prisons, she said, for "<strong>intimidation</strong> and oppression."</p>
<p>Oleg Kozlovsky, of Amnesty International, said political prisoners can be safe from the abuse that regular prisoners suffer. But there are still ways to make political prisoners feel bad.</p>
<p>Navalny, he said, spent months in a cell on his own for breaking small rules such as not having his uniform buttoned the right way or not putting his hands behind his back at the right time.</p>
<p>The time in the small cell – where it could be very cold in winter or very hot in summer – was not good for Navalny's health. He had been poisoned in the past and was still suffering from the effects of the poison.</p>
<p>Kara-Murza's wife said her husband had also been poisoned. Although he is only 42, his health has worsened. She said he needs exercise and physical therapy to help his arms and legs.</p>
<p>Alexei Gorinov is 62. He criticized the war and was sent to prison for seven years.</p>
<p>He has breathing problems and had a medical operation to remove one of his lungs. He is now in a prison hospital, but his lawyer says he is mistreated. Guards wake him up every two hours. He considers it a form of torture.</p>
<p>There have been calls for prison reform in recent years. Vaypan of the Memorial group, said whatever led to Navalny's death shows the prison system has crossed a line.</p>
<p>It's a "worrying signal," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>critic </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who disagrees with something or someone and who speaks or writes in opposition to what they disagree with</p>
<p><strong>cot </strong>–n. a small bed that folds</p>
<p><strong>grim </strong><em>–adj.</em> unhappy and without hope</p>
<p><strong>isolate </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause someone to be kept apart from others, often as punishment</p>
<p><strong>solitary cell </strong><em>–n.</em> a room in a prison that is meant to hold only one person who is being kept apart from others as a more severe form of punishment</p>
<p><strong>sew </strong><em>–v. </em>to use thread and cloth to make or repair clothes</p>
<p><strong>intimidation </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of threatening someone with harm or trouble usually to prevent them from doing or saying something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Costs, Performance Influence Decisions on Electric School Buses  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/costs-performance-influence-decisions-on-electric-school-buses.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The first electric school buses in the United States began operating about 10 years ago in California. Fewer than one percent of the 489,000 school buses in the U.S. were electric at the end of 2023.</p>
<p>However, the number of electric school buses currently operating or that have been ordered from a manufacturer has more than tripled in the last two years. That information comes from the Electric School Bus Initiative of the non-profit World Resources Institute, or WRI, based in Washington D.C.</p>
<p>The WRI said that increase means 10 times as many students now ride electric school buses — from around 20,000 in 2020 to 200,000 three years later. The number of states with electric bus laws or goals also grew from two to 14 between 2020 and last year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rock Creek Forest Elementary School students exit a diesel bus before attending school, Friday, Feb. 2, 2024, in Chevy Chase, Md. At right is an electric school bus. (AP Photo/Tom Brenner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/29ae78dc-1e10-432b-8be1-e077840c8978_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rock Creek Forest Elementary School students exit a diesel bus before attending school, Friday, Feb. 2, 2024, in Chevy Chase, Md. At right is an electric school bus. (AP Photo/Tom Brenner)</span></div>
<p>People and organizations that want electric school buses can find it difficult to get local officials to find ways to pay for them.</p>
<p>"It's just a matter of breaking down these barriers," said Alicia Cox. She is a mother of two in Jackson, Wyoming. Her state is the only one that does not have a single <strong>school district</strong> with an electric bus operating or on order.</p>
<p>Cox's son, a second grader, often rides a diesel bus to school.</p>
<p><strong>Problems with electric buses </strong></p>
<p>Parents and local officials say one of the biggest problems with electric school buses is their cost. Even with the fuel and <strong>maintenance</strong> savings of an electric bus, they cost two to three times more than diesel fueled buses.</p>
<p>The Environmental Protection Agency says it has a $5 billion program for <strong>zero-emissions</strong> buses. The money comes from an infrastructure law passed by the U.S. Congress under the administration of President Joe Biden in 2021. Nearly 440 <strong>grants</strong> and <strong>rebates </strong>totaling about $1.8 billion have already been released. The goal of the federal money is to replace thousands of buses across several hundred school districts in the U.S.</p>
<p>Demand for the money has been "heartening," said Christine Koester. She is a director for the Clean School Bus Program at the EPA.</p>
<p>In addition to federal money, supporters have successfully pushed to use other money. That includes money from federal government legal cases, like the Volkswagen emissions settlement. In that case, the U.S. government brought legal action against the German carmaker for having a system that gave false car emissions results.</p>
<p>For school districts that are not receiving federal money, there are other possibilities. These include <strong>leasing </strong>buses from companies that supply the buses and the equipment needed. This method spreads costs out over time.</p>
<p><strong>Choices </strong></p>
<p>Dearborn Public Schools is a Detroit area school district in the Midwestern state of Michigan. Seventy percent of families in the district are poor. Communications director David Mustonen said the district was interested in new technology when it began operating its first electric bus in December 2022.</p>
<p>The district bought an electric school bus with a $300,000 federal grant. The bus has been operational only about three of the 12 months since then. That is because of maintenance needs and learning about the device. That is not <strong>discouraging </strong>Dearborn from moving forward with adding 18 additional electric school buses. But those problems represent a risk other school districts may not want to take.</p>
<p>There are other problems slowing the change to electric buses. School districts sometimes take a long time to approve electric buses. Manufacturing of the buses can be delayed, and electric buses require special electrical connections for charging. And, of course, electricity costs money, too.</p>
<p>Wyoming refused federal money from the EPA because of concerns about how far the buses could travel. There were also concerns about cold temperatures. Wyoming is a very large Western state where travel distances are big and, in the winter, temperatures can get very cold. Electric battery performance decreases in cold temperatures.</p>
<p>"Even though diesel is not as clean, it's getting the job done," Cox said schools and<strong> fleet </strong>managers tell her.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Alexa St. John reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>school district </strong>– n. an area established by a local government for the administration of public schools which has a budget and is supervised by local government officials</p>
<p><strong>maintenance </strong>– n. the act of keeping property or equipment in good condition by making repairs</p>
<p><strong>zero-emissions</strong> –adj. letting off no gasses that people do not like or considered harmful</p>
<p><strong>grant</strong> – n. an amount of money that is given by a government to be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>rebate</strong> – n. an amount of money that is paid back to you</p>
<p><strong>lease</strong> – v. to use (something) for a period of time in return for payment</p>
<p><strong>discourage</strong> – v. to make someone less likely to do something; to make someone less hopeful about doing something</p>
<p><strong>fleet</strong> –n. a group of vehicles that is supervised for an organization or force</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Lessons from the War in Ukraine  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/three-lessons-from-the-war-in-ukraine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A volunteer carries a woman as she is evacuated from a flooded Kardashynka village of the bank Dnipro river, in Kherson, Ukraine on June 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Evgeniy Maloletka)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f994-08dc33d93e9d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A volunteer carries a woman as she is evacuated from a flooded Kardashynka village of the bank Dnipro river, in Kherson, Ukraine on June 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Evgeniy Maloletka)</span></div>
<p>My name is Kateryna Denysenko; I work at the Gymnasium of Veselianka.</p>
<p>War is always a tragedy.</p>
<p>It ruined lives, separated families, and destroyed cities.</p>
<p>Like many life-changing events, war could also be viewed as a way to teach us important things. Thucydides, an ancient Athenian historian and general, once wrote, "War is a stern teacher." And today, we are going to share three important lessons the war in Ukraine has taught us.</p>
<p><strong>Volunteer work and donations are important.</strong></p>
<p>If there was one important lesson to share, it would have been this: volunteer work and donations are important!</p>
<p>Let's be honest. We often pay little attention when someone asks us to donate money, clothes, food, or blood to someone in need. We may feel that our help would be too small. And we spend even less time on volunteer work, thinking that it takes time and energy and may not be useful.</p>
<p>Ukrainians may argue with that. We understand that even the smallest amount of money can help to buy armor and weapons for our army. And the more people decide to help, the safer our soldiers feel, and the more protected the country becomes.</p>
<p>But you should not forget about people in need. If you donate your clothes, food, or blood to those who were seriously wounded or lost their homes, you will help them survive. Your small act of kindness will also help them save some of their resources to move on.</p>
<p>Volunteer work also matters a lot for Ukrainians. You can help by removing parts of fallen buildings or by cooking free meals for soldiers. Your participation will greatly help others!</p>
<p><strong>If you want to do something, do it.</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes, we do not say good things to others. We may be too shy to give a compliment. Or we do not know if the person will like what we say. Maybe, our words will be out of place.</p>
<p>Sometimes, we do not get around to visiting certain places. Who needs to spend their time going to a historical place, a park, or an old café? These places have existed for so long. They would not disappear, would they?</p>
<p>Since the start of the war, Ukrainians have known the harsh reality.</p>
<p>We know that you may never see someone again. They may flee to another city for safety, their house may collapse, or they can go to war and never come back. And the place you always wanted to visit may be destroyed by a missile.</p>
<p>We rarely tell our family members and friends how happy we are to have them in our lives. You may never have another chance to tell them how much you love and value them. But if you tell them something kind, your words will support and encourage them in such uncertain times.</p>
<p>That is why we remember the rule: if you want to say something good or go somewhere nice, do it now. Do not wait until tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>There is always a reason to be grateful.</strong></p>
<p>Lastly, we take many things in our lives for granted. We expect to sleep well at night, eat healthy meals, have a place to live, and go to school or work. We get used to them so much that they become routine and even boring.</p>
<p>Before we know it, we are looking for something new and fresh and something unusual. But people in Ukraine know the value of routine and boring things in their daily lives.</p>
<p>When the noise from missiles keeps us awake, we begin to appreciate a good sleep. When we have to study remotely, or we lose our workplace due to the war, we appreciate the time with our classmates, teachers, or colleagues.</p>
<p>As we spend our days and nights in a bomb shelter or move far away from our homes, we begin to appreciate the place we live and the meals we cook and eat.</p>
<p>This may be one of the most important lessons from the war so far. We should appreciate these small, but very important things in our lives.</p>
<p>In his 28th song, Ukrainian songwriter Hryhorii Skovoroda wrote, "What you need is easy to get, what you do not need is hard to get." And now, after going through the war, and losing so many different things, we can agree that the simplest ones are the most important in our lives.</p>
<p>These were the three most important lessons from the war in Ukraine. We hope they will inspire you to value the simplest things in your life, to visit the places you always wanted to visit, to do small acts of kindness for people in need, and to show your love and gratitude to your closest people!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the writer</h2>
<p>Kateryna Denysenko was born in Donetsk, Ukraine. At the age of 13, she was forced to leave her hometown due to the invasion of the Russian Federation and move to the village of Veselianka, in the Zaporizhzhia area. In 2020, she graduated from the Zaporizhzhia Pedagogical College with professional qualification as a teacher of primary education and foreign language at primary school. Since 2020, she has been an English teacher at the Gymnasium of Veselianka.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Did Human Ancestors Lose Their Tails?  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/how-did-human-ancestors-lose-their-tails.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Our very ancient animal ancestors had <strong>tails</strong>. Why don't we have them now?</p>
<p>From the time of Charles Darwin, a scientist from the 1800s who studied evolutionary biology, scientists have questioned why and how this happened.</p>
<p>The answer is somewhere around 20 million or 25 million years ago. That was the time apes, the group of animals humans are part of, split from another animal group, m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s. During that split, our branch of the tree of life lost its tail.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Skeletons of a human and a m&lt;I&gt;&lt;I&gt;onkey&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/I&gt; await installation at the Steinhardt Museum of Natural History in Tel Aviv, Israel on Monday, Feb 19, 2018. (AP Photo/Oded Balilty, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7770b6c8-b28b-45e7-9e8e-f8dd2c39c025_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Skeletons of a human and a m<i><i>onkey</i></i> await installation at the Steinhardt Museum of Natural History in Tel Aviv, Israel on Monday, Feb 19, 2018. (AP Photo/Oded Balilty, File)</span></div>
<p>Now, scientists have identified at least one of the genetic differences that led to this change.</p>
<p>"We found a single <strong>mutation</strong> in a very important gene," said Bo Xia. He is a geneticist at the Broad Institute and helped write the study recently released in the publication <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>The researchers compared the genomes of six kinds of apes, including humans, and 15 kinds of m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s with tails to find important differences between the groups. Once they identified an important mutation, they tested their theory by using the gene-<strong>editing</strong> tool CRISPR. They used it to change the same place in <strong>embryos </strong>of an animal often used in laboratories, mice. Those mice were born without tails.</p>
<p>Xia said, however, that other genetic changes may also play a part in losing tails.</p>
<p>Another mystery: Did having no tails help these ape ancestors – and eventually, humans – survive? Or was it just a chance mutation in a population that survived for other reasons?</p>
<p>"It could be <strong>random</strong> chance, but it could have brought a big evolutionary <strong>advantage</strong>," said Miriam Konkel. She is an evolutionary geneticist at Clemson University, who was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>As to why having no tails may have helped our ancestors, there are many interesting theories. They include some that link being tailless to learning to walk upright.</p>
<p>Rick Potts directs the Human Origins Project of the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C. He was not involved in the research. Potts suggests being tailless may have been a first step toward some apes standing upright, even before they left the trees.</p>
<p>Not all apes live on the ground today. Orangutans and gibbons are tailless apes that still live in trees. But Potts notes that they move very differently than m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s, who move along the tops of branches, using their tails for balance. Those apes hang below branches, holding onto the branches with their arms while hanging largely upright.</p>
<p>New York University biologist Itai Yanai helped write the study. He said that losing our tails was clearly a large change. But the only way to truly know the reason "would be to invent a time machine," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tail </strong><em>– n. </em>the part of an animal's body that extends from the animal's back end</p>
<p><strong>mutation </strong><em>– n.</em> the part of an animal's body that extends from the animal's back end</p>
<p><strong>edit </strong><em>– v.</em> to make changes</p>
<p><strong>embryo </strong><em>– n.</em> a human or animal in the early stages of development before it is born or hatched</p>
<p><strong>random </strong><em>– adj. </em>in a way that does not follow a particular plan or pattern</p>
<p><strong>advantage </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as a good position or condition) that helps to make someone or something better or more likely to succeed than others</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Health Officials Urge Older Adults to Get Latest COVID-19 Vaccine  (2024/3/3) | 美国疾控中心督促老年人再接种加强针</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-health-officials-urge-older-adults-to-get-latest-covid-19-vaccine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>U.S. health officials are urging older adults to get an additional updated COVID-19 vaccine shot.<br/>
美国卫生官员敦促老年人再接种一针更新版新冠疫苗。</p>
<p>The advice for Americans 65 and older was recently issued by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).<br/>
美国疾控预防中心最近发布了针对65岁及以上美国人的建议。</p>
<p>A statement by CDC Director Mandy Cohen explained the new guidance. "Most COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations last year were among people 65 years and older. An additional vaccine dose can provide added protection ... for those at highest risk."<br/>
美国疾控预防中心主任曼迪·科恩在一份声明中对这份新的指导意见做出了解释。“去年新冠肺炎死亡和住院患者多数都是65岁及以上人群。对这些高危人群来说，接种一剂加强针可以提供更多防护。</p>
<p>The CDC said an additional dose of the vaccine can provide increased protection, even if older adults received the updated shot version launched last autumn.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心表示，即使老年人接种了去年秋天推出的更新疫苗，再接种一剂疫苗也可以提供更多的保护。</p>
<p>The new guidance suggests individuals who did receive the updated shot – which became available last September – should wait at least four months before getting the latest dose.<br/>
新的指导意见建议，接种了去年9月推出的更新疫苗的人群，应该至少等待四个月才能接种最新的疫苗。</p>
<p>The CDC's decision, or recommendation, came after much debate over whether to say older people "may" get the shots or "should" do so. That discussion demonstrates the ongoing debate among experts about how necessary additional COVID-19 shots are.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心的决定或建议，是在对老年人接种这剂疫苗是“可选择”，还是“应该”进行了大量辩论之后做出的。这一讨论表明，专家们正在就额外接种新冠疫苗的必要性进行辩论。</p>
<p>Some doctors have said they think most older adults are effectively protected after getting the shot last autumn. And studies have suggested the shots stay effective for six months.<br/>
一些医生表示，他们认为大多数老年人在去年秋天接种疫苗后得到了有效的保护。研究表明，这些疫苗的有效期为六个月。</p>
<p>But health officials have noted the body's vaccine-activated defenses can decrease over time, especially in older people. The CDC had recommended additional COVID-19 shots, called boosters, for older adults in 2022 and 2023.<br/>
但卫生官员指出，随着时间的推移，疫苗激活的人体防御能力会下降，尤其是在老年人中。美国疾控预防中心在2022年和2023年建议为老年人额外接种新冠疫苗加强针。</p>
<p>COVID-19 can still present serious health risks, especially to older people and those with existing medical conditions. The CDC says there are still more than 20,000 hospitalizations and more than 2,000 deaths each week from COVID-19. Individuals 65 years and older have the highest hospitalization and death rates.<br/>
新冠肺炎仍可能带来严重的健康风险，尤其是对老年人和既有病患。美国疾控预防中心表示，新冠肺炎每周仍然导致2万多人住院，2000多人死亡。65岁及以上人群的住院率和死亡率最高。</p>
<p>Some members of the CDC group that approved the latest advice said the word "should" in the guidance is meant to persuade more doctors and drug stores to offer the shots.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心批准这一最新建议的小组的一些成员表示，指南中的“应该”一词旨在说服更多的医生和药店提供疫苗。</p>
<p>"Most people are coming in either wanting the vaccine or not," Dr. Jamie Loehr told The Associated Press. He is a member of the CDC's deciding committee and a family doctor in Ithaca, New York. "I am trying to make it easier for providers to say, ‘Yes, we recommend this.'"<br/>
詹米·勒尔博士告诉美联社：“大多数人要么想接种疫苗，要么不想接种。”他是美国疾控预防中心决策委员会的成员，也是纽约伊萨卡的一名家庭医生。“我试图让提供疫苗者更容易说出，‘是的，我们建议这样做。’”</p>
<p>In September, the government ordered a new COVID-19 shot based on a version of the virus called XBB.1.5. That single-target vaccine replaced combinations that had targeted both the first COVID-19 version and a much earlier Omicron version.<br/>
去年9月，美国政府下令接种一剂新的新冠疫苗，该疫苗是基于XBB.1.5病毒版本。这种单靶点疫苗取代了针对第一种新冠肺炎版本和更早的奥密克戎版本的组合。</p>
<p>The CDC recommended that vaccine version for everyone 6 months and older. It also urged people with weak immune systems to get a second shot up to two months after the first.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心建议6个月及以上人群接种该疫苗。它还敦促免疫系统较弱人群在接种第一针后两个月内接种第二针。</p>
<p>But most Americans did not listen to that advice. The latest CDC data shows that 13 percent of U.S. children got the shots, while 22 percent of U.S. adults did. The vaccination rate for adults 65 and older is higher, at nearly 42 percent.<br/>
但大多数美国人没有听从这个建议。美国疾控预防中心的最新数据显示，接种了这剂疫苗的美国儿童为13%，而美国成年人为22%。65岁及以上人群的疫苗接种率更高，接近42%。</p>
<p>"People are tired of getting all these shots all the time," Dr. David Canaday told the AP. He is an infectious diseases expert at Case Western Reserve University in Cleveland, Ohio.<br/>
大卫·卡纳迪博士告诉美联社：“人们已经厌倦了一直接种这些疫苗。”他是俄亥俄州克利夫兰市凯斯西储大学的传染病专家。</p>
<p>Canaday, who does not serve on the CDC's advisory group, added, "We have to be careful about over-recommending the vaccine."<br/>
卡纳迪不在美国疾控预防中心的咨询小组任职，他补充道，“我们必须对过度推荐疫苗保持谨慎。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Professors’ Group Speaks Out about Changes at Florida College  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/professors-group-speaks-out-about-changes-at-florida-college.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>College professors and their students often say they should be permitted to <strong>pursue</strong> knowledge without too many restrictions from the government.</p>
<p>One organization that supports the idea of <strong>academic</strong> freedom is the American Association of University Professors (AAUP). The AAUP is a non-profit group based in Washington D.C. that aims to support academic freedom and <strong>tenure</strong>. The group is concerned that national and state political leaders are interfering too much with colleges and universities.</p>
<p><strong>AAUP expresses concern </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A student makes her way past the sign at New College of Florida, Jan. 20, 2023, in Sarasota, Fla. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/700a7e3e-1475-46c6-a43e-572aea5df5f3_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A student makes her way past the sign at New College of Florida, Jan. 20, 2023, in Sarasota, Fla. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara, File)</span></div>
<p>In early February, the AAUP <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.aaup.org/news/time-now-resist-political-interference">spoke out</a> about what it said were attempts to control "what may be said, taught, or thought" in American colleges and Universities.</p>
<p>It pointed to hearings at the U.S. Congress in December that brought the presidents of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Harvard University and the University of Pennsylvania to Washington. They each were asked if they would punish speech calling for genocide against the Jewish people.</p>
<p>In the days and weeks after the hearing, the presidents of the University of Pennsylvania and Harvard stepped down from their jobs. Some said the answers they gave to Congress played a part.</p>
<p>At first, Harvard president Claudine Gay received support from a number of Harvard professors. But she decided to leave her job after being accused of <strong>plagiarism</strong> in her academic writing. After Gay left her position, the AAUP spoke out about the way influential people worked to push her out.</p>
<p>Irene Mulvey is the head of AAUP. She said the way Gay was pushed out of her job "(did) not <strong>bode</strong> well for academic freedom."</p>
<p><strong>Research into New College of Florida</strong></p>
<p>On February 26, AAUP released a statement about its concerns over academic freedom. It said actions at the New College of Florida, a small school in Florida's State University System, did not meet "widely accepted <strong>standards</strong> of academic government."</p>
<p>The group said Ron DeSantis, the Florida governor, had changed the college's top leadership group to restrict academic freedom. AAUP described some of the changes that began in early 2023 in a report released last December. The report is called "Political Interference and Academic Freedom in Florida's Public Higher Education System."</p>
<p>After studying the report, AAUP's top leaders, known as the governing council, voted to speak out against, or <strong>sanction</strong>, what it called "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> politically motivated takeover" of the school. The group has only sanctioned 12 other universities in its history.</p>
<p>The December report said DeSantis targeted New College of Florida because he believed it was too "woke." The report says conservatives now define the word as: "politically liberal or progressive...especially in a way that is considered unreasonable or extreme."</p>
<p>The governor appointed a group of six new people to the college's board of trustees. The board is a college or university's top leadership group.</p>
<p>That group pushed out New College of Florida's president and worked to restrict the kinds of study programs the school could offer. The new trustees also worked to change the way professors applied for tenure, which guarantees those who have it a job for life. Many of the new trustees had written papers and made comments criticizing critical race theory (CRT). The theory centers on the idea that racism is systemic in the country's institutions and that most social interactions can be explained by race.</p>
<p>The board members also spoke against DEI, or diversity, equity and inclusion, a movement aiming to change how society is made up.</p>
<p><strong>No longer safe</strong></p>
<p>One law professor in Florida, LeRoy Pernell, told AAUP what was happening in the state was a "reign of terror." Pernell teaches law at Florida A&amp;M University. That term was first used to describe the French Revolution, which took place more than 225 years ago.</p>
<p>New College is a state school, which means Florida provides part of its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/harvard-president-s-ouster-leads-to-concerns-about-academic-freedom/7427004.html">budget</a> and it is governed under state laws. For years, New College had been permitted to be "<strong>quirky</strong>." That means it welcomed students and professors who had unusual interests and wanted to follow study programs outside of normal ones.</p>
<p>Many students who felt uncomfortable at more traditional colleges went to New College of Florida and said they felt happy and safe. LBGTQ students say they chose the school because it was open to those who did not follow traditional sexual or gender ideas.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Leininger is a science professor. In a 2023 story, she called New College "one of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/small-florida-college-worries-about-government-involvement/7037843.html#comments">most unique places</a> ... that exists in American higher education."</p>
<p>The AAUP talked with professors at other Florida universities who said they were concerned about the changes at New College of Florida. They said professors are worried about their own ability to seek academic freedom. Some are looking for jobs in other states.</p>
<p>Carolyne Ali-Khan is an education professor at the University of North Florida. "These governmental attacks from the State of Florida have made us unsafe," she told the AAUP.</p>
<p>Kenneth Nunn is a former law professor at the University of Florida. He said good job candidates who are Black are no longer considering Florida schools, "because they see attacks on CRT as attacks on what they do."</p>
<p><strong>What comes next?</strong></p>
<p>In its report, the AAUP said it offered the chancellor, or top leader, of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fldoe.org/schools/higher-ed/fl-college-system/about-us/colleges.stml" target="_blank">Florida College System</a>, a chance to present Florida's side of the story. The chancellor, Kathy Hebda, said no because, she said, the AAUP would not "fairly and fully consider any testimony."</p>
<p>When the sanction came out, a representative from New College of Florida noted that the AAUP's decision has no ability to force changes or prevent a university from operating. In a statement to the <em>Tampa Bay Times</em>, New College spokesman Nathan March called the report an attempt to get attention.</p>
<p>The AAUP did say it is not too late to prevent what happened at New College of Florida from happening in other places.</p>
<p>"The time for intervention has not passed—yet. We call on all professional organizations, unions, faculty, students, staff, administrators, and communities across the country to fight such "reforms"," it wrote. The group called academic freedom an important part of democratic societies.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for VOA Learning English based on AAUP's report and news reports and information.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pursue </strong>–<em>v</em>. to seek something that is difficult to find or catch</p>
<p><strong>academic </strong>–<em>adj</em>. related to education especially college education; something that is found in schools but not in professional life or the real world</p>
<p><strong>tenure </strong>–<em>n</em>. the right to have a job for life that exists mainly in academic jobs</p>
<p><strong>plagiarism </strong>–<em>n</em>. the charge of having copied someone's writings without their permission, outside of normal rules</p>
<p><strong>bode </strong>–v. to be a sign of the future</p>
<p><strong>standards </strong>–<em>n</em>. (pl.) a level of quality or ability that must be reached and maintained</p>
<p><strong>sanction </strong>–<em>v</em>. to speak out against something</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong>–<em>adj</em>. something that has never happened before</p>
<p><strong>quirky </strong>–<em>adj</em>. having unusual qualities that are not generally considered normal</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you worried about restrictions on academic freedom? Do you feel there is academic freedom where you live? </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Read the Riot Act  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/read-the-riot-act.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>In life, there are times when we must tell others about their bad behavior or unsafe actions. Sometimes that means giving them a strongly worded warning or <strong>scolding </strong>them. We can also <u>read them the riot act.</u></p>
<p>A riot is a violent public disorder. And that is where the expression comes from.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Students clash with riot police in front of the Greek Parliament during a demonstration against the government's plans for private universities, in Athens, Feb. 1, 2024. (Photo by Angelos TZORTZINIS / AFP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-85a7-08dc2355e3e6_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Students clash with riot police in front of the Greek Parliament during a demonstration against the government's plans for private universities, in Athens, Feb. 1, 2024. (Photo by Angelos TZORTZINIS / AFP)
</span></div>
<p>The <em>Merriam-Webster</em> online dictionary says it dates back to the early 1700s England, when opponents of King George I began a series of protests.</p>
<p>The British government wanted to stop the protests. So, they passed a law called the "Riot Act." It permitted officials to break up gatherings of 12 or more people by reading a speech out-loud. If the protestors did not leave, they would be guilty of a crime punishable by death. By 1819, "riot act" was also being used more generally for any severe warning or <strong>reprimand.</strong></p>
<p>The law is no longer enforced <strong>across the pond</strong>, as we sometimes refer to Britain. But the term <u>to read the riot act</u> is still alive and well today.</p>
<p>We read someone the riot act to severely scold them. Reading the riot act can include some shouting – and, in fact, often does.</p>
<p>We can use this expression in just about any situation where someone has made a big mistake – at work, with our friends, and with our family.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear it used between two friendly coworkers who are talking about a family situation.</p>
<p><em>A: Wow, who was that on the phone? I could hear her yelling at you all the way over here. </em></p>
<p><em>B: It was my aunt reading me the riot act. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Why? What did you do?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, I forgot to go to her house for dinner last night. And she made all my favorite dishes.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Oh. That is a big mistake. I'm not surprised she read you the riot act. </em></p>
<p><em>B: And it was her birthday.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Oh wow. I'm surprised she is still speaking to you.</em></p>
<p><em>B: I know! I feel awful! So, to make it up to her, I'm taking her out to dinner at a restaurant that serves HER favorite dishes. </em></p>
<p>If VOA Learning English stopped teaching English, our listeners would have every right to read us the riot act.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories.</em></p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scold </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to find fault noisily or angrily : to criticize severely or angrily</p>
<p><strong>reprimand </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>severe or formal criticism</p>
<p><strong>across the pond </strong><em>– idiomatic expression </em>the other side of the Atlantic Ocean</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Cyprus, Former Pilot Makes Halloumi Cheese the Old Ways  (2024/3/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/in-cyprus-former-pilot-makes-halloumi-cheese-the-old-ways.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>On a recent cold winter night in the Cypriot capital Nicosia, long lines of people began to form in a public parking area. The crowd was gathering for the arrival of cheesemaker Pantelis Panteli and the load of Halloumi he had for sale.</p>
<p>Panteli is a relative newcomer to the tradition of Halloumi-making. He had a career as a pilot with Cyprus Airways until 2013, He lost the job as the former company started closing down. Panteli decided to try a very different line of work: cheese-making. The man had found his new career.</p>
<p>But, now the newcomer has become an unlikely defender of traditional cheese-making for Cyprus's prized Halloumi.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pantelis Panteli (R) and a worker prepare halloumi on his farm in Kokkinotrimithia, Cyprus February 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Yiannis Kourtoglou)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2a0e-08dc37c92cd7_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pantelis Panteli (R) and a worker prepare halloumi on his farm in Kokkinotrimithia, Cyprus February 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Yiannis Kourtoglou)</span></div>
<p>The European Union named Halloumi a product of Protected Designation of Origin (PDO) in 2021. That means that only approved producers from Cyprus can market the cheese under that name. In exchange for the PDO, Cyprus agreed to increase the quantity of ewe or goat milk to just over 50 percent by July 2024.</p>
<p>But Cypriot farmers are protesting the agreement over a dispute about the <strong>ingredients</strong>. Industry <strong>stakeholders</strong> say ewe and goat's milk is highly seasonal, and could therefore affect production levels. Cheese makers had threatened to shut their operations because there was not enough milk. And cattle-raising farmers were angered at the threat to the milk cow market.</p>
<p>So Cyprus officials now plan to delay the agreement to 2029.</p>
<p><strong>Halloumi debate</strong></p>
<p>Soft, rubbery Halloumi can be eaten raw. There are also many ways to cook it --- over a fire or heated in liquid or oil. The cheese keeps its shape well in cooking. It is a popular food and the island's second largest export. Medicines are first.</p>
<p>But there is a dispute within Cyprus about what makes true Halloumi cheese. Should it be made from cow's milk which has a <strong>mellower</strong> taste? Or should it be made from goat and ewe milk, as traditionalists argue?</p>
<p>Panteli started making Halloumi with guidance from a family member. "It was all trial and error with a small pot, then a bigger pot - and just like Steve Jobs - in our <strong>garage</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>He uses ewe's milk to make his Halloumi. He cooks the milk in <strong>rennet</strong> which thickens the liquid to a solid form called a curdle. After resting, curdles are cut and reheated. Panteli adds salt and puts them in a solution called brine for a few hours. Then, they are done and he prepares for market.</p>
<p>Panteli only has a permit to sell directly to <strong>consumers</strong>. And he is limited to producing 150 liters of milk a day.</p>
<p>But his product is popular. He makes videos on TikTok and the social media service X to let people know where to find him. He usually sells all his cheese within two hours of opening sales.</p>
<p>"Nobody is making the real thing anymore, and that is our aim," Panteli said. He spoke to the Reuters news agency while standing near about 300 noisy sheep at his farm west of Nicosia.</p>
<p>But some farmers on the Mediterranean island say that Panteli's method is not workable for all.</p>
<p>Nicos Papakyriakou is head of the organization that represents cow farmers. He said that based on an older 1985 trade agreement, Halloumi cheese is made out of not only goat and ewes' milk but cows' milk as well.</p>
<p>He says the mellow taste of cows' milk has permitted Halloumi to capture overseas markets. "The PDO says it should smell like a farm," he said. He questioned if people would buy it if it smelled "like goats!"</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Michelle Kambas reported this story for Reuters. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ingredient</strong> - n. things that are used to make a food product</p>
<p><strong>stakeholder</strong> - n. person or business that invests money in something</p>
<p><strong>mellow</strong> - adj. having a pleasing flavor</p>
<p><strong>garage</strong> - n. part of a building in which a car is kept</p>
<p><strong>rennet</strong> - n. a substance used in cheese-making to separate milk into curdles</p>
<p><strong>consumer</strong> - n. a person who buys goods and services</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
