<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>NASA’s First Asteroid Samples Arrive on Earth  (2023/9/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/nasa-s-first-asteroid-samples-arrive-on-earth.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A <strong>capsule</strong> carrying <strong>asteroid</strong> material captured in space three years ago has arrived safely on Earth.</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA's Osiris-Rex spacecraft released the capsule Sunday during a pass by Earth. A parachute floated the capsule down to the surface as it landed in a restricted military area in the Utah desert.</p>
<p>NASA officials said the capsule arrived as planned with no observable damage. Within two hours of landing, it was already inside a temporary clean room belonging to the U.S. Defense Department.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Recovery team members carry a capsule containing NASA's first asteroid samples to a temporary clean room at Dugway Proving Ground in Utah on Sunday, Sept. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, Pool)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0e9f-08dbbdecbbbc_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Recovery team members carry a capsule containing NASA's first asteroid samples to a temporary clean room at Dugway Proving Ground in Utah on Sunday, Sept. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, Pool)</span></div>
<p>The <strong>sealed</strong> container holding the <strong>samples</strong> was being flown to NASA's Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas. It will then be closely examined in a new, specially designed laboratory.</p>
<p>Dante Lauretta, with the University of Arizona, is the project's lead scientist. He told reporters he got so emotional after the successful sample recovery that he "broke into tears." Lauretta said his team cannot wait to start examining the material. "For me, the real science is just beginning." Lauretta will stay with the samples all the way to Texas.</p>
<p>NASA's planetary science director, Lori Glaze, said she thinks the samples will be a "treasure" for scientific examination "for years and years to come."</p>
<p>Osiris-Rex began its <strong>mission</strong> in 2016. It reached Bennu, about 320 million kilometers from Earth, two years later. The spacecraft completed its asteroid sample operation in October 2020. Its robotic arm touched the asteroid Bennu for a few seconds to produce dust and rock samples for collection.</p>
<p>At the time, scientists said Osiris-Rex had captured much more asteroid material than they had expected. NASA reported in 2020 that some material had spilled out and floated away during the collection process.</p>
<p>Japan is the only other country to bring back asteroid samples from space. Those collection efforts resulted in much less material being captured. The rock and dust samples that arrived Sunday represent the largest space samples reaching Earth besides material returned by NASA in the past from the moon.</p>
<p>Engineers have estimated the capsule holds about 250 grams of material from Bennu. But it will likely take a few weeks to get an exact measurement, said NASA <strong>curator </strong>Nicole Lunning. NASA said it plans to discuss details about the captured samples next month.</p>
<p>Osiris-Rex is already on its way to another asteroid, Apophis, which it is expected to reach in 2029.</p>
<p>Scientists say the asteroid samples contain remains from the building blocks of our early solar system. Researchers say the samples' present-day chemistry and mineral makeup are mostly unchanged since forming about 4.5 billion years ago. This means the samples likely hold valuable data about the early development of rocky planets such as Earth.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>capsule </strong><em>– n. </em>the part of a spacecraft that carries people and equipment</p>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>objects made of rock and metal that orbit the sun, but are smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>seal </strong><em>– v. </em>to fully close a container so that no air or liquid can enter or escape</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>a flight by an aircraft or spacecraft to perform a specific task</p>
<p><strong>curator </strong><em>– n</em>. a person who is in charge of the things in a museum or at an organization</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What to Know about October's Solar Eclipse  (2023/9/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/what-to-know-about-october-s-solar-eclipse.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Millions of people in the Americas will be in a position to see a solar eclipse on October 14.</p>
<p>Weather permitting, viewers will be able to see the moon as it is passing in front of the sun during the eclipse. The astronomical event can be seen in parts of the United States, Mexico, and several countries in Central America and South America.</p>
<p><strong>What is an annular solar eclipse?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An annular eclipse at a waterfront park in Yokohama, near Tokyo, Monday, May 21, 2012. (AP Photo/Shuji Kajiyama)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ba53-08dbbdc4fa05_cx8_cy9_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An annular eclipse at a waterfront park in Yokohama, near Tokyo, Monday, May 21, 2012. (AP Photo/Shuji Kajiyama)</span></div>
<p>A solar eclipse happens when the moon passes between Earth and the sun. The moon blocks the view of some or all of the sun's face as it passes in front of the sun.</p>
<p>The one that will happen on October 14 is called an "annular solar eclipse." This happens when the moon passes between Earth and the sun at a time when the moon is at or close to its farthest point from our planet.</p>
<p>Because the moon is farther than usual from Earth during an annular solar eclipse, the moon will not completely cover the sun like a "total eclipse."</p>
<p>It will instead look like a dark circle on top of the sun's larger, bright face in the sky. As a result, the eclipse will momentarily look like a "<strong>ring</strong> of fire" surrounding the dark circle of the moon. A total eclipse will happen on April 8, 2024. It will pass over Mexico, the United States, and Canada.</p>
<p><strong>Where can it be seen?</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. space agency NASA says the path in the United States where the <strong>maximum</strong> amount of sun will be covered runs through several states beginning at 16:13 GMT. It will start in the state of Oregon, and then pass through California, Nevada, Utah, Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas.</p>
<p>The path then crosses over parts of Mexico, Guatemala, Belize, Honduras, Nicaragua, Panama, Colombia, and Brazil before ending at sunset in the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>People in much larger parts of North America, Central America, and South America will be able to see less of the sun covered, but it is still something to witness.</p>
<p><strong>What is the safest way to watch an eclipse?</strong></p>
<p>Experts warn that it is unsafe to look directly at the bright sun without using specialized eye protection designed for seeing the sun. Eyes can become damaged when looking at the sun without protection.</p>
<p>Because the sun is never fully blocked by the moon in an annular solar eclipse, it is never safe to look directly at it without such eye protection.</p>
<p>Viewing it through a camera, binoculars, or telescope, without making use of a special <strong>filter</strong> for the sun can cause severe eye injury, experts say.</p>
<p>They advise using safe viewing glasses for the sun or a safe handheld viewer for the sun at all times during an annular solar eclipse. They note that regular sunglasses are not safe for viewing the sun.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ring </strong>– <em>n</em>. something that is shaped like a circle</p>
<p><strong>maximum </strong>– <em>n</em>. the highest number or amount that is possible or allowed</p>
<p><strong>filter </strong><em>– n.</em> a device that prevents some kinds of light, sound, or electronic noises from passing through</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Breeding Special Mosquitoes to Fight Dengue  (2023/9/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/breeding-special-mosquitoes-to-fight-dengue.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>For many years, preventing dengue fever in Honduras has meant teaching people to avoid mosquito bites. Now, Hondurans are being taught a more effective way to control the disease — and it goes against everything they have learned.</p>
<p>Recently, a small group of people cheered as Hector Enriquez freed mosquitoes from a glass <strong>jar</strong>. Enriquez did that to bring attention to a program to suppress the viral disease dengue fever. He did so by releasing millions of special mosquitoes in the Honduran capital of Tegucigalpa.</p>
<p>Scientists <strong>bred</strong> the mosquitoes. The small insects carry bacteria called Wolbachia that stop the spread of the disease. When these mosquitoes reproduce, they pass on the bacteria and reduce future outbreaks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Lourdes Betancourt prepares a jar containing mosquito eggs to hang from a tree in her yard, in Tegucigalpa, Honduras, Aug. 23, 2023. The mosquitoes that hatch will carry bacteria called Wolbachia that interrupt the transmission of dengue. (AP Photo/Elmer Martinez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-20aa-08dbb604bc5c_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Lourdes Betancourt prepares a jar containing mosquito eggs to hang from a tree in her yard, in Tegucigalpa, Honduras, Aug. 23, 2023. The mosquitoes that hatch will carry bacteria called Wolbachia that interrupt the transmission of dengue. (AP Photo/Elmer Martinez)</span></div>
<p>The nonprofit World Mosquito Program based in Australia launched the new plan for battling dengue. And it is being tested in more than 10 countries. With more than half the world's population at risk of dengue infection, the World Health Organization is watching the mosquito releases in Honduras and other places closely in order to expand the plan worldwide.</p>
<p>In Honduras, about 10,000 people are known to be sickened by dengue each year. The health organization Doctors Without Borders is partnering with the mosquito program over the next six months to release 9 million mosquitoes carrying the Wolbachia bacteria.</p>
<p>"There is a desperate need for new approaches," said Scott O'Neill, founder of the mosquito program.</p>
<p><strong>Dengue infection rising</strong></p>
<p>Scientists have made progress in recent years to reduce the threat of infectious diseases, including diseases spread by mosquitos, like malaria. But dengue is the exception: Its rate of infection keeps going up.</p>
<p>Public health studies estimate that around 400 million people across about 130 countries get infected each year with dengue. An estimated 40,000 people die each year from it.</p>
<p>Traditional methods of preventing mosquito-<strong>borne</strong> illnesses have not been effective against dengue.</p>
<p>The Aedes aegypti mosquitoes that most commonly spread dengue are resistant to <strong>insecticides</strong>. They are most active during the day when people are not protected by bed <strong>nets</strong>. And the dengue virus is harder to control through vaccines.</p>
<p>"We need better tools," said Raman Velayudhan, a researcher from the WHO's Global Neglected Tropical Diseases Program. "Wolbachia is definitely a long-term, sustainable solution."</p>
<p>Velayudhan and other experts from the WHO plan to promote further testing of Wolbachia bacteria in other parts of the world.</p>
<p><strong>Wolbachia bacteria</strong></p>
<p>The Wolbachia bacteria exist naturally in about 60 percent of mosquitoes but not in the Aedes aegypti.</p>
<p>About 40 years ago, scientists aimed to use Wolbachia to drive down mosquito populations. Because male mosquitoes carrying the bacteria only produce <strong>offspring</strong> with females that also have it, scientists would release infected male mosquitoes into the wild to breed with uninfected females.</p>
<p>But they made a surprising discovery: Mosquitoes carrying Wolbachia did not spread dengue — or other related diseases, including yellow fever, Zika and chikungunya. And since infected females pass on Wolbachia to their offspring, they will eventually "replace" a local mosquito population with one that carries the virus-blocking bacteria.</p>
<p>This involves a change in thinking. Scientists are now replacing mosquitoes instead of killing them.</p>
<p>O'Neill's laboratory first tested the replacement plan in Australia in 2011. The World Mosquito Program has run tests affecting 11 million people across 14 countries, including Brazil, Mexico, Colombia, Fiji and Vietnam.</p>
<p>In 2019, a large field test in Indonesia showed a 76 percent drop in reported dengue cases after Wolbachia-infected mosquitoes were released.</p>
<p>Scientists are still not sure how Wolbachia bacteria blocks the spread of the virus. And it is not clear whether the bacteria will work equally well against all versions, or strains, of the virus. It also is not clear if some strains might become resistant over time.</p>
<p>Bobby Reiner is a mosquito researcher at the University of Washington. He said, "It's certainly not a <strong>one-and-done</strong> fix, forever guaranteed."</p>
<p><strong>Raising Wolbachia-infected mosquitoes</strong></p>
<p>The World Mosquito Program breeds 30 million mosquitoes a week at a factory in Medellín, Colombia. Once workers confirm that the new mosquitoes are infected with Wolbachia, their eggs are dried and sent off to test areas for release.</p>
<p>The Doctors Without Borders team in Honduras recently went around Tegucigalpa to enlist local help in <strong>incubating</strong> mosquito eggs bred in the Medellin factory.</p>
<p>They received permission to hang glass jars from tree branches that contained water and mosquito eggs. After about 10 days, the mosquitoes would <strong>hatch </strong>and fly off. That same day, workers from Doctors Without Borders released thousands of dengue-fighting mosquitoes into the air.</p>
<p>Some of the most common questions from the community were about whether Wolbachia would harm people or the environment. Workers said that the bites from the special mosquitoes were harmless.</p>
<p>María Fernanda Marín is a 19-year-old student working for Doctors Without Borders. She showed neighbors a photo of her arm covered in bites to help earn their trust.</p>
<p>Lourdes Betancourt is a 63-year-old volunteer with the Doctors Without Borders team. She had been sickened by dengue several times and was not sure about the new plan at first. But Betancourt now urges her neighbors to let the "good mosquitoes" grow in their yards.</p>
<p>"I tell people not to be afraid, that this isn't anything bad, to have trust," Betancourt said. "They are going to bite you, but you won't get dengue."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Maria Verza and Maddie Burakoff reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>jar</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a glass container that usually comes with a screw on top</p>
<p><strong>breed</strong> <em>–v.</em> to raise and keep animals or plants to produce more of the same kind</p>
<p><strong>borne </strong><em>–adj.</em> carried by or spread by</p>
<p><strong>insecticide </strong><em>–n</em>. a chemical poison used to kill insects</p>
<p><strong>bed net </strong><em>–n.</em> a material that is woven to let air through but to keep things like insects out</p>
<p><strong>offspring </strong><em>–n.</em> the young of a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>one-and-done </strong><em>–adj. (informal)</em> done once and not again</p>
<p><strong>incubate </strong><em>–v.</em> to keep eggs or very young living things in a condition that is good for growth and development</p>
<p><strong>hatch <em>–</em></strong><em>v.</em> to be born from an egg</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Striking Writers Announce Deal with Hollywood Producers  (2023/9/26) | 美国编剧协会宣布与好莱坞制作人达成协议</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/striking-writers-announce-deal-with-hollywood-producers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The Writers Guild of America (WGA) said Sunday that it had reached an agreement with Hollywood movie and television studios. The announcement signaled that the group's five-month strike is nearing an end.<br/>
美国编剧协会周日表示，已与好莱坞影视工作室达成协议。这标志着该组织为期五个月的罢工行将结束。</p>
<p>The WGA is the labor group that represents writers in the United States who work on many movies and television programs.<br/>
美国编剧协会是一家劳工组织，它代表着美国从事诸多影视节目的编剧。</p>
<p>The writers' group said its members will not yet return to work, but they will no longer protest – or picket – outside movie studios.<br/>
该编剧团体表示，其成员尚未返回工作岗位，但他们将不再在电影制片厂外抗议。</p>
<p>The WGA said it reached an agreement with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television producers for a tentative three-year deal. It is called "tentative," which means not certain, because it must still be approved by the WGA's leaders and members. A vote could happen this week.<br/>
美国编剧协会表示，它与电影电视制片人联盟达成了一项为期三年的暂定协议。它被称为“暂定”，意思是不确定，因为它仍然必须得到美国编剧协会领导人和成员的批准。投票可能在本周进行。</p>
<p>The WGA said its labor stoppage lasted more than 140 days. If it had gone five days longer, the strike would have been the longest in WGA history.<br/>
美国编剧协会表示，其停工持续了140多天。如果罢工时间再延长五天，这次罢工将是美国编剧协会历史上持续时间最长的一次。</p>
<p>When the new contract is approved, programs that depend on writers who have not been working could be back on television within days. Those include nightly comedy programs such as The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon and Jimmy Kimmel Live!.<br/>
当新合同获得批准后，那些依赖于罢工编剧的节目可能会在几天内重回屏幕。其中包括每晚的喜剧节目，如吉米·法伦和吉米·金梅尔的《今夜秀》！。</p>
<p>The news made some media experts think the actors' group – known as SAG-AFTRA – could be close to ending its strike.<br/>
这一消息让一些媒体专家认为，美国电影电视演员工会可能即将结束罢工。</p>
<p>SAG-AFTRA congratulated the WGA on reaching its agreement. It used words such as "strength, resiliency and solidarity" to describe the writers' group's decision to hold out for a good deal.<br/>
美国电影电视演员工会祝贺美国编剧协会达成协议。它用“力量、韧性和团结”等词来形容编剧团体坚持要求达成协议的决定。</p>
<p>SAG-AFTRA added, "We remain committed to achieving the necessary terms for our members." It also said it wants the studio leaders to "return to the table and make a fair deal that our members deserve and demand."<br/>
美国电影电视演员工会补充道，“我们仍然致力于为我们的会员达成必要条款。”它还表示，希望好莱坞影视工作室领导人“回到谈判桌上，做出我们会员应得和要求的公平交易。”</p>
<p>The writers and studio heads made their agreement without intervention from government officials. That has happened in the past.<br/>
编剧和好莱坞影视工作室负责人在没有政府官员干预的情况下达成了协议。这种情况过去也曾发生过。</p>
<p>State and local government leaders congratulated the two groups on their new plan. California Governor Gavin Newsom said he was "grateful the two sides have come together."<br/>
州和地方政府领导人对这两个团体的新计划表示祝贺。加州州长加文·纽瑟姆表示，他“很感激双方走到了一起。”</p>
<p>One of the main issues that caused the strike was how writers are paid by streaming video services such as Netflix. Another issue was the use of artificial intelligence technology in the creation of scripts. The strike stopped production on a number of daily television programs and delayed upcoming television shows and movies that had been planned for production.<br/>
导致罢工的主要问题之一是作家如何通过Netflix等流媒体视频服务获得报酬。另一个问题是在脚本创作时使用人工智能技术。这场罢工停止了一些日常电视节目的制作，并推迟了原本计划制作的即将播出的电视节目和电影。</p>
<p>The writers started their strike on May 2. Film and television actors stopped working on July 14. The two groups had not gone on strike at the same time since 1960.<br/>
编剧们于5月2日开始罢工。电影和电视演员于7月14日停止工作。自1960年以来，这两个团体从未同时举行过罢工。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Drug Could Block Bone Loss in Astronauts in Space  (2023/9/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/study-drug-could-block-bone-loss-in-astronauts-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say a new drug compound has been found to prevent bone loss in humans visiting space.</p>
<p>The drug was tested on mice on the International Space Station (ISS). A new study reports the compound was engineered to help increase the formation of new bone material.</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA has long studied the effects of space travel on human health. Astronauts who have spent long periods in space <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-long-periods-in-space-can-shrink-the-heart/5838247.html" target="_blank">have taken part in major studies</a> that looked at their health before, during and after their trips, or missions.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by NASA shows astronaut Frank Rubio floating inside the cupola, the International Space Station's " ap="" for="" holds="" longest="" now="" record="" rubio="" spaceflight.="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-d6c6-08dbbb7820b6_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg" the="" to="" u.s.="" via="" window="" world.=""/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by NASA shows astronaut Frank Rubio floating inside the cupola, the International Space Station's "window to the world." Rubio now holds the record for the longest U.S. spaceflight. (NASA via AP)</span></div>
<p>NASA announced that American astronaut <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/station/research/news/frank-rubio-year-in-space" target="_blank">Frank Rubio</a> recently set the agency's record for the longest single spaceflight by a U.S. astronaut. Rubio, who is set to return to Earth on September 27, has spent 371 days in space. NASA astronaut Mark Vande Hei set the earlier record in March of 2022 after living in space for 355 days.</p>
<p>Some of the main health problems for humans are related to the gravitational conditions in space. Past studies have shown the low gravity environments in space can greatly reduce or stop the formation of new bone material.</p>
<p>NASA has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/station/research/news/b4h-3rd/hh-preventing-bone-loss-in-space">estimated</a> that astronauts spending more than six months in space can lose between six and 10 percent of bone matter. Some experiments in astronauts measured changes in their upper leg. Development of new bone can take at least three or four years after astronauts return to Earth, NASA says.</p>
<p>The conditions astronauts experience in space can result in bone loss up to 10 times more than is seen in human patients dealing with the bone loss disease osteoporosis, NASA notes.</p>
<p>Currently, physical exercise is the main method astronauts use to reduce bone loss during long periods in space. Generally, crew members aboard the ISS spend about 2.5 hours each day exercising in an effort to reduce the gravitational effects of space.</p>
<p>Past research on the subject has suggested a group of drugs widely used to treat osteoporosis, called bisphosphonates, have shown promise in Earth-based experiments on bone loss. That research continues.</p>
<p>But the new study shows success combining a bisphosphonate with another substance that has shown promise in helping to regrow bone material. That substance is called NELL-1. It was discovered by scientist Kang Ting at the Massachusetts-based Forsyth Institute.</p>
<p>The study was led by a team from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uclahealth.org/news/engineered-compound-shows-promise-preventing-bone-loss-space">In a statement</a>, the research team said the resulting compound, a molecule called BP-NELL-PEG, was given to mice aboard the ISS to test its effectiveness.</p>
<p>The experiments were carried out by astronauts who arrived on the ISS in June 2017. Half the mice remained on the ISS for nine weeks, while the rest were flown back to Earth four-and-a-half weeks after launch. Both sets of mice were given either BP-NELL-PEG or a salt solution containing no medicine.</p>
<p>The researchers reported both sets of mice who were given the BP-NELL-PEG compound showed "a <strong>significant </strong>increase in bone formation" during the experiment period. The team added that neither the mice treated on Earth nor those that received the drug in space experienced any observable side effects.</p>
<p>Chia Soo is with UCLA's School of Medicine and helped lead the research. She said the findings hold great promise for, in her words, "the future of space exploration, particularly for missions involving extended stays in microgravity."</p>
<p>Another member of the team was former UCLA engineering professor Benjamin Wu. He noted that the study could open the door to the same compound being used to treat patients with extreme osteoporosis and other bone-related conditions on Earth.</p>
<p>The scientists are still examining data on the live mice who returned to Earth halfway through the experiment. Researcher Soo said they hope the data "will provide some <strong>insight</strong> on how to help future astronauts recover from longer... space missions."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>significant</strong> – adj. important or noticeable</p>
<p><strong>insight</strong> – n. the ability to understand what something is really like</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australia Puts Water Quality Sensors in Great Barrier Reef  (2023/9/25) | 澳大利亚在大堡礁安装水质传感器</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/australia-puts-water-quality-sensors-in-great-barrier-reef.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Australia's government has placed sensors in parts of the Great Barrier Reef in an effort to record water quality.<br/>
澳大利亚政府在大堡礁部分区域安装了传感器以记录水质。</p>
<p>The Great Barrier Reef covers about 344,000 square kilometers of area off Australia's northeast coast. It contains hundreds of islands and thousands of natural structures, known as reefs.<br/>
大堡礁位于澳大利亚东北海岸，面积约344000平方公里。它包含数百个岛屿和数千个珊瑚礁。</p>
<p>The sensors measure levels of sediment and carbon materials flowing from the Fitzroy River into Keppel Bay in Queensland state. The area sits within the southern part of the Great Barrier Reef. Such substances can damage sea life.<br/>
这些传感器负责测量从菲茨罗伊河流入昆士兰州吉宝湾的沉积物和碳物质的水平。该地区位于大堡礁的南部。上述物质会破坏海洋生物。</p>
<p>The Australian government agency Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organization (CSIRO) operates the program. The agency says the effort uses the sensors and satellite data to measure changes in water quality.<br/>
澳大利亚政府机构联邦科学与工业研究组织负责该项目。该机构表示，这项工作利用传感器和卫星数据来测量水质的变化。</p>
<p>Experts say the quality of Australia's coastal and inland waterways is being threatened by warming temperatures, urbanization, deforestation and pollution.<br/>
专家表示，澳大利亚沿海和内陆水道的水质正受到气温升高、城市化、森林砍伐和污染的威胁。</p>
<p>The reef is one of seven test areas of CSIRO's AquaWatch Australia Mission. The research team hopes to establish 15 testing areas by 2026.<br/>
大堡礁是澳大利亚联邦科学与工业研究组织水质监测任务的七个试验区之一。研究小组希望在2026年前建立15个试验区。</p>
<p>Alex Held leads the program. He told VOA that sediments can be harmful to ocean life because they can block sunlight from the seafloor. The lack of sunlight can hurt the growth of sea plants and other organisms. Sediments can also settle on the tops of coral reefs, affecting sea life there as well.<br/>
亚历克斯·赫尔德领导该项目。他告诉美国之音，沉积物可能对海洋生物有害，因为它们会阻挡海底的阳光。缺乏阳光会损害海洋植物和其他生物的生长。沉积物也会沉积在珊瑚礁顶部，影响那里的海洋生物。</p>
<p>Held said the sensors and satellites will be used to measure the effectiveness of programs meant to reduce the flow, or runoff, of river sediment into the sea.<br/>
赫尔德表示，这些传感器和卫星将用于衡量旨在减少河流沉积物流入大海流量项目的有效性。</p>
<p>Held noted that the Australian government already operates a series of programs aimed at reducing the effects of sediments on sea life. These include efforts to keep plants growing along riverbeds and other bodies of water to help keep sediments out.<br/>
赫尔德指出，澳大利亚政府已经实施了一系列旨在减少沉积物对海洋生物影响的计划。这些措施包括努力让植物沿着河床和其他水体生长，以帮助阻挡沉积物。</p>
<p>Environmentalists have warned that the Great Barrier Reef faces a number of threats. These include climate change, pollution and runoff of agricultural products. The reef – which runs about 2,300 kilometers – has been on the United Nations World Heritage List since 1981.<br/>
环保人士警告说，大堡礁面临许多威胁。其中包括气候变化、污染和农产品径流。该珊瑚礁全长约2300公里，自1981年以来一直被列入联合国世界遗产名录。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Easy Houseplants for Forgetful Caregivers  (2023/9/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/easy-houseplants-for-forgetful-caregivers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Jessica Damiano is an expert at taking care of plants. She writes stories about how to keep plants in good condition for The Associated Press. But even she has killed houseplants.</p>
<p>Damiano said she has killed plants like a Monstera, a snake plant, an African violet and more orchids than she would like to admit.</p>
<p>She said it is not that she does not know how to take care of these houseplants, she just <strong>neglected</strong> them. She added that the plants are among the hardest to keep alive.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Sept. 18, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a low-maintenance Aloe vera plant in Syosset, NY. (Jessica Damiano via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/45abac40-6ae5-41a1-8449-55f4ffbdd0a7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This Sept. 18, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a low-maintenance Aloe vera plant in Syosset, NY. (Jessica Damiano via AP)</span></div>
<p>As a result, Damiano chooses houseplants that need the least amount of care for her home. She looks for plants that deal well with too little water, that grow well with limited light, and can be moved around. Also, these sorts of houseplants are best for beginners to grow.</p>
<p>Damiano's spider plant needs only two things: moderate to bright sunlight and <strong>moist</strong> soil. She said she keeps it by a window, and she pours in whatever water she has left over from the night. Some days, she does not water the plant. And the spider plant creates many plants for replanting, even with one or two fertilizer treatments a year.</p>
<p>Another plant, a pothos, is perfectly happy nowhere near a window. It gets the light it needs from a kind of light <strong>bulb </strong>called an LED. She gives the plant a good amount of water each time the soil completely dries out. She said the plant is doing well, with leaves growing halfway to the floor.</p>
<p>Chinese evergreen is a beautiful houseplant that does well in low-light conditions. Damiano said all you need to do is keep the plant's soil lightly moist at all times and fertilize every other month over the winter and every month for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Catching Z's means to sleep. And the ZZ plant, Zamioculcas zamiifolia, requires so little care that you can almost sleep while taking care of it, Damiano said. It does not like a lot of water or bright light. Make sure the soil <strong>drains</strong> well. The plant actually does best in low-light conditions.</p>
<p>The cast iron plant is about as resistant as its name sounds. Damiano said it does not even want your attention. Avoid providing too much sunlight. It prefers electric light or light from a north-facing window. Permit the soil to dry out between waterings and fertilize every other month in summer and autumn and just once during the winter.</p>
<p>One houseplant, the aloe plant, can be used for treating burns. When needed, just cut open a leaf and use the watery <strong>gel</strong> from within on an injury. That liquid not only protects burned skin, but also the plant, reducing its dependency on you. Just place it by a window that provides bright, indirect sunlight and water every three weeks, and less often during winter.</p>
<p>Similar plants called succulents share aloe's ability to store water within their leaves. These sorts of plants usually do well inside where conditions are dry and warm. Most also share aloe's lack of requirements, making them a good fit for new, or neglectful, plant parents.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>neglect </strong>– <em>v</em>. to fail to take care of or to give attention to (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>moist </strong>– <em>adj</em>. slightly or barely wet: not completely dry</p>
<p><strong>bulb </strong>– <em>n</em>. a glass tube that produces light when it is supplied with electricity</p>
<p><strong>drain </strong><em>– v.</em> to remove (liquid) from something by letting it flow away or out</p>
<p><strong>gel </strong><em>– n.</em> a thick substance that is like jelly and that is used in various products</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Rural Hospitals in the US Are Closing Maternity Centers  (2023/9/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/why-rural-hospitals-in-the-us-are-closing-maternity-centers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Alisha Alderson is a 45-year-old woman from rural eastern Oregon. In August, she was pregnant and just a few weeks from having her baby.</p>
<p>But that month, the only hospital <strong>maternity</strong> center near to her closed. She decided to stay with her brother in the city of Boise, Idaho to be close to a hospital.</p>
<p>In the United States, many rural hospitals have been closing <strong>maternity</strong> centers. The centers are areas of the hospital used only for mothers to give birth to their babies.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Katie O'Brien holds her son, Bennett, on Tuesday, Aug. 29, 2023, in the birthing room where she delivered him in July at the Henry County Medical Center in Paris, Tenn. (AP Photo/Mark Humphrey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d398de0d-13e0-4d6c-aba4-efe3d10895a5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Katie O'Brien holds her son, Bennett, on Tuesday, Aug. 29, 2023, in the birthing room where she delivered him in July at the Henry County Medical Center in Paris, Tenn. (AP Photo/Mark Humphrey)</span></div>
<p>Fewer than half of rural hospitals are now believed to have maternity units. That means pregnant women might have to travel long distances to have their babies under hospital supervision in specialized centers.</p>
<p>The <em>Associated Press </em>(<em>AP</em>) reports that birth centers are now increasing in the U.S. A midwife is a person who is trained to help women give birth but who is not a doctor. These centers however still need a hospital nearby in case of serious problems.</p>
<p>More than 2 million women of childbearing age live in places that some observers call "maternity care deserts." These are mainly rural areas that do not have hospitals with specialized maternity centers or obstetricians. An obstetrician is a doctor who specializes in the health of pregnant women.</p>
<p>Some doctors and researchers say that having fewer maternity units makes having babies less safe. A 2019 study of information from 2007 to 2015 said that rural <strong>residents</strong> have a nine percent greater chance of facing life-threatening problems or death from pregnancy and birth "compared with urban residents."</p>
<p>Dr. Eric Scott Palmer specializes in helping babies born early and newborns with high-risk <strong>complications</strong>. He used to serve as a doctor at Henry County Medical Center in rural Tennessee before the hospital ended obstetric care in September 2023.</p>
<p>He said, "Moms have complications everywhere. Babies have complications everywhere."</p>
<p><strong>Reasons for closures</strong></p>
<p>Peiyin Hung is with the University of South Carolina's Rural and Minority Health Research Center. She said that there are several reasons why maternity units are closing.</p>
<p>Hung said there has been a decrease in the number of births in the United States. There are few workers in hospitals. And there are other reasons. For example, health care providers say government health <strong>insurance</strong> for the poor, called Medicaid, does not pay them enough for their services.</p>
<p>The chief of Henry County Medical Center in Paris, Tennessee, John Tucker, said that closing the obstetrics, or OB, unit of the hospital was necessary to save the hospital itself.</p>
<p>Tucker said that 70 percent of the births there were covered by Medicaid. That number is above the national average of 42 percent. Tennessee's Medicaid program only pays the hospital $1,700 for each baby born.</p>
<p>Private insurance usually pays more. In the state of Oregon in 2021, the <strong>median</strong> payment to hospitals for a <strong>cesarean section</strong>, or C-section, was $16,000. That is five times more than what Medicaid would provide for the same operation.</p>
<p>Tucker also said there were problems with having the right number of workers. He said when there are fewer births, hospitals lose money because their costs are fixed. "Whether we've got one baby on the floor or three, we still <strong>staff</strong> at the same level because you...have to be prepared for whatever comes in."</p>
<p><strong>A solution for some</strong></p>
<p>Corina Fitch is a midwife at The Farm Midwifery Center in Summertown, Tennessee. It is an independent center where pregnant women can receive maternity care. Fitch measures women's stomachs, takes their blood, listens to fetal heartbeats, and gives nutritional information.</p>
<p>These kinds of centers could be an answer to the lack of maternity care choices in rural areas. Many states are now taking steps to support more independent birth centers. In Connecticut, Governor Ned Lamont signed a law that will <strong>license</strong> these centers letting them provide care for low-risk pregnancies.</p>
<p>A 2020 report from the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine said there is a lack of data about independent birth centers. It said researchers do not fully understand the relationship between birth settings and maternal death or complications. That is partly because there are a small number of births at independent centers.</p>
<p>The Farm Midwifery Center reported that fewer than two percent of women decided to get a C-section. Five percent of patients were transported to hospitals in the center's first 40 years. Usually, women give birth at the center or at their homes.</p>
<p>Fitch said, "We always have a backup plan because we know birth is unpredictable and things can come up."</p>
<p>Some doctors told the <em>AP</em> that rural hospitals still need to be part of any answer. They think that state governments need to do more.</p>
<p>This June in Oregon, Baker City hospital announced that it was going to close its maternity center. Oregon politicians got involved.</p>
<p>They suggested temporarily using obstetric nurses from the US Public Health Service Commissioned Corps. The Corps is a group of military health care workers within the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. The group usually helps with natural disasters and disease outbreaks.</p>
<p>However, that did not happen. The public health service sent officials who advised establishing an independent birth center among other things.</p>
<p>Alisha Alderson — the woman who had to go to Idaho for pregnancy care — is married to Shane Alderson. He said that rural communities should not have limited health care because of their size or because of the number of people on Medicaid.</p>
<p>Alderson said, "That's not equitable. People can't survive like that."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Claire Rush and Laura Ungar reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>maternity </strong><em>— n. </em>relating to the time when a woman gives birth to a baby</p>
<p><strong>resident </strong>–n. a person who lives in a place, is not a visitor and legally calls the place their home</p>
<p><strong>complication</strong> - n. a problem that makes a disease or condition more dangerous or harder to treat</p>
<p><strong>insurance </strong>–n. the agreement called a policy in which the policy holder pays a company regularly so that the company will cover most of the cost of a large health, or other, expense</p>
<p><strong>income</strong> – <em>n</em>. money that is earned from work, investments, business, etc.</p>
<p><strong>median </strong>–n. the middle value in a group of numbers</p>
<p><strong>cesarean section </strong>- n. a surgical operation for giving birth in which a cut is made in the mother's body in order to deliver the baby (also called C-section)</p>
<p><strong>staff </strong>–n. a group of people who work for an organization or business</p>
<p><strong>license </strong><em>– v. </em>to give someone official permission to do or have something</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. </em></p>
<p><em>Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html" target="_blank" title="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Programs Aim to Increase Number of Black Doctors  (2023/9/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/programs-aim-to-increase-number-of-black-doctors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 September 2023</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">The American Medical Association (AMA) recently said the U.S. Supreme Court's ruling on affirmative action dealt a "serious blow" to the medical field's goal of increasing the number of Black doctors.</p>
<p>Affirmative action describes the idea that it is good for society to favor people who come from groups thought to have been discriminated against in the past.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the nation's high court ruled it is unlawful for colleges and universities to consider race in choosing students.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Dr. Starling Tolliver, a dermatology resident at Wayne State University, works at Wayne Health in Dearborn, Michigan, on Tuesday, August 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ba325e7e-2b9d-438c-90d7-34cbd4accccc_cx15_cy1_cw84_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Dr. Starling Tolliver, a dermatology resident at Wayne State University, works at Wayne Health in Dearborn, Michigan, on Tuesday, August 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)</span></div>
<p>Because the Supreme Court's decision includes medical schools, the AMA said the ruling will hurt "gains made in the battle against health <strong>inequities</strong>.</p>
<p>Many medical schools used affirmative action ideas to increase the number of Black students. But even with those efforts, a University of California at Los Angeles study in 2021 said the percentage of Black doctors had only increased by four percent from 1900 to 2018.</p>
<p>Experts believe increasing the number of Black doctors could help Black people's health. Right now, only six percent of physicians in the U.S. are Black but 13 percent of the population is Black.</p>
<p><strong>'A crisis of humanity'</strong></p>
<p>A series of reports by the <em>Associated Press</em> (<em>AP</em>) said that Black people do not get taken care of as well as white people starting at birth. The <em>AP </em>reported that patients said doctors ignored or brushed aside their concerns partly because of <strong>bias</strong> and racism within the U.S. medical system.</p>
<p>Uché Blackstock is an emergency doctor in New York City. He wrote a book called <em>Legacy: A Black Physician Reckons with Racism in Medicine</em>.</p>
<p>He called the low number of Black doctors "a crisis of humanity."</p>
<p>Starling Tolliver is a 30-year-old Black doctor trying to influence people's opinions. She is in her final year of residency – or training – in dermatology. A dermatologist is a doctor who specializes in diseases of the skin. She is training at Wayne State University in Detroit, Michigan.</p>
<p>As a girl growing up in the Midwestern city of Akron, Ohio, she felt like her dream of being a doctor was out of reach. She did not often see doctors who looked like her when she went for treatments for a condition that caused her to lose her hair.</p>
<p>She stayed with her goal of becoming a doctor because she made an agreement with two friends. When they were young, they all said they wanted to be doctors, so they could help other Black people.</p>
<p>One of the friends, Charmaine, became a nurse and one, Maria, died as a teenager. Tolliver said Maria's death made her work harder.</p>
<p>"I'm going to continue to go on this path of medicine," Tolliver said. "Not only for myself, but for Maria, and to <strong>potentially</strong> help others in the future from similar backgrounds..."</p>
<p><strong>Minorities less likely to seek care for skin problems</strong></p>
<p>Tolliver's plan of being a skin doctor might be a good way to help Black people. The Association of American Medical Colleges says just 65 of almost 800 applicants for residencies in dermatology were Black in 2020. But many Blacks do not go to dermatologists for treatment.</p>
<p>The AP reports that minority patients are half as likely to see dermatologists when compared to white patients. Also, more Black men die from skin cancer compared to men of other races. That information came from a study published earlier this year in the <em>Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</em>.</p>
<p>Dr. Ashley Wysong was one of the writers. She said 75 percent of white men survive skin cancer but only 52 percent of Black men do.</p>
<p>She said if there is a difference in results for patients being treated for the same problem, "we have to look at ways that we are falling short."</p>
<p><strong>Efforts to support minorities in dermatology</strong></p>
<p>Some education experts say ending affirmative action might increase interest in medical schools at HBCUs, or historically black colleges and universities. Morehouse College, in Atlanta, receives over 7,000 medical school applications each year for only 115 openings. The medical school's president and CEO is Dr. Valerie Montgomery Rice. She said she expects the number of <strong>applicants</strong> to rise at Morehouse and other HBCU medical schools.</p>
<p>Tolliver, the dermatology resident, said financial aid programs that target minority students who are interested in becoming doctors are important. The American Academy of Dermatology has a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.aad.org/member/career/diversity/diversity-pathways">program</a> called Pathways. Its goal is to increase the number of minority dermatology residents from 100 in 2022 to 250 by 2027. The program aims to help young people who are interested in medicine and guide them into dermatology.</p>
<p>It targets high school students and supports them as they go to college and medical school. Some receive financial aid.</p>
<p>Tolliver received financial aid from Ohio State University for her studies, but she also believes Pathways was important for her later training.</p>
<p><strong>Financial aid and mentoring</strong></p>
<p>Azariah Providence is a 17-year-old high school student who lives in the U.S. Virgin Islands. She hopes to be a dermatologist one day. She joined the Pathways program last month. She wants to be a skin doctor so she can help other girls who have skin problems like she did.</p>
<p>She said she never had a chance to talk with and learn from minority college students and doctors before. Providence said it is important for Black people to learn to care for skin because some problems appear differently on Black skin than white skin.</p>
<p>She hopes more people who look like her can get "a correct <strong>diagnosis</strong>...and the correct treatment," from dermatologists.</p>
<p>Adam Friedman is a dermatologist and the leader of the department at George Washington School of Medicine in Washington, D.C. He said updating textbooks is important, but programs such as Pathways are very important.</p>
<p>As Tolliver finishes her training, she said she hopes she can push dermatologists to seek better outcomes – especially for Black women. She said her goal since childhood has been "for Black women to see the beauty of themselves, within themselves."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>inequities </strong><em>–n.</em> unfair or unequal things</p>
<p><strong>bias </strong>–n. to lean to one side; to not be balanced but, instead, to show only one side</p>
<p><strong>potentially </strong>–adv. something that could be or has the possibility of becoming real</p>
<p><strong>applicant </strong>–n. a person who is seeking entry into a school or trying to get a job; anyone who applies to get something</p>
<p><strong>diagnosis </strong>–n. the act or process of finding out what disease, illness, sickness or other problem affects a patient</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>No Need to 'Gild the Lily'  (2023/9/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/no-need-to-gild-the-lily.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Now it's time for <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give examples and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Before we talk about today's idiom, let's talk about words that you will need to know – gilt and gild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A lily is seen on display at the Chelsea Flower Show in London, Britain, May 23, 2016. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/09320000-0a00-0242-0869-08db0a0935ba_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A lily is seen on display at the Chelsea Flower Show in London, Britain, May 23, 2016. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)</span></div>
<p>"Gilt" as a noun is the gold, or something that looks like gold, laid on a surface. It can also be an adjective. "Gild" is a verb. It means to cover with a fine layer of gilt. Sometimes we add gilt to a plain material like wood to make it look better. In fact, entire buildings can be gilded to make them more pleasing to the eye.</p>
<p>Word experts say American writer Mark Twain created the term "Gilded Age." In the 1873 novel, <em>The Gilded Age: A Tale of Today</em>,<em> </em>he and co-writer Charles Dudley Warner made fun of newly rich people. They discussed how these people would cover wood and other objects with a thin <strong>layer</strong> of gold to make them look more costly.</p>
<p>So, when you gild something you could be trying to cover up something <strong>ugly</strong>. But sometimes we may try to improve something that cannot be improved. It is already wonderful just the way it is. And our attempts to make it better can make it worse.</p>
<p>Take for example, a lily. Lilies are beautiful flowers. Like many beautiful things in nature, they do not need any additions to make them more beautiful.</p>
<p>And that brings us to the idiom <u>gild the lily</u>.</p>
<p>If I "gild the lily," I add some unnecessary <strong>decoration </strong>to something already beautiful. The thing I add is <strong>superfluous</strong>. It is not needed.</p>
<p>Imagine if someone added a really bright shiny gold frame to the Mona Lisa painting. The frame is so bright that it is hard to see the smile on the famous woman. That would be <u>gilding the lily</u>.</p>
<p>However, we use this expression to talk about anything, not just artwork or objects. We gild the lily anytime we try to improve something that is already excellent.</p>
<p>For example, my friend has good bone structure and lovely skin. She's just gilding the lily when she wears makeup.</p>
<p>Here is another example. Once I went to a beautiful garden. It had flowers of every height and color. It had a fish pond and was completely lined with beautiful trees and bushes. The garden was beautiful and peaceful. It was perfect. And then the owners built a tall structure in the middle of it. The structure was made almost of entirely of <strong>stained glass</strong>, like church windows. And while it was beautiful, it was truly gilding the lily. When the sun shone through it, you could not see one flower.</p>
<p>Here are some expressions that are similar: To go overboard, to overdo it, or to get carried away. Listen to this example.</p>
<p><em>A: I got carried away with the decorations on the birthday cake. </em></p>
<p><em>B: Yeah, you really went overboard with the <strong>sprinkles</strong>. The cake was so pretty and now I can't even see it!</em></p>
<p>Experts on the website Meriam Webster explain where the expression came from. The website says that "gild the lily" comes from Shakespeare. But the expression has changed over the years. In his play <em>The Life and Death of King John</em> the line is actually "to paint the lily."</p>
<p>Here is the shortened form from that play -- Act 4, Scene 2: "To gild refined gold, to paint the lily / To throw a <strong>perfume</strong> on the violet.... / Is wasteful and <strong>ridiculous</strong> <strong>excess</strong>."</p>
<p>These days we just say "gild the lily."</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>layer</strong> <em>– n.</em> one thickness or fold over or under another</p>
<p><strong>ugly </strong><em>– adj. </em>horrid or unpleasant especially to the sight</p>
<p><strong>decoration </strong><em>– n. </em>something that decorates or beautifies</p>
<p><strong>superfluous </strong><em>– adj. </em>going beyond what is enough or necessary</p>
<p><strong>stained glass </strong><em>– n. </em>glass colored or stained (as by fusing metallic oxides into it) for decorative applications (as in windows)</p>
<p><strong>sprinkles </strong><em>– n. </em>small particles of candy used as a topping</p>
<p><strong>perfume</strong> <em>– n. </em>the scent of something sweet-smelling</p>
<p><strong>ridiculous</strong> <em>– adj. </em>extremely silly or unreasonable</p>
<p><strong>excess </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount beyond what is usual, needed, or asked</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Herbert Hoover: Blamed  (2023/9/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-herbert-hoover.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Herbert Hoover. He took office in 1929.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Herbert Hoover" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1b6d12d8-ba04-4363-b77e-28046d51100f_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Herbert Hoover</span></div>
<p>Hoover was president for the early years of what Americans call the Great Depression. During those years, the United States economy slid into a severe recession.</p>
<p>Many banks and businesses failed. At times, nearly one in four people in the U.S. workforce were unemployed. Millions of people lost their homes and savings.</p>
<p>Hoover did not cause the depression. The conditions had been in place before he took office.</p>
<p>But many Americans blamed Hoover for their suffering. They believed he permitted the economic crisis to continue – and even deepen – during his time in office.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Herbert Hoover was born in a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nps.gov/heho/index.htm">small house</a> in the state of Iowa. His parents were Quakers. Their religion valued simplicity, hard work, equality among people, and peaceful resolution of conflict.</p>
<p>Hoover and his brother and sister were influenced by these beliefs, even after their parents died.</p>
<p>By the time young Herbert Hoover was nine, he was an <strong>orphan</strong>. He moved to the state of Oregon, in the Pacific Northwest, and lived with an uncle.</p>
<p>Hoover did not <strong>thrive</strong> in that situation. Reports say that he usually kept to himself. And he did not do particularly well in school.</p>
<p>Yet one official from Stanford University liked what he saw in the young man – hard work and a desire to learn new things. At the time, Stanford University was just getting established. It admitted Hoover into its first class.</p>
<p>Hoover had to work hard at Stanford, both in class and to earn money to pay tuition. But the experience brought many <strong>benefits</strong>.</p>
<p>Hoover studied geology, and went on to work as a mining engineer. The job led to positions in Australia, China and other parts of the world. He became an internationally-known expert on mining. He also wrote a leading textbook on mining.</p>
<p>These experiences, along with good business investments, led to great wealth for Hoover.</p>
<p>At Stanford, he also met the woman who would become his wife. Her name was Lou Henry. She was the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://125.stanford.edu/early-stanford-women/">first woman from Stanford</a> to complete a study program with a degree in geology.</p>
<p>The Hoovers went on to have two sons.</p>
<p><strong>Humanitarian work</strong></p>
<p>During World War I, the Hoovers' lives changed dramatically. The family was living in London when the war began. U.S. government officials asked Hoover to organize an evacuation effort for American tourists who were in Europe. In only a few weeks, Hoover's committee succeeded.</p>
<p>Later, he helped get food and supplies to people in Belgium.</p>
<p>As a result, Hoover earned a public image as a smart, skilled humanitarian.</p>
<p>When the United States entered World War I, President Woodrow Wilson asked Hoover to lead the government's Food Administration.</p>
<p>In that position, Hoover led an effort to change Americans' behavior in order to support the war effort. He asked them to limit the kinds of food they ate and goods they bought.</p>
<p>The effort was, for the most part, successful. Americans called their moves to limit their <strong>consumption</strong> "to Hooverize."</p>
<p>Hoover went on to organize programs to aid other countries, including Russia. He also helped parts of the U.S. recover after terrible flooding.</p>
<p>And, as secretary of commerce, he pushed businesses, researchers, and government officials to work together. Hoover aimed to reduce "<strong>boom and bust</strong>" cycles and keep the U.S. economy healthy.</p>
<p>In all his efforts, Hoover urged Americans to choose to participate. He did not believe in using government requirements to force cooperation.</p>
<p>Instead, he supported "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.hooverpress.org/American-Individualism-P635.aspx">individualism</a>" – the idea that Americans must protect the qualities of creativity, equal <strong>opportunity</strong>, and service to others.</p>
<p>Hoover's beliefs were popular with many Americans at the time – and with many Americans today.</p>
<p>In the election of 1928, Hoover easily won the presidency. He promised to continue leading the country down the path of <strong>prosperity</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When Hoover took office in 1929, he <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/02/hoover-delivers-presidential-inaugural-address-march-4-1929-219984">said</a>, "I have no fears for the future of our country. It is bright with hope."</p>
<p>That was in March.</p>
<p>In October, <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/1929-stock-market-crash">the U.S. stock market crashed</a>. Thousands of investors lost their savings.</p>
<p>The event was part of a sharp downturn in the economies of the United States and of many other countries.</p>
<p>At first, Hoover believed the downturn would pass. But as time went on, the situation grew worse. Businesses could not expand their workforce. Farmers could not afford to harvest their crops. Everyday people had too little money to pay for housing costs and, in some cases, food. And then banks across the country began to fail.</p>
<p>President Hoover worked hard to fix the problems. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.gilderlehrman.org/history-by-era/new-deal/resources/herbert-hoover-great-depression-and-new-deal-1931%E2%80%931933">tried many approaches</a>: creating government agencies, urging private and public groups to cooperate, and working to balance the federal budget.</p>
<p>But Hoover did not want to use federal money to provide direct aid to Americans. He worried that such actions would make people dependent on the government, and reduce people's individual power and <strong>morale</strong>.</p>
<p>Nor did he want to use the federal government to try to control the economy. Government intervention, he said, would lead to socialism, and eventually destroy the country's founding beliefs.</p>
<p>Instead, Hoover tried to support states and businesses indirectly and urged people to find ways to help one another.</p>
<p>Yet many lawmakers and members of the public rejected Hoover's measures as <strong>insufficient</strong>, and even cruel.</p>
<p>Some used his name differently than they had before he took office. Now, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/hoover/campaigns-and-elections">they called</a> the dirty shelters where hungry and homeless people lived "Hoovervilles."</p>
<p>And they called men's empty pockets "Hoover flags."</p>
<p>Although Hoover tried to persuade Americans that he was protecting their interests in the long run, voters refused to elect him for a second term.</p>
<p>Instead, they overwhelming chose a president who promised an activist federal government and a hopeful "new deal" for Americans.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>After they left the White House, the Hoovers retired to their home in Palo Alto, California.</p>
<p>Lou Henry Hoover died in 1944. But Hoover lived 20 more years, many of them working for the public good. He helped international relief efforts, advised the U.S. government, and led committees to reform the presidency.</p>
<p>Hoover also commented on later presidents and their policy decisions. He was especially critical of government programs set up to provide aid and intervention in Americans' lives.</p>
<p>Until his death from cancer at the age of 90, Hoover remained committed to his beliefs. He spoke for limiting the power of the federal government and for supporting freedom of opportunity for individuals.</p>
<p>But in the eyes of many Americans, Hoover is linked to the failure of the federal government to lessen the Great Depression.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>_____________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>orphan</strong> - n. a child whose parents are dead</p>
<p><strong>thrive</strong> - <em>v.</em> to grow or develop successfully : to flourish or succeed</p>
<p><strong>benefit</strong> -<em> n.</em> a good or helpful result or effect</p>
<p><strong>consumption</strong> -<em> n.</em> the use of something</p>
<p><strong>boom and bust</strong> - <em>n.</em> a rapid increase in growth or economic success, followed by sudden economic losses</p>
<p><strong>opportunity</strong> - <em>n.</em> an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>prosperity</strong> -<em> n.</em> the state of being successful usually by making a lot of money</p>
<p><strong>morale</strong> - <em>n.</em> the feelings of enthusiasm and loyalty that a person or group has about a task or job</p>
<p><strong>insufficient</strong> - <em>adj.</em> not having or providing enough of what is needed : not sufficient</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Flying Taxis to be Made in Ohio, Home of Wright Brothers  (2023/9/23) | 空中的士将在莱特兄弟故乡量产</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/flying-taxis-to-be-made-in-ohio-home-of-wright-brothers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The same area where the Wright brothers developed the first airplane will soon see electric planes that take off and land vertically.<br/>
在莱特兄弟发明第一架飞机的同一片土地上，很快将能看到电动飞机垂直起降。</p>
<p>The planes, called "flying taxis" will be produced under an agreement between the state of Ohio and Joby Aviation at Dayton International Airport.<br/>
这些被称为“空中的士”的飞机将根据俄亥俄州和乔比航空公司在代顿国际机场达成的协议被生产出来。</p>
<p>Ohio Governor Mike DeWine told The Associated Press, "When you're talking about air taxis, that's the future."<br/>
俄亥俄州州长麦克·德温告诉美联社：“说起空中的士，这就是未来。”</p>
<p>Around the world, electric vertical takeoff and landing (eVTOL) aircraft, or flying taxis, are becoming more common. Still, questions remain about noise levels and charging demands.<br/>
在世界各地，电动垂直起降飞机或空中的士正变得越来越普遍。尽管如此，噪音水平和充电需求仍然存在疑问。</p>
<p>Developers say the planes are nearing the day when they will provide a way to move individual people or small groups from the top of buildings and parking spaces to their destinations.<br/>
开发商表示，这些飞机即将提供一种将个人或少部分人从建筑物顶部和停车场地运送到目的地的方式。</p>
<p>The Wright brothers, Orville and Wilbur, lived and worked in Dayton, Ohio. In 1910, they opened the first U.S. airplane factory there. To connect with this history, Joby's official announcement Monday took place at Orville Wright's home, Hawthorn Hill, and ended with a special flight of a copy of the Wright Model B Flyer.<br/>
莱特兄弟奥维尔和威尔伯在俄亥俄州代顿生活和工作。1910年，他们在那里开设了第一家美国飞机工厂。为了与这段历史联系起来，乔比航空周一在奥维尔·莱特位于霍索恩山的故居正式宣布了这一消息，并以一架莱特B型飞行者飞机的特别飞行结束。</p>
<p>Engineers designed Joby's production aircraft to transport a pilot and four passengers at speeds of up to 321.87 kilometers per hour. The aircraft can cover a distance of up to 160.93 kilometers. It is a quiet machine that can barely be heard in most cities, the company said. The plan is to place them in aerial ridesharing networks beginning in 2025.<br/>
工程师们设计了乔比航空的量产飞机，它以每小时321.87公里的速度运送一名飞行员和四名乘客。这架飞机的飞行距离可达160.93公里。该公司表示，这是一台安静的机器，在大多数城市几乎听不到它的噪音。该公司计划从2025年开始将它们纳入空中的士网络。</p>
<p>Joby Aviation is a 14-year-old company that went public in 2021 and became the first eVTOL firm to receive a special kind of permission, or certification, from the U.S. Air Force. Its production efforts are supported by partnerships with Toyota, Delta Air Lines, Intel and Uber.<br/>
乔比航空是一家成立14年的公司，它于2021年上市，并成为第一家获得美国空军特别认证的电动垂直起降飞机公司。它的生产工作得到了与丰田、达美航空、英特尔和优步合作的支持。</p>
<p>The $500 million project is supported by up to $325 million in payments from the state of Ohio. With the money, Joby plans to build an Ohio facility capable of delivering up to 500 aircraft a year and creating 2,000 jobs. The U.S. Department of Energy has invited Joby to apply for a loan to support development of the facility as a clean energy project.<br/>
这个价值5亿美元的项目得到了俄亥俄州高达3.25亿美元的资金支持。有了这笔钱，乔比航空计划在俄亥俄州建造一座工厂，每年可交付500架飞机，并创造2000个就业机会。美国能源部已邀请乔比航空申请贷款，以支持该设施作为清洁能源项目的开发。</p>
<p>Joby CEO JoeBen Bevirt told the AP that the company chose Ohio after a large and competitive search. Ohio's financial deal was not the largest, but the chance to bring the operation to the birthplace of aviation — with a workforce experienced in the field — led to the deal, he said.<br/>
乔比航空首席执行官乔本·贝维特告诉美联社，该公司在进行了大规模竞争性的搜索后选择了俄亥俄州。他说，俄亥俄州的金融交易并不是最大的，但有机会将业务带到航空业的发源地，以及拥有该领域经验丰富的员工，这些优势最终促成了这笔交易。</p>
<p>The announcement comes as a group of Ohio's congressional representatives has recently increased efforts to draw the U.S. Air Force's new U.S. Space Command headquarters or Space Force units to Ohio. There, too, state leaders point to the history of the Wrights, as well as Ohio-born astronauts John Glenn and Neil Armstrong.<br/>
俄亥俄州的一群国会代表最近加大了将美国空军新的美国太空司令部总部或太空军部队吸引到俄亥俄州的力度。州领导人也提到了莱特兄弟的历史，以及俄亥俄州出生的宇航员约翰·格伦和尼尔·阿姆斯特朗。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>For US, Art in Federal Buildings Is a Must  (2023/9/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/for-us-art-in-federal-buildings-is-a-must.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artwork has been a part of federal structures almost since the founding of the United States.</p>
<p>A good example is the U.S. Capitol Building with its <strong>domed</strong> <strong>ceiling</strong>, paintings and statues. And the Washington Monument to honor the nation's first president was completed in 1888.</p>
<p>Jennifer Gibson is the director of the Center for Fine Arts at the General Services Administration (GSA), the agency that supervises federal buildings. She says art in federal buildings is a record of the past and "creates a <strong>dynamic</strong> presence in towns and cities and border stations across the country."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="For US, Art in Federal Buildings Is a Must" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a685-08dbb08b118d_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">For US, Art in Federal Buildings Is a Must</span></div>
<p>In the 1960s, a presidential committee stated that "...fine art should be <strong>incorporated</strong> into the designs of federal buildings with emphasis on the work of living American artists."</p>
<p>Today, the government still spends about 0.5 percent of the federal budget to commission, or order, new artwork for federal spaces.</p>
<p>The commissions are decided by a group that includes the lead designer of the building, those who will occupy the space, community members, arts professionals, and the GSA. Artists are given details about the building project and asked to propose artwork they think is best for the space.</p>
<p>New York artist James Carpenter created two artworks for federal buildings. They included a ceiling for a courtroom in Phoenix, Arizona, and a <strong>sculpture</strong> for another courthouse in Salt Lake City, Utah.</p>
<p>Carpenter said, "My work is really about how to <strong>enhance</strong> or influence, in a very positive way, people's experience of spaces..."</p>
<p>For some artists, requests to provide art for federal buildings may not be related to making money. Artists can make commissions as much as $1 million from non-government artworks. The average commission for art in federal buildings is around $100,000. And the process can take several years, limiting an artist's ability to work on other art projects. Carpenter said the Salt Lake City project took a total of 12 years.</p>
<p>"They're looking at it as a way to <strong>participate</strong> in what's going on in the nation and to be part of its history," Gibson says. "This is for the nation. This is permanent. We will take care of it. And it's your way to participate."</p>
<p>The commissioned artworks can be found in 428 federal buildings across the country. Overall, the GSA's fine art collection contains 26,712 works, including some that date back to the 1850s.</p>
<p>Most of the artworks are paintings, <strong>sculptures</strong> and<strong> photographs </strong>created in the 1930s. That was the time the government employed artists during the Great Depression.</p>
<p>The collection belongs to the American people as a record of the history of American culture.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dome </strong>–n. a shape; the top of a building that has a round shape and a circular base</p>
<p><strong>ceiling </strong>–n. the top of a room</p>
<p><strong>incorporate </strong>–v. include</p>
<p><strong>dynamic</strong>–adj. having a lot of ideas, energy and interest</p>
<p><strong>sculpture</strong> –n. a form of art in which hard materials are worked into object that has width, height, and depth</p>
<p><strong>enhance </strong>–v. to increase or improve in value, quality, desirability, or attractiveness</p>
<p><strong>participate</strong> –v. to have a share in something in common with others</p>
<p><strong>photograph </strong>–n. images made with a camera</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>On Time or In Time?  (2023/9/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/on-time-or-in-time.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "in time" and "on time?"</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Dear VOA,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8322-08dbba1f71d9_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>What is the difference between "in time" and "on time?" I appreciate that you can help me understand them. I'm looking forward to seeing your answer.</p>
<p>Have a great day,</p>
<p>Nguyen</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for this great question, Nguyen! Both "on time" and "in time" have to do with being <strong>punctual</strong> and deadlines. Sometimes people use these expressions interchangeably, but they are different. And "in time" has a few more uses.</p>
<p>Let's look at each one.</p>
<p><strong>On time</strong></p>
<p>"On time" is an expression that includes a preposition (on) and a noun (time). If something is "on time" it arrives at or by an exact time or deadline. It is not late. You can think of "on time" as when something happens. And if it happens at that exact time, then it is "on time."</p>
<p><em>Jordan did not submit her homework on time, so she received 5 points off. </em></p>
<p><em>The train is always on time so I am never late to work. </em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "in time."</p>
<p><strong>In time</strong></p>
<p>"In time" is also an expression that includes a preposition (in) and the noun "time." Like "on time," it is used to talk about deadlines and times.</p>
<p>It means early enough or not too late for something to happen. Often, we use it to talk about something in relation to another event or thing using another preposition "for" after the expression.</p>
<p><em>Even though my train was late, I got to work in time for the meeting. </em></p>
<p><em>We made it home in time to watch our favorite show. </em></p>
<p>"In time" is also used two other ways.</p>
<p>In music, "in time" means to keep a <strong>rhythm</strong> or speed.</p>
<p><em>The tap dancer was able to keep time with the musicians. </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>punctual </strong><em>– adj. </em>doing something at the expected time</p>
<p><strong>rhythm</strong> <em>– n.</em> a regular, repeated pattern of sounds or movements</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia Aims to Meet Water Needs with Solar Power  (2023/9/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/saudi-arabia-aims-to-meet-water-needs-with-solar-power.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Saudi Arabia is a dry place. In many areas, people there depend on turning saltwater from the Persian Gulf and Red Sea into drinkable, fresh water. That process is called <strong>desalination</strong>.</p>
<p>Desalination centers supply drinking water to cities and towns in the kingdom. However, observers say the process of desalination is not good for the environment because it mostly uses oil and gas.</p>
<p>One goal of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman is to make Saudia Arabia a leader in business and <strong>tourism</strong>. For this, the country must meet growing demands for water.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Asian laborers of the Saudi National Water Company working at a construction site in a road in the capital Riyadh. Saudi Arabia. (Fayez Nureldine / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4e5d-08dbb781444e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Asian laborers of the Saudi National Water Company working at a construction site in a road in the capital Riyadh. Saudi Arabia. (Fayez Nureldine / AFP)</span></div>
<p>But Saudi Arabia's environmental goal is to reach <strong>net-zero emissions</strong> by 2060. So, the country's leaders say they want to reduce the amount of carbon gases produced. Some people say carbon gases are warming the Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>A desalination plant in the eastern part of the country uses <strong>solar panels</strong>. The Jazlah plant is the first in Saudi Arabia to use solar power for desalination on a large <strong>scale</strong>. Officials said the panels will help save 60,000 tons of carbon emissions each year.</p>
<p>More projects like Jazlah are needed because Prince Mohammed has another goal. He wants to increase the population to 100 million people by 2040. The country's current population is about 32.2 million.</p>
<p>Marco Arcelli is chief of ACWA Power, the company that operates the Jazlah plant. He said, usually "the population grows, and then the quality of life of the population grows." That means more water will be needed in the future.</p>
<p>Using desalination is a "do or die" issue, said historian Michael Christopher Low. He has studied the kingdom's struggle with water at the University of Utah in the United States. Low said this issue is a matter of survival for Saudia Arabia. At the same time, he added, "there are limits" to how desalination can be done so that it does not affect the environment.</p>
<p><strong>Current use of fossil fuels</strong></p>
<p>The Saline Water Conversion Corporation (or SWCC) is a government company that operates desalination and power plants in Saudi Arabia. The company says it produces 11.5 million cubic meters each day at 30 centers. But growth has come at a cost, especially at centers that use oil or gas.</p>
<p>The AFP press agency reports that, by 2010, Saudi desalination plants were using 1.5 million <strong>barrels</strong> of oil per day. That is more than 15 percent of today's production.</p>
<p>The SWCC said it wants to cut 37 million metric tons of carbon emissions by 2025. The company hopes to do this by moving away from plants that use heat to separate water from salt to plants like Jazlah that use solar electricity-powered systems.</p>
<p>The SWCC said in its latest report that solar power is expected to expand to 770 megawatts compared to 120 megawatts today. But how long that will take is unclear.</p>
<p>In the future, there is little doubt Saudi Arabia will be able to build the systems required to produce the water it needs.</p>
<p>"They have already done it in some of the most <strong>challenging</strong> settings, like massively desalinating on the Red Sea and providing desalinated water up to the highlands of the holy cities in Mecca and Medina," said Laurent Lambert. He is with the Doha Institute for Graduate Studies.</p>
<p>At desalination plants across the kingdom, Saudi employees understand how important their work is.</p>
<p>The Ras Al-Khair center produces 1.1 million cubic meters of water per day with 740,000 from heat technology and the rest from another process. The plant struggles to make enough fresh water because of high demand.</p>
<p>Much of the water goes to Riyadh. That city requires 1.6 million cubic meters per day. It could require as much as 6 million cubic meters a day by 2030, said one employee who was not permitted to talk to the media and remains unidentified.</p>
<p><strong>A short history of Saudi desalination</strong></p>
<p>Saudi Arabia first turned to desalination more than 100 years ago. During the rule of the Ottoman Empire, administrators used <strong>filtration</strong> machines for Muslim travelers observing the Hajj who had to deal with a lack of water and cholera.</p>
<p>Drinking water has been a problem for Saudi Arabia since its founding in 1932. This led to geological studies that also helped identify the country's huge supplies of oil and gas. Leaders since have supervised the birth of the kingdom's modern desalination systems beginning in 1970.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo adapted this AFP story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>desalination </strong><em>–n.</em> the process of removing salt from saltwater to make drinkable water</p>
<p><strong>tourism </strong><em>–n.</em> the industry of providing food and services for people who travel for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>net-zero emissions </strong><em>–expression</em> the idea of having the release of carbon gasses balance the amount of carbon removed from the atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>solar panel </strong>–n. a device that captures the sun's light and changes it into electrical current</p>
<p><strong>scale </strong>–n. the level or amount of something</p>
<p><strong>barrel </strong>–n. a measure used in the oil trade</p>
<p><strong>challenging </strong>–adj. difficult or hard to do</p>
<p><strong>filtration </strong>–n. the process of removing something from water or another substance, usually to purify it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Offers Work Permits to Thousands of Venezuelans Already in Country  (2023/9/22) | 美国给数万名在美委内瑞拉人提供工作许可</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-offers-work-permits-to-thousands-of-venezuelans-already-in-country.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The administration of U.S. President Joe Biden says it will temporarily stop deportations of nearly half a million Venezuelans already in the country. In addition, the immigrants will be able to get permission to work.<br/>
拜登政府表示，将暂时停止驱逐已在美国境内的近50万委内瑞拉人。除此之外，这些移民将能够获得工作许可。</p>
<p>It is estimated that about 472,000 Venezuelan immigrants entered the U.S. on or before July 31. They now have the ability to get Temporary Protected Status (TPS) that will last for 18 months. About 243,000 Venezuelans already have the status from a 2021 policy change that was renewed last year.<br/>
据估计，约有47.2万委内瑞拉移民在7月31日或之前进入了美国。他们现在可以获得持续18个月的临时庇护身份。自一项2021年政策改革去年更新以来，约有24.3万委内瑞拉人已经获得了这一身份。</p>
<p>The promise of work permits will not affect people who cross the border illegally and seek asylum. People who enter the country illegally must wait for six months to receive work permits.<br/>
工作许可的承诺不会影响非法越境寻求庇护的人士。非法入境者必须等待六个月才能获得工作许可。</p>
<p>The policy for Venezuelans is important because they make up such a large number of the migrants who have been arriving in the country recently.<br/>
这项针对委内瑞拉人的政策很重要，因为他们在最近抵达美国的移民中占了很大一部分。</p>
<p>Biden, a member of the Democrat Party, is seeking reelection in 2024. During Biden's time in office, the country has faced more illegal border crossings than ever before. The mass migration is partly the result of people fleeing severe economic and political problems in Venezuela.<br/>
民主党人拜登正在寻求2024年的连任。在拜登执政期间，该国面临的非法越境事件比以往任何时候都多。大规模移民的部分原因是人们逃离委内瑞拉严重的经济和政治问题。</p>
<p>It is estimated that at least 7.3 million Venezuelans have left the country in the last 10 years. Most have migrated to neighboring South American countries. But in the last three years, many have been coming to the United States.<br/>
据估计，过去10年至少有730万委内瑞拉人离开了该国。大多数移民到了邻近的南美国家。但在过去的三年里，许多人来到了美国。</p>
<p>On Wednesday, New York City Mayor Eric Adams praised the Biden administration's plan to expand work permits for newly arrived migrants.<br/>
周三，纽约市市长埃里克·亚当斯赞扬了拜登政府扩大新移民工作许可的计划。</p>
<p>However, news media have reported that local officials have said it is difficult to deal with large numbers of migrants entering cities and towns.<br/>
然而，新闻媒体报道称，当地官员表示，很难处理大量进入城镇的移民。</p>
<p>New York City, for example, is required to provide housing for anyone who needs it. The city is currently paying to house about 60,000 newly arrived migrants.<br/>
例如，纽约市被要求为任何有需要者提供住房。该市目前正在支付约6万名新移民的住房费用。</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) said the expansion of protected status for Venezuelans was needed. It said this was because of "Venezuela's increased instability and lack of safety."<br/>
美国国土安全部表示，有必要扩大委内瑞拉人的受保护身份。它说，这是因为“委内瑞拉的不稳定增加和安全缺乏。”</p>
<p>The number of migrants crossing the U.S.-Mexico border illegally dropped in May. But crossings returned to high levels in the following months.<br/>
5月份，非法穿越美墨边境的移民人数有所下降。但在接下来的几个月里，越境人数又恢复到了高位。</p>
<p>The Biden administration said the U.S. Department of Defense will send an additional 800 military troops to the border. That is in addition to 2,500 National Guard troops already deployed. The aim is to aid U.S. Customs and Border Protection operations.<br/>
拜登政府表示，美国国防部将向边境增派800名军人。这是对已部署到位的2500名国民警卫队士兵的补充。目的是协助美国海关和边境保护局的行动。</p>
<p>Also, the Biden administration will expand a program launched in May to quickly process migrant families seeking asylum and possibly to deport them.<br/>
此外，拜登政府将扩大5月启动的一项计划，以快速处理寻求庇护的移民家庭并可能将他们驱逐出境。</p>
<p>The DHS said it would increase the time that work permits are valid for some immigrants, including asylum-seekers, to five years. This would permit the government to work on processing new requests.<br/>
国土安全部表示，将把包括寻求庇护者在内的一些移民的工作许可有效期延长至五年。这将使政府能够处理新的申请。</p>
<p>The DHS also said it has deported 253,000 people to more than 150 countries since May 12.<br/>
国土安全部还表示，自5月12日以来，已将25.3万人驱逐到150多个国家。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Will Office of the Future Be Like?  (2023/9/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/what-will-office-of-the-future-be-like.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has changed how people in the U.S. work.</p>
<p>Before the pandemic, only 5.7 percent of people worked from their homes. But a recent report from the business advisor McKinsey &amp; Company found that 58 percent of people worked from home at least one day a week in 2022.</p>
<p>Ryan Luby helped write the report. He said the office needs to change because the <strong>role</strong> of the workplace has changed.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="What Will Office of the Future Be Like?" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-70b4-08dbb45e5ff2_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">What Will Office of the Future Be Like?</span></div>
<p>Aditya Sanghvi is with the property business of McKinsey &amp; Company. He said: "The office has suddenly become a choice. It's an <strong>option</strong>. And the office has to be better for someone than working from home and <strong>enduring</strong> the commute to come into the office."</p>
<p>One change office spaces need is more <strong>focus</strong> on community in the workplace. "When you get to the office, if you're not <strong>engaging</strong> with anyone else, you might as well not be there," Luby said.</p>
<p>He added, "The office should be a place where you're doing group work."</p>
<p>Sanghvi added that, in the new workspace, people should feel like "there's no difference between whether or not someone's sitting with you in the office or somebody's [on] video."</p>
<p>The office of the future might even help workers with their personal responsibilities.</p>
<p>"One of the reasons that a lot of people work from home is that they have to pick up the kids or take care of the dog," Sanghvi said. "And so, what if there were [animal] care in the building? What if there was child care in the building?"</p>
<p>Sanghvi believes companies that own the office space should be more active in changing workspaces for the new way of life.</p>
<p>The U.S. General Services Administration (GSA) is the government agency that supervises federal buildings. The GSA has been a leading force in establishing what the office of the future will look like.</p>
<p>Chuck Hardy is GSA's chief <strong>architect</strong>. He supervises GSA's Workplace Innovation Lab, a 25,000-square-foot space inside the organization's headquarters in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>"What we're trying to do is create a workplace and an environment that allows you to be as productive as you can be without getting in the way. And that means a <strong>variety</strong> of spaces for a variety of the people that work for us," Hardy said.</p>
<p>The Workplace Innovation Lab will be open for one year. Federal workers can try out the latest in workplace <strong>furnishings</strong> and technology and then provide comments on their experience.</p>
<p>Some spaces in the lab look like traditional workspaces. Some spaces feel pleasant. Almost everything can be moved around. The air quality is controlled, and technology that is believed to be good for the environment is being tested.</p>
<p>Hardy said the office of the future needs three qualities. It should be well-designed, serve a purpose and feel pleasant.</p>
<p>All of this might mean that the office of the future could feel a little bit more like home.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for the Voice of America. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>role</strong>–<em>n</em>. the part that a person or something plays in an activity or operation</p>
<p><strong>option</strong>–<em>n</em>. one of several choices that can be made in a situation</p>
<p><strong>endure</strong>–<em>v</em>. to suffer</p>
<p><strong>focus</strong>–<em>n</em>. bring attention and thought to a subject, issue or problem</p>
<p><strong>engage</strong>–<em>v</em>. to communicate or be involved with others in a meaningful way</p>
<p><strong>variety</strong>–<em>adj</em>. different in size, amount, degree, or nature</p>
<p><strong>architect</strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who plans, designs and supervises the building of structures</p>
<p><strong>furnishings</strong>–<em>n</em>. the furniture, curtains, carpets, and decorations in a space</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Offering Coffee and Tea  (2023/9/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/offering-coffee-and-tea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Consider a time you asked someone to drink tea, coffee, or soda. What kinds of terms and structures did you use?</p>
<p>In this week's Everyday Grammar, we will explore a point of connection between grammar and social situations. We will talk about how to ask others if they would like a drink. You will learn about <strong>modals </strong>as well as <strong>formal</strong> and <strong>informal</strong> kinds of questions.</p>
<p>Let's start with some important terms and ideas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-acda-08dbbaced82d_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p><strong>Modals </strong></p>
<p>Modals play a central part in everyday discussions about drinks such as coffee or tea.</p>
<p>Modals are short words that change the meaning of the main verb. They express something about the speaker's <strong>attitude</strong> – whether something is permitted, necessary, possible, and so on.</p>
<p>In English, we have a number of modals. But for the purposes of today's lesson, let's pay careful attention to two of them: would and can.</p>
<p>We generally use "would" to ask a polite question or make a polite offer. We use "can" for the same purpose, although it is a little less formal.</p>
<p>Let's take an example. Imagine you are in your house or working in a restaurant. You want to offer a drink to your guest or customer. We have two ways to do that – one that involves "would" and one that involves "can."</p>
<p>So, you might ask:</p>
<p><em>Would you like something to drink?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>Can I get you something to drink?</em></p>
<p>The main difference between our two questions is the degree of politeness. Generally, "would" is considered more polite and formal.</p>
<p>Both "would" and "can" are acceptable in a number of situations. Your house guest or customer would surely be happy to hear either of them.</p>
<p><strong>With friends, classmates, family </strong></p>
<p>Now let us consider a different kind of situation. Maybe you are out with friends and want to ask them to get something to drink. We can make polite offers with "would" and "can," as in:</p>
<p><em>Would you like to get tea?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>Can I get you a coffee?</em></p>
<p>But we can also use the helping verb "do" to ask yes or no questions. For example, you might ask a friend:</p>
<p><em>Do you want to get a coffee?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>Do you want to <strong>grab </strong>a drink?</em></p>
<p>Such structures are friendly but less formal. As a result, you might not want to use them with your teacher or your boss, unless you are very close with them.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Now let's take some time to work with these ideas.</p>
<p>Imagine you are leading a business meeting with representatives from another company. Your visitors enter the meeting room, and you decide you want to offer them something to drink. How might you make your offer?</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>There are several possible answers, but the best two choices involve "would" or "can," as in:</p>
<p><em>Would you like something drink?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>Can I offer you something to drink?</em></p>
<p>These two sentences are polite and acceptable in official situations.</p>
<p>Now consider the following sentence:</p>
<p><em>Do you want something to drink?</em></p>
<p>Why is this sentence not the best choice for an official business meeting?</p>
<p>The question is not very formal nor especially polite. So, "Do you want something to drink?" is probably not the best choice to use with representatives from another company.</p>
<p>But, for family and good friends? That's a question they are usually happy to hear!</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>Today we explored a few key ideas that connect to everyday situations – inviting someone to get a drink, offering a guest something to drink.</p>
<p>There are, of course, other ways to ask if others want something to drink. However, the structures we explored today are among the most commonly used because they work well in most situations.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in The Story</h2>
<p><strong>modal </strong><em>– n.</em> a verb (such as can or would) that is usually used with another verb to express ideas such as possibility, necessity, etc.</p>
<p><strong>formal</strong> <em>– adj.</em> suitable for serious or official speech</p>
<p><strong>informal</strong> –<em> adj.</em> having a friendly and relaxed quality</p>
<p><strong>grab</strong> <em>– verb</em> to get (something) in a quick and informal way</p>
<p><strong>attitude </strong>–<em> n.</em> a mental position with regard to a fact or state</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google Links Bard AI Tool to Its Other Products  (2023/9/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/google-links-bard-ai-tool-to-its-other-products.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google has linked its Bard artificial intelligence (AI) tool to its Gmail service and other company offerings. The American-based search engine company says the change will permit its users to easily use the AI technology across different product areas.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://bard.google.com/">Bard</a> is a chatbot, a computer-driven system designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. Such tools are also known as "generative AI" or "large language models."</p>
<p>The first widely released chatbot was ChatGPT. It was launched by technology company OpenAI late last year. Google announced the launch of its Bard tool last February. And shortly thereafter, Microsoft announced it was redesigning its Bing search engine to include OpenAI's chatbot technology. Microsoft has invested billions of dollars in OpenAI.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, various Google logos are displayed on a Google search, Monday, Sept. 11, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-4085-08dbb9ecc2e6_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, various Google logos are displayed on a Google search, Monday, Sept. 11, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>In an announcement Tuesday, Google said it had created a system that makes it possible for users to extend the AI tool to other company services, or apps. This brings Bard technology to Google products including Gmail, Drive, YouTube, Maps, etc.</p>
<p>The system to expand the AI tool to other Google apps is called Bard Extensions. Users can decide which apps they want to add Bard to. This can be done by going to Google's Chrome browser and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/extensions">following the process</a> to activate new extensions. For the moment, Bard Extensions is only available in English.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://blog.google/products/bard/google-bard-new-features-update-sept-2023/">In a statement</a> explaining the change, Google gave several descriptions of how users could use Bard with other apps. For example, a user of Gmail could ask Bard to create a <strong>summary</strong> of all emails dealing with a particular subject.</p>
<p>Another example is a possible solution to someone planning a major family trip. In such a case, a series of Google apps can be used together with Bard.</p>
<p>The user can ask Bard to search through Gmail messages to get available trip dates from the emails of multiple family members. At the same time, a user can ask Bard to use Google Flights to look up flight dates that would work for the trip. Bard can also be used to book available hotel rooms and connect with Google Maps to provide everyone with directions to the airport. And users could also use Bard to find YouTube videos of things to do during the trip.</p>
<p>Another example Google gives is how Bard can link up with other apps to assist someone with a job search. In this case, Google suggests asking Bard to "find my <strong>resume</strong> titled June 2023 from my Drive and summarize it to a short paragraph personal statement."</p>
<p>Another new add-on for Bard permits users to invite others into their Bard <strong>conversations</strong>.</p>
<p>In its announcement, Google also said it had created a way for users to <strong>verify</strong> whether information produced by the Bard tool is correct or not. This move is seen as an effort by Google to help users get over concerns about its AI system returning false, outdated or damaging results.</p>
<p>Google says the use of Bard's "Google it" <strong>button</strong> can test the correctness of its results. When people use this button, Bard's results are compared with the results of a Google search on the same subject. Then, Bard points out the differences in its own results compared to information returned from Google search.</p>
<p>Google senior product director Jack Krawczyk told Reuters news agency the company thought it was important to add this ability to help users find the most truthful results.</p>
<p>"We are presenting (Bard) in a way that it admits when it's not confident," Krawczyk said. He added that the effort is part of a goal by Google to build user trust in generative AI tools, while holding Bard accountable for its performance.</p>
<p>In announcing Bard Extensions, Google promised to protect users' privacy by blocking its employees from seeing any personal information Bard gets from apps such as Gmail or Drive. It said it had also taken steps to prevent data linked to Bard from being used to target users with ads or to train the AI tool.</p>
<p>Krawczyk noted that currently, Bard users can only pull in information from other Google apps. However, he said Google is already working with other companies to be able to connect their apps to Bard in the future.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse and Google. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>summary </strong><em>– n. </em>a short description that provides the main facts or ideas about something</p>
<p><strong>resume </strong><em>– n. </em>a document describing a person's qualifications and past employment history that is used to help someone find a job</p>
<p><strong>conversation </strong><em>– n. </em>the act of speaking or communicating with another person</p>
<p><strong>verify </strong><em>– v. </em>to confirm or prove that something is true</p>
<p><strong>button </strong><em>– n. </em>a switch that is pressed to control a piece of equipment</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Earth Outside ‘Safe Operating Space for Humanity’  (2023/9/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/study-earth-outside-safe-operating-space-for-humanity.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new study from international researchers says that Earth is outside of its "safe operating space for humanity" in six of nine measures of its health. The study added that two of the remaining three measures are moving in the wrong direction.</p>
<p>The international scientists published the study in <em>Science Advances</em>. They said Earth's climate, <strong>biodiversity</strong>, land, freshwater, nutrient pollution, and human-made compounds are outside of "safe operating space for humanity."</p>
<p>The scientists said only the acidity of the oceans, the health of the air, and the ozone layer are within limits considered to be safe.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Haze blankets the main business district in Jakarta, Indonesia on August 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0ef196cd-6726-4047-b900-d3d3594c9d44_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Haze blankets the main business district in Jakarta, Indonesia on August 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara, File)</span></div>
<p>The ozone layer is mainly high in the atmosphere and prevents dangerous solar radiation from reaching the surface of the Earth.</p>
<p>But the study warned that both the ocean and air pollution are moving in the wrong direction.</p>
<p>Johan Rockstrom is a climate scientist who helped write the study. He is director of the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research in Germany. He said, "We are in very bad shape." He compared the Earth to a weakening, sick patient.</p>
<p>In 2009, Rockstrom and other researchers created nine "<strong>boundary</strong> areas" and used measurements of them to judge Earth's health. The latest study continued research from a similar one in 2015. The latest study added a sixth area to the unsafe listing.</p>
<p>Rockstrom said the Earth's water went from being safe to being "<strong>out-of-bounds.</strong>" The scientists said this was because of river run-off. They said better measurements and understanding of the issue had shown there was a problem.</p>
<p>Rockstrom said these boundaries would decide the future of the planet. He added the nine measures have been "scientifically well established" by other studies. If Earth can <strong>manage</strong> these nine measures, Earth could be more-or-less safe. But it is not, he said.</p>
<p>The nine measures were compared with each other in different ways. The team used computer <strong>simulations </strong>to predict the future. They would, for example, make predictions based on increases in the average temperature of the Earth. The team found, if one area was affected badly by a temperature change then all areas were affected badly. The team also found that if one area improved, all areas improved.</p>
<p>The scientists said the simulations showed that one of the most powerful ways to help the climate is to clean up land and to save forests. Returning forests to the late 20th century levels would provide natural areas to store carbon dioxide instead of in the air, where it traps heat, the study said.</p>
<p>Rockstrom added that biodiversity is in the most troubling area but does not get as much attention.</p>
<p>However, the study said the ozone layer is improving. This shows that when the world and its leaders decide to deal with a problem, it can be fixed.</p>
<p>Neil Donahue is a Carnegie Mellon chemistry and environment professor. He said, "for the most part there are things that we know how to do" to improve the remaining problems.</p>
<p>Some biodiversity scientists, like Duke University's Stuart Pimm, have disputed Rockstrom's methods, saying they are not worth much.</p>
<p>Granger Morgan is a Carnegie Mellon environmental engineering professor and was not part of the study. He said, "Experts don't agree on exactly where the limits are, or how much the planet's different systems may <strong>interact</strong>, but we are getting dangerously close."</p>
<p>Morgan said he has often said if we do not cut back on how we are harming the Earth, "we're <strong>toast</strong>." He added, "This paper says it's more likely that we're burnt toast."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>boundary </strong>–n. an area where something ends, and another begins</p>
<p><strong>out-of-bounds </strong>–adj. an area that is outside the place where a game is played</p>
<p><strong>biodiversity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the existence of many different kinds of plants and animals in an environment</p>
<p><strong>manage </strong><em>– v.</em> to keep (something) under your control</p>
<p><strong>simulation </strong><em>– n.</em> something that is made to look, feel, or behave like something else especially so that it can be studied or used to train people</p>
<p><strong>interact </strong><em>– v.</em> to come together and have an effect on each other</p>
<p><strong>be toast </strong><em>– idiom to</em> be in a lot of trouble</p>
<p><strong>toast </strong><em>– n.</em> bread that has been sliced and then made crisp and brown by heat</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Former Argentine Torture Center Added to UNESCO Heritage  (2023/9/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/former-argentine-torture-center-added-to-unesco-heritage.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Argentina has welcomed a United Nations decision to include a former secret detention and torture center as a World Heritage site.</p>
<p>A UN Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) conference in Saudi Arabia agreed this week to include the ESMA Museum and Site of Memory on its list of places "considered to be of outstanding value to humanity."</p>
<p>The former Navy School of Mechanics, known as ESMA, is in the Argentinian capital, Buenos Aires. It contained the most infamous illegal detention center that operated during Argentina's last dictatorship --- from 1976 through 1983. It now operates as a museum and a larger site of memory, including offices for government agencies and human rights organizations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Photographs of people who disappeared during Argentina's dictatorship are displayed on the wall where students walk through the ESMA Museum and Site of Memory on Sept. 19, 2023. (AP Photo/Rodrigo Abd)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-c311-08dbb9ed54bd_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Photographs of people who disappeared during Argentina's dictatorship are displayed on the wall where students walk through the ESMA Museum and Site of Memory on Sept. 19, 2023. (AP Photo/Rodrigo Abd)</span></div>
<p>Argentina's President Alberto Fernández praised UNESCO's decision in a video message. The memory must be kept alive, he said, "so that no one in Argentina forgets or denies the horrors that were experienced there."</p>
<p>Fernández later said to the United Nations General Assembly in New York on Tuesday afternoon: "By actively <strong>preserving</strong> the memory that denialists want to <strong>conceal</strong>, we will prevent that pain from <strong>recurring</strong>."</p>
<p>It is estimated that some 5,000 people were detained at the ESMA during the dictatorship. Many detainees were tortured and later disappeared. It also housed many who were later thrown into the ocean or rivers from planes known as "death flights."</p>
<p>The ESMA also housed pregnant women brought from other illegal detention centers. They were kept there until they gave birth and their babies were later taken away by military officers.</p>
<p>Argentina's Human Rights Secretary Horacio Pietragalla Corti praised the decision to recognize the site. He said it is a strong answer "to those who deny or seek to downplay state terrorism and the crimes of the last civil-military dictatorship."</p>
<p>A video posted on social media by Argentina's Foreign Ministry showed the official with tears in his eyes as he celebrated the UNESCO decision.</p>
<p>Pietragalla was one of the babies taken by military officers and raised under a false identity. The group Grandmothers of Plaza de Mayo discovered his birth history, as well as those of 132 other stolen babies through genetic testing.</p>
<p>Argentina has done more than any other Latin American country to bring crimes of former dictatorships to trial. It has held almost 300 trials, all linked to crimes against humanity, since 2006.</p>
<p>The ESMA's addition to the World Heritage list speaks to more than just Argentina. Pietragalla called the recognition "a <strong>tribute</strong> to the thousands of disappeared individuals in our continent."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>preserve</strong> - v. to keep something from a loss</p>
<p><strong>conceal</strong> - v. to keep secret</p>
<p><strong>recur</strong> - v. to occur again</p>
<p><strong>tribute</strong> - n. something that you do to show respect</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Library Group: Objections to Books More Common  (2023/9/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-library-group-objections-to-books-more-common.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American Library Association (ALA) says book bans and attempted bans continue to rise in the United States. The group notes that efforts now extend beyond schools to public libraries.</p>
<p>Through the first eight months of 2023, the ALA said there were 695 <strong>challenges</strong> to library materials and services, involving 1,915 books.</p>
<p>People have sought to remove books they consider offensive from school libraries for a long time. But this year, the challenges have been near-equally divided between schools and libraries open to the general public, the ALA said Wednesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The American Library Association reported Wednesday, Sept. 20, 2023, that challenges to books in schools and public libraries will likely reach record highs in 2023, topping what had been a record pace in 2022. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ca9d-08dbba024604_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The American Library Association reported Wednesday, Sept. 20, 2023, that challenges to books in schools and public libraries will likely reach record highs in 2023, topping what had been a record pace in 2022. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)</span></div>
<p>Deborah Caldwell-Stone directs the association's Office for Intellectual Freedom. She said, "The <strong>irony</strong> is that you had some <strong>censors</strong> who said that those who didn't want books pulled from schools could just go to the public libraries."</p>
<p>The ALA defines a challenge as a "formal, written <strong>complaint</strong> filed with a library or school requesting that materials be removed because of content or appropriateness."</p>
<p>Many of the challenges came from Moms for Liberty. The group has organized efforts nationwide and has called for more parental control over books available to children.</p>
<p>"There used to be a roughly one-to-one <strong>ratio</strong>, where a parent would complain about an individual book, like in the days when many were objecting to Harry Potter," Caldwell-Stone said. "Now you have people turning up at meetings and asking that 100 <strong>titles</strong> be removed."</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the Chicago-based association issued its yearly top 10 list of books most objected to in 2022. Many of them included racial and/or LGBTQ issues. Maia Kobabe's <em>Gender Queer</em> topped the list, followed by George Johnson's <em>All Boys Aren't Blue</em> and Nobel literature-prize winner Toni Morrison's <em>The Bluest Eye</em>.</p>
<p>Teachers and librarians have been criticized a lot in 2023.</p>
<p>At Chapin High School in the state of South Carolina, some students said that a teacher made them feel "<strong>ashamed</strong> to be Caucasian." The teacher, they said, assigned them to read Ta-Nehisi Coates' <em>Between the World and Me</em>. The book is an open letter to his son about police violence against Black people. It won the National Book Award in 2015. The school removed the book from the study program.</p>
<p>In Front Royal, Virginia, local officials are planning to cut money for the Samuels Public Library. The move follows complaints from conservatives about books about gay, lesbian and transgender issues.</p>
<p>Iowa Governor Kim Reynolds recently signed into law a bill that calls for books describing sex acts to be removed from school libraries.</p>
<p>The ALA's opposition to book bans has also led some communities to withdraw their membership or support, including Campbell County in Wyoming and a local library in Midland, Texas. Missouri officials announced the state would withdraw support from the ALA after new laws limiting young people's ability to get books considered unacceptable for children.</p>
<p>"I think this <strong>trend</strong> is going to continue," Caldwell-Stone said, "at least for as long these groups want to go after whole <strong>categories</strong> of books."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Hillel Italie reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>challenge</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>to formally dispute whether something should or should not be done</p>
<p><strong>irony</strong> <em>–n.</em> language used in a way that is different from its literal meaning and which the user finds funny</p>
<p><strong>censor </strong>–n. a person who examines books, movies, and other media and removes things considered offensive or unacceptable by society</p>
<p><strong>complaint </strong>–n. a statement of dissatisfaction with a condition or situation</p>
<p><strong>ratio </strong>–n. the relationship that exists between one amount and another</p>
<p><strong>title </strong>–n. literally the name of a book, but which is used as another word for a book itself</p>
<p><strong>ashamed </strong>–adj. to feel bad or guilty about something you have done</p>
<p><strong>trend </strong>–n. the general movement of change or development in an issue; something that is becoming more common</p>
<p><strong>category </strong>–n. a number of similar things that are grouped together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Strange-looking Tomato Can Still Be Tasty  (2023/9/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/strange-looking-tomato-can-still-be-tasty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>This is the time of year when many gardeners are harvesting tomatoes. <em>Associated Press</em> gardening expert Jessica Damiano recently reported about the many pictures of strangely shaped tomatoes sent to her from fans of her gardening advice. She said people sometimes question if the tomatoes are okay to eat.</p>
<p>The good news, Damiano said, is that there is nothing wrong with the deformed fruits. Unless otherwise diseased, they are perfectly good for eating. Their unusual appearance does not affect their taste or <strong>nutritional</strong> value.</p>
<p><strong>What's going on here?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This September 2021 photo provided by Richard Gill shows a tomato with a genetic mutation in North London, England. (Richard Gill @happymrgill via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/abb5449a-808a-4d13-b104-46210bb41c72_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This September 2021 photo provided by Richard Gill shows a tomato with a genetic mutation in North London, England. (Richard Gill @happymrgill via AP)</span></div>
<p>If you have ever cut open a tomato, you know they are divided into <strong>internal</strong> parts, called locules, which contain seeds and a substance called gel. Most tomatoes have about four or five locules; other kinds of the fruit, like cherry tomatoes, contain two or three. Plum or Roma tomatoes have two locules.</p>
<p>But when a plant experiences temperature extremes, cell division in the developing fruit can go off track. Temperatures over 32 degrees Celsius during the day and 27 overnight can lead the tomato to form an extra locule. But there is not enough room inside a tomato for the extra part, so it grows on the outside of the fruit.</p>
<p>Not every tomato on an affected plant will be deformed, however.</p>
<p><strong>What are the chances?</strong></p>
<p>"Under the right conditions (temperatures that are too hot or even too cold), this could affect one or two tomatoes per plant, depending on where they are in the development process and what the (weather) conditions are," said Timothy McDermott. He is an assistant <strong>professor</strong> and extension educator at Ohio State University.</p>
<p>The likelihood of one of your tomatoes developing a locule <strong>oddity</strong> is estimated to be about one in a thousand, McDermott said.</p>
<p>Any tomato can grow an extra locule. But, Damiano noted, <strong>heirloom</strong> kinds seem more likely to have this genetic <strong>mutation</strong> than <strong>hybrids</strong>.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Hot tomato?</strong></p>
<p>The extra-locule mutation is not the only abnormality caused by extreme heat. Conditions including sunscald, <strong>blossom</strong> drop, halted fruit formation and <strong>ripening</strong> can also arise when plants are grown outside their usual temperature limit.</p>
<p>Provide <strong>shade</strong> for your plants when temperatures are predicted to remain above 32 degrees Celsius for several days. Attach a piece of 40 to 50 percent shade cloth to stakes inserted into the ground around the plant. Leave it in place from 12 to 4 p.m., when the sun is at its strongest. Then remove it to avoid problems caused by a lack of sunlight.</p>
<p>And, when harvesting your crop, remember: the funny-looking tomatoes taste just as good!</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for the Associated Press. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nutritional </strong><em>– adj. </em>containing nutrients that support health and growth</p>
<p><strong>internal </strong><em>– adj. </em>inside of something</p>
<p><strong>oddity</strong> <em>– n. </em>something strange or unusual</p>
<p><strong>heirloom</strong> <em>– adj. </em>a kind of cultivated plant that has survived for several generations usually due to the efforts of private individuals</p>
<p><strong>mutation </strong><em>– n. </em>a change especially a genetic change in a plant or animal that affects its appearance, function or structure in some way</p>
<p><strong>hybrid </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>a living thing, especially a plant, that is created by combining two different kinds of plants</p>
<p><strong>ripening </strong><em>– n. </em>the process in fruit of becoming ready to eat or use</p>
<p><strong>blossom </strong><em>–n.</em> the flower formed by a plant to produce a fruit</p>
<p><strong>shade </strong><em>– n. </em>an area blocked from sunlight</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Citizenship Test Changes Might Require Better English Skills  (2023/9/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/citizenship-test-changes-might-require-better-english-skills.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United States admitted over 967,000 people as new citizens in 2022.</p>
<p>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) said that was the largest number of people <strong>naturalized</strong> since 2008.</p>
<p>To become a U.S. citizen, a candidate needs to live in the country as a permanent <strong>resident</strong> for at least five years and be over 18 years old. After applying, a candidate for citizenship needs to pass an interview with a USCIS officer.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A participant from Bangladesh takes the Naturalization Oath of Allegiance to the United States of America, on June 30, 2017, during a naturalization ceremony at the New York Public Library in New York. (AP Photo/Michael Noble Jr.)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fad7-08dbb9246924_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A participant from Bangladesh takes the Naturalization Oath of Allegiance to the United States of America, on June 30, 2017, during a naturalization ceremony at the New York Public Library in New York. (AP Photo/Michael Noble Jr.)</span></div>
<p>In the interview, an official <strong>assesses </strong>the person for their English ability, knowledge of American history and government, and personal background. Over 96 percent of people pass the naturalization test. But changes are coming to the test that could make it more difficult for English learners.</p>
<p>Carolyn Quinn and John Schmelzer teach a free class in Montgomery County, Maryland, to help prepare people living in the area for the interview. They said it is most important that people are able to understand the questions the interviewer is asking. It is not as important to speak in grammatically correct sentences. The question the interview is trying to answer is: "Do these people understand enough English to be a <strong>functioning</strong> citizen?" Schmelzer said.</p>
<p>At the beginning of each class, Quinn and Schmelzer ask their students simple "small talk" questions they might hear in the interview, like "How did you get here today?" or "Why do you want to become a United States citizen?" Much of the interview is based on questions on the Application for Naturalization Form, called the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uscis.gov/sites/default/files/document/forms/n-400instr.pdf">N-400</a>. Most are personal questions related to employment, family and personal history.</p>
<p>Rajbit Kahn took Quinn's class and passed the naturalization interview in August. She said the class gave her more <strong>confidence</strong> to speak English in the interview. Before the class, she rarely spoke English, she said. But now, "I talk to anyone."</p>
<p>However, Quinn stresses to her students that her class is not an English class. And she has students enter her class without enough English knowledge to pass the interview.</p>
<p>With the increase in Afghan immigrants into the United States, Quinn said she has had a few Afghan women come into her class. She said, "They never had any kind of schooling. So, they don't know how to write. They don't know how to read. They don't know letter sounds." Often, family members with better English skills will fill out the N-400 <strong>form</strong> for them. But they would be unable to answer the interview questions themselves.</p>
<p>Possible changes to the naturalization interview would make civics questions multiple choice to "reflect current best practices in test design," USCIS said in a document explaining the update to the test. Schmelzer said that would make the test harder for immigrants who may not have a great understanding of American history or English.</p>
<p>For now, students memorize 100 <strong>civics</strong> questions. Ten of the questions will be asked on the day of the interview and applicants must answer six correctly to pass. One question is "Name one war fought by the United States in the 1800s." Currently, people just need to memorize one war fought during that 100-year period. But a multiple-choice test would require knowledge of four wars presented as answer choices and know which one was fought in the 1800s.</p>
<p>"You're forcing them to expand their memorization," Schmelzer said.</p>
<p>Another proposed change would add a speaking test to assess English ability. The officer would present three photos and the interviewee would have to describe what is happening in the pictures. Currently, English knowledge is assessed through questions from the N-400 and other small-talk questions.</p>
<p>The new interview changes are currently being tested in several locations around the country. USCIS will hear <strong>feedback</strong> about the tests before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Quinn and Schmelzer said the test should be updated. Just one civics question is related to a female American historical figure, Schmelzer said.</p>
<p>But Quinn questions what is to be gained by making changes to the test to make it harder.</p>
<p>People in her class "put their souls" into becoming citizens. "How much more do we need to ask them to do?" she said.</p>
<p>John Yepow is another of Quinn's students who along with his wife, recently became a U.S. citizen. Yepow came from the Democratic Republic of Congo. He lived in Zambia for 10 years before moving to the United States.</p>
<p>Yepow, who works as a medication technician, said he follows American politics closely. He calls himself a lifelong learner and has even taken online classes about American history.</p>
<p>"I want to learn and make sure I'm <strong>integrated</strong> into American society," he said.</p>
<p>Yepow added: "This is the land of <strong>opportunity</strong>. We are dreaming big." He said he will make sure to <strong>take advantage </strong>of every opportunity."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Mateo</p>
<p>And I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>naturalize </strong><em>— v. </em>to be permitted to become a citizen of a country that you were not born in or did not have citizenship in before</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>to lawfully live in a place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>assess </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to make a judgement about a person or a thing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>functioning </strong>–adj. able to carry out the necessary requirements</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>confidence </strong><em>–n.</em> a feeling that you can do something correctly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>form </strong>–n. an official document that is used to get information about a person</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>civics </strong>–n. the study of the rights and duties of a citizen and how government is supposed to work</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>feedback </strong><em>— n. </em>information that is given to a person about their performance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>integrate </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to become a functioning part of a larger group</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>opportunity </strong><em>— n. </em>a chance to succeed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>take advantage of </strong><em>— v. </em>to use something in a way that help you</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Senate Permits More Clothing Choices  (2023/9/20) | 美国参议院放宽着装要求</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-senate-permits-more-clothing-choices.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The U.S. Senate's majority leader said this week that the legislative body will no longer enforce a dress code on its floor. A dress code is a set of rules about what may and may not be worn.<br/>
美国参议院多数党领袖本周表示，该立法机构将不再强制执行着装规定。着装规定是一套关于可以穿什么和不可以穿什么的规则。</p>
<p>Senator Chuck Schumer, the majority leader, said in a statement, "Senators are able to choose what they wear on the Senate floor. I will continue to wear a suit."<br/>
多数党领袖、参议员查克·舒默在一份声明中说：“参议员可以选择他们在参议院的穿着。我将继续穿西装。”</p>
<p>The change comes after Senator John Fetterman, a Democrat from Pennsylvania, has been voting from the doorways of the Senate to avoid violating the dress code. While other senators wear business clothes or dresses in the Capitol building, Fetterman usually wears informal clothes like shorts at work.<br/>
此前，宾夕法尼亚州民主党参议员约翰·费特曼一直在参议院门口参加投票，以避免违反着装规定。当其他参议员在国会大厦穿着职业装或正装时，费特曼通常在工作时穿着短裤等非正式服装。</p>
<p>Schumer did not talk about Fetterman in his statement about the dress code. But the loosening of the dress code will only apply to senators, not other employees.<br/>
舒默在关于着装规定的声明中没有提及费特曼。但放宽着装规定只适用于参议员，而不适用于其他雇员。</p>
<p>During his campaign for the U.S. Senate, Fetterman suffered a stroke, a serious medical condition that happens when the brain does not get enough oxygen from the blood. Earlier this year, Fetterman checked himself into a hospital for treatment on depression.<br/>
费特曼在竞选美国参议员期间中风，当大脑无法从血液中获得足够的氧气时就会发生这种严重的疾病。今年年初，费特曼住进了一家医院接受抑郁症治疗。</p>
<p>When Fetterman returned from treatment, he started wearing more informal clothes, which he says make him more comfortable.<br/>
当费特曼治疗结束后，他开始穿非正式服装，他说这让他更舒服。</p>
<p>The changes in dress code were met with disapproval from some of the Senate's more formal members.<br/>
着装规定的改变遭到了参议院一些较庄重议员的反对。</p>
<p>Kansas Sen. Roger Marshall, a Republican, said it is a "sad day in the Senate" and that the people who Fetterman and Schumer represent should be embarrassed.<br/>
堪萨斯州共和党参议员罗杰·马歇尔表示，这是“参议院令人悲伤的一天”，费特曼和舒默所代表的人群应该感到尴尬。</p>
<p>Republican Sen. Susan Collins of Maine agreed, arguing that the new rules discredit what the Senate represents. "I plan to wear a bikini tomorrow to the Senate floor," Collins joked. A bikini is what one wears when swimming.<br/>
缅因州共和党参议员苏珊·柯林斯对此表示赞同，认为新规定不符合参议院的形象。柯林斯开玩笑说：“我计划明天穿比基尼去参议院。”比基尼是游泳时穿的。</p>
<p>Fetterman said he was not sure if he would start making use of the new rules just yet. He said it is nice to have them as a choice, but he plans to not use them very often and not overuse them.<br/>
费特曼表示，他还不确定自己是否会开始利用新规则。他说，有选择总是好事，但他计划不经常利用它们，也不过度利用它们。</p>
<p>Fetterman said of his critics, "They're freaking out, I don't understand it." He said there are more important things they should be working on instead of what he wears.<br/>
费特曼谈到他的批评者时说：“他们吓坏了，我对此很是不明白。”他说，他们应该做一些更重要的事情，而不是盯着他的穿着。</p>
<p>Not all Republicans were troubled by the change. Missouri Sen. Josh Hawley was wearing jeans on Monday evening. He says he normally wears informal clothes when he flies in from his home state for the first votes of the week.<br/>
并非所有共和党人都对这一变化感到不安。密苏里州参议员乔什·霍利周一晚上穿着牛仔裤。他说，当他从家乡飞过来参加一周的首次投票时，他通常会穿着非正式的衣服。</p>
<p>"Now I can vote from the Senate floor on Mondays," Hawley said, noting that he usually wears a suit and tie every other day. A tie is a piece of formal clothing.<br/>
霍利说：“现在周一我可以在参议院投票了，”他指出，他通常每隔一天就穿西装打领带。领带是正装配饰。</p>
<p>Nearby, Connecticut Sen. Chris Murphy was also without a tie. The Democrat said he has gotten in trouble with the Senate's official clothes police, called Sergeant-at-Arms, in the past for not wearing a tie on the floor.<br/>
邻近的康涅狄格州参议员克里斯·墨菲也不打领带。这位民主党人说，他过去曾因在参议院不打领带而与“纠仪长”发生过冲突。</p>
<p>"They would tell us when we were doing it wrong," Murphy said.<br/>
墨菲说：“他们会在我们穿错时告诉我们。”</p>
<p>It is unclear if the rules for more formal wear were actually written down anywhere. But Schumer's statement means employees will no longer criticize senators for their choice of clothing or ask them to vote from the doorway.<br/>
目前尚不清楚正式着装要求是否有明文规定。但舒默的声明意味着员工将不再批评参议员的服装选择，也不再要求他们在门口参加投票。</p>
<p>"I think we should all want to be more comfortable," Fetterman told a group of reporters on Monday. He added that now that they have that choice, and if people want to wear a suit, "... then that's great."<br/>
费特曼周一对记者们说：“我认为我们应该都想更舒适。”他补充说，现在他们有了这样的选择，如果人们想穿西装，“……那就太好了。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India, Canada Expel Diplomats over Killing of Sikh Activist  (2023/9/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/india-canada-expel-diplomats-over-killing-of-sikh-activist.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>India expelled a Canadian diplomat Tuesday and accused Canada of interfering in its <strong>internal</strong> affairs.</p>
<p>The move came one day after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said his government was investigating a possible connection between India and the killing of a Sikh activist, Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>
<p>Nijjar, a Canadian citizen, was an activist in the Sikh independence movement. He was shot to death on June 18 outside a Sikh cultural center in Surrey, British Columbia.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A sign outside the Guru Nanak Sikh Gurdwara temple is seen after the killing on its grounds in June 2023 of Sikh leader Hardeep Singh Nijjar, in Surrey, British Columbia, Canada September 18, 2023. (REUTERS/Chris Helgren)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5b508147-97c3-4c93-817b-060f003da28a_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A sign outside the Guru Nanak Sikh Gurdwara temple is seen after the killing on its grounds in June 2023 of Sikh leader Hardeep Singh Nijjar, in Surrey, British Columbia, Canada September 18, 2023. (REUTERS/Chris Helgren)
</span></div>
<p>Canada expelled a top Indian diplomat in protest.</p>
<p>The Indian government has denied any involvement in Nijjar's killing. But Trudeau said, "We are simply laying out the facts as we understand them." He added, "We want to work with the government of India to lay everything clear and to ensure there are proper processes."</p>
<p>India has repeatedly accused Canada of supporting the Sikh independence movement, called Khalistan. The movement is banned in India but has support among the Sikhs living in other countries.</p>
<p>In 2020, the Hindu nationalist government of Prime Minister Narendra Modi called Nijjar a terrorist. Indian media reported that he was suspected of organizing a bombing in Punjab, India, and training terrorists in a small area near Vancouver, Canada.</p>
<p><strong>What is the Khalistan movement?</strong></p>
<p>The Sikh independence movement began as an armed <strong>insurgency</strong> in the 1980s among Sikhs demanding a separate homeland. It was centered in northern Punjab state, where Sikhs are the majority. Sikhs make up about 1.7 percent of India's total population.</p>
<p>In 1984, Indian forces attacked the Golden Temple, Sikhism's holiest religious center, in order to capture separatists who had taken refuge there. The government reported around 400 killed in the operation. But Sikh groups say thousands were killed. The dead included Sikh militant leader Jarnail Singh Bhindranwale, whom the Indian government accused of leading the armed insurgency.</p>
<p>On October 31, 1984, Prime Minister Indira Gandhi, who ordered the attack on the temple, was <strong>assassinated</strong> by two of her bodyguards, who were Sikhs.</p>
<p>Her death led to several anti-Sikh riots. Crowds of Hindus went from house to house across northern India, pulling Sikhs from their homes and killing them.</p>
<p>There is no active insurgency in Punjab today, but the Khalistan movement still has supporters in India and abroad. And Prime Minister Narendra Modi's government has also arrested leaders from groups that are linked to the movement.</p>
<p><strong>How strong is the movement outside India?</strong></p>
<p>India has been asking countries like Canada, Australia and Britain to take legal action against Sikh activists. India has raised these concerns with Canada, where 770,000 Sikhs make up nearly two percent of the country's population.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Sikh protesters removed an Indian flag and broke the window at the country's office in London to protest the arrest of a Sikh religious leader. Protesters also smashed windows at the Indian consulate in San Francisco and fought with embassy workers.</p>
<p>The Indian government has accused Khalistan supporters in Canada of damaging Hindu temples with "anti-India" graffiti and of attacking India's diplomatic office in Ottawa during a protest in March.</p>
<p>Last year, Paramjit Singh Panjwar, a Sikh militant leader and head of the Khalistan Commando Force, was shot dead in Pakistan.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>internal </strong>–adj. taking place inside a country or organization<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>insurgency</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>usually a violent attempt or long militant effort to take control of a government or area; a rebellion</p>
<p><strong>assassinate</strong><em> –v.</em> to kill someone for political reasons</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Costa Rica, Natural Farms Provide Refuge for Birds  (2023/9/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/in-costa-rica-natural-farms-provide-refuge-for-birds.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Small farms with natural trees and forests that block sunlight can provide a refuge for some bird populations, a study in Costa Rica found.</p>
<p>For 18 years, bird expert James Zook has been collecting records on nearly 430 kinds of <strong>tropical </strong>birds found on farms and natural forests in the Central American country.</p>
<p>While birds do best in natural rainforests, Zook said some <strong>species</strong> usually found in forests can establish populations in "diversified farms." Diversified farms are farms that contain areas similar to a natural forest environment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo provided by researchers shows a royal flycatcher bird in Las Cruces Biological Station in Coto Brus, Costa Rica in March 2018. (J. Nicholas Hendershot via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f8e04fa9-daf7-496c-89bf-eaa17f47f1c6_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo provided by researchers shows a royal flycatcher bird in Las Cruces Biological Station in Coto Brus, Costa Rica in March 2018. (J. Nicholas Hendershot via AP)</span></div>
<p>"How you farm matters," said Nicholas Hendershot. He is a Stanford University environmental scientist. He helped write the study published recently in <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.</em></p>
<p>"In these diversified farms, you see growth over the long term in bird species with specialized needs," Hendershot said. These specialized needs include safe and protected areas from the sun for birds to build their homes and different kinds of food sources.</p>
<p>That kind of farming is very different to industrial agriculture or agriculture where only one crop like pineapple or bananas are planted, he said.</p>
<p>Natalia Ocampo-Penuela is a University of California, Santa Cruz environmental scientist who was not involved in the study. She said the findings may seem to make sense without research. But she added that it is very rare to have detailed data over a long time from tropical areas to show that diversified farming can support some forest bird populations.</p>
<p>"With 18 years of data, you can show the species is <strong>persisting</strong> in that area, not simply passing by," she said.</p>
<p>Of the 305 species found in diversified farms, 75 percent showed <strong>stable</strong> or growing populations over the time of study. These include birds like the collared aracari as well as several members of the manakin family – colorful birds known for their complex mating dances.</p>
<p>Ruth Bennett is a scientist at the Smithsonian Migratory Bird Center. She was not involved in the research. She said, "It's a huge <strong>contribution</strong> to have documented that some birds aren't just going there, but staying there and populations are growing,"</p>
<p>Still, such safe environments, called habitats, do not balance out overall population losses from the creation of large industrial farms from natural forests, the writers warned. Zook compared a large pineapple farm to a "bird desert."</p>
<p>Increasingly, scientists say saving species will require paying attention to areas affected by humans, not just untouched areas.</p>
<p>Ocampo-Penuela said modern efforts to save species have to happen not only inside protected areas, but also within agricultural areas and even cities. She said these efforts have to happen where there is at least a possibility that some species could live there.</p>
<p>I'm Greg Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>the tropics </strong><em>– n.</em> the part of the world that is near the equator where the weather is very warm</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>persist</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to continue to do something or to try to do something even though it is difficult or other people want you to stop</p>
<p><strong>stable </strong><em>– adj.</em> in a good state or condition that is not easily changed or likely to change</p>
<p><strong>contribution </strong><em>– n.</em> something that is done to cause something to happen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Who Should Get the Updated COVID Shot?  (2023/9/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/who-should-get-the-updated-covid-shot.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>American health officials say most people should get the updated COVID-19 vaccine this year.</p>
<p>Last week, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) approved the updated COVID-19 shots from Pfizer and its partner BioNTech as well as from Moderna. A third vaccine from Novavax remains under study.</p>
<p><strong>Who should get the updated vaccines?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo provided by Pfizer in September 2023 shows single-dose vials of the company's updated COVID vaccine for adults. U.S. regulators have approved updated COVID-19 vaccines from Pfizer and Moderna, shots. (Pfizer via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1e81-08dbb56e57e8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo provided by Pfizer in September 2023 shows single-dose vials of the company's updated COVID vaccine for adults. U.S. regulators have approved updated COVID-19 vaccines from Pfizer and Moderna, shots. (Pfizer via AP)</span></div>
<p>U.S. health officials approved the shots for adults and children as young as six months old. They said starting at age five, most people can get a single shot even if they have never had a COVID-19 shot. Younger children might need more shots depending on their history of COVID-19 infections and vaccinations.</p>
<p>CDC Director Mandy Cohen said last month that she expects the COVID shots to be given yearly like the flu vaccines. However, not all doctors agree that everyone needs them every year.</p>
<p>Dr. William Schaffner, an infectious diseases specialist at Vanderbilt University, is an advisor to the CDC. He said, "If you're six months of age or older, you should get a flu vaccine. Sounds good to me for COVID also."</p>
<p>Another CDC advisor is Dr. Paul Offit, a University of Pennsylvania infectious disease expert. He said he believes the shots should be given yearly to high-risk groups. Studies have not shown the updated shots protect against disease in lower-risk populations, Offit said.</p>
<p>In Britain, the British government's vaccine committee said only adults 65 and older and people at risk will be offered the shot as they are the most likely to benefit.</p>
<p><strong>Will the shots be effective?</strong></p>
<p>Unlike last year's shot which targeted both the <strong>original</strong> virus and the Omicron <strong>variant</strong>, the updated shot takes aim at an Omicron sub-variant named XBB.1.5. The drug companies added that early testing has shown that the updated shots work against the latest sub-variant BA.2.86.</p>
<p>Officials from the World Health Organization (WHO) recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/new-covid-19-variant-expands-internationally/7247990.html">said BA.2.86 has already been identified in several countries</a>, including the United States, Switzerland, South Africa, Israel, Denmark and Britain.</p>
<p>The severity of the COVID-19 pandemic has decreased. But WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said the new COVID-19 variants show that the virus remains a health threat around the world.</p>
<p>The CDC said last month that only 42 percent of people said in a study that they would or probably would get the new vaccine. Yet only about 20 percent of American adults got an updated shot, called a booster, when it was offered a year ago.</p>
<p>Doctors hope enough people will get vaccinated to help avoid another "tripledemic" like last year. At that time, U.S. hospitals said they had to deal with an early flu season, a rise in respiratory syncytial virus known as RSV, and another sudden increase in coronavirus cases.</p>
<p>This year, hospitals in the U.S. reported a small increase in COVID-19 patients over the summer. But the number was much smaller than the year before. Officials said earlier vaccinations or infections have helped prevent severe disease and death. But most Americans have not had a vaccination in about a year.</p>
<p>The CDC says that people can get a yearly flu shot and the updated COVID shot at the same time. The agency says there is no difference in effectiveness or side effects.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and Reuters sources. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>original</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj. </em>happening or existing first</p>
<p><strong>variant</strong> <em>–v.</em> something that is a little different from members of a group of similar things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pope Welcomes Russia’s New Ambassador to Vatican  (2023/9/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/pope-welcomes-russia-s-new-ambassador-to-vatican.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Pope Francis has officially welcomed Russia's new ambassador to the Vatican.</p>
<p>The leader of the Roman Catholic Church met with Ambassador Ivan Soltanovsky Monday in Vatican City as the diplomat presented his official documents.</p>
<p>Soltanovsky is replacing Ambassador Alexander Avdeev. Avdeev met with Francis in February 2022 at Russia's Embassy in Rome, the day after Russian forces invaded Ukraine.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pope Francis meets with Russian ambassador to the Vatican Ivan Soltanovsky at the Vatican, September 18, 2023. (Vatican Media/&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;173;Handout via REUTERS) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-49c3-08dbb86ef1e8_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pope Francis meets with Russian ambassador to the Vatican Ivan Soltanovsky at the Vatican, September 18, 2023. (Vatican Media/<i>&amp;#</i>173;Handout via REUTERS) </span></div>
<p>Soltanovsky's visit came shortly after Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov said the government was ready to meet again with the Catholic Church's Ukraine peace <strong>envoy</strong>, Cardinal Matteo Zuppi.</p>
<p>"The Vatican is continuing its efforts. The papal envoy will come back (to Russia) soon," Lavrov said last Friday. He was speaking to a group of diplomats and ambassadors during a discussion about Ukraine in Moscow.</p>
<p>Zuppi was appointed by Pope Francis in May. Since then, he has visited the Ukrainian capital Kyiv, as well as Moscow, Washington D.C. and Beijing.</p>
<p>At first, Zuppi's efforts seemed centered on a program that seeks to reunite Ukrainian children taken to Russia after the invasion of Ukraine. However, the diplomat also discussed restarting grain exports from Ukraine's Black Sea ports during talks with Chinese officials in Beijing.</p>
<p>When he returned to Italy, Zuppi said his talks in Beijing resulted in an important sharing of ideas. He also expressed hope about Lavrov's comments about a second visit. During a trip to Moscow in June, Zuppi met with Russia's minister for children's rights, Maria Lvova-Belova, and an adviser to President Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>The International Criminal Court issued an arrest warrant in late March for Lvova-Belova and Putin. The court accused them of kidnapping children from Ukraine. Russian officials have denied organizing any forced <strong>adoptions </strong>during the war.</p>
<p>Zuppi spoke to the TV2000 broadcaster of the Italian bishops conference over the weekend. He said Lavrov's openness to a second meeting was "important because peace is made through <strong>dialogue</strong> and finding the possible and necessary spaces."</p>
<p>Francis has followed the Holy See's tradition of neutrality in conflicts by trying to keep open paths of negotiation with both Ukraine and Russia.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>envoy</strong><em> –n. </em>someone sent to represent their government in another country</p>
<p><strong>adoption </strong><em>– n. </em>a legal process in which individuals officially become the parents of someone else's child</p>
<p><strong>dialogue </strong><em>– n. </em>a official discussion between countries or groups of people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>U.S., Iran to Exchange Prisoners  (2023/9/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/u-s-iran-to-exchange-prisoners.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken announced that seven Americans have been released by Iran after the nations agreed to a prisoner exchange also involving Qatar and South Korea.</p>
<p>South Korea said on Monday it is working with the United States and Iran to release restrictions on $6 billion of frozen Iranian money. The U.S. is releasing the money as part of the prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>The money is being <strong>transferred</strong> to Qatar. Then, seven people with <strong>dual</strong> U.S. citizenship, who have been imprisoned or detained in Iran, are expected to leave Tehran for Doha. Officials told <em>Reuters </em>news service that, from there, they will travel to the United States. Qatar <strong>mediated</strong> the deal during months of talks.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo published August 11, 2022 shows the spokesman of the Iranian Ministry of the Exterior. (Iranian Ministry of the Exterior, via AP Archives)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7e0c-08dbb862e978_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">In this photo published August 11, 2022 shows the spokesman of the Iranian Ministry of the Exterior. (Iranian Ministry of the Exterior, via AP Archives)</span></div>
<p>In return, five Iranians detained in the U.S. will be released so they can travel to Iran. Iranian officials and Iran's state news agency have said one of those detainees is expected to remain in the United States.</p>
<p>The exact timing of the transfer of the money has yet to be announced.</p>
<p>The deal was first made public on August 10. But the countries continue to disagree on many issues. They include Iran's nuclear program, Iran's effort to influence the Persian Gulf area, U.S. <strong>sanctions</strong> and America's military presence in the Persian Gulf.</p>
<p>South Korea is "currently making efforts to ensure smooth progress of all procedures so that it will be resolved once and for all," the country's foreign ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>The U.S. dual citizens to be released include 51-year-old Siamak Namazi and 59-year-old Emad Sharqi, both businessmen, and 67-year-old Morad Tahbaz, an environmentalist. Tahbaz also holds British nationality. Iran released them from prison and put them under house arrest last month.</p>
<p>A fourth U.S. citizen was also released into house arrest, while a fifth was already under house arrest. Their identities have not been released.</p>
<p>Iranian officials named the five Iranians to be released by the U.S. as: Mehrdad Moin-Ansari, Kambiz Attar-Kashani, Reza Sarhangpour-Kafrani, Amin Hassanzadeh and Kaveh Afrasiabi. Two Iranian officials said Afrasiabi would remain in the United States.</p>
<p>As a first step in the deal, the United States suspended sanctions to permit the transfer of $6 billion in Iranian money from South Korea to Qatar. The money had been blocked in South Korea, which is normally one of Iran's largest oil buyers, because of U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Qatar agreed to <strong>monitor</strong> how Iran uses the money to ensure it goes to non-sanctioned humanitarian goods, like food and medicine.</p>
<p>The transfer of Iran's money has faced criticism from U.S. lawmakers including opposition Republican Party members. They said the deal is equal to paying a <strong>ransom</strong> for U.S. citizens. The administration of President Joe Biden has defended the deal.</p>
<p>Qatar held at least eight sets of talks involving Iranian and U.S. negotiators. The negotiators worked from separate hotels. People told <em>Reuters</em> that they exchanged proposals through Qatari mediators. Earlier talks dealt mainly with the nuclear issue. Later, talks turned to the prisoner releases.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hyonhee Shin reported this story for Reuters. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transfer </strong>–v. to move something from one place to another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dual </strong><em>— adj. </em>having qualities of two different things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mediate </strong><em>— v. </em>to aid negotiations between sides opposing sides in an effort to reach an agreement</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sanction </strong><em>—n.</em> measures taken against a country or individual aimed at making them observe local or international law usually in the form of economic restrictions</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>monitor</strong><em> </em>–v. to watch or observe for a special purpose over a long period of time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ransom </strong><em>— n. </em>money that is paid to free someone who has been captured or kidnapped</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA: Oxygen-producing Device on Mars Performed above Expectations  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/nasa-oxygen-producing-device-on-mars-performed-above-expectations.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA says a device placed on Mars to produce oxygen has performed better than expected in a series of experiments.</p>
<p>The system is called MOXIE. It is designed to change, or convert, carbon dioxide captured from the Mars atmosphere into oxygen. The instrument works through a process called electrolysis. This process uses extreme heat to separate oxygen atoms from molecules of carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Carbon dioxide makes up about 95 percent of the Martian atmosphere, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2019/with-mars-methane-mystery-unsolved-curiosity-serves-scientists-a-new-one-oxygen">reports</a>. The rest is mostly molecular nitrogen and argon. Molecular oxygen makes up just 0.16 percent of the Martian atmosphere.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Technicians at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory lower the MOXIE instrument into the belly of the Perseverance rover in an undated photograph in Pasadena, California. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4b93-08dbb60f23f3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Technicians at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory lower the MOXIE instrument into the belly of the Perseverance rover in an undated photograph in Pasadena, California. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>But future exploration of Mars and possibly other planets by humans will require a large supply of oxygen. NASA has said the chemical element will be necessary for astronauts to breathe and to produce rocket fuel for launches carried out from the Martian surface.</p>
<p>NASA financed the MOXIE demonstration experiment. A team from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) created the device.</p>
<p>The MOXIE instrument was carried to Mars aboard NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover. Perseverance arrived on the Red Planet in February 2021. The device is a box-shaped instrument attached to the rover.</p>
<p>NASA reported its first results with the MOXIE system in April 2021. At the time, the space agency reported the device had successfully converted carbon dioxide from the Martian atmosphere into oxygen. In the first experiment, MOXIE produced 5.4 grams of oxygen in one hour. NASA then carried out a series of additional experiments to test the effectiveness of the system.</p>
<p>In a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/nasa-s-oxygen-generating-experiment-moxie-completes-mars-mission">statement</a> issued earlier this month, leaders of the demonstration project said MOXIE had completed its 16th and final experiment. They noted the device's "<strong>impressive</strong> performance" had proven it was possible to capture oxygen from the Martian atmosphere. Such oxygen "could help supply breathable air or rocket <strong>propellant</strong> to future astronauts," the statement said.</p>
<p>NASA said that MOXIE had produced a total of 122 grams of oxygen since Perseverance landed on Mars. This amount is about what a small dog would breathe in 10 hours. While the amount of oxygen is small, it represented the first experimental capture of a natural resource from the environment of another planet.</p>
<p>When working at its highest level of effectiveness, the instrument was able to produce 12 grams of oxygen in one hour. NASA says this is twice as much as its engineers first estimated the system could produce.</p>
<p>The MOXIE team has also been measuring the purity of the oxygen the device produces. Overall, it has reported the instrument produced oxygen that was at least 98 percent pure.</p>
<p>The latest experiments with MOXIE on Mars are designed to help NASA build a much larger version of the system. A full-sized device could be deployed on Mars in the future.</p>
<p>A NASA explanation of the instrument states: "The goal of a Big MOXIE would be to make and store all the oxygen that the astronaut and their rocket would need for their <strong>mission</strong> before they even launch." Such a system would need to make between 2,000 to 3,000 grams of oxygen per hour, the space agency noted.</p>
<p>Trudy Kortes is the director of technology demonstrations at NASA Headquarters in Washington D.C. She said the agency was pleased to be able to support such a technology. "By proving this technology in real-world conditions, we've come one step closer to a future in which astronauts ‘live off the land' on the Red Planet," Kortes said.</p>
<p>MIT's Michael Hecht leads the MOXIE development operation. He said in a statement the team's work will next center on working on the larger version of MOXIE. In addition, scientists will need to create equipment to liquefy and store the produced oxygen.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impressive </strong><em>– adj. </em>making or attempting to make a marked impression</p>
<p><strong>propellant </strong><em>– n. </em>an explosive substance of fuel that causes something to move forward</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>a flight by an aircraft or spacecraft to perform a specific task</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rights Groups: Mining in the DRC Threatens Human Rights  (2023/9/18) | 人权组织称刚果采矿威胁人权</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rights-groups-mining-in-the-drc-threatens-human-rights.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rights groups say mining cobalt and copper in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, known as the DRC, has led to human rights abuses.<br/>
人权组织表示，在刚果民主共和国开采钴和铜导致了侵犯人权的行为。</p>
<p>London-based Amnesty International and a rights group based in the DRC released a report on the issue on September 11. It said mining companies forcibly removed people from their homes and farmland. Many of those affected said they were not paid enough.<br/>
总部位于伦敦的大赦国际和总部位于刚果民主共和国的一家人权组织于9月11日就此问题发布了一项报告。报告称，矿业公司强行将人们从家中和农田中赶走。许多受此影响的人士表示，他们未得到足够赔偿。</p>
<p>The recent report also said people were attacked, including sexually attacked, and also had their property destroyed or damaged.<br/>
最近的报告还说，人们遭到袭击，包括性侵，他们的财产也遭到破坏。</p>
<p>Cobalt is an element needed for long-lasting batteries in things like electric vehicles and similar technologies. The DRC is believed to have more cobalt than any other country in the world. The country is also Africa's top producer of copper, which is needed in the electrical industry.<br/>
钴是电动汽车和类似技术中的长效电池所需的元素。据信，刚果民主共和国的钴储量超过了世界上任何其他国家。该国也是非洲最大的铜生产国，电力行业需要铜。</p>
<p>Criticism of the trade in cobalt, copper and other minerals in the DRC is not new. Amnesty International accused the cobalt mining industry there of using child labor in 2016.<br/>
对刚果民主共和国钴、铜和其他矿产贸易的批评并不是什么新鲜事。大赦国际在2016年指责那里的钴矿业使用童工。</p>
<p>In July, the U.S. House of Representatives introduced a measure to ban imported products containing cobalt and copper mined through child labor or other abusive conditions in the DRC.<br/>
7月，美国众议院出台了一项措施，禁止进口刚果民主共和国含有通过童工或其他虐待条件下所开采钴和铜的产品。</p>
<p>Amnesty International has also reported many incidents of violence related to mining activity. In 2016, it said soldiers burned down a settlement to begin work on a cobalt and copper mine. The fire left a two-year-old girl with scars that will affect her for the rest of her life.<br/>
大赦国际还报告了许多与采矿活动有关的暴力事件。据报道，2016年，士兵们烧毁了一个定居点，以便开始开采钴铜矿。大火给一名两岁女孩留下了伤痕，这将影响她的余生。</p>
<p>The rights groups said they talked to 133 people during separate visits in February and September 2022. The people were in six places around Kolwezi, a city in the south of the country, and were affected by the abuses related to cobalt and copper mining.<br/>
人权组织表示，他们在2022年2月和9月的单独访问中与133人进行了交谈。这些人生活在该国南部城市科尔韦齐周边的六个地方，受到了与钴和铜矿开采有关的虐待行为的影响。</p>
<p>One neighborhood, home to 39,000 people, has been facing destruction because of the expansion of a copper and cobalt mine since 2015.<br/>
自2015年以来，由于一座铜钴矿的扩建，一处居住着39000人的社区一直面临着破坏。</p>
<p>The rights groups studied documents, photos, videos, satellite images and company communications.<br/>
人权组织研究了文件、照片、视频、卫星图像和企业通信。</p>
<p>Amnesty International said companies are not doing enough to deal with human rights concerns. Chemaf is a cobalt and copper mining company based in Dubai that operates in the DRC.<br/>
大赦国际表示，企业在处理人权问题上做得不够。Chemaf是一家总部位于迪拜的钴和铜矿开采公司，该公司在刚果民主共和国开展业务。</p>
<p>Following protests in 2019, the company paid $1.5 million to former residents through local officials. People received between $50 and $300. But the report said that was not enough. None of the former residents were able to secure good housing.<br/>
在2019年的抗议活动之后，该公司通过当地官员向原先的居民支付了150万美元。人们收到了50到300美元。但报告称这还不够。原先的居民没人能够获得良好的住房。</p>
<p>The rights groups said the world is demanding more "green" technologies that are not linked to climate change. However, the mining of minerals that are needed for these green technologies are causing social and environmental harm.<br/>
人权组织表示，世界正在要求更多与气候变化无关的“绿色”技术。然而，这些绿色技术所需的矿产开采正在造成社会和环境危害。</p>
<p>The group said removing carbon from the world economy "must not lead to further human rights violations."<br/>
该组织表示，从世界经济中消除碳“绝不能导致进一步侵犯人权”。</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Letting Mosquitoes Bite You for Science  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/letting-mosquitoes-bite-you-for-science.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>It is lunchtime. And mosquitoes find their way to Ella Branham's arm at a Salt Lake City lab in the American state of Utah.</p>
<p>"They're not very aggressive and they're kind of <strong>picky</strong> eaters," said Branham. She breathed into a glass tank to attract the insects to the carbon dioxide in her breath. "So I'll be feeding them with my arm."</p>
<p>Branham had volunteered to let the South American mosquitoes, called sabethes cyaneus, feed on her blood. She is doing so to help produce eggs and maintain the colony for education and research at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A colony of sabethes cyaneus mosquitoes feed on Ella Branham at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District on Monday, Aug. 28, 2023, in Salt Lake City. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9db9-08dbb5e82ffe_cx6_cy15_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A colony of sabethes cyaneus mosquitoes feed on Ella Branham at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District on Monday, Aug. 28, 2023, in Salt Lake City. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)</span></div>
<p>The <strong>district</strong> is one of many mosquito control areas around the United States that seek to control one of the world's deadliest animals. Mosquitoes are expected to strengthen as climate change creates a warmer and wetter environment.</p>
<p>Mosquitoes can carry viruses including dengue, yellow fever, chikungunya and Zika. They are especially threatening to public health in Asia and Africa but are closely watched in the United States. Local agencies reported more than 1,100 cases of West Nile virus in 2022, says the U.S. Centers for Disease Control.</p>
<p>Most humans who get West Nile show no <strong>symptoms</strong>. But for some, it can cause <strong>vomiting, </strong>fever<strong> </strong>and in rare cases seizures or meningitis. Over roughly the last 25 years, nearly 3,000 deaths and more than 25,000 hospitalizations connected to West Nile were reported throughout the U.S., mostly in August.</p>
<p>West Nile deaths have been reported this year in states including Texas and Colorado. Mosquitoes are also thought to have caused malaria infections of people in Maryland, Florida and Texas.</p>
<p>Ary Faraji is a disease expert and the director of the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District. He said the mosquito season is starting earlier and lasting longer as the climate has warmed. The district used to shut down each year in mid-September, but that has gotten later and later. Last year, district workers were still setting and checking traps until late November.</p>
<p>And this year, workers estimated that there were five times as many mosquitos in May compared to the average year. There was an unusually snowy winter in Salt Lake City and a very rainy spring that left more water for mosquitoes to <strong>breed</strong> in.</p>
<p>That is where the health threat comes in. While both males and females feed on sugar or nectar throughout their lives, females require blood to provide nutrition to their eggs.</p>
<p>The workers, including scientists and students, use drones, boats and vehicles to trap, sort and test mosquitos for viruses. Their work considers how things like weather systems and population growth will affect the spread of disease.</p>
<p>The more people there are close to a lot of mosquitos, the higher the chance of spread, Faraji said. The wetland areas surrounding Utah's Great Salt Lake are problematic, he added.</p>
<p>Though dangerous, mosquitoes are also important to ecosystems throughout the world. Some serve as <strong>pollinators</strong> or food sources to fish, birds and frogs.</p>
<p>"We try to maintain a balance and suppress them to the point that they're not negatively affecting communities," Faraji said. "Taking them away would definitely <strong>negatively</strong> impact our ecosystem overall."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>abate </strong><em>— v. </em> to become weaker</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>district </strong><em>— n. </em>an area established by a government for official government business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>symptom </strong><em>— n. </em>a change in the body or mind which indicates that a disease is present</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vomit </strong><em>— n. </em>to have the food, liquid, etc., that is in your stomach come out through your mouth because you are sick</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breed </strong><em>— v. </em>to produce offspring by sexual reproduction</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pollinator </strong><em>— n. </em>to give pollen from another plant of the same kind so that seeds will be produced</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>negative </strong><em>— adj. </em>harmful or bad</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan Says Visitors Disrespecting Mount Fuji  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/japan-says-visitors-disrespecting-mount-fuji.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>On a gray and rainy Saturday, buses arrive continually at a base station of Japan's Mount Fuji. The buses release foreign visitors<strong> </strong>in front of stores and restaurants.</p>
<p>The area looks similar to a <strong>theme</strong><strong> park</strong>. It is not what most Japanese would expect below the 3,776-meter mountain. Mt Fuji is considered an important religious area. And Japanese honor the mountain for its perfectly balanced form.</p>
<p>"Hey, no smoking here!" a store worker told a man wearing shorts and holding a can of beer. He was standing in front of the red "torii" gate which marks the entrance to the Shinto religious center ahead.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Visitors are seen at the fifth stage on the slopes of Mount Fuji, Japan's highest mountain 3,776 metres (12,388 ft), in Fujiyoshida, Japan on September 9, 2023. (REUTERS/Mariko Katsumura)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b01167f0-ddf7-4992-8535-df76e28ac00c_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Visitors are seen at the fifth stage on the slopes of Mount Fuji, Japan's highest mountain 3,776 metres (12,388 ft), in Fujiyoshida, Japan on September 9, 2023. (REUTERS/Mariko Katsumura)</span></div>
<p>Mt Fuji sits between the Yamanashi and Shizuoka areas in eastern Japan. It has always been popular with local and foreign visitors.</p>
<p>But a recent increase in visitors to Japan has led to high levels of pollution and other difficulties, officials say. They add they may be forced to take extreme measures. They may restrict the number of visitors by limiting the only way to visit the mountain by a yet-to-be-built public transportation system.</p>
<p>"Fuji faces a real crisis," Masatake Izumi, a Yamanashi area official, told reporters recently. It was the last weekend before the paths closed for the year.</p>
<p>"It's uncontrollable and we fear that Mt Fuji will soon become so <strong>unattractive</strong>, nobody would want to climb it," he said.</p>
<p>Mt Fuji was listed as a UNESCO World Heritage area 10 years ago, further increasing its popularity. World Heritage areas are places that the UN protects for having great value to humanity.</p>
<p>But the listing came with conditions that Japan reduce the number of visitors, environmental harm from visitors, and fix man-made areas designed for visitors.</p>
<p>However, the number of visitors has increased. "Subaru," the fifth and largest base station, had about 4 million visitors this summer. That is a 50 percent increase from 2013.</p>
<p>Despite the hard work of cleaners, businesses, and volunteers, social media is filled with posts about dirty bathrooms and waste along the climbing path.</p>
<p>Izumi worries that the International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS), which advises the World Heritage Committee, could come looking for an <strong>update</strong>.</p>
<p>"Bullet climbing" is where climbers try to climb Japan's tallest mountain for sunrise and go down the mountain on the same day. Officials say that it is a growing problem as well.</p>
<p>Rescue requests totaled 61 this year, up 50 percent from last year. Non-Japanese visitors make up about 25 percent, Shizuoka area police found. An official said most were poorly equipped, suffering from cold temperatures or the height of the mountain. Yamanashi police did not have similar data.</p>
<p>One local visitor said restrictions will have to come.</p>
<p>"Any Japanese person would want to climb Mt Fuji at least once in their life," said 62-year-old Jun Shibazaki, who arrived to visit. "But it's so <strong>crowded</strong>. Limited entry might be something we have to live with."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Mariko Katsumura reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>theme park </strong><em>– n.</em> an amusement park where the rides and attractions are based on a particular theme</p>
<p><strong>unattractive </strong><em>– adj.</em> not beautiful, interesting, or pleasing</p>
<p><strong>update</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> a report that includes the most recent information about something</p>
<p><strong>crowded </strong><em>– adj.</em> filled with too many people or things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Professors Blame Pandemic for College Students’ Math Troubles  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/professors-blame-pandemic-for-college-students-math-troubles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>"This is a huge issue," said one college math professor.</p>
<p>"This is <strong>significant</strong> and deep," said another.</p>
<p>They were talking about their students who are still struggling with <strong>basic</strong> math skills three years after the start of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="George Mason undergraduate math major David Wigginton writes an equation on a whiteboard as students Ethan Hill, right, and Diego Fonseca, center, take part in a summer math boot camp on Thursday, Aug. 1, 2023 at George Mason University in Fairfax. Va. (AP Photo/Kevin Wolf)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e418dcfa-2aa1-49b0-b5a4-aa872e9fc3b6_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">George Mason undergraduate math major David Wigginton writes an equation on a whiteboard as students Ethan Hill, right, and Diego Fonseca, center, take part in a summer math boot camp on Thursday, Aug. 1, 2023 at George Mason University in Fairfax. Va. (AP Photo/Kevin Wolf)</span></div>
<p>Most of the students are in their first or second year in college. But when the pandemic started in 2020, they were still in high school, learning algebra or early calculus.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, many U.S. schools closed to in-person classes and started teaching by video call. Education experts said they believed students would catch up.</p>
<p>College professors said they hoped for a "<strong>rebound</strong>" by now. But it has not happened in most places.</p>
<p>As a result, universities in the U.S. are trying to find ways to fix the problem. Some offer summer math camps. Others called on students to learn from each other, a process known as "peer tutoring." Still others offer basic math classes students can take while also attending classes such as calculus.</p>
<p>Brian Rider is the head of the math program at Temple University near Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>"It's not that they're unprepared," he said. "They're almost damaged."</p>
<p>Rider said he hated to say that, but "they're so behind."</p>
<p><strong>One teacher's experience</strong></p>
<p>Erin Vorke is a math instructor at Eastern Florida State College. Many of her students must take a math class to get a two-year associate degree and move on to a four-year college. Some are high school students who are getting college credit. She told VOA about her experience.</p>
<p>She said some of her students did not get a good <strong>foundation</strong> in math even before the pandemic started. Once they missed time in class, their troubles increased.</p>
<p>"It's definitely become a lot worse since the pandemic. And what I've been told is that everyone was just being passed through while they were in high school...I have a lot of students who can't work with <strong>negative</strong> numbers, I have students who don't know what an <strong>even</strong> number is."</p>
<p>Vorke said she cannot stop her class to teach students something they should have learned when they were in middle school.</p>
<p>"I slow down as much as I can, but I have to cover my <strong>curriculum</strong>," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Students struggling</strong></p>
<p>Diego Fonseca is a student in northern Virginia, just outside of Washington, D.C. Nineteen-year-old Fonseca recently finished high school. This summer, he took a math "<strong>boot camp</strong>" at George Mason University so he could "<strong>brush-up</strong>" on math learning. He was one of about 100 students trying to improve their math skills.</p>
<p>He said he did well in physics and computer science while in high school, but he did not get good scores on a math placement test for college. He wanted to take calculus, but in three tries on the test, he did not get a good enough score. He was permitted to take the test four times and wanted to do better on his final attempt.</p>
<p>He was not having trouble with the math he learned recently, but he did not learn algebra well early in high school when schools closed in 2020.</p>
<p>"I didn't have a <strong>hands-on</strong>, in-person class," Fonseca said. He later said he had trouble with more difficult algebra.</p>
<p>The math troubles are a problem for students at universities across the U.S. who want to study engineering and science. Many are being placed into low math classes, which means they are falling behind in their study programs.</p>
<p>Colleges say the pandemic learning problems affected both reading and math, but math skills suffered more, and recovery has been slow.</p>
<p>Maria Emelianenko is one of the math professors at George Mason. She said students are in difficult pre-calculus and calculus classes and they cannot add simple <strong>fractions</strong>.</p>
<p>Jessica Babcock is a math professor at Temple. She said she realized how big of a problem she had while grading a test last year. Nearly all her students missed what she thought was a simple question.</p>
<p>"It was a striking moment," she said.</p>
<p>Babcock teaches a basic math class that includes material students should have learned in their first year of high school. Before the pandemic, it had about 800 students. But by 2021 there were almost 1,400.</p>
<p>Education researchers say math is a "hands-on" subject and it was hard to teach with students learning from home. If students moved on to subjects like geometry or trigonometry without learning algebra, learning gaps could go unnoticed for years. In addition, they say parents have an easier time helping their children with reading than math at home.</p>
<p><strong>'Many students gave up on math'</strong></p>
<p>Katherine Strunk is an education expert who now heads the graduate school of education at the University of Pennsylvania. She led a study that looked at learning problems in Michigan.</p>
<p>She said minority students and low-income students had the most problems during the pandemic.</p>
<p>"They're the ones who are going to suffer the longer-term <strong>consequences</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>Babcock, the Temple professor, said many students gave up on math. They did not come for help and continued getting poor grades on tests.</p>
<p>The problems made Babcock change her class this year. The class has discussions, making students more involved in the learning process.</p>
<p>"We really want students to feel like they're part of their learning," Babcock said.</p>
<p>That kind of class, said Vorke, may be more helpful for students who wonder when they will use algebra or other math in the future. She is part of a group of educators at her college who teach what she called "real-world problems (students) can actually relate to," each summer.</p>
<p>"If you go shopping, and there's a sale, and you want to figure out how much you'll be paying for an item that's 10 percent off. That's algebra," Vorke said.</p>
<p>After the summer boot camp, Fonseca said he chose to start his college studies at Northern Virginia Community College. In two years, he can move on to George Mason. He recently took the placement test again. On his final attempt, he qualified for calculus.</p>
<p>"I didn't have any expectation I'd do that," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press and his own reporting.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>significant </strong><em>–adj.</em> important in some way</p>
<p><strong>basic </strong><em>–adj.</em> simple and low-level</p>
<p><strong>rebound </strong><em>–n.</em> a return to an earlier, better condition</p>
<p><strong>foundation </strong><em>–n.</em> the base on which later learning is built</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong><em>–adj.</em> less than zero</p>
<p><strong>even </strong><em>–adj</em>. a multiple of two</p>
<p><strong>curriculum </strong><em>–n.</em> the classes that are part of a school study program</p>
<p><strong>boot camp </strong><em>–n.</em> an intensive training program aimed at getting students to become much better in a short period of time</p>
<p><strong>brush up </strong><em>–v.</em> to improve skills or knowledge usually some time after learning them</p>
<p><strong>fraction </strong><em>–n.</em> non-whole numbers that are expressed as division of one whole number into another</p>
<p><strong>hands-on </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving actually doing something rather than reading or thinking about it</p>
<p><strong>consequences </strong><em>–n. (usually pl.) </em>the results of words or actions</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Icing on the Cake' Is As Good As It Sounds  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/icing-on-the-cake-is-as-good-as-it-sounds.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore English words and expressions. We give you examples and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a <strong>delicious</strong> <strong>dessert</strong> made from flour, butter, sugar, and <strong>flavorings</strong> such as vanilla, chocolate, or my favorite, coconut. We are talking about cake!</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Cakes with different icing and flavors are for sale ahead of Valentine's Day in London, Britain, February 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Peter Nicholls)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-164b-08db0e50cba7_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Cakes with different icing and flavors are for sale ahead of Valentine's Day in London, Britain, February 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Peter Nicholls)</span></div>
<p>Cake is a commonly served sweet treat at celebrations. And the word also appears in several English idioms.</p>
<p>Back in 2022, we taught the idiom <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/have-your-cake-and-eat-it-too/6808031.html">to have your cake and eat it too</a>. This means to have the best of both worlds. You do not have to choose between two good things. Another expression is <u>a piece of cake.</u> This describes something that is very easy to do or finish.</p>
<p>Because of all the sugar and butter, we probably should not eat too much cake. But it is so good! And sometimes having a lot of something good is better. That is the message of today's show.</p>
<p>Most cakes are made up of two parts: the part made from flour and the sweet topping, or icing.</p>
<p>Now, a cake without the sweet icing on top is already great. After all, it's made with lots of butter and sugar. It's sweet and satisfying. So, the icing is not really necessary. But it makes the cake extra special.</p>
<p><strong>Icing on the cake</strong></p>
<p>And that is the meaning of the idiom <u>icing on the cake</u>. Something already good is made better by the addition of something else. If you describe something as <u>icing on the cake</u> or <u>the icing on the cake</u>, you mean that it makes a good thing even better, or sweeter!</p>
<p>Let's hear an example.</p>
<p><em>She loves her new job and her new co-workers. So, getting her own parking spot was <u>the icing on the cake</u>! She hates looking for parking. </em></p>
<p>The idiom <u>icing on the cake</u> has another meaning. It can be someone's greatest <strong>accomplishment </strong>or victory.</p>
<p>Here is an example of that usage.</p>
<p><em>He had achieved the highest level of success in the company. So, his <strong>fancy</strong> new title was simply <u>icing on the cake</u>. </em></p>
<p><strong>Cherry on top</strong></p>
<p>We have another dessert saying that means about the same thing. Some cakes or ice cream dishes have a special topping: a sweetened cherry.</p>
<p>So, if something is the <u>cherry on top</u>, it is an addition that turns something good into something great!</p>
<p><em>The Taylors bought the house without even knowing it had a large garden in the back. That was the <u>cherry on top</u> since they both love to garden.</em></p>
<p>Sometimes we use the ‘cherry on top' when making an appeal for assistance.</p>
<p>Let's say, I really need a friend's help. I might say, "Please help me! Pretty please with a cherry on top." This specially worded appeal often does the trick and the help comes! But, just know that it can also make you sound a little <strong>desperate</strong>!</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo!</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>delicious</strong> <em>– adj.</em> appealing to one of the bodily senses especially of taste or smell</p>
<p><strong>dessert</strong> <em>– n. </em>a usually sweet course or dish (as of pastry or ice cream) usually served at the end of a meal</p>
<p><strong>flavoring </strong><em>– n. </em>a substance added to food or drink to give it a desired taste</p>
<p><strong>accomplishment </strong><em>– n.</em> an ability, social quality, or skill gained through training or practice</p>
<p><strong>fancy </strong><em>– adj. </em>impressive</p>
<p><strong>desperate </strong><em>– adj. </em>being beyond or almost beyond hope</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Calvin Coolidge: Silent  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-calvin-coolidge.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Calvin Coolidge. He was the vice president under <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-warren-harding/4018013.html">Warren Harding</a>. When Harding died suddenly a little more than two years into his term, Coolidge became president.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Calvin Coolidge" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5765aa12-6437-4c9a-9107-fdf3e26d3c0a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Calvin Coolidge</span></div>
<p>Coolidge is linked to two opposing ideas. The first idea is quiet restraint.</p>
<p>The president's nickname was "Silent Cal." He rarely took part in <strong>casual conversation</strong>. And as a leader, he often thought the best action was not to take any action.</p>
<p>Many voters liked his "cool" style. Coolidge quickly earned a public image as a serious man who did not spend money or words easily.</p>
<p>But Coolidge is also linked to a period in U.S. history known as the Roaring Twenties.</p>
<p>In those years, the 1920s, the American economy was generally good. Many people spent money on exciting things – such as the still-new automobile – and on entertainment, including alcoholic drinks, cigarettes, and dancing. Creative expression such as jazz and Art Deco architecture became popular.</p>
<p>Calvin Coolidge is often given credit for helping fuel the Roaring Twenties with his pro-business economic policies.</p>
<p>But some historians <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/coolidge/impact-and-legacy"><strong>caution</strong></a> against remembering Coolidge's business freedom policies too <strong>fondly</strong>. They say he helped create the conditions for the severe economic depression that followed his presidency.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Calvin Coolidge and his sister were born and raised on a farm in the northeast state of Vermont.</p>
<p>Coolidge spoke highly of both his parents.</p>
<p>His father owned a store, and also held local political offices. He had a public image for honesty, public service, and <strong>thrift</strong>.</p>
<p>Young Calvin Coolidge helped his father in the store, and hoped to be just like him.</p>
<p>Coolidge also admired his mother's strong character. He was 12 years old when she died, and he wrote that losing her was "the greatest <strong>grief</strong> that can come to a boy."</p>
<p>Six years later, his sister also died.</p>
<p>Their deaths made young Calvin Coolidge even more serious than he already was.</p>
<p>But Coolidge was also known for his <strong>wit</strong> – a kind of humor that often depends on word play or intelligence. As a student at Amherst College in Massachusetts, Coolidge became known as an able and funny public speaker.</p>
<p>That skill helped him rise in politics. He began with lower-level offices in Massachusetts, and later served as that state's governor.</p>
<p>Along the way, he married <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/first-ladies/grace-coolidge">Grace Anna Goodhue</a>, a teacher for the deaf. She was known to be warm and social, and the couple were reported to have a loving marriage. They went on to have two sons.</p>
<p>In 1920, the Republican Party nominated Coolidge to be its vice presidential candidate. In general, voters liked the Republican <strong>ticket</strong>. They were ready for a change after the reform policies and international <strong>engagement</strong> of Democrat <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-president-woodrow-wilson/4001252.html">Woodrow Wilson</a>.</p>
<p>Sure enough, the Republicans won the election in a landslide.</p>
<p>But Coolidge did not enjoy the office of vice president very much. He had little power in the government. During meetings, he often remained silent.</p>
<p>One summer night he and his wife were on vacation in Vermont. His father, Colonel Coolidge, woke them up in the middle of the night with some dramatic news: President Harding had died.</p>
<p>Reporters quickly gathered at the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nps.gov/nr/travel/presidents/calvin_coolidge_homestead.html">small farmhouse</a>. Colonel Coolidge had not put electricity in the house. So everyone watched by the light of an oil lamp.</p>
<p>Colonel Coolidge was a public official. He used the family Bible and a copy of the Constitution to <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/calvin-coolidge-takes-oath-of-office-after-hardings-death">swear in his son</a> as the 30<sup>th</sup> U.S. president.</p>
<p>Then the country's new leader did a very <strong>sensible</strong> thing: he went back to bed.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>President Coolidge believed in limited government, especially limited federal government. He permitted state and Cabinet officials to decide as many issues as they could.</p>
<p>Coolidge used his authority to <strong>focus</strong> mostly on the country's economy.</p>
<p>At the time he took office, the U.S. was at the start of an economic <strong>boom</strong>. Coolidge tried to <strong>maintain</strong> that <strong>prosperity</strong>. He did not <strong>regulate</strong> businesses too much, and he sharply reduced taxes, especially on the wealthy.</p>
<p>By nearly every measure, the economy grew.</p>
<p>But the policies also widened the divide between rich and poor Americans, and put the country's economy in a risky situation.</p>
<p>More and more people began to invest their money in the stock market. Some put their dollars in dangerous investments.</p>
<p>And business owners produced more goods than most members of the public could really <strong>afford</strong>. Increasingly, people borrowed money on credit to pay for <strong>luxury</strong> goods.</p>
<p>At the same time, the economic situation of many American farmers was getting worse. The weather had been unusually dry in some places. And the price of food was falling.</p>
<p>Farmers asked the federal government for assistance. But Coolidge rejected several bills that might have helped them. The bills had other problems, Coolidge reasoned, and he did not think that the federal government should intervene in the situation.</p>
<p>So the farmers continued to suffer.</p>
<p>But most voters remained supportive of Coolidge. Even though the president was considered a quiet person, he spoke often on the radio, appeared in a talking film, met with reporters regularly, and posed in funny costumes for photographers.</p>
<p>He easily won elected in 1924. Historians believe he could have won another term, too, in 1928. But Coolidge chose not to seek office.</p>
<p>Some believed he was too saddened by the death of his teenaged son. Shortly after Coolidge became president, the boy had been playing tennis and slightly wounded his toe. The wound became infected. The infection spread to the boy's blood. A few days later, he died.</p>
<p>Although Coolidge continued his presidency, he later said the joy had gone from the job.</p>
<p>But when he decided not to seek re-election, he did not talk about his feelings. Instead, he simply wrote a note to reporters saying: "I do not choose to run for President in 1928."</p>
<p>His secretary of commerce, Herbert Hoover, was elected instead. Coolidge retired to his home in Massachusetts and led a quiet private life.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>President Coolidge was well-liked by most Americans. Later presidents – including Ronald Reagan – sought to follow some of his economic policies.</p>
<p>But many historians have questioned those policies. They say that Coolidge did not pay enough attention to the situation of farmers. And they say the stock market was rising too fast.</p>
<p>Seven months after Coolidge left office, the U.S. economy collapsed.</p>
<p>The country was still deep in the Great Depression when Coolidge passed away. He died – quietly, of course – during an afternoon nap at the age of 60.</p>
<p>His will was but a single sentence.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Caty Weaver was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>_______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>casual</strong> - <em>adj. </em>happening by chance : not planned or expected</p>
<p><strong>conversation</strong> - <em>n.</em> talking in an informal way</p>
<p><strong>fondly</strong> - <em>adv. </em>in a loving way</p>
<p><strong>thrift </strong>- <em>n. </em>careful use of money so that it is not wasted</p>
<p><strong>grief</strong> - <em>n. </em>deep sadness caused especially by someone's death</p>
<p><strong>wit</strong> - <em>n. </em>an ability to say or write things that are clever and usually funny</p>
<p><strong>ticket</strong> - <em>n.</em> a list of the candidates supported by a political party in an election</p>
<p><strong>engagement</strong> -<em> n.</em> the act or state of being involved with something</p>
<p><strong>sensible</strong> - <em>adj.</em> having or showing good sense or judgment</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Art, Culture of an Old New York Train Station  (2023/9/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/art-culture-of-an-old-new-york-train-station.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The first subway station in New York City was designed to be a <strong>masterpiece</strong> and was considered a "<strong>jewel in the crown</strong>" when it opened.</p>
<p>The trains in New York City's public transportation system, its subway, mostly run underground. Today, the main concern of subway designers is that their systems work correctly.</p>
<p>New York's subway opened in 1904. City Hall Station was one of New York City's first underground subway stations. Now called Old City Hall Station, it was built during a time when many public buildings and spaces were designed to appear <strong>majestic</strong>. The goal was to demonstrate that New York could compete culturally with great European cities, sometimes called metropolises.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Visitors take pictures during a tour of the City Hall Station, New York City, June 3, 2018. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-973d-08dba975b0b8_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Visitors take pictures during a tour of the City Hall Station, New York City, June 3, 2018. </span></div>
<p>"It was a statement that New York City had arrived at the level of the great European metropolises like London and Paris, Rome, Madrid...that New York City was taking its place as a world city," said Clifton Hood. Hood is a history professor at Hobart and William Smith Colleges in Geneva, New York.</p>
<p>Inside Old City Hall Station, the top is not flat in shape but <strong>curved</strong> instead. The walls rise up to create a high, round shape known as a vault. Square pieces of glass, called tiles, shine. Some of the lights in the station are called chandeliers. These are beautiful hanging lights that hold many individual light <strong>bulbs</strong> and look like huge pieces of jewelry.</p>
<p>Polly Desjarlais is with the New York Transit Museum. She said she was "blown away" when she first saw the old station. She used words like "lovely, elegant and really unique space" to describe the station.</p>
<p>"I've heard [the station] be described as a celebration of curves, because there are a lot of curves. Everything is sort-of rounded," Desjarlais said.</p>
<p>But those beautiful curves are why the station is no longer part of the normal subway system. Its rounded <strong>platform</strong> cannot fit long trains.</p>
<p>"The platform at City Hall is really curved. It's a very, very tight curve, and the platform itself is just over 200 feet long. So, it's short," Desjarlais said. "As the subway got busier...trains got longer, and we added cars...We were growing those platforms and making them longer..."</p>
<p>Although it is no longer part of the subway system, Old City Hall Station is still being used. One train line, the No. 6, uses the Old City Hall Station to turn around. And while the public cannot enter the station from the street, the members of the New York Transit Museum can see the station a few times a year at a cost of about $50.</p>
<p>Over the years, there have been ideas to make the old station a restaurant or a place for travelers to the city to visit. However, security concerns put those ideas to rest. Today, the unofficial way for the public to see the old station is by taking the No. 6 train and staying on after the last stop. Then, the train turns around at the Old City Hall Station, and riders will be able to see the majestic space.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for VOA. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>masterpiece</strong>–<em>n</em>. a work of outstanding art</p>
<p><strong>jewel in the crown</strong> –<em>expression</em> something that is the best among similar, often costly or beautiful things</p>
<p><strong>majestic</strong>–<em>adj</em>. having or showing extreme beauty</p>
<p><strong>curved</strong> –<em>adj</em>. a smooth, rounded line or shape</p>
<p><strong>bulb</strong> –<em>n</em>. an electric device that produces light</p>
<p><strong>platform</strong>–<em>n</em>. an area where people stand to wait for or enter and exit a train</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Awareness vs. Consciousness  (2023/9/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/awareness-vs-consciousness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "awareness" and "consciousness."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Dear teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Awareness vs. Consciousness " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1d4a-08dbb52e44ff_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Awareness vs. Consciousness </span></div>
<p>I am Mayer from Colombia. I hope you are well.</p>
<p>I would like to know the difference between the words, "awareness" and "consciousness."</p>
<p>Thanks a lot,</p>
<p>Mayer</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for this wonderful question, Mayer.</p>
<p>"Awareness" and "consciousness" share somewhat similar definitions.</p>
<p>The <em>Merriam-Webster</em> dictionary defines "awareness" as having knowledge and understanding that something is happening or exists. And it defines "consciousness" as being aware of things around you or something within oneself.</p>
<p>But these two words can have many different meanings.</p>
<p>Let's look at each one more closely.</p>
<p><strong>Awareness</strong></p>
<p>"Awareness" is a noun that comes from the adjective "aware." When you are aware of something, you know or you have a sense that something exists. For example:</p>
<p><em>Many drivers have no awareness of other cars in their blind spots, areas around the car that they cannot easily see. </em></p>
<p><em>In <strong>yoga</strong>, your mind and your body connect to bring awareness to places of pain so that you can ease it. </em></p>
<p>We often talk about "awareness" of social or political causes or beliefs. This is one of the meanings that is shared with "consciousness."</p>
<p><em>World Pangolin Day is celebrated on February 18th to raise more awareness for these animals.</em></p>
<p>Let's move on to "consciousness."</p>
<p><strong>Consciousness</strong></p>
<p>"Consciousness" is a noun that has several meanings. It comes from the adjective "conscious." When you are "conscious," you are awake and can think and make decisions for yourself.</p>
<p><em>When you are asleep, you are not conscious. </em></p>
<p>Your "consciousness" is your physical and mental state of being conscious or awake.</p>
<p><em>She lost consciousness after she fell and hit her head. </em></p>
<p>Your "consciousness" also includes your mind and thoughts.</p>
<p><em>Don't let his bad feelings cloud your consciousness. </em></p>
<p>And lastly, "consciousness" is the belief that people can have, or it can be an interest or knowledge of certain ideas.</p>
<p><em>Greta Thunberg helped younger people to have more interest in climate consciousness and activism. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Mayer.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>yoga </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of exercises for gaining bodily or mental control and well-being</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France Bans iPhone 12 Over Radiation, Belgium Considering Move  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/france-bans-iphone-12-over-radiation-belgium-considering-move.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Belgium says it plans to study possible health risks from electromagnetic radiation release by Apple's iPhone 12 smartphone.</p>
<p>Belgium's move comes after French <strong>regulators </strong>ordered Apple to stop selling the iPhone 12. French officials said the phone creates more electromagnetic radiation than the European Union permits. Apple disputes this. The company said the device meets all requirements.</p>
<p>The French government agency that oversees wireless communications <strong>frequencies</strong> said it issued the order after the phone failed one of two tests. The tests are related to the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_elOPCnYI">amount</a> of electromagnetic waves the body can <strong>absorb</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man looks at Apple iPhones at a shop in Bilbao, Spain on September 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Vincent West)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/82a23220-a6d9-4ccf-985e-39d6863d2f64_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man looks at Apple iPhones at a shop in Bilbao, Spain on September 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Vincent West)</span></div>
<p>Apple released the iPhone 12 in late 2020. It is unclear why the phone did not pass the agency's latest tests or why only the iPhone 12 is affected.</p>
<p>France's <strong>digital </strong>minister said the iPhone 12's radiation levels are still much lower than levels that scientific studies found could harm users. The French agency said its tests do not test normal phone use.</p>
<p>The National Frequency Agency on Tuesday called on Apple to use all means to fix the problem for phones already in use. It said it would study <strong>updates</strong> to the phones. If they do not work, "Apple will have to <strong>recall</strong>" phones that have already been sold, it said.</p>
<p>The agency recently tested 141 cellphones. It found that when the iPhone 12 is held in a hand or near the body, its level of electromagnetic energy absorption is 5.74 watts per kilogram. That is higher than the EU requirement of 4 watts per kilogram or less.</p>
<p>Watts per kilogram is a measure of the rate at which energy is absorbed by the body.</p>
<p>The phone passed a separate test of radiation levels for devices kept in heavy clothes or in a container, the agency said.</p>
<p>Malcolm Sperrin is director of medical physics at Britain's Royal Berkshire hospital group. He said the radiation limits are set well below the level at which harm will happen. He said a small increase above those limits is unlikely to affect a person's health.</p>
<p>Users of the iPhone 12 should be able to download an update that prevents the radiation from going above the limit, Sperrin said.</p>
<p>It is not clear why this model appears to release higher radiation. But it might be related to when the phone is seeking a connection to send or receive signal, he said.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization says it has not found any harm to health caused by the use of mobile phones. Apple said the iPhone 12 has been approved by many international bodies and meets requirements for radiation around the world.</p>
<p><strong>Other country's responses </strong></p>
<p>Belgium's latest action on the phone raises the possibility that other European countries might ban the model after France.</p>
<p>Italy said it would take no steps for now. But Germany's network regulator BNetzA said that the work in France could act as a guide for Europe. The agency said that it might reconsider the smartphone for the German market if the situation progresses in France.</p>
<p>A Dutch digital organization said it was looking into Apple's phone and would ask the U.S. company for an explanation. But it said that there was no immediate risk.</p>
<p>Britain has not announced any plans after France's decision.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English using material from The Associated Press and Reuters. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>frequency </strong>–n. the measure of radio waves used for communications</p>
<p><strong>regulate </strong><em>– v.</em> to make rules or laws that control (something)</p>
<p><strong>absorb </strong><em>– v.</em> to take in (something, such as a liquid) in a natural or gradual way</p>
<p><strong>digital </strong><em>– adj.</em> using or characterized by computer technology</p>
<p><strong>update </strong><em>– n.</em> a change or addition to computer software that includes the most recent information</p>
<p><strong>recall </strong><em>– v.</em> to ask people to return (a product with a defect or problem)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is Green Hydrogen a Truly Clean Burning Fuel?  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/is-green-hydrogen-a-truly-clean-burning-fuel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Green hydrogen has been presented around the world as a clean energy solution. But is this fuel truly clean burning? And what does it take to produce it?</p>
<p><strong>What is hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>Hydrogen is the lightest chemical element. It has no color, taste, or smell, and can combine with oxygen to form water.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="P V R Murthy, center, general manager at Oil India Limited, pump station 3, shows a part of a hydrogen plant in Jorhat, India, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-944b-08dbafe782f4_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">P V R Murthy, center, general manager at Oil India Limited, pump station 3, shows a part of a hydrogen plant in Jorhat, India, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)</span></div>
<p><strong>What is green hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>To be considered green hydrogen, the production process of separating hydrogen from other elements must be powered by <strong>renewable</strong> energy.</p>
<p>Hydrogen has been produced and widely used for more than 100 years, mainly to make fertilizers and plastics and to process oil. The gas has mostly been produced from <strong>fossil fuels</strong>, especially natural gas.</p>
<p>Industry estimates predict the worldwide market for green hydrogen could reach $410 billion by 2030. This would double its current market size.</p>
<p><strong>What can green hydrogen be used for?</strong></p>
<p>Green hydrogen can be used in several industries, including steelmaking, <strong>concrete</strong> production and in manufacturing chemicals and fertilizers. It can also be used to produce electricity, as a fuel for transportation and to heat homes. Supporters say green hydrogen could be used to make these processes better for the environment.</p>
<p>Francisco Boshell is an energy expert at the International Renewable Energy Agency in Abu Dhabi, the United Arab Emirates. He told the Associated Press (AP) that he is hopeful about green hydrogen being able to produce more clean energy. This could especially be true with energy from renewables like sun and wind power, which cannot easily be stored for later use.</p>
<p><strong>Are there concerns about green hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>Boshell said one problem with hydrogen is its unpredictability. The gas is highly flammable, meaning it can easily catch fire, and requires special pipelines for safe transport. This means most green hydrogen will likely be used close to where it is produced.</p>
<p>The Energy Transitions Commission is a research group based in London. Its experts said in a 2021 report that, because hydrogen is highly flammable and difficult to transport, its use for heating buildings and other uses is limited. The commission is calling for <strong>net-zero</strong> <strong>emissions</strong> by 2050.</p>
<p>The report said hydrogen is also less effective than direct electrification methods. This is because some energy is lost when renewable resources are changed into hydrogen and then that hydrogen is changed again to power. The report suggested that the gas could be used as a way to avoid storing electricity in <strong>batteries</strong>.</p>
<p>Some studies have questioned the high cost of hydrogen production as well as its investment risks. There are concerns linked to a greater need for water than other clean power systems. Critics have also pointed out the lack of international guidelines that make it difficult for a worldwide market to develop.</p>
<p>Robert Howarth is an environmental expert and professor of environmental biology at Cornell University in New York state. He told the AP he thinks green hydrogen is being praised too much, in part because of <strong>lobbying</strong> efforts by the oil and gas industry.</p>
<p>But Boshell, of the International Renewable Energy Agency, disagreed. His organization has projected hydrogen demand will grow to 550 million tons by 2050. That would be up from the current 100 million tons.</p>
<p>The International Energy Agency says production of hydrogen is responsible for creating around 830 million tons of carbon dioxide per year. Boshell said just replacing this so-called gray hydrogen – hydrogen produced from fossil fuels – would establish a long-term market for green hydrogen.</p>
<p>"The first thing we have to do is start replacing the existing demand for gray hydrogen," he said. "And then we can add additional demand and <strong>applications</strong> of green hydrogen as a fuel for industries, shipping and aviation."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>renewable </strong><em>– adj. </em>any naturally occurring kind of energy, such as sunlight or wind</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>– n. </em>fuels such as coal, oil, or natural gas that are formed in the Earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>concrete </strong><em>– n</em>. a hard substance using in building operations</p>
<p><strong>net-zero </strong><em>– v. </em>when a country, city, or territory removes as many emissions as they produce</p>
<p><strong>emission </strong><em>– n. </em>the act of sending something out such as a gas, heat, or light</p>
<p><strong>battery </strong>–n. a device that stores electricity chemically</p>
<p><strong>lobby </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to persuade a politician, the government or an official group that a particular thing should or should not happen</p>
<p><strong>application </strong>–n. uses for a product, resource, idea or method</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Say a Common Cold Medicine is Ineffective  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/experts-say-a-common-cold-medicine-is-ineffective.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>American government experts who studied a popular medicine used for colds say the drug is likely not effective and should not be taken by mouth.</p>
<p>Sixteen experts for the U.S. Food and Drug Administration examined the drug phenylephrine. The drug is in many medicines that treat nasal <strong>congestion</strong>, a condition also known as a stuffy nose. The medicines include Sudafed, Allegra and Dayquil among others.</p>
<p>The experts read a scientific <strong>review</strong> released by the FDA before they met. The scientific study said there were many mistakes in earlier tests of phenylephrine's effectiveness. It said the FDA no longer accepted the earlier testing results.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - On Sept. 12, 2023 advisers to the Food and Drug Administration said that an ingredient, phenylephrine, is ineffective at relieving nasal congestion. Shown here is Sudafed containing another ingredient at Hospital Discount Pharmacy in 2005. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6154-08dbb5505c5e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - On Sept. 12, 2023 advisers to the Food and Drug Administration said that an ingredient, phenylephrine, is ineffective at relieving nasal congestion. Shown here is Sudafed containing another ingredient at Hospital Discount Pharmacy in 2005. </span></div>
<p>One of the experts was Dr. Mark Dykewicz. He is an allergy specialist at Saint Louis University School of Medicine. Dykewicz said, "Modern studies, when well <strong>conducted</strong>, are not showing any improvement in congestion with phenylephrine."</p>
<p>Phenylephrine is an over-the-counter drug. Anyone can buy it at a store. A doctor's order is not required to purchase it. Phenylephrine is the most popular decongestant in a market valued at $2.2 billion dollars.</p>
<p>If the FDA follows the advice of the experts, companies that make the medicine will have to remove it from stores. These companies include Johnson &amp; Johnson, Bayer and other leading drug makers.</p>
<p>The drug would remain in medicines taken through the nose, however. The nasal <strong>spray</strong> form of phenylephrine is considered effective and there are no plans to review it.</p>
<p>But offering higher amounts of the drug by mouth is not possible because it can increase blood pressure to dangerous levels.</p>
<p>Researchers at the University of Florida first requested that the FDA remove phenylephrine from a list of approved drugs. The same researchers questioned the drug's effectiveness in 2007. They said they found no difference between using the drug and using an inactive substance called a placebo.</p>
<p>Phenylephrine has been sold in different forms for 75 years. Dr. Theresa Michele leads the FDA's office of nonprescription drugs. She said, "Any time a product has been on the market that long, it's human nature to make <strong>assumptions</strong> about what we know about the product."</p>
<p>The FDA reviewers said the studies they examined showed how quickly the body processes phenylephrine. The research shows that too little of the drug reaches the area of the nose when the medicine is taken by mouth. Forms of the drug sprayed into the nose appear more effective.</p>
<p>The reviewers said barring the drug from medicine taken by mouth would avoid the "unnecessary costs and delay in <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_MAAS5KIO">care of taking</a> a drug that has <strong>no</strong> <strong>benefit</strong>.</p>
<p>The FDA has not updated its list of approved drugs to treat nasal congestion since 1995. The process for changing the list takes years. But Congress passed a law in 2020 that would speed the process for drugs that do not require a doctor's permission to use.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Matthew Perrone reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>congestion</strong> <em>–n. (medical)</em> blocked with fluid</p>
<p><strong>pharmacist </strong><em>–n.</em> a person whose job it is to prepare and sell drugs that doctors order for their patients</p>
<p><strong>spray </strong><em>–n.</em> liquid that is forced out of a container in very small drops</p>
<p><strong>assumption </strong><em>–n</em>. something that a person thinks is true but of which they have no proof</p>
<p><strong>no</strong> <strong>benefit</strong> <em>–phrase</em> something that does not have a useful or good result</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Phrasal Verbs with 'Along'  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/three-phrasal-verbs-with-along.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Sometimes, the Learning English program <em>Ask A Teacher</em> receives questions from learners that we are not able to answer on that program. The question might be more <strong>advanced</strong>, and the answer longer, than we have time for on <em>Ask A Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>But the questions are worthy! So, in this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore Noura's question about phrasal verbs with "along."</p>
<p>Noura writes that she does not understand why we add "along" to such words as "come," "send" and "<strong>tag</strong>." She says that she does not see any changes to their meanings when "along" is added.</p><div class="contentImage"><img along="" alt="Three Phrasal Verbs with " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1b5a-08dbb47bd25b_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Three Phrasal Verbs with "Along" </span></div>
<p>Let's answer Noura's question about these three phrasal verbs.</p>
<p><strong>Along </strong></p>
<p>"Along" as a preposition means in a line <strong>matching</strong> the length or direction of something. It can also mean points on or near something.</p>
<p><em>We drove along the coast of Maine.</em></p>
<p>We use "along" in this sentence to say that we drove on a road that runs next to, or near, the coast.</p>
<p><em>We saw beautiful <strong>beach </strong>houses along the drive.</em></p>
<p>Here we use "along" to mean points. The beach houses are the points.</p>
<p>Along as an adverb has many meanings. We can use "along" to describe the forward movement of something. It can also mean to be "in the company of" or "in addition to."</p>
<p>When we add "along" to a verb, we get these more exact meanings.</p>
<p><strong>What are phrasal verbs?</strong></p>
<p>Phrasal verbs are groups of words made up of a verb and another short word or words. Together, these groups of words mean something different from what the individual words suggest. As a result, you can think of phrasal verbs as kinds of special expressions.</p>
<p>There are many phrasal verbs in English, and often each phrasal verb can have different meanings.</p>
<p>Let's try to simplify Noura's three phrasal verbs, "come along," "send along" and "tag along."</p>
<p><strong>Come along</strong></p>
<p>"Come along" is our first phrasal verb. It means to go with or <strong>accompany </strong>someone. Usually that person is the one who leads the way. So, the person that is "coming along" is the secondary person, who is okay with someone leading them.</p>
<p><em>Do you mind if I come along to the store with you? I just need a few<strong> </strong>things for dinner.</em></p>
<p>Come along is a phrasal verb with other meanings, too.</p>
<p>It can mean to make progress.</p>
<p><em>Your painting is coming along nicely. It is almost done.</em></p>
<p>And lastly, "come along" means to make an appearance.</p>
<p><em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/super-blue-and-blood-a-guide-to-different-full-moons/7250151.html">Blue moons</a> come along every two or three years, usually.</em></p>
<p><strong>Send along</strong></p>
<p>The next phrasal verb with "along" is "send along." It has two meanings. The first meaning is to send something additional with something else.</p>
<p><em>My sister mailed me a gift last week and sent along a letter from my parents.</em></p>
<p>In addition to the gift, the letter was also sent.</p>
<p>"Send along" also means to dismiss. Usually, we can separate this phrasal verb for this meaning.</p>
<p><em>The teacher sent the children along to lunch.</em></p>
<p><strong>Tag along</strong></p>
<p>"Tag along"<strong> </strong>is like "come along." It means to follow someone else, but with an added meaning that the person "tagging along" might not be so welcomed or is just following the other person. It has a more <strong>negative</strong> association than "come along."</p>
<p><em>Sam's little sister always tags along when he plays outside with his friends.</em></p>
<p>The verb "tag" by itself can mean to attach as an additional element or to follow closely. While both meanings share similarities to "tag along," the phrasal verb has additional meaning "tagged" on.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today, we looked at three phrasal verbs with the preposition "along." Phrasal verbs have their own separate meaning apart from the original verbs and preposition/adverb combination. "Come along" and "tag along" are similar, but "tag along" has a more negative association. You might want someone to come along with you, but tagging along, probably not. "Send along" has two meanings, to dismiss and to send something together with something else.</p>
<p>Thanks for the question, Noura. We hope our exploration of come, send and tag along has cleared up some of the mystery around phrasal verbs.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advanced</strong> – <em>adj</em>. having a high level of skill or difficulty</p>
<p><strong>tag</strong> – <em>v</em>. to choose for a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>matching </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having the qualities and looking appealing together</p>
<p><strong>beach </strong>– <em>n</em>. an area covered with sand that is by a body of water</p>
<p><strong>accompany </strong><em>– v. </em>to go somewhere with someone</p>
<p><strong>ingredient</strong> <em>– n. </em>one of the things used to make a food product</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong><em> </em>–<em> adj. </em>having harmful or undesirable effects</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI Development Requires Large Amounts of Water  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/ai-development-requires-large-amounts-of-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say the methods used to create artificial intelligence (AI) systems require large amounts of water. As a result, people are calling on AI developers to reduce their water usage and take more responsibility for the environmental resources they use.</p>
<p>The <em>Associated Press</em> recently reported on water usage by American-based OpenAI, the company that launched the ChatGPT AI tool. ChatGPT is a so-called "chatbot" designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. Such tools are also known as "generative AI" or "large language models."</p>
<p>The development and training methods used to create large language models require powerful computing systems. This process uses a lot of electricity and produces a lot of heat. Data center operators pump in water to keep equipment cool.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Traffic is shown on Interstate 35 near a Microsoft data center, Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023, in West Des Moines, Iowa. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0622-08dbb3d9f565_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Traffic is shown on Interstate 35 near a Microsoft data center, Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023, in West Des Moines, Iowa. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)</span></div>
<p>Open AI – which is backed by software maker Microsoft – operates a series of data centers in West Des Moines, Iowa. The city in the central part of the state is home to about 68,000 people.</p>
<p>"They're building them as fast as they can," said Steve Gaer, who served as the city's mayor when Microsoft first arrived. He said the software maker was attracted to the city because of its efforts to improve public projects. The former official also said Microsoft provided a huge amount of money in taxes in support of the efforts.</p>
<p>"But," Gaer said of the company, "they were pretty secretive on what they're doing out there."</p>
<p>In 2020, Microsoft said it was developing one of the world's most powerful supercomputers for OpenAI. At the time, it did not name the Iowa city as home to the project. Microsoft described the effort as a "single system" with a huge number of <strong>semiconductors</strong> and processors to support AI workloads.</p>
<p>In late May, Microsoft President Brad Smith made his first public comment about the company's new "AI supercomputing data center" in West Des Moines. He noted the center was built to support development efforts for the ChatGPT system.</p>
<p>Water is taken from the nearby Raccoon and Des Moines rivers to cool down the Microsoft-OpenAI computing equipment, the <em>AP</em> reports. In its latest environmental report, Microsoft said its worldwide water usage rose 34 percent from 2021 to 2022 to almost 1.7 billion gallons. Industry experts have suggested the large increase was directly linked to the company's AI research.</p>
<p>"It's fair to say the majority of the growth is due to AI," said Shaolei Ren. He is a researcher at the University of California, Riverside who has been studying the environmental effects of AI products such as ChatGPT.</p>
<p>In a paper set to be published later this year, Ren's team estimates ChatGPT takes up 500 milliliters of water each time someone asks the tool a series of between five and 50 questions. The estimate also includes indirect usage companies generally do not measure. This includes water used to cool power plants that supply the data centers with electricity.</p>
<p>"Most people are not <strong>aware</strong> of the resource usage <strong>underlying </strong>ChatGPT," Ren said. "If you're not aware of the resource usage, then there's no way that we can help <strong>conserve</strong> the resources."</p>
<p>Ren noted that Google reported a 20 percent growth in water usage during the same period. He believes that growth is largely linked to the American-based search engine company's AI development work.</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a recent statement to the <em>AP</em> that it is investing in research to measure the environmental effects of AI activities. The company promised to work on ways "to make large systems more <strong>efficient</strong>, in both training and <strong>application</strong>."</p>
<p>In its own statement, OpenAI said it had given "considerable thought" to the best use of computing power. "We recognize training large models can be energy and water-intensive," it said.</p>
<p>A West Des Moines government document from 2022 says the city "will only consider future data center projects" from Microsoft if those projects can "demonstrate and <strong>implement</strong>" technology to <strong>significantly</strong> reduce water usage from current levels.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– n. </em>a material, such as silicon, that permits electricity to move through it more easily when its temperature increases</p>
<p><strong>underlying </strong><em>– adj. </em>used to describe something on which something else is based</p>
<p><strong>conserve </strong><em>– v. </em>to keep and protect something from damage, change or waste</p>
<p><strong>efficient </strong>– <em>adj. </em>working or operating quickly and in a safe, organized way</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>– n. </em>the way in which something can be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>aware </strong>– <em>adj.</em><strong> </strong>having or showing realization, perception, or knowledge</p>
<p><strong>implement </strong><em>– v.</em> to take steps to put into practice; to carry out</p>
<p><strong>significant </strong>– <em>adj.</em><strong> </strong>of a noticeably or measurably large amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>App Identifies Birds by Sound  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/app-identifies-birds-by-sound.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Tracee Herbaugh lives in the Boston area of Massachusetts.</p>
<p>Herbaugh thought she was alone in her <strong>backyard</strong> recently when she used the Merlin Bird ID app. She learned from listening that she was surrounded by more than 12 kinds of birds.</p>
<p>There were the familiar blue jays, cardinals and goldfinch. But the app also identified birds like chimney swift, northern flicker, fish crow, killdeer and gray catbird.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology shows a winter wren. (James Davis/Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6a52-08db105cbf18_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology shows a winter wren. (James Davis/Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology via AP)</span></div>
<p>Two birds identified by the app, veery and great horned owl, even had a red <strong>dot</strong> next to their names. The red dot meant it was a rare sighting.</p>
<p>Herbaugh wrote: "Who knew all these birds could be in one yard?"</p>
<p>Cornell Lab of Ornithology is the maker of Merlin Bird ID. The app was released in 2014. At first, the app only identified birds by sight called Photo ID. The user answered a series of questions to help identify the bird, such as date, area, color, and size. The app became popular during the pandemic when people increasingly wanted to be outdoors.</p>
<p>In 2021, Cornell Lab added Sound ID to identify birds by their sound. In the United States alone, Merlin's Sound ID can identify over 700 kinds of birds. More than 7 million people now use the Merlin Bird ID worldwide.</p>
<p>Alli Smith works on the Merlin project at Cornel Lab. Smith said birdwatching by sound "opens up a whole new world." Even if you cannot see the birds, Smith added, "you can hear their beautiful songs and know they're sharing your neighborhood."</p>
<p>Other bird-identifying apps include the Audubon Bird Guide, ChirpOMatic, Picture Bird and Smart Bird.</p>
<p><strong>Connecting with people</strong></p>
<p>More than birds, Herbaugh said the app also helped her reconnect with people across the country.</p>
<p>When Herbaugh shared her bird list on social media, two childhood friends who also used the app messaged her about it.</p>
<p>Her relative in Montana shared a list that included hawks, raptors and hummingbirds. And even her young children now quickly go for the app any time they hear an unfamiliar bird call.</p>
<p>Herbaugh has identified 45 birds on her list so far. She said her children are now the ones driving her to get more on the bird list.</p>
<p>Smith said when people write to Merlin, they often talk about connection. She said, "There are so many little wonders around and it's fun to share that with people."</p>
<p>I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Tracee Herbaugh reported this story for The Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>backyard</strong>–<em>n</em>. the area outside around a house</p>
<p><strong>dot</strong>–<em>n</em>. a small round mark</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift Takes MTV's Top Award  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/taylor-swift-takes-mtv-s-top-award.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Taylor Swift took home the top prize at the 2023 MTV Video Music Awards (VMAs) for her <em>Anti-Hero</em> music video.</p>
<p>The music network's yearly awards show took place at the Prudential Center in Newark, New Jersey.</p>
<p>"This is unbelievable. The fact that this is a fan-voted award means so much to me," Swift said in her acceptance speech. "I can't believe it was a year ago that I announced the <em>Midnights </em>album."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Joey Fatone, from center, Lance Bass, and Justin Timberlake of NSYNC present the award for best pop to Taylor Swift, far left, for Anti-Hero during the MTV Video Music Awards on September 12, 2023, at the Prudential Center in Newark, N.J. (Photo by Charles Sykes/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/013566e3-6899-44b8-b19d-44539a245179_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Joey Fatone, from center, Lance Bass, and Justin Timberlake of NSYNC present the award for best pop to Taylor Swift, far left, for "Anti-Hero" during the MTV Video Music Awards on September 12, 2023, at the Prudential Center in Newark, N.J. (Photo by Charles Sykes/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>The night's first presenters were from the male musical act NSYNC. They reunited to hand the best <strong>pop</strong> video award to Swift.</p>
<p>Swift received the most nominations of any performer. Swift later returned to the stage to receive the song of the year award for <em>Anti-hero</em> and also the best direction award.</p>
<p>The performer received nine awards in total. Those included artist of the year in a group of nominees made up of women for the first time on the VMA show.</p>
<p>Ice Spice, who worked with Swift on <em>Karma (Remix)</em>, won best new artist.</p>
<p>New music filled the show with songs from Nicki Minaj who also was the <strong>host</strong>. Minaj performed the new song <em>Last Time I saw You</em>. She then performed a piece from her upcoming <em>Pink Friday 2 </em>album.</p>
<p>The award show centered on showing music's international power. K-pop, or Korean pop, boy group Tomorrow X Together and Brazilian artist Anitta introduced a new song together, <em>Back for More</em>.</p>
<p>Another K-pop group, Stray Kids, performed the song <em>S-Class</em>. Mexican singer Peso Pluma performed a song called <em>Lady Gaga </em>and Colombian singer Karol G sang <em>Oki Doki </em>and another song <em>Tá OK (remix)</em>.</p>
<p>Tiffany Haddish presented the award for "Best Afrobeats," a new award group. Afrobeats is music with influences from Africa and Black American culture. Rema and Selena Gomez won the award for the popular song <em>Calm Down. </em></p>
<p>"Africa in the house!" Rema said in his acceptance speech. Gomez said, "I want to send all of my love to Nigeria, thank you."</p>
<p>Colombian star Shakira received the Video Vanguard Award and performed a mix of her popular songs.</p>
<p>"MTV, thank you for being such a big part of my career since I was only 18 years old," Shakira said. She also thanked her parents and her children, who she brought to the show.</p>
<p>"This is for you my people, my Latin American people, inside and outside this country," she said in the Spanish language.</p>
<p>Diddy received the Global Icon Award from Mary J. Blige and his daughter Chance Combs. He is the third act to receive the award, after the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_bl5dFMm0">Red Hot</a> Chili Peppers in 2022 and the Foo Fighters in 2021.</p>
<p>The artist also performed at the VMAs for the first time since 2005. The performance was a collection of some of his most popular songs like <em>Bad Boy for Life </em>and <em>Mo Money Mo Problems</em>.</p>
<p>Lil Wayne opened the show with a performance of his new single <em>Kat Food. </em>Olivia Rodrigo then brought her <em>Vampire</em> music video to the stage before performing <em>Get Him Back!</em></p>
<p>Later, Anitta would win the "best Latin" award for the second year. In her acceptance speech, she laughed, saying, "I wanna thank myself." And she added, "Because I work so hard!"</p>
<p>French Montana, a performer who presented an award, brought attention to an effort to provide aid to victims of the Morocco earthquake. The performer grew up in Morocco.</p>
<p>The VMA show ended with a celebration of 50 years of the musical form <strong>hip-hop</strong>. It included Nicki Minaj, Lil Wayne, LL Cool J, and DMC of Run-DMC.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Sherman reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pop </strong><em>– n.</em> music that is popular</p>
<p><strong>host </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who talks to guests on a television or radio show</p>
<p><strong>hip-hop </strong><em>– n.</em> rap music</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>North Korean, Russian Leaders Meet to Discuss Military Aid  (2023/9/14) | 朝俄领导人会晤讨论军事援助</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/north-korean-russian-leaders-meet-to-discuss-military-aid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin met Wednesday at Russia's new spaceport in the Far East.<br/>
朝鲜领导人金正恩和俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京星期三在俄罗斯位于远东的新航天港会晤。</p>
<p>Putin showed Kim the Vostochny Cosmodrome spaceport and discussed the possibility of sending a North Korean cosmonaut into space. After the tour, Putin and Kim talked for several hours about world issues and possible areas of cooperation.<br/>
普京陪同金正恩参观了东方航天发射场(又称沃斯托奇尼航天港)，并讨论了将一名朝鲜宇航员送入太空的可能性。参观结束后，普京和金正恩就世界问题和潜在合作领域进行了几个小时的交谈。</p>
<p>At lunch, Kim gave a toast to Putin's health, to the victory of "great Russia" and Korean-Russian friendship. He predicted victory for Russia in, what he called, its "sacred fight" with the West in the Ukraine war.<br/>
午餐时，金正恩为普京的健康、“伟大俄罗斯”的胜利和韩俄友谊干杯。他预测俄罗斯将在乌克兰战争中与西方的“神圣之战”中获胜。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Russia seeking help with ammunition<br/>
俄罗斯寻求弹药援助</span></p>
<p>Putin suggested that military cooperation was discussed but released few details. Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu also attended the talks. However, Russian officials said sensitive discussions between the neighbors were a private matter.<br/>
普京表示，双方讨论了军事合作，但没有透露任何细节。国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古也出席了会谈。然而，俄罗斯官员表示，这两个邻国之间的理性讨论是私事。</p>
<p>U.S. and South Korean officials have expressed concern that the rare meeting could lead to a deal to supply Russia with ammunition for the war in Ukraine.<br/>
美国和韩国官员表示担心，这次罕见的会议可能会达成一项为俄罗斯提供弹药供给乌克兰战争的协议。</p>
<p>Concern about the two countries' military cooperation grew after Shoigu visited North Korea in July. Kim then visited his weapons factories, which experts said aimed to support North Korea's weapons modernization and show military supplies for export to Russia.<br/>
绍伊古7月访问朝鲜后，西方对两国军事合作的担忧加剧。金正恩随后参观了他的武器工厂，专家们称这些工厂旨在支持朝鲜的武器现代化，并展示出口到俄罗斯的军事物资。</p>
<p>Putin is believed to be seeking North Korean supplies of aging ammunition and rockets from the time when the Soviet Union existed. Such a request would mark a change from the period of the Korean War which lasted from 1950 to 1953. At that time, Russia gave weapons to support North Korea's invasion of South Korea.<br/>
据信，普京正寻求朝鲜提供苏联存在时的老化弹药和火箭。这样的要求将标志着1950年至1953年朝鲜战争时期的变化。当时，俄罗斯提供武器支持朝鲜入侵韩国。</p>
<p>James Nixey is the director of the Russia and Eurasia program at London-based research group Chatham House. He said Russia cannot produce enough weapons for the war in Ukraine and any deal with North Korea would be to ensure that immediate needs are met.<br/>
詹姆斯·尼克希是伦敦查塔姆研究所俄罗斯和欧亚大陆项目的负责人。他说，俄罗斯无法为乌克兰战争生产足够的武器，与朝鲜的任何协议都将确保满足眼前的需求。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">North Korea wants space technology<br/>
朝鲜想要太空技术</span></p>
<p>The decision to meet at the Vostochny Cosmodrome suggests Kim is seeking Russian help in developing spy satellites. In recent months, North Korea has repeatedly failed to put its first military spy satellite into orbit.<br/>
在东方航天发射场会面的决定表明，金正恩正在寻求俄罗斯帮助开发间谍卫星。近几个月来，朝鲜一再失败，未能将其首颗军事间谍卫星送入轨道。</p>
<p>Official photos showed Kim brought Pak Thae Song, head of North Korea's space science and technology committee, and Kim Myong Sik who is linked with spy satellites and submarine-based nuclear ballistic missile efforts.<br/>
官方照片显示，金正恩带来了朝鲜太空科学技术委员会主席朴泰成，以及与间谍卫星和潜艇核弹道导弹有关的金明植。</p>
<p>When asked by Russian media that attended the meeting, if Russia would help Kim build satellites, Putin said: "That's why we came here."<br/>
当被参加会议的俄罗斯媒体问及俄罗斯是否会帮助金正恩建造卫星时，普京说：“这就是我们来这里的原因。”</p>
<p>Putin told Russian state TV that Kim will visit two more cities in the Russian Far East on his own after the meeting. Kim is expected to visit an aircraft factory in Komsomolsk-on-Amur and then go to Vladivostok to observe Russia's Pacific Fleet, a university and other places.<br/>
普京对俄罗斯国家电视台说，会谈结束后，金正恩将独自访问俄罗斯远东地区的另外两个城市。预计金正恩将参观阿穆尔河畔科索莫尔斯克的一家飞机工厂，然后前往符拉迪沃斯托克观看俄罗斯太平洋舰队、一所大学和其他地方。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google's Search Engine at Center of Antitrust Trial  (2023/9/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/google-s-search-engine-at-center-of-antitrust-trial.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Department of Justice accuses Google Tuesday of using its internet search engine to push out competitors and limit new ideas.</p>
<p>Kenneth Dintzer is the Justice Department's lead lawyer. He said, "This case is about the future of the internet and whether Google's search engine will ever face meaningful competition."</p>
<p>Over the next 10 weeks, federal lawyers and state attorneys general will try to prove that Google unfairly controls the market in its favor by making its search engine the first choice in software and on devices that people use every day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Various Google logos are seen in search results on two devices in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0d03-08dbb3b34ea7_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Various Google logos are seen in search results on two devices in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>The case is similar to the <strong>antitrust</strong> trial brought against computer software maker Microsoft in 1998. At that time, the government accused Microsoft of using its strength in software to force computer makers to use its other products, including the Internet Explorer web browser. The case ended with restrictions to prevent Microsoft from having total control of the marketplace.</p>
<p>Many Google products including the Chrome web browser, Gmail, YouTube, and online maps are extremely popular. But none have controlled the market and become as valuable as its internet search engine.</p>
<p>The government accuses Google of paying billions of dollars yearly to make its search engine the first choice on the iPhone and web browsers such as Apple's Safari and Mozilla's Firefox. The legal action notes that Google also requires its search engine to be a part of the Android operating system used by smartphones of many manufacturers.</p>
<p>Dintzer said, "This is Google saying: Take it or leave it." He said that Google's moves prevented Apple from developing a search engine of its own.</p>
<p>Google argues that it faces many competitors although it controls about 90 percent of the internet search market. The company says it faces competition from search engines such as Microsoft's Bing and DuckDuckGo and websites like Amazon and Yelp. These websites let users ask questions about what to buy or where to go.</p>
<p>The company also argues that it faces competition from new technology like artificial intelligence (AI). Microsoft, for example, is adding AI abilities from its partner Open AI to its Bing search engine. That move in early February forced Goggle to equip its search engine with results that come from AI-aided processes.</p>
<p>Google says users can always use any other search engine. But continuous improvements to its search engine are the reason why users keep coming back. It is a process that made the name Google <strong>synonymous</strong> with looking things up on the internet.</p>
<p>However, critics say the quality of search results has decreased. They note that Google uses its engine to sell advertisements. The company brings attention to its products over those of competitors.</p>
<p>Today, the stock market value of Google's parent company, Alphabet, is $1.7 trillion. The company employs 182,000 people. Most of the money Google makes comes from $224 billion in yearly ad sales. The sales come through a network of digital services that are linked by the search engine, which answers billions of requests a day.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>antitrust </strong><em>–adj. </em>related to cases brought by a government against a company that appears to control so much of a market that it prevents normal market competition</p>
<p><strong>synonymous</strong> <em>–adj.</em> having the same meaning as</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
