<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>America’s Poor Math Skills Raise Concerns  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/america-s-poor-math-skills-raise-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many Americans joke about how bad they are at math. But, labor experts and others in the United States are not laughing. They say the nation's ever-decreasing math skill threatens U.S. economic competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Jim Stigler is a professor at the University of California, Los Angeles. He studies the process of teaching and learning subjects, including math. He said, "The <strong>advances</strong> in technology that are going to drive where the world goes in the next 50 years are going to come from other countries, because they have the <strong>intellectual</strong> capital and we don't."</p>
<p>The Education Reporting Collaborative, a coalition of eight news agencies, is documenting the math crisis facing schools. Members of the Collaborative are <em>AL.com</em>, <em>The Associated Press</em>, <em>The Christian Science Monitor</em>, <em>The Dallas Morning News</em>, <em>The Hechinger Report</em>, <em>Idaho Education News</em>, <em>The Post and Courier</em> in South Carolina, and <em>The Seattle Times</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Teacher Jerry Howland explains an equation during the Bridge to Calculus summer program at Northeastern University in Boston on Tuesday, Aug. 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Reba Saldanha)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7f50d41b-ac80-4bf9-ad5a-0076921ab067_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Teacher Jerry Howland explains an equation during the Bridge to Calculus summer program at Northeastern University in Boston on Tuesday, Aug. 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Reba Saldanha)</span></div>
<p>The U.S. military has called for a major program to support education in science, technology, education, and math (STEM). It argues that the U.S. is dangerously behind other nations. The Defense Department says China produces eight times as many college <strong>graduates</strong> in these study fields as the United States. It says Russia produces four times as many engineers as the U.S.</p>
<p>Government labor experts say the number of jobs in areas requiring math skill will increase by more than 30,000 each year through the end of 2030. That is much faster than most other kinds of jobs.</p>
<p>"Mathematics is becoming more and more a part of almost every career," said Michael Allen. He chairs the math department at Tennessee Technological University.</p>
<p>But most American students are not prepared for those jobs. In the most recent Program for International Student Assessment tests in math (PISA), U.S. students tested lower than students from 36 other education systems around the world. Students in China tested the highest.</p>
<p>Only one in five American high school students planning to attend college is prepared for college-level study in STEM, say experts at the National Science and Technology Council, a government group.</p>
<p>However, students from other countries are preparing to lead in these areas, reports the National Foundation for American Policy, a non-profit organization. It says only one in five graduate students in math-heavy fields at U.S. universities are American. The rest come from other countries. Most will leave the U.S. when they finish their programs.</p>
<p>In Massachusetts, employers are expecting a shortage over the next five years of 11,000 workers in the life sciences alone.</p>
<p>"It's not a small problem," said Edward Lambert Jr. He is director of the Massachusetts Business Alliance for Education. "We're just not starting students, <strong>particularly</strong> students of color and from lower-resourced families, on career paths related to math and computer science and those things in which we need to stay competitive, or starting them early enough," he said.</p>
<p>"This is not an educational question alone," said Josh Wyner, a vice president of the Aspen Institute, a <strong>think tank</strong>. In July, it warned that other nations are gaining near to America's technological power.</p>
<p>It urged decision makers to make education an important national security goal. "We are no longer keeping <strong>pace</strong> with other countries, particularly China," the Aspen report says, calling this a "dangerous" failure.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jon Marcus reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advances </strong>– <em>n</em>. progress in the development or improvement of something</p>
<p><strong>intellectual </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to the ability to think in a logical way</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to earn a degree or diploma from a school, college, or university</p>
<p><strong>particularly </strong><em>– adv.</em> more than usually</p>
<p><strong>think tank </strong><em>– n.</em> an organization that consists of a group of people who think of new ideas on a particular subject or who give advice about what should be done</p>
<p><strong>pace </strong><em>– n.</em> the speed at which something happens</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Grower Sets World Record for Heaviest Pumpkin  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/us-grower-sets-world-record-for-heaviest-pumpkin.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American teacher from Minnesota has set a record for growing the world's heaviest pumpkin, which weighed 1,247 kilograms.</p>
<p>Travis Gienger was named the winner Monday of the 50th World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, California.</p>
<p>The 43-year-old won the same contest in 2022. His winning pumpkin last year weighed 1,161 kilograms. Still, Gienger told The Associated Press he was surprised to win the world record. "I was not expecting that," he said. "It was quite the feeling."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Travis Gienger of Anoka, Minn., reacts after winning the Safeway 50th annual World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, Calif., Monday, Oct. 9, 2023. Gienger won the event with a pumpkin weighing 2749 pounds. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0c80-08dbc9b23820_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Travis Gienger of Anoka, Minn., reacts after winning the Safeway 50th annual World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, Calif., Monday, Oct. 9, 2023. Gienger won the event with a pumpkin weighing 2749 pounds. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)</span></div>
<p>Gienger is a teacher at Anoka Technical College in Anoka, Minnesota. He teaches agriculture and growing methods and has been producing pumpkins for nearly 30 years. Gienger says his father also raised pumpkins and this got him interested.</p>
<p>The past world record for the heaviest pumpkin was set by a grower in Italy who produced a 1,226-kilogram <strong>gourd</strong> in 2021, the Guinness World Records organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://newsroom.ap.org/detail/Pumpkinweighing2749poundswinsCaliforniacontestsetsworldrecordforbiggestgourd/dbe2b22743e332998c204f2191b2a46f/text?Query=pumpkin%2520contest&amp;mediaType=text&amp;sortBy=&amp;dateRange=Anytime&amp;totalCount=1&amp;currentItemNo=0">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Gienger – who grows the pumpkins on his home property – said this year he decided to give his plants extra care. This included watering them up to 12 times a day and feeding them food, or fertilizer, a little more than usual.</p>
<p>Gienger first competed in Half Moon Bay's yearly contest in 2020. He has won three of the city's last four pumpkin contests. "I put in the work so that I can put a smile on people's faces and it's just so nice coming out here to see everyone in this town," Gienger said.</p>
<p>The pumpkin champion won a $30,000 prize for growing the biggest pumpkin and setting a world record.</p>
<p>Gienger's pumpkin will be shown along with the runner-up winners at the city's upcoming Art and Pumpkin Festival. At the event, visitors will be able to look at the pumpkin prizes and take pictures with the growers.</p>
<p>In the United States, pumpkins are popular throughout the autumn.</p>
<p>During the U.S. holiday Halloween – on October 31 – many people <strong>decorate</strong> the orange gourds and turn them into "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/jack-o--lantern-why-is-it-named-jack-/5630153.html">jack-o'-lanterns</a>." A jack-o'-lantern is a pumpkin that has been <strong>carved</strong>, usually to show a frightening or funny face.</p>
<p>Pumpkins are also a seasonal favorite for Americans to make pumpkin pie. This <strong>dessert</strong> food is traditionally eaten on Thanksgiving Day, which this year falls on November 23.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gourd</strong> <em>– n.</em> a large fruit with a hard shell</p>
<p><strong>decorate</strong> <em>– v. </em>to add something to an object or place, especially to make it more inviting</p>
<p><strong>carve</strong> <em>– v. </em>to make something by cutting into something</p>
<p><strong>dessert</strong> <em>– n.</em> a sweet food usually eaten at the end of a meal</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France Worries about Bedbugs as 2024 Summer Olympics Near  (2023/10/11) | 巴黎奥运将近 臭虫困扰法国</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/france-worries-about-bedbugs-as-2024-summer-olympics-near.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Officials in France are worried about the spread of an insect called the bedbug as Paris prepares to hold the 2024 Summer Olympic Games.<br/>
在巴黎准备举办2024年夏季奥运会之际，法国官员担心一种名为臭虫的昆虫的传播。</p>
<p>Prime Minister Elizabeth Borne called a meeting of ministers to deal with the bedbug crisis. The country's transportation minister, Clé ment Beaune, recently met with transportation companies to make a plan for monitoring and disinfecting.<br/>
法国总理伊丽莎白·博尔内召开了一次部长会议以应对臭虫危机。法国交通部长克莱门特·伯恩最近会见了交通公司，制定了监测和消毒计划。</p>
<p>Beaune also spoke about reducing worry caused by reports on social media. He told reporters there is no increase in bedbug cases. He added that 37 cases reported in the bus and Metro train system and many other reports from trains have proved false.<br/>
博恩还谈到了减少社交媒体报道引起的担忧。他告诉记者，臭虫案例没有增加。他补充说，公共汽车和地铁系统报告的37起案例以及火车上的其它许多报告都被证明是虚假的。</p>
<p>The National Agency for Health and Food Safety reported that 11 percent of households had a bedbug problem between 2017 and 2022. Because many people might not want to say in public that they have a bedbug problem, the agency used a poll by the company Ipsos to collect the information.<br/>
法国国家卫生和食品安全局报告称，2017年至2022年间，该国11%的家庭发生过臭虫问题。由于许多人可能不想在公开场合说他们遇到臭虫问题，该机构利用益普索公司的一项民意调查来收集信息。</p>
<p>The insects are about the size of an apple seed. They neither jump nor fly. However, they have become more resistant to chemicals used to kill insects. And they can stay alive for up to a year with no food.<br/>
这些昆虫大约有苹果籽那么大。它们既不跳也不飞。然而，它们对用来杀死昆虫的化学物质具有更强的抵抗力。而且它们可以在没有食物的情况下存活长达一年。</p>
<p>The carbon dioxide humans give off makes the insects become active and try to bite, explained Jean-Michel Berenger. He is a scientist who studies insects. He raises bedbugs in his laboratory in the infectious diseases division of the Méditerranée University Hospital in the city of Marseille.<br/>
让-米歇尔·贝林格解释说，人类释放的二氧化碳使这种昆虫变得活跃并试图叮咬。他是一位研究昆虫的科学家。他在马赛市地中海大学附属医院传染病科的实验室里饲养臭虫。</p>
<p>For now, Berenger said, this much is clear: "Bedbugs have infested the media."<br/>
贝林格说，就目前而言，这一点很清楚：“媒体都在说臭虫。”</p>
<p>Experts say it makes no difference if a home is clean or dirty. The insects simply want to bite people to get blood, explained Berenger.<br/>
专家说，家里脏与不脏没什么区别。贝伦格解释说，这些昆虫只是想咬人吸血。</p>
<p>"Whether you live in a dump or a palace, it's the same thing to them," he said.<br/>
他说：“无论你住在垃圾场还是宫殿里，对他们来说都是一样的。”</p>
<p>Worry about bedbugs has increased business for insect control companies in France. They use dogs to smell the special odor that bedbugs make. Then, they use hot steam to kill the bugs.<br/>
对臭虫的担忧让法国昆虫防治公司的业务增加。他们用狗来闻臭虫产生的特殊气味。然后，他们用热蒸汽杀死虫子。</p>
<p>Kevin Le Mestre is director of Lutte Antinuisible, a company that removes unwanted insects and animals such as rats. He said that in the past, people would not call his company even if they had been bitten by a bedbug. But now he said his company is getting many calls from people worried about the insects.<br/>
凯文·勒·梅斯特雷是病虫害防治公司的董事，该公司负责消灭老鼠之类不受欢迎的昆虫和动物。他说，过去即使被臭虫叮咬，人们也不会给他的公司打电话。但现在他说，他的公司接到了许多担心昆虫的人打来的电话。</p>
<p>The increase in public worry began about a month ago after reports of bedbugs at a Paris movie theater. Videos began popping up on social media, showing the little insects on trains and buses.<br/>
大约一个月前，巴黎一家电影院传出臭虫的报道后，公众的担忧开始加剧。社交媒体上开始出现视频，显示这些小昆虫在火车和公共汽车上。</p>
<p>Some government officials want to create new rules to fight against bedbugs.<br/>
一些政府官员希望制定新的规则来对抗臭虫。</p>
<p>Lawmaker Mathilde Panot recently brought a glass container of bedbugs to the Parliament to criticize the government, claiming it had let the insects spread quickly.<br/>
议员玛蒂尔德·帕诺最近带着一个装有臭虫的玻璃容器来到议会，批评政府，声称政府让臭虫迅速传播。</p>
<p>Because bedbugs travel easily on clothing or in luggage, they are a cause of worry for officials ahead of the 2024 Olympic games.<br/>
由于臭虫在衣服或行李上很容易传播，因此它们是官员们在2024年奥运会之前担心的一个原因。</p>
<p>"All human population movements are profitable for bedbugs because they go with us, to hotels, in transport," said Berenger.<br/>
贝林格说：“所有的人口流动都对臭虫有利，因为它们会和我们一起去酒店、乘坐交通工具。”</p>
<p>Beaune, the transport minister, is hopeful that steps can be taken to reduce the public's fear. But, he added, "It's hell, these bedbugs."<br/>
交通部长博恩希望能够采取措施来减少公众的恐惧。但是，他补充道，“这些臭虫糟糕透了。”</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mining Companies Consider Renewable Energy  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/mining-companies-consider-renewable-energy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mining companies produce important metals needed to build electric car <strong>batteries</strong> and <strong>solar panels</strong>.</p>
<p>Devices called <strong>smelters</strong> process the rock and minerals so the metal can be purified and sold to manufacturers. The work requires a lot of energy.</p>
<p>The advisory business McKinsey &amp; Company says mining operations produce between four and seven percent of the world's <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> emissions. Those are gases released into the atmosphere that some scientists say are warming the planet.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A worker in a protective suit pokes a metal rod to tap slag from a smelting furnace at PT Vale Indonesia's nickel processing plant in Sorowako, South Sulawesi, Indonesia, Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/eb483678-ce6d-4fff-a549-e13673714c3e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A worker in a protective suit pokes a metal rod to tap slag from a smelting furnace at PT Vale Indonesia's nickel processing plant in Sorowako, South Sulawesi, Indonesia, Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023.</span></div>
<p>Some of the companies that use mined materials include Apple, Hyundai and Mercedes. Those companies are now putting pressure on mining companies to use less energy. Many of those companies have environmental, social and governance, or ESG, <strong>commitments</strong>. The ESG commitments require companies such as Apple and carmaker Volvo to choose materials that are made in a less harmful way when possible.</p>
<p>Some mining companies are thinking about how they can change their business methods to use less energy and create less pollution.</p>
<p>The pressure is changing the way mines in Indonesia, Chile and Canada operate.</p>
<p>On the island of Sulawesi in Indonesia, the Brazilian mining company Vale runs its smelters using hydroelectric power instead of diesel fuel. The hydroelectric power comes from three dams the company built years ago. Vale now says it can reduce its carbon dioxide by over 1 million tons per year. The company says its greenhouse gas emissions are down by one-fifth since 2017.</p>
<p>The smelter in Sulawesi produces 75,000 tons of nickel each year. The metal is used for batteries, electric cars and many machines used around the home. While the company runs the smelter on hydroelectric power, other machines still require coal power.</p>
<p>The demand for metals such as nickel and cobalt is rising as more people drive electric cars and use solar panels to power their homes. But as new mines open and active mines increase operations, environmental activists wonder if the mining companies can continue to reduce pollution.</p>
<p>Activists say pressure is important to get industries to create less pollution. In Chile, mines that produce copper, lithium and other materials use some energy from solar farms. In Canada, the Raglan mine in the far northern part of Quebec produces nickel with the help of wind power.</p>
<p>Michael Goodsite teaches civil and environmental engineering at the University of Adelaide in Australia. He said the mines that are moving away from diesel fuel are setting a good example.</p>
<p>"How they move from fossil fuel operations to other energy sources can and should be learned from by others," he said.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, President Joko Widodo has pushed for his country to develop its own industries. One of those industries is mining. Indonesia is the world's largest producer of nickel and Vale recently signed a deal for a $4.5 billion processing center. Some of the investment came from Ford, the U.S.-based automaker.</p>
<p>Ford is concerned about how its materials are produced. Ford official Christopher Smith said the company can "help <strong>ensure</strong> that the nickel we use in electric vehicle batteries is mined ... produced within the same ESG standards as...our business around the world."</p>
<p>But mining companies may not be able to change fast enough for people worried about climate change.</p>
<p>Coal is used to power some of Vale's metal processing in Indonesia. Febriany Eddy is chief of Vale Indonesia. She said the company plans to change from coal to liquefied natural gas. Experts say the gas is not as bad as coal.</p>
<p>Eddy said it is the best current choice. The company believes better options may not be available for 15 to 20 years.</p>
<p>She said she could wait for the perfect solution, or she can work with natural gas saying, "it is a transition, only." Eddy said natural gas will reduce emissions by 40 percent.</p>
<p>Some climate activists say natural gas still produces methane and carbon dioxide, which, they say, hurt the environment.</p>
<p>But Eddy said Vale can save money in the long run by producing its own energy in Indonesia. She said hydroelectric power reduces the company's carbon emissions and also permits the company to save money. "We are no longer that (<strong>vulnerable</strong>) to fuel and coal costs – because we have hydropower," she said.</p>
<p>Some products will still be made by businesses that are not making energy changes Goodsite, the university professor in Australia, said when asked about China.</p>
<p>He added that some of the changes will come because businesses want to reduce their energy use. However, he said change will happen if people, who he called "end users," who buy cars and mobile phones and other products choose to buy things made from different materials.</p>
<p>And he said people have to be ready to pay a lot more for these new products. "We all need to be prepared to pay a significant <strong>premium</strong> for that," Goodsite said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennet. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>battery </strong>–n. a device that stores electricity and provide direct electrical current</p>
<p><strong>solar panel </strong>–n. a device that turns strong sunlight into direct electrical current</p>
<p><strong>smelter </strong>–n. a machine that melts rock that contains minerals to purify the mineral or metal</p>
<p><strong>greenhouse gas </strong>–n. a gas believed to trap heat in the Earth's atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>commitment </strong>–n. a promise to do something</p>
<p><strong>ensure </strong>–v. to make something likely to happen</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong>–adj. easily hurt, harmed or weakened</p>
<p><strong>premium </strong>–n. something with an added cost compared to a regular cost</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Study Long-lasting Ancient Structures  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-study-long-lasting-ancient-structures.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ancient builders across the world created structures that are still standing today, thousands of years later.</p>
<p>Roman engineers built thick <strong>concrete</strong> sea barriers, for example. Mayan builders created sculptures to their gods, and Chinese builders raised walls against invaders.</p>
<p>But there are many recent structures that are already starting to fail. The concrete that makes up much of our modern world lasts around 50 to 100 years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Visitors tour the interior of the Pantheon's dome in Rome, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4a21-08dbc522a635_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Visitors tour the interior of the Pantheon's dome in Rome, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)</span></div>
<p>A growing number of scientists have been studying materials from long-ago. They are breaking apart pieces of buildings and reading historical texts hoping to learn how they have stood for thousands of years.</p>
<p>The research has turned up a surprising list of materials that were mixed into old buildings. They include tree bark, volcanic ash, rice, beer and even urine. These unexpected materials could have the ability to get stronger over time and "heal" cracks when they form.</p>
<p>Figuring out how to copy these features could have real impacts today. While our modern concrete has the strength to hold up very tall buildings and heavy <strong>infrastructure</strong>, it cannot compete with the <strong>endurance</strong> of these ancient materials.</p>
<p>With the rising threats of climate change, there is a growing call to make construction more <strong>sustainable</strong>. A recent UN report estimates that the built environment is responsible for more than a third of carbon dioxide <strong>emissions </strong>worldwide. Cement production alone makes up more than 7 percent of those emissions.</p>
<p><strong>Is ancient Roman concrete better?</strong></p>
<p>Many researchers have turned to the Romans. Starting around 200 BCE, the Roman Empire was building concrete structures that have stood the test of time. That includes the Pantheon to the <strong>aqueducts</strong> that still carry water today.</p>
<p>Even in places where seawater has been hitting structures for ages, you will find concrete "basically the way it was when it was poured 2,000 years ago," said John Oleson. He is an archaeologist at the University of Victoria in Canada.</p>
<p>Most modern concrete starts with Portland cement, a powder made by heating limestone and clay to super-high temperatures and grinding them up. That cement is mixed with water to create a <strong>paste</strong>. Then, materials like rock and gravel are added.</p>
<p>Records from ancient builders show the Roman process was similar. The ancient builders mixed materials like burnt limestone and volcanic sand with water and gravel, creating chemical reactions to tie everything together.</p>
<p>Now, scientists think they have found an important reason why some Roman concrete has held up structures for thousands of years. The ancient material has an unusual power to repair itself. Exactly how is not yet clear, but scientists are starting to find reasons why.</p>
<p>Admir Masic is a civil and environmental engineer at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. In a study, he said this power comes from <strong>chunks</strong> of limestone throughout the Roman material that is not mixed in evenly. Researchers used to think these chunks were a sign that the Romans were not mixing up their materials well enough.</p>
<p>Instead, the scientists found that the chunks could fuel the material's "self-healing" abilities. When cracks form, water enters the concrete, Masic explained. That water activates the leftover lime, creating new chemical reactions that can fill in the damaged sections.</p>
<p><strong>Ancient Roman ... skyscrapers?</strong></p>
<p>Today's builders cannot just copy the ancient processes. Even though Roman concrete lasted a long time, it could not hold up heavy buildings. "You couldn't build a modern skyscraper with Roman concrete," Oleson said. "It would collapse when you got to the third story."</p>
<p>Instead, researchers are trying to take some of the ancient materials and add them into modern mixes. Masic is part of a company that is trying to build new projects using "self-healing" concrete.</p>
<p>People do not need to make things last quite as long as the Romans did to have an impact, Masic said. If we add 50 or 100 years to concrete's lifespan, he said, "we will require less <strong>demolition</strong>, less maintenance and less material in the long run."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>concrete </strong><em>— n. </em>a hard, strong material that is used for building and made by mixing cement, sand, and broken rocks with water</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>— n. </em>the basic equipment and structures that are needed for a country, region, or organization to function properly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>endurance </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability to do something difficult for a long time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be used without being completely used up or destroyed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emissions </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>aqueduct </strong><em>— n. </em>a structure that looks like a bridge and that is used to carry water over a valley</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>paste </strong><em>— n. </em>a soft, wet mixture of usually a powder and a liquid</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>chunk </strong><em>— n. </em>a thick piece of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>demolition </strong><em>— n. </em>deliberate destruction of a building or other structure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>WHO Approves a Second Malaria Vaccine  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/who-approves-a-second-malaria-vaccine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) approved a second malaria vaccine last week. The decision could offer a less costly and readily available shot to help fight the disease.</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said the U.N. health agency approved the new malaria vaccine based on advice from two expert groups. They suggested the shot could be given to children at risk of the disease.</p>
<p>"As a malaria researcher, I used to dream of the day we would have a safe and effective vaccine against malaria. Now we have two," Tedros said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A nurse administers the malaria vaccine to an infant at the Lumumba Sub-County hospital in Kisumu, Kenya, July 1, 2022. (REUTERS/Baz Ratner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-aadd-08dbc3833ea3_cx17_cy13_cw82_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A nurse administers the malaria vaccine to an infant at the Lumumba Sub-County hospital in Kisumu, Kenya, July 1, 2022. (REUTERS/Baz Ratner)</span></div>
<p>Britain's Oxford University developed the new three-shot vaccine along with the Serum Institute of India. Research suggests it is more than 75 percent effective. The vaccine can protect people for another year with an additional shot called a booster. Tedros said the shot would cost about $2 to $4 and could be available in some countries next year.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, health officials in the African countries of Ghana and Burkina Faso also approved the vaccine.</p>
<p>Infected mosquitos spread the <strong>parasitic</strong> disease when they bite people.</p>
<p>"This is one more tool we will now have, but it's not going to replace bed nets and <strong>spraying</strong> <strong>insecticides</strong>," said John Johnson of the aid group Doctors Without Borders. "This is not the vaccine that's going to stop malaria," he added. Johnson was not part of the expert groups that advised the WHO.</p>
<p>The WHO approved the first malaria vaccine in 2021. The U.N. agency described the vaccine development as an "historic" effort to end the deadly disease in Africa. The continent is home to most of the world's estimated 200 million malaria cases and 400,000 malaria deaths.</p>
<p>But that vaccine, known as Mosquirix and made by GSK, is only about 30 percent effective. The treatment requires four shots and becomes less effective within months.</p>
<p>WHO experts, however, said the data to date on the GSK and Oxford-developed vaccines does not show which one is more effective.</p>
<p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation had been one of the GSK vaccine's biggest financial supporters. But, the non-profit ended its support for Mosquirix last year. It said the GSK shot was less effective than officials would like and that money would be better used elsewhere.</p>
<p>"The big difference with these two vaccines is <strong>access</strong>," Johnson told the <em>Associated Press</em>. He noted that about 10 countries or more could get the GSK vaccine in the next few years.</p>
<p>GSK has said it can only produce about 15 million treatments a year. The Serum Institute has said it could make up to 200 million treatments of the Oxford vaccine a year.</p>
<p>Alister Craig is with Britain's Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine. He said countries still waiting for the GSK vaccine should turn to the Oxford vaccine instead.</p>
<p>If the new vaccine is widely available across Africa, it could greatly reduce severe sickness and deaths caused by malaria in a few years, Craig said.</p>
<p>Neither of the vaccines stops <strong>transmission</strong> of malaria. As a result, immunization campaigns alone would not be enough to prevent epidemics. And, reports of resistance to malaria drugs are on the rise.</p>
<p>"You would be foolish to think that this vaccine is going to be the end of the malaria story," Craig said.</p>
<p><strong>Dengue vaccine</strong></p>
<p>In a separate decision, the WHO's expert group also approved the dengue vaccine made by Takeda. European Union drug officials approved the dengue vaccine earlier.</p>
<p>The WHO advised that the dengue vaccine be used in children aged 6 to 16 in countries where the disease is widespread.</p>
<p>Dengue killed almost 1,000 people this year in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Maria Cheng reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>parasitic</strong> - <em>adj</em>. living in another animal or person</p>
<p><strong>spray</strong> - <em>v</em>. to put a stream of small drops of liquid on (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>insecticide</strong> - <em>n</em>. a chemical substance used to kill insects</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> - <em>n</em>. a way to get to something</p>
<p><strong>transmission</strong> - <em>n</em>. the act or process by which something is spread or passed on</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>London’s Pointe Black Ballet School Aims to Break Racial Barriers  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/london-s-pointe-black-ballet-school-aims-to-break-racial-barriers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>It was a criticism about her Afro-<strong>braided</strong> hair that led Ruth Essel to create what she calls a safe space for Black dancers.</p>
<p>The founder of Pointe Black Ballet School in London said when she was a child, teachers and others all but punished her for not following the traditional <strong>ballerina </strong>way.</p>
<p>"I'll never forget my first time about to dance on a West End <strong>stage</strong>," said Essel. That was the time the 10-year-old wore her hair braided at dance practice. Her mother had spent her last $120 to get her hair done.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ruth Essel of Pointe Black Ballet School teaches finishing positions in south London, Britain, July 22, 2023. Essel sees it as a safe space for Black dancers and a way to create a network of studios, dancers, and teachers. (REUTERS/Alishia Abodunde) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-2d67-08dbc59e9311_cx7_cy2_cw92_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ruth Essel of Pointe Black Ballet School teaches finishing positions in south London, Britain, July 22, 2023. Essel sees it as a safe space for Black dancers and a way to create a network of studios, dancers, and teachers. (REUTERS/Alishia Abodunde) </span></div>
<p>Her happiness disappeared when her teacher pointed at her in an almost all-white group of dancers. The teacher told her to take out her braids because it looked like "a <strong>mess</strong>."</p>
<p>That was just one of several times Essel was made to feel bad about being different. "These are all things that happened before I was 16 years old, and I didn't know any better," she said.</p>
<p>These difficulties led Essel to establish Pointe Black in 2020 at the age of 26.</p>
<p>"I wanted there to be a Black environment. I wanted there to be people who looked like me. I wanted there to be a teacher that looked like me," she said.</p>
<p>She said it felt like she was given power when she could finally wear black clothes and shoes rather than the traditional pink color for ballerinas, "because it was closer to my color."</p>
<p>Ballet has expanded across the world with famous ballet dancers from Asia, South America, and Cuba. But many still think of ballet dancers as light skinned. And classical ballet companies try to have a similar look for dancers in classical works like <em>Swan Lake</em>. That makes it harder for dancers of color.</p>
<p>Some 2.2 percent of dancers at the top four ballet companies in Britain are of Black ancestry. That percentage is in line with the country's Black population at 3 percent, said Sandie Bourn of Britain's Society for Dance Research in 2017.</p>
<p>A spokesperson noted that keeping <strong>diversity </strong>is important to everyone at The Royal Academy of Dance, saying "Dance is for everybody."</p>
<p>But Essel wants to speed up change by introducing new ideas. She said her shows use African dances and music. And dancers wear different hairstyles, including twists, rolls and afros. She added, "... it's really just about celebrating the person no matter where they come from."</p>
<p>Maya Beale-Springe is a 10-year-old student at Pointe Black and another ballet school. She enjoys exploring different kinds, or types, of ballet.</p>
<p>"I get to experience different types of ballet, different music," she said after a perfect practice for an upcoming show.</p>
<p>Essel teaches all the classes in her school. She said, "Everything about my school is what my younger self would have wanted."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Alishia Abodunde and Muvija M reported this story for Reuters. </em><em>Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>braid </strong>– <em>n</em>. an arrangement of hair made by weaving three sections together</p>
<p><strong>ballet </strong>– <em>n</em>. a kind of dancing that is performed on a stage and that uses dance, music, costumes, and scenery to tell a story</p>
<p><strong>stage </strong>– <em>n</em>. a raised platform in a theater, auditorium where the performers stand</p>
<p><strong>mess </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very dirty or untidy state or condition</p>
<p>and that you will not allow anyone or anything to stop you</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong><em>– n.</em> the state of having people who are different races or who have different cultures in a group or organization</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Nobel Economics Prize Goes to Professor Studying Gender in Workplace  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/nobel-economics-prize-goes-to-professor-studying-gender-in-workplace.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Nobel Prize in economics has been awarded to Claudia Goldin for her work on the <strong>gap</strong> between men and women in the workplace.</p>
<p>The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences announced the prize on Monday. The 77-year-old Goldin is only the third woman among 93 past Nobel economics prizewinners. She is a professor at Harvard University.</p>
<p>Goldin's research has shown that even in the field of economics, women earn about 13 percent less than men. The pay gap prevents some women from continuing their education.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="US economist Claudia Goldin, who was awarded the Nobel prize in economics, talks to the press at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, on October 9, 2023. (Photo by Lauren Owens Lambert / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6926e4c1-0b1b-4996-a508-6207161b2226_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">US economist Claudia Goldin, who was awarded the Nobel prize in economics, talks to the press at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, on October 9, 2023. (Photo by Lauren Owens Lambert / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The Nobel committee credits Goldin with finding missing data to better explain continuing differences between both the pay and work involvement, or participation, of men and women.</p>
<p>The group called Goldin "a <strong>detective</strong>" who found new data sources and "creative ways to use them to measure these unknowns."</p>
<p>Goldin studied information related to female participation in the workplace over 200 years and found that their pay started low and never caught up to men.</p>
<p>She looked at women whose jobs went uncounted, such as those who worked on farms alongside their husbands or made clothing at home. Goldin said the pay gap that existed then still exists today, even as women gain higher levels of education than men.</p>
<p>In the 1990s, she said, American women led the world in their labor participation rate. But the rate has dropped since then.</p>
<p>"I think something has happened in America," Goldin said. "We have to ... ask questions about piecing together the family, the home ... with the marketplace and employment."</p>
<p>Even as women have made education gains, Goldin notes, they still often feel pressure to stay at home to care for children or to choose jobs that permit them to be available to children.</p>
<p>"They graduate from college at much higher rates than men. They do better in high school than men do. So why are there these differences?" Goldin asked.</p>
<p>Randi Hjalmarsson of the Nobel committee said Goldin's work does not provide specific solutions to the problem. However, she said Goldin did identify "the source of the gap, and how it's changed over time ..."</p>
<p>Hjalmarsson added, "By finally understanding the problem and calling it by the right name, we will be able to pave a better route forward."</p>
<p>Goldin suggested men need to do a better job sharing childcare and work responsibilities. Women, she said, often miss out on career progress that comes with working longer hours or on weekends because they feel pressure to care for children.</p>
<p>She also suggested that the U.S. government put more money into after-school programs. "Very few of us have jobs that finish at 3 p.m.," she said. Goldin noted that women in Canada, France and Japan currently have a higher labor participation rate than those in the U.S.</p>
<p>Goldin said some of the work still needs to be done by <strong>couples</strong>. She notes that "couple equity also leads to more gender equity." Goldin also noted that girls pay attention to how their mothers participated in work and that "each generation (learns) from the successes and failures of <strong>preceding</strong> generations."</p>
<p>The prize comes with an award of about $1 million and will be presented at a ceremony in Sweden later this year.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this report for VOA Learning English based on reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gap </strong>–n. the distance between two things, such as man's pay and a woman's pay</p>
<p><strong>couple </strong>–n. two people who live together and have a romantic or sexual relationship</p>
<p><strong>detective </strong>–n. a person who solves a mystery or finds an answer to something unknown</p>
<p><strong>preceding </strong>–adj. existing or happening before</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>China Aims to Grow Influence in Space with ‘Tiangong’ Station  (2023/10/9) | 中国计划利用“天宫”空间站扩大太空影响力</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/china-aims-to-grow-influence-in-space-with-tiangong-station.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>China plans to increase the size of its space station in the coming years.<br/>
中国计划在未来几年扩大其空间站的规模。</p>
<p>The station will offer astronauts from other countries a different choice for near-Earth missions. The International Space Station (ISS), led by NASA, is nearing the end of its service life.<br/>
该空间站将为其他国家的宇航员提供近地任务的不同选择。由美国宇航局主导的国际空间站的使用寿命即将结束。</p>
<p>The China Academy of Space Technology (CAST) said the operational lifetime of the Chinese space station will be more than 15 years. The organization is China's main space contractor. Chinese officials made the estimate recently at the 74th International Astronautical Congress in Baku, Azerbaijan.<br/>
中国空间技术研究院表示，中国空间站的使用寿命将超过15年。该研究院是中国的主要太空承包商。中国官员最近在阿塞拜疆巴库举行的第74届国际宇航大会上做出了这一估计。</p>
<p>That new operational lifetime would be more than the 10 years announced earlier.<br/>
这一新的运营寿命将比之前宣布的10年更长。</p>
<p>China's space station, known as Tiangong, or the Celestial Palace in Chinese, has been operational since late 2022. It holds up to three astronauts and orbits 450 kilometers above Earth.<br/>
中国天宫空间站自2022年底开始运行。它最多可容纳三名宇航员，在地球上空450公里的轨道上运行。</p>
<p>After an increase from three to six modules, Tiangong will be about 180 metric tons.<br/>
在从三个模块增加到六个模块后，天宫号将达到约180公吨。</p>
<p>Tiangong is 40 percent of the mass of the ISS, which can hold a crew of seven astronauts. But the ISS, in orbit for more than 20 years, is expected to stop service after 2030.<br/>
天宫的质量相当于国际空间站的40%，国际空间站可容纳7名宇航员。但国际空间站在轨道上运行了20多年，预计将在2030年后停止服务。</p>
<p>China has said it expects to become "a major space power". Chinese state media said last year as Tiangong became fully operational that China would be no "slouch" as the ISS headed toward retirement. State media added that "several countries" had asked to send their astronauts to the Chinese station.<br/>
中国表示，它希望成为“一个重要的太空大国”。中国官方媒体在去年天宫全面投入使用时表示，随着国际空间站即将退役，中国将会毫不逊色。官方媒体补充说，已经有“数个国家”要求将宇航员送往中国空间站。</p>
<p>But, the European Space Agency (ESA) said this year it did not have the financial or "political" approval to take part in Tiangong.<br/>
但是，欧洲航天局今年表示，它没有获得参加天宫的财政或“政治”批准。</p>
<p>The announcement suspended a plan that had been developed over years for a visit by European astronauts.<br/>
该公告暂停了一项多年来为欧洲宇航员访问制定的计划。</p>
<p>The Global Times wrote at the time: "Giving up cooperation with China in the manned space domain is clearly short-sighted, which reveals that the U.S.-led camp confrontation has led to a new space race."<br/>
中国《环球时报》当时写道：“放弃与中国在载人航天领域的合作显然是短视的，这表明美国领导的阵营对抗导致了一场新的太空竞赛。”</p>
<p>Tiangong has become a symbol of China's growing influence and belief in its space missions. U.S. law bans China from any work, direct or indirect, with NASA.<br/>
天宫已经成为中国在太空任务日益增长的影响力和信心的象征。美国法律禁止中国与美国宇航局进行任何直接或间接的合作。</p>
<p>Russia is highly involved in the ISS and has similar space diplomacy plans. Russia suggested that its partners in the BRICS group - Brazil, India, China and South Africa - could build a module for its new space station.<br/>
俄罗斯高度参与了国际空间站，并有类似的太空外交计划。俄罗斯建议其在金砖国家集团的合作伙伴——巴西、印度、中国和南非——可以为其新的空间站建造一个模块。</p>
<p>Roscosmos, the Russian space agency, said last year that it was planning to build a space station. The goal is for the station to have six modules that could hold up to four astronauts.<br/>
俄罗斯航天局去年表示，它正计划建造一个空间站。空间站的目标是拥有六个模块，最多可容纳四名宇航员。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA to Launch Spacecraft to Observe Metal-rich Asteroid  (2023/10/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/nasa-to-launch-spacecraft-to-observe-metal-rich-asteroid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA is preparing to launch a spacecraft designed to observe an <strong>asteroid</strong> made mostly of metal.</p>
<p>The launch of the vehicle, called Psyche, is set for October 12 from Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>
<p>The spacecraft will fly to an asteroid also called Psyche. It orbits the sun between Mars and Jupiter. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/asteroids/16-psyche/">says</a> the asteroid was discovered by an Italian astronomer in 1852. Since it was the 16th asteroid discovered, it is sometimes also called 16 Psyche.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This artist illustration depicts NASA's Psyche spacecraft, which will conduct a direct exploration of an asteroid thought to be a stripped planetary core. (NASA/JPL-Caltech)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/EDAA46D5-5DD0-4769-8218-15C4E58F711D_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This artist illustration depicts NASA's Psyche spacecraft, which will conduct a direct exploration of an asteroid thought to be a stripped planetary core. (NASA/JPL-Caltech)</span></div>
<p>Psyche will be NASA's first trip, or mission, to an asteroid that contains a large amount of metal. Past missions explored asteroids made mostly of rock or ice.</p>
<p>Astronomers say the asteroid Psyche is about 280 kilometers at its widest point. They believe it may be part of a center, or core, of a planetesimal. This is an object thought to be the metallic remains of an early rocky planet. Scientists think Psyche is made up mostly of iron and nickel, similar to Earth's center.</p>
<p>NASA believes the asteroid could have separated during violent crashes that happened during our solar system's early creation. Scientists think data collected on the asteroid could provide new details about how rocky planets, including Earth, formed.</p>
<p>But NASA says the object could also turn out to be something else, such as "a different kind of iron-rich body that formed from metal-rich material somewhere in the solar system."</p>
<p>The space agency <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/press-kits/psyche/mission">expects</a> Psyche to travel about 3.6 billion kilometers over six years to reach the asteroid. If the spacecraft reaches its target as planned in August 2029, it will then start orbiting the object for at least two years.</p>
<p>Once in orbit, the mission team will examine data gathered by several science instruments aboard the spacecraft. Psyche will take pictures, map the asteroid's surface and collect data on what materials are contained in the object.</p>
<p>NASA says once Psyche separates from its launch vehicle, it will use a different kind of <strong>propulsion</strong> system never tried in missions beyond the moon.</p>
<p>The system to be used is called solar electric propulsion. Large solar <strong>panels</strong> will be extended outward from the main part of the spacecraft to collect light from the sun. The panels then change, or convert, this sunlight into electricity that powers the spacecraft's <strong>thrusters</strong>.</p>
<p>Psyche will depend on solar electric propulsion to reach its target. NASA describes the thrust as "gentle," but strong enough to push the spacecraft through its long trip. The spacecraft is also set to get a gravitational push when it passes by Mars in May 2026.</p>
<p>NASA said experiments have shown that solar electric propulsion can be highly effective. Scientists estimate Psyche's thrusters "could operate nearly nonstop for years without running out of fuel."</p>
<p>In addition, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/solar-electric-propulsion-makes-nasas-psyche-spacecraft-go">says</a> Psyche will be carrying nearly 1,000 kilograms of propellant, xenon gas, in its tanks. Xenon is also used in automobile headlights and some televisions. Agency engineers have estimated the mission would need to burn through about 15 times that amount of propellant if the Psyche spacecraft used traditional chemical thrusters.</p>
<p>Lindy Elkins-Tanton, with Arizona State University, is the lead investigator for the mission. She said NASA had always planned on having Psyche use an electric propulsion system. "Without it, we wouldn't have the Psyche mission," Elkins-Tanton said.</p>
<p>NASA says the Psyche mission also includes a technology demonstration involving a laser-based data communications system. This experiment is designed to "test the ability of lasers to <strong>transmit</strong> data at increased rates beyond the moon."</p>
<p>The technology to be tested in the demonstration is known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/solar-system/deep-space-optical-communications-dsoc/">optical communications</a>." It is meant to one day replace the radio communication systems long used by NASA to transmit data between Earth and space. NASA says a laser-based communication method will permit the agency to send and receive data faster and more effectively.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and Reuters.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong><em>– n.</em> a force that pushes something forward</p>
<p><strong>panel </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
<p><strong>thruster </strong>– <em>n. </em>an engine that produces propulsion by releasing a jet of fluid or a stream of particles</p>
<p><strong>transmit </strong>– <em>v. </em> to send</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Columbus or Indigenous Peoples’ Day?  (2023/10/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/columbus-or-indigenous-peoples-day.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>This Monday is Columbus Day in the United States.</p>
<p>The U.S. government established Columbus Day as a national holiday in 1934 to honor the explorer Christopher Columbus. The day recognizes Columbus's arrival in the Americas in October 1492.</p>
<p>Recently, critics have said that Columbus did not "discover" America since native people already lived there. His explorations helped open the way for a huge migration of Europeans to what they called The New World. This brought war, disease and death to many native peoples.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by Johnston, R.I., Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr., a statue of Christopher Columbus stands in a park Tuesday, Sept. 26, 2023, in Johnston, Rhode Island. (Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr. via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-bf0a-08dbc5cc1ffd_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by Johnston, R.I., Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr., a statue of Christopher Columbus stands in a park Tuesday, Sept. 26, 2023, in Johnston, Rhode Island. (Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr. via AP)</span></div>
<p>Some American states have since moved away from honoring Columbus and instead observe a day for Native American people.</p>
<p>In 2021, President Joe Biden issued the first-ever presidential proclamation of Indigenous Peoples' Day. The day is to be celebrated along with Columbus Day.</p>
<p>The May 2020 death of George Floyd, an unarmed Black man in the state of Minnesota, led to nationwide protests against police use of force and racial injustice. Protestors directed some of their anger at statues and monuments honoring Confederate officials from the American Civil War. Many cities then removed the statues and monuments said to be connected to racial injustice, racism and slavery.</p>
<p>The anger led to protest attacks on memorials to Columbus around the country. Statues of the explorer were taken down in Boston, Chicago and many other cities.</p>
<p><strong>A statue was removed, then returned</strong></p>
<p>In the Rhode Island capital of Providence, a statue of Christopher Columbus was also removed in June 2020. The removal came after protestors covered it with red paint and a sign, reading "Stop celebrating genocide." The statue was placed in storage and then purchased for about $50,000 by former Providence Mayor Joseph Paolino.</p>
<p>After three years out of the public eye, the statue will return to a park in the city of Johnston, about 14 kilometers west of the capital. The statue will be officially uncovered on Monday.</p>
<p>Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena Jr. said people of his heavily Italian-American town are pleased to give the statue a new home.</p>
<p>"It's important and not just for Italian Americans. It's American history. It's world history, if you look at it from a historical <strong>perspective</strong>," he said. "People should learn about him, the good and the bad."</p>
<p>Not everyone is happy with the return of the explorer's statue.</p>
<p>Harrison Tuttle is president of Black Lives Matter Rhode Island PAC. Tuttle said he understands the connection that many of Italian ancestry feel for Columbus. But he wished the mayor had spoken with members of the community who were offended by the decision to return the statue.</p>
<p>"My grandmother who helped raise me was Italian and I grew up in a majority Italian neighborhood," he said. "At the same time, there are better ways to celebrate your <strong>heritage</strong> and culture without celebrating someone who in my opinion is the exact opposite of what Italian culture is."</p>
<p>Darrell Waldron, director of the Rhode Island Indian Council, is the son of a Narragansett father and a Wampanoag mother. He said he and others hoped that the statue would have been sold off and kept out of public view, with money going toward a new statue.</p>
<p>"I would love to see a statue of Native women," he said. "It doesn't always have to be a man."</p>
<p>The debate over the statue in Rhode Island is part of a larger debate in America about what to call the federal holiday that falls on Monday, October 9, this year.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Mario Ritter, Jr. of VOA and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>perspective</strong> - n. a way of thinking about or understanding something</p>
<p><strong>heritage</strong> - n. traditions, achievements, beliefs, etc... that are part of the history of a group ore nation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Universities Work to Protect American Wine Grapes from Wildfire Smoke  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/universities-work-to-protect-american-wine-grapes-from-wildfire-smoke.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The West Coast of the United States produces over 90 percent of America's wine, an alcoholic drink. However, the area is also <strong>prone</strong> to wildfires.</p>
<p>Such fires cost the American wine industry billions of dollars in 2020. The smoke affects the<strong> flavor</strong> of the growing grapes that later become the wine. And, the flavor is undesirable, say some wine drinkers.</p>
<p>So, wine experts from state universities in the area are working together to protect wine grapes from wildfire smoke.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Oregon State University students show Pinot noir grapes at the university's vineyard near Alpine, Ore., on Friday, Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Selsky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/89dfdbd5-1502-41d4-9d8a-52b64f3da6b0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Oregon State University students show Pinot noir grapes at the university's vineyard near Alpine, Ore., on Friday, Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Selsky)</span></div>
<p>In 2020, economists say, wildfires caused billions of dollars of losses, which included the wine industry.</p>
<p>As a result, the U.S. Department of Agriculture is paying for grape research at some state schools. They include University of California, Davis (UC Davis), Oregon State University and Washington State University. The research investment is worthy, agriculture officials say, because wine grapes are America's highest-value crop.</p>
<p>Tom Collins is a wine scientist at Washington State. He said "the ability to continue to make wine" is at risk in areas where smoke might be more common.</p>
<p>Cole Cerrato is a researcher working on the problem in Oregon. He stood in Oregon State's vineyard, near the small town of Alpine. He lit a fire and blew the smoke through a hose and into a row of grapes covered in plastic.</p>
<p>Cerrato and other researchers have done this before. They turned the treated grapes into wine. The result was, the wine had an unpleasant flavor of smoke and ash.</p>
<p>The scientists are working to find a way to keep the smoke from getting through the grape skins and creating a bad taste in the wine.</p>
<p>Some are trying to create a process that will treat wine and remove the smokiness. But they are concerned such a process might remove some of the wine's good flavors, too.</p>
<p>Others think they can combine smoke-affected grapes with other grapes. The mix might lessen the smoky flavor.</p>
<p>And Collins is working on a <strong>spray</strong> made from water and a kind of clay that would protect the grapes from smoke. But all the grapes would need to be washed first before being turned into wine.</p>
<p>Oregon State is experimenting with a similar spray treatment for grapes.</p>
<p>In addition, the USDA has provided $7 million toward setting up smoke sensors in vineyards.</p>
<p>Anita Oberholster is leading the efforts to save the wine grapes at UC Davis. In an internet post by UC Davis, she said a network of <strong>sensors</strong> would help grape growers learn if their grapes are at risk. In addition, the readings from the sensors will permit the growers to prove their grapes are free from smoke damage.</p>
<p>Winemakers are glad that the universities are working to help the industry. Greg Jones runs the Abacela winery in southern Oregon and is the director of the state's winemaking trade group.</p>
<p>He said the research has "gone a long way." Now the grape-growers can quickly find out if the fruit has been hurt by the smoke. In the past, winemakers would not know about the wine until it was ready to drink.</p>
<p>"I think it's increasingly clear that we're not likely to find a magic <strong>bullet</strong>," Collins said. But, he said, the researchers will find ways to keep the wine business successful.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>prone</strong>–adj. likely to do or suffer from something</p>
<p><strong>flavor </strong>–n. the taste of something</p>
<p><strong>spray</strong>–n. liquid forced out of a container in very small drops</p>
<p><strong>sensor </strong>–n. a device that detects something, such as the presence of smoke</p>
<p><strong>bullet </strong>–n. a piece of metal shot out of a gun</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do You Stay 'In Shape'?  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-do-you-stay-in-shape.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give you definitions, examples, and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today, we talk about <strong>fitness</strong> and exercise. <u>Keeping in shape</u> is a common expression for staying physically fit!</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People exercise inside Warren Hills cemetery in Harare, Zimbabwe, November 24 ,2022. (REUTERS/Philimon Bulawayo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/03370000-0aff-0242-02cc-08dad585c86c_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People exercise inside Warren Hills cemetery in Harare, Zimbabwe, November 24 ,2022. (REUTERS/Philimon Bulawayo)</span></div>
<p>What sort of exercise do you enjoy? How do you get in shape? If you are already in shape, how do you stay in shape?</p>
<p>I used to walk a lot for work and that kept me in good shape. Five days a week I would walk to the train station, walk to the office and then climb stairs. At lunch, my coworkers and I would take a walk outside. Our office is in a beautiful area of Washington, D.C., surrounded by <strong>museums</strong> and <strong>monuments</strong>. So that adds up to a lot of walking!</p>
<p>But then, in 2020 like so many others, I started working from home. I became worried that without all that walking, I would quickly get out of shape! So, I made time for more swimming and short walks around my <strong>neighborhood</strong>. Those two kept me in shape.</p>
<p>Using the word "shape" when talking about fitness and health makes sense. Sometimes, we can describe the human body in terms of size and shape. But we can also use the word "shape" to talk about our projects, our activities, our actions and behaviors.</p>
<p>So, <u>shape up</u> also means to correct bad behavior. For example, a boss might warn an underperforming employee to <u>shape up</u>. The boss may take this expression one step further. She or he might add a threat by saying <u>shape up or ship out.</u></p>
<p>Talking about ships, we also describe things that are clean or running smoothly as <u>shipshape</u>. A ship that is orderly and clean runs more smoothly and is safer. Remember, on a ship, you can be very far away from help. So, keeping things in good order prevents accidents and big problems.</p>
<p>So, what happens if a situation or a project was in trouble but is now going well? Well, we can say <u>things are shaping up</u>. If it's not going well, we can say the project is in <u>bad shape</u>.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear two friends use some of these expressions.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, how's the project going?</em></p>
<p><em>B: It's going well. Everything is <u>shipshape</u> now.</em></p>
<p><em>A: What do you mean ‘now'?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, last week we ran into some trouble. An employee <strong>wasn't pulling his weight</strong> and things weren't getting done. </em></p>
<p><em>A: What did you do?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I told him, "<u>Shape up or ship out</u>." </em></p>
<p><em>A: That's pretty <strong>harsh</strong>! </em></p>
<p><em>B: Maybe, but he <u>shaped up</u>. Now he's a valuable member of the team. I think he was overworked and dealing with some personal issues.</em></p>
<p><em>A: We all run into trouble sometimes. Hey, talking about being overworked ... let's take a break in a bit. I need a walk!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Sounds good. The project is in good shape. But I have to make sure I stay in good shape too!</em></p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. We hope you enjoyed learning some "shape" expressions and verbal phrases.</p>
<p>Practice using them the next time you want to talk about getting or staying physically fit.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fitness </strong><em>–n.</em> physical health and strength</p>
<p><strong>museum </strong><em>–n.</em> a building where interesting or valuable things are collected, shown to the public, or studied</p>
<p><strong>monument </strong><em>–n.</em> a building, artwork or place dedicated to the memory of a person or event</p>
<p><strong>neighborhood </strong><em>–n. </em>the people living near one another</p>
<p><strong>to pull your weight </strong><em>–idiom</em> to do a fair share of work</p>
<p><strong>harsh </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is unpleasant or difficult to accept</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Franklin Roosevelt: Powerful (Part 2)  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt-part-2.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Earlier we told about his rise to power, and his health problems. When he was 39 years old, FDR – as he was often called – became <strong>paralyzed</strong> from the waist down. He was never able to walk independently again.</p>
<p>But that did not prevent him from becoming one of the country's most powerful presidents.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7839e5c5-a69d-40ca-b953-5e64fe4efbf2_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt</span></div>
<p><strong>Presidency: The Great Depression and the New Deal</strong></p>
<p>When FDR took office, the United States was in a severe economic depression. Many farmers were not able to sell their crops for profit. Banks across the country had failed. A number of Americans lost their savings and their homes. And more than 25% of the workforce did not have a job.</p>
<p>Yet when FDR took office in 1933, he told people, "The only thing we have to fear is fear itself."</p>
<p>When Americans think of FDR, they often think of that statement. It showed his spirit of hope and <strong>confidence</strong> for which he became known.</p>
<p>Americans also remember FDR for the way he began his presidency. In his <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/first-100-days-meaning/3824866.html">first 100 days</a>, he signed more than 70 bills into law. Some led to major changes in the country. They helped calm the country's banking industry, provided federal aid directly to farmers and the unemployed, and created public works programs.</p>
<p>The acts formed the base of what FDR and others called the New Deal.</p>
<p>Some New Deal programs – including the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/civilian-conservation-corps">Civilian Conservation Corps</a> and the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/history-of-the-tva">Tennessee Valley Authority</a> – created government-funded jobs. In addition to providing a paycheck for workers, the programs were meant to improve and care for the country's natural resources. For example, workers planted trees, made roads, and built dams and power plants.</p>
<p>Americans continue to experience the effects of these programs today.</p>
<p>FDR is also remembered for the way he communicated with the public. At that time, as many as 90% of Americans owned a radio. So, from time to time, FDR spoke to the public on radio broadcasts that became known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/fireside-chats">fireside chats</a>."</p>
<p>The term created an image of the president sitting <strong>comfortably</strong> near a fireplace, talking informally with a few close friends. In fact, FDR gave these talks from his office in the White House. But his voice was warm, and he spoke in an easy, conversational way to listeners, whom he called "my friends."</p>
<p>The combination of FDR's hope, energy, and affectionate concern for everyday Americans made him popular with many voters. He was re-elected easily in 1936.</p>
<p>But FDR had critics, too. Some pointed out that many of his programs failed. They cost a lot of money or were simply not effective.</p>
<p>Others said that FDR's policy of massive government intervention was not American. It restricted capitalism and the free market.</p>
<p>Still others observed that FDR's programs did not help everyone equally. Many New Deal programs aimed to put young, white American men to work. Women, racial minorities, and older Americans were often overlooked.</p>
<p>Critics and supporters alike also noted that FDR greatly expanded the power of the presidency. He added a number of full-time positions to the <strong>executive</strong> branch of government. And he took on the power of Congress to make laws.</p>
<p>Even the Supreme Court found that FDR had, in some cases, gone too far. It ruled that some of his actions were illegal.</p>
<p>FDR worried that the Supreme Court would block many of his other New Deal programs, too. So he proposed a rule. It would give the president power to appoint six new members to the nine-member court. His appointments would almost certainly make sure that his New Deal programs could continue.</p>
<p>Many historians point to FDR's efforts at "court-packing" as one of the most extreme examples of his attempts to expand presidential power.</p>
<p>But Congress did not accept FDR's proposal. Nine justices remained on the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>However, those justices went on to approve FDR's actions anyway. They supported programs such as <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/fdr-signs-social-security-act">Social Security</a>, which was set up to help older adults, disabled people, and others who needed support; and the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Wagner-Act">Wagner Act</a>, which permitted workers to organize in a trade union.</p>
<p>While these efforts and other programs were important parts of FDR's reform efforts, they did not stop the Great Depression. None of the New Deal programs really did. The economy continued to struggle.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: Declaration of war</strong></p>
<p>For several years, the president had been warning lawmakers and other Americans about the political forces in Japan, Germany, and Italy. Leaders in those countries supported nationalist movements and had already invaded or taken control of other areas.</p>
<p>By 1941, more than 30 countries were involved in the conflict.</p>
<p>Many Americans had wanted the U.S. to remain neutral. They regretted becoming involved in World War I. For years, they had taken steps to prevent another major international conflict. Lawmakers had even banned the U.S. government from selling or giving weapons to warring countries.</p>
<p>But FDR believed World War II was different. He believed that Germany was the clear aggressor and needed to be stopped.</p>
<p>So, in the 1930s, FDR received permission from Congress to provide weapons to the countries opposing Germany. After Germany took control of France, FDR received permission to give direct military aid to Britain.</p>
<p>In addition, FDR began preparing the U.S. military for war.</p>
<p>On December 7, 1941, Japanese forces bombed American ships at the U.S. Navy base in Pearl Harbor, Hawaii. More than 2,400 Americans died at Pearl Harbor, and more than 1,700 were wounded.</p>
<p>The day after Pearl Harbor was attacked, Congress quickly approved FDR's request to declare war against Japan.</p>
<p>Three days later, Germany and Italy declared war on the United States. American lawmakers responded <strong>in kind</strong>. The U.S., which had remained neutral for many years, was now completely involved in World War II.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: World War II</strong></p>
<p>During the war, FDR directed much of his attention to what would happen after the fighting stopped. He wanted to create an international order that would improve peace and cooperation. To that end, he helped organize 26 countries into a group he called the United Nations.</p>
<p>FDR also believed that the world's future security depended, in large part, on cooperation between the U.S. and the Soviet Union. He worked hard to create friendly relations with the Soviet leader, Joseph Stalin.</p>
<p>Stalin, FDR, and British prime minister Winston Churchill all famously met at the Russian town of Yalta.</p>
<p>There, the three men discussed plans to bring World War II to an end. They decided to demand that Germany surrender unconditionally. They also talked about diplomatic relations after the war ended.</p>
<p>At the time, many Americans believed the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://history.state.gov/milestones/1937-1945/yalta-conf">Yalta conference</a> was a success. Soviet officials agreed to enter the war against Japan. In return, U.S. officials said the Soviet government could re-gain control over parts of Northeastern China. Soviet officials also agreed to let countries in Eastern Europe hold free elections, and to share rights to veto U.N. decisions.</p>
<p>In the eyes of many Americans, the Yalta agreement showed that the United States and the Soviet Union would be able to cooperate.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>FDR did not live to see the effects of the Yalta agreement, or even the end of the conflict.</p>
<p>He had been president for 12 years. A few weeks before the Yalta Conference, he had been sworn-in yet again.</p>
<p>FDR had already served longer than any U.S. president. All others before him had followed the custom set by the first president, George Washington. They had served no more than two terms.</p>
<p>In the winter of 1944, FDR was beginning his fourth term. But people close to him said he did not look well. Doctors also warned Roosevelt that his health was suffering.</p>
<p>So, in April, FDR went to a warm water<strong> resort</strong> in Georgia where he often rested and recovered his strength. There, he suffered a cerebral hemorrhage. In other words, his brain began to bleed.</p>
<p>World leaders, including Stalin and Churchill, said they were shocked he had died. Many Americans felt the same. They stood alongside train tracks as his body was carried from Georgia to his childhood home in New York.</p>
<p>He is buried there, at Hyde Park. In 1962, his wife Eleanor died and was buried next to him.</p>
<p>Today, Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt are important <strong>figures</strong> in U.S. history. Many programs from the New Deal are still in effect now. FDR also changed the position of president into an active, powerful leader who legally intervenes in the economy and seems to have a personal relationship with Americans.</p>
<p>And Eleanor Roosevelt developed a strong voice of her own. Her humanitarian efforts and work on behalf of civil rights and women's rights have given her a <strong>legacy</strong> independent from her husband.</p>
<p>Both admirers and critics point to the Roosevelts' influence as evidence of their strong feelings about the couple.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>paralyzed</strong> - <em>adj. </em>unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
<p><strong>comfortably</strong> - <em>adv. </em> in a relaxed and easy way</p>
<p><strong>executive</strong> -<em> n. </em>the executive branch of a government (related to the presidency)</p>
<p><strong>in kind </strong>- <em>phrase </em> in a way that is equal or very similar to what someone else has done for you</p>
<p><strong>resort </strong>- <em>n. </em>a place where people go for vacations</p>
<p><strong>figures</strong> - <em>n.</em> people who have a specified status or who are regarded in a specified way</p>
<p><strong>legacy</strong> - <em>n.</em> something that happened in the past or that comes from someone in the past</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Traditional Work of Aymara Women in Danger of Disappearing  (2023/10/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/traditional-work-of-aymara-women-in-danger-of-disappearing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>In northern Chile, Teófila Challapa learned to weave, or make cloth, surrounded by the high hills and sandy roads of the Atacama Desert.</p>
<p>"<strong>Spin</strong> the <strong>threads</strong>, girl," her grandmother told her fifty years ago.</p>
<p>The 59-year-old Challapa is Aymara, a native South American Indian people. She raises alpacas and llamas. The animals' hair can be cut off and turned into cloth called wool.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Te&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;243;fila Challapa weaves on her loom at home in Cariquima, Chile, on July 31, 2023. Challapa, 59, prays before beginning her work: " because="" earth="" give="" me="" me.="" mother="" munoz="" not="" one="" photo="" produce="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8e90-08dbc5d479d3_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg" strength="" the="" who="" will="" you=""/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Te<i>&amp;#</i>243;fila Challapa weaves on her loom at home in Cariquima, Chile, on July 31, 2023. Challapa, 59, prays before beginning her work: "Mother Earth, give me strength, because you're the one who will produce, not me." (AP Photo/Ignacio Munoz)</span></div>
<p>"We had no clothes or money, so we needed to learn how to dress with our own hands," said Challapa. She lives in Cariquima, a town with fewer than 500 people near the Chile-Bolivia border.</p>
<p>The knowledge of weaving passes from one generation to another, securing Aymara families' connection with their land.</p>
<p>Challapa prays before beginning her work: "Mother Earth, give me strength, because you're the one who will produce, not me."</p>
<p>Among the 3 million Aymaras who live along the borders of Chile, Peru, and Bolivia, the Earth is known as "Pachamama." Acts to honor Pachamama and asks for Earth's <strong>blessings </strong>are a part of everyday life for the people.</p>
<p>"I believe in God, but the Earth provides us with everything," Challapa said.</p>
<p>Pachamama <strong>inspires</strong> Challapa's work in textiles. It provides means for survival, too.</p>
<p>"My animals are my mother," Challapa said.</p>
<p>Her alpacas and llamas were a source of meat, wool, and emotional support during the difficult years she spent as a single parent raising her children.</p>
<p>Aymara weavers cut off their animals' wool in October when the weather is warmer. The llamas keep several centimeters of wool to keep them warm and ready for the "floreo." During this ancient ceremony celebrated in February, Aymaras tie wool flowers to their animals identifying them as their property. They also thank Pachamama for providing them the things they need.</p>
<p>Once the wool is collected and cleaned, the weavers use their fingers to pull threads out of it. The threads are grouped together and placed on a weaving machine called a loom.</p>
<p>Aymara women like Challapa use the money they make from the sale of wool products to send their children to school.</p>
<p>"I thank God because I always told myself: I don't want them to be like me," said Marcelina Choque, another woman weaver who lives in the town of Pozo Almonte. "This is my only profession. If I don't sell, I have nothing."</p>
<p>Such generational progress comes with mixed emotions, however. "I taught my daughters how to weave just like me, but now that they have other jobs, they don't weave anymore," Choque said.</p>
<p>Several woman weavers say the traditional work may end because younger Aymara are moving away from their hometowns. The weavers say there are few young Aymara women who know how to use a loom.</p>
<p>"In rural areas, there is a <strong>significant</strong> migration of young people, and the population is aging," said Luis Pizarro, who works at the Agricultural Development Institute of Chile.</p>
<p>The organization supports rural development for Chilean communities connected to the Aymara culture, Pizarro said. The goal is to increase the farming of alpacas and llamas and products through special events and online.</p>
<p>Recently, the Institute held a <strong>fashion</strong> show inside a shopping center in the city of Iquique. Teófila Challapa, María Choque and other women had their daughters serves as models at the show and sold some of their work.</p>
<p>"We try to get daughters and granddaughters of artisans involved in their cultural inheritance," Pizarro said.</p>
<p>Nayareth Challapa (no relation to Teófila) speaks proudly about her mother who taught her how to pick the perfect plants for coloring the cloth.</p>
<p>"The colors of our textiles are related to nature: the earth, the sky, the hills. The land is sacred for us," the 25-year old said. She said the work represents the maker's emotions as well as the "llamas, flowers and mountains she wants to keep present."</p>
<p>Nayareth Challapa moved to a city to attend university like so many others. But home is never far from her heart.</p>
<p>"When migrating, many forget their ethnicity and leave their roots behind," Challapa said. "But my family tries to avoid that.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>María Teresa Hernández reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>thread </strong>– <em>n</em>. a long, thin piece of cotton, silk, or wool used for sewing</p>
<p><strong>spin </strong>– <em>v</em>. <strong> </strong>to draw out and twist into yarn or thread</p>
<p><strong>blessing </strong>– <em>n</em>. something that makes one happy or content</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong>– <em>n</em>. to cause to have a particular thought or feeling</p>
<p><strong>significant </strong>– <em>n</em>. of a noticeably or measurably large amount</p>
<p><strong>fashion </strong>– <em>n</em>. a common style especially of dress during a particular time or among a certain group</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Jailed Iranian Activist Wins Nobel Peace Prize  (2023/10/7) | 伊朗女活动家获得2023年诺贝尔和平奖</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/jailed-iranian-activist-wins-nobel-peace-prize.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Imprisoned Iranian activist Narges Mohammadi won the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday. Mohammadi was recognized for women's rights and democracy, and against the death penalty.<br/>
周五，被监禁的伊朗活动家纳吉斯·穆罕默迪获得诺贝尔和平奖。穆罕默迪因捍卫妇女权利和民主，以及反对死刑而获得认可。</p>
<p>Fifty-one-year-old Mohammadi has kept up her activism although she has been arrested many times by Iranian officials and has been sentenced to years in prison. She has remained a leader of nationwide, women-led protests. Major protests followed the death last year of a 22-year-old woman in police custody.<br/>
51岁的穆罕默迪一直在积极行动，尽管她多次被伊朗官员逮捕，并被判处多年监禁。她一直是伊朗国内由妇女领导的抗议活动的领导者。去年，一名22岁女子在警方拘留期间死亡，引发了大规模抗议活动。</p>
<p>Berit Reiss-Andersen is the chair of the Norwegian Nobel Committee. She said the prize is "a recognition of the very important work of a whole movement in Iran with its undisputed leader, Narges Mohammadi."<br/>
贝里特·赖斯-安德森是挪威诺贝尔委员会主席。她说，该奖项是“对伊朗整个运动及其无可争议的领导人纳吉斯·穆罕默迪所做的非常重要的工作的认可。”</p>
<p>Reiss-Andersen started the announcement with the words "Woman, Life, Freedom" in Farsi — the slogan of the protest movement in Iran. She said the committee hopes to send a message to women around the world with the award. She also urged Iran to release Mohammadi in time for the prize ceremony on December 10.<br/>
赖斯-安德森在宣布这一消息时用波斯语写下了“女人，生命，自由”，这是伊朗抗议运动的口号。她说，委员会希望通过这个奖项向世界各地的女性传递一个信息。她还敦促伊朗及时释放穆罕默迪，以参加12月10日的颁奖典礼。</p>
<p>Reiss-Andersen said Mohammadi has been imprisoned 13 times. She was imprisoned for the recent protests over the death of Mahsa Amini, a woman who died after being arrested by Iran's morality police for wearing a loose headscarf. More than 500 people were killed and over 22,000 arrested in a security campaign against the protests.<br/>
赖斯-安德森说穆罕默迪已经被监禁了13次。她因最近针对马赫萨·阿米尼之死的抗议活动而入狱，这位妇女因戴着宽松的头巾被伊朗道德警察逮捕后死亡。在一场针对抗议活动的安全运动中，有500多人死亡，22000多人被捕。</p>
<p>Last month, Mohammadi wrote from Tehran's Evin Prison to The New York Times. She wrote, "What the government may not understand is that the more of us they lock up, the stronger we become."<br/>
上个月，穆罕默迪在德黑兰埃温监狱给《纽约时报》写了一封信。她写道：“政府可能不明白的是，他们把我们关得越多，我们就会变得越强大。”</p>
<p>Her husband Taghi Rahmani lives in Paris with their two children. Rahmani, who has not seen his wife for at least 11 years, could not reach her after the announcement. He told the Associated Press that his wife always says: "Every single award will make me more intrepid, more resilient and more brave for realizing human rights, freedom, civil equality and democracy."<br/>
她的丈夫塔吉·拉哈马尼和他们的两个孩子住在巴黎。拉赫曼尼已经至少11年没有见到他的妻子了，在该消息宣布后，他无法联系到她。他告诉美联社，他的妻子总是说：“每一个奖项都会让我在实现人权、自由、公民平等和民主方面更加勇敢、更有韧性和更有勇气。”</p>
<p>Their son, Ali Rahmani, noted that the prize was not just for his mother. He said, "Iranian men and women have been fighting for over a year. This prize is for the entire population, for the whole struggle from the beginning since the Islamic government came to power."<br/>
他们的儿子阿里·拉赫曼尼指出，这个奖项不仅仅是颁给他的母亲。他说：“伊朗人民已经抗争了一年多。这个奖项是颁给全体人民自伊斯兰政府上台以来进行的整个斗争。”</p>
<p>There was no official reaction from the Iranian government. But the unofficial news agency Fars said Mohammadi had "received her prize from the Westerners" for her actions "against the national security."<br/>
伊朗政府没有做出任何官方反应。但非官方的法尔斯通讯社表示，穆罕默迪因其“危害国家安全”的行为“获得了西方人的奖励”。</p>
<p>Mohammadi is the 19th woman to win the 122-year-old prize. It also marks the fifth time that the Peace Prize has been given to someone who is in prison or under house arrest. Past winners include Martin Luther King, Jr. and Nelson Mandela.<br/>
穆罕默迪是第19位获得这个已有122年历史的奖项的女性。这也是和平奖第五次颁发给被监禁或软禁的人。过去的获奖者包括马丁·路德·金和纳尔逊·曼德拉。</p>
<p>The five-member Norwegian Nobel Committee chooses the Nobel Peace Prize winner, and the award is presented in Oslo, unlike all the other Nobel Prizes.<br/>
由五名成员组成的挪威诺贝尔委员会选出诺贝尔和平奖获得者，该奖项在奥斯陆颁发，这与其他所有诺贝尔奖不同。</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ethiopian Coffee Stores Find Fans Far from Home  (2023/10/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/ethiopian-coffee-stores-find-fans-far-from-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>When Yared Markos moved to London 25 years ago, he did not see any Ethiopian coffee shops. Now, there are at least 12 around a city known for its tea drinkers.</p>
<p>In Ethiopia, coffee is usually drank at the end of each meal. Drinking coffee is a communal activity for Markos. When he first immigrated to London from Ethiopia 23 years ago, he did not understand the culture.</p>
<p>"They sell our coffee in Starbucks and other places, but they don't follow our traditions," said Markos, who has owned Kaffa Coffee since 2004. The shop is now in an East London neighborhood. It holds coffee ceremonies every weekend in the summer. It also holds cultural events and fills special orders.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Anteneh Mulu, 46, poses behind the counter after serving a customer at his coffee shop, The Ethiopian Coffee Company, in central London on Thursday, Aug. 31, 2023. (AP Photo/Almaz Abedje)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5888-08dbc518ed67_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Anteneh Mulu, 46, poses behind the counter after serving a customer at his coffee shop, The Ethiopian Coffee Company, in central London on Thursday, Aug. 31, 2023. (AP Photo/Almaz Abedje)</span></div>
<p>"<strong>Tourists</strong> will walk by and smell the coffee and come in asking questions," Markos said. "It makes people want to learn more about the culture."</p>
<p>Among some of the most popular Ethiopian kinds of coffee are the flowery Yirgacheffe, fruity Limu and nutty Kochere.</p>
<p><strong>An ancient tradition</strong></p>
<p>Markos named Kaffa after the southwestern area in Ethiopia where coffee beans are believed to have been discovered about 1,200 years ago.</p>
<p>An old story says that an Ethiopian goat farmer once noticed his goats acting strangely one day after eating <strong>berries</strong> from a tree. He tried them himself and felt energized and awake. The farmer took the berries to a religious worker, a monk, who threw them in a fire, calling them the work of the <strong>devil</strong>.</p>
<p>A strong smell was released, so the monks saved the burnt coffee, putting it in a container with hot water. When they drank the liquid, they realized it helped them stay awake during nightly prayers.</p>
<p>Coffee contains a lot of <strong>caffeine</strong>, a substance that has the effect of keeping people awake and feeling energetic.</p>
<p>Over the years, coffee-making in Ethiopia has changed into ceremonies led by the women in households.</p>
<p>"The social value of the coffee ceremony is one of our biggest traditions," Markos said.</p>
<p><strong>How the coffee is made</strong></p>
<p>Fresh coffee "beans" are heated in a <strong>pot</strong> for a few minutes before being passed around, so everyone can breathe its smell. The beans are then ground down to a powder and placed inside an Ethiopian coffee pot, traditionally made of clay, on top of a stove.</p>
<p>While the coffee is being made, frankincense, a substance from a tree, is burned to <strong>enhance</strong> the taste. Once the water comes to a boil several times, the coffee is placed in a small cup called a sini.</p>
<p><strong>International coffee day</strong></p>
<p>Almost 10 years ago, the International Coffee Organization, with 77 member countries, officially marked October 1 as International Coffee Day. This year, the group is calling for a safe and healthy working environment in places involved in the coffee trade.</p>
<p>The London Coffee Festival started in 2011. It also provides a chance for coffee lovers to come together. Anteneh Mulu is one of the owners of The Ethiopian Coffee Company in central London. He said the festival has helped spread Ethiopian coffee to a new community.</p>
<p>Mulu and his business partner Polly Hamilton opened their store in 2013. Like Kaffa Coffee, they import directly from Ethiopia, where beans are named for the area where they were grown.</p>
<p>As Ethiopia's traditions spread outside the country, both Markos and Mulu hope more people will be pushed to value their community over concerns about drinking caffeine in their coffee.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tourist </strong><em>— n. </em>someone who travels to a place for pleasure and not for work</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>berry </strong><em>–n.</em> a small kind of fruit</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>the devil </strong><em>–n.</em> the most powerful evil spirit in many religions</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enhance </strong><em>— v. </em>to improve or increase the effect of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>caffeine </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>a chemical compound made by a number of plants including the coffee and tea plants that affects the nervous system of animals</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pot </strong><em>–n.</em> a container for cooking</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Do Songs Break Grammar Rules?  (2023/10/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/why-do-songs-break-grammar-rules.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! Our question for today on <em>Ask a Teacher</em> comes from a reader in Brazil.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>I have an easy question. Why does Sir Elton John use "don't" and not "doesn't" in the song <em>This Train Don't Stop There Anymore</em>?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3e66-08dbc5d80844_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Thanks</p>
<p><strong><em>Luiz, Brazil</em></strong></p>
<p>Dear Luiz,</p>
<p>That's a great question. As an English teacher, I often hear things in songs that do not follow grammar rules. Sometimes, I believe it is because the songwriter wants to speak in a way that is used by another community. Also,<strong> informal</strong>, or everyday, language is often not completely grammatical.</p>
<p><strong>Songwriting partners</strong></p>
<p>Let's look at some of the words of <em>This Train Don't Stop There Anymore</em>. It appears in a collection of songs called <em>Songs from the West Coast</em>, published in 2001. The songwriter Bernie Taupin co-wrote this and many other songs with Elton John. Taupin wrote the words and John wrote the music. Taupin said he was always interested in "Americana," the culture and history of America, and in country and western music. That helps explain the images and language he put into this song.</p>
<p>In the first part, the singer says he does not believe in <strong>miracles</strong> anymore and has lost strong feelings about romantic love. The second part brings in images of an old kind of train:</p>
<p><em>I used to be the main express<br/>
All steam and whistles heading west<br/>
Picking up my pain from door to door<br/>
Riding on the storyline, furnace burning overtime<br/>
But this train don't stop<br/>
This train don't stop<br/>
This train don't stop there anymore</em></p>
<p>The singer tells us of the strong emotions he once had by comparing them to a fast, or express<em>,</em> train. The high, sharp sound of a train warning people of its approach is called a whistle. Old trains used to be powered by steam engines that let out whistles as they passed through towns.</p>
<p>If we connect these words to the earlier part of the song, we can get a picture in our mind of a lonely, <strong>isolated</strong> place. A town where the train no longer stops is usually a quiet place with little activity. We can suppose that town is like the singer's heart.</p>
<p>My understanding of the song is that the singer is saying he no longer wants to be in love because the feeling is too strong. Continuing the image of the train, he sings,</p>
<p><em>It really means my engine's breaking down</em></p>
<p>What do you think, Luiz? Would the song be just as good if Elton John sang, "That train doesn't stop there anymore?" Maybe it would not have the quality of informal language Taupin was hoping for.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em> for this week. Do you have a question for the teacher? Write to us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>This Train Don't Stop There Anymore lyrics <i></i>169; Universal Music Publishing Group</em></p>
<p><em>What do you think of songs that break grammar rules? Are there any in your language, too? Write to us in the Comments Section. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Online ‘Digital Divide’ Leaves Girls Behind  (2023/10/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/report-online-digital-divide-leaves-girls-behind.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new report suggests many girls across the world are not using the internet because of online abuse, discrimination or other issues.</p>
<p>The report was produced by a non-profit group called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://girleffect.org/">Girl Effect</a>. The organization carries out research and programs aimed at linking young girls to education, useful products and technology. The effort was also supported by the Malala Fund, the United Nations Children's agency UNICEF and the Vodafone Americas Foundation.</p>
<p>The report says many girls face numerous barriers to using the internet, especially on mobile devices. Girl Effect describes a situation on the internet that it says can favor boys over girls. It calls the situation a "digital divide."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Thai Buddhist Monks walk past a line of internet users at an internet expo on May 25, 2000. (REUTERS/File photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-751d-08dbc5aadd3d_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Thai Buddhist Monks walk past a line of internet users at an internet expo on May 25, 2000. (REUTERS/File photo)</span></div>
<p>"The digital <strong>gender </strong>divide is real and is creating public spaces where women, especially girls, are being left behind," <a class="wsw__a" href="https://girleffect.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/2023-Girls-and-Mobile-Report-FINAL.pdf">said</a> Girl Effect chief executive Jessica Posner Odede in a statement. She added that girls are often told they are "<strong>vulnerable</strong>, less <strong>competent</strong>, and unable to protect themselves online."</p>
<p>The group's report said these kinds of statements can reshape girls' beliefs and opinions and prevent them from fully taking part in numerous online activities. This can severely limit the information they see and can block educational and job progress.</p>
<p>Online abuse and concerns about internet safety have resulted in many girls "setting up more protections and behaving more conservatively when connecting with others and sharing personal information online," the report said.</p>
<p>The report is based on a public opinion study involving more than 10,000 boys and girls aged 14 to 21. A separate part questioned parents of the youth. Data was collected in seven countries: Ethiopia, India, Jordan, Kenya, Nigeria, Rwanda and Tanzania. Comparative data came from Britain and the United States.</p>
<p>The report noted that, "Women across low- and middle-income countries are seven percent less likely than men to own a mobile phone and are 19 percent less likely to use mobile internet."</p>
<p>The report suggests a digital gender divide exists although governments worldwide have taken steps to prevent it. A UNICEF study released earlier this year showed that in 54 countries, there is a median gender ratio of 71. This means that for every 100 young boys and men who use the internet, only 71 young girls and women do.</p>
<p>Recent studies have also shown that women experience more online abuse, persuading large numbers of girls to quit social media services such as Facebook and Instagram.</p>
<p>The Girl Effect report found that among digitally connected youth, 12 percent more girls than boys said they feel <strong>self-conscious</strong> while using social media. The report also said girls are 11 percent less likely to place photos or comments online compared to boys of the same age.</p>
<p>Mitali Nikore is a gender policy specialist at research group Nikore Associates based in New Delhi. She told the Thomson Reuters Foundation that girls who limit their online activity often carry this behavior with them into the workplace. This can lead to difficulties for women who might hold back "in demonstrating their skills and building strategic connections," Nikore said.</p>
<p>Nikore noted she thinks several things are needed to help solve the problems girls are facing. One is to improve the availability of mobile devices for girls and young women across the world. Other possible solutions include establishing more digital <strong>literacy</strong> programs and efforts to end gender-based discrimination.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gender </strong><em>– n. </em>the state of being male or female</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>– adj. </em>easy to hurt or attack physically or emotionally</p>
<p><strong>competent </strong><em>– adj. </em>able to do something well</p>
<p><strong>self-conscious </strong><em>– adj. </em>to be too aware of what other people are thinking about you and your appearance</p>
<p><strong>literacy </strong><em>– n. </em>the ability to read and write</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Norwegian Writing about Life’s ‘Basic Choices’ Wins Nobel in Literature  (2023/10/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/norwegian-writing-about-life-s-basic-choices-wins-nobel-in-literature.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Swedish Academy awarded this year's Nobel Prize in Literature to a Norwegian known for considering life's "basic choices" in his 40 years of work.</p>
<p>Sixty-four-year-old Jon Fosse was first published in the 1980s and became well known in the 1990s. His works include a play called <em>Someone Is Going to Come</em> which was performed to praise in Paris in 1999. Later, he wrote a series of books called the <em>Septology,</em> which he finished in 2021. The last part of <em>Septology</em>, called <em>A New Name</em>, was a finalist for the Booker Prize in 2022.</p>
<p>Fosse created plays, books and children's books. He also worked on a <strong>translation</strong> of the Bible into Norwegian. He is known for writing in the Nynorsk language, which is understandable to all Norwegians. But it is used by only 10 percent of the nation's 5.4 million people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Norwegian playwright Jon Fosse poses for a photo at his home near Frekhaug, north of Bergen in Norway on October 5, 2023, after the Swedish Academy awarded him the 2023 Nobel literature prize. (Photo by EIRIK HAGESAETER / Bergensavisen / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1c108256-345f-4aaa-a888-7406f9f5e9bb_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Norwegian playwright Jon Fosse poses for a photo at his home near Frekhaug, north of Bergen in Norway on October 5, 2023, after the Swedish Academy awarded him the 2023 Nobel literature prize. (Photo by EIRIK HAGESAETER / Bergensavisen / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Swedish Academy member Anders Olsson said Fosse's work has had a "universal <strong>impact</strong>." The Academy also called his work "innovative" and noted his ability to "give voice to the unsayable." The group explained that his books discuss life's "deepest feelings" about things like life and death.</p>
<p>Fosse said he had been thinking he might be awarded the prize for the last 10 years, but he was still surprised to get the phone call on Thursday.</p>
<p>He told a Swedish broadcaster: "I've been part of the discussion for 10 years and have...prepared myself for 10 years that it could happen."</p>
<p>He told a Norwegian broadcaster he has no more prizes left to win. "Everything will be downhill from now on." He noted that he started writing as a boy and his first work came out 40 years ago. "I don't plan to compete with myself," he said. The writer added he will celebrate the prize "calmly" with his family.</p>
<p>Fosse said 1969 Nobel literature prize-winner Samuel Beckett of Ireland influenced his writing style. Beckett wrote the play <em>Waiting for Godot</em>.</p>
<p>Guy Puzey is a teacher of Scandinavian studies at the University of Edinburgh in Scotland. He called Fosse's writing "<strong>sparse</strong>" and said his "simple expressions...take on a lot deeper meaning..."</p>
<p>The Associated Press notes critics might call Fosse a "safe" choice for his "<strong>highbrow</strong>" writing only known to people in "small literary circles."</p>
<p>The Academy has been criticized for being too centered on men from Northern Europe and North America. That includes criticism from Annie Ernaux, last year's winner. Only 17 of 119 winners have been women.</p>
<p>Recent winners who have been popular writers include Mario Vargas Llosa of Peru, Kazuo Ishiguro of Japan, and Alice Munro of Canada. The Academy got a lot of attention for choosing American musician Bob Dylan in 2016.</p>
<p>Supporters say recent winners, including Dylan, show that the Nobel committee is interested in writers who are both popular and praised by critics.</p>
<p>Fosse's publisher says his work has been translated into 40 languages and his plays have been produced over 1,000 times. And he is the fourth Norwegian to win the prize but the first since 1928.</p>
<p>Fosse will receive a gold medal and about $1 million at the Nobel prize award ceremony in Stockholm, Sweden, on December 10.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press, Reuters and other sources. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>translation </strong><em>–n.</em> a version of a written work that is in another language than the original</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>–n.</em> influence or an effect</p>
<p><strong>sparse </strong><em>–adj.</em> less than might seem necessary; covering thinly</p>
<p><strong>highbrow </strong><em>–adj.</em> interested only in serious things and not playful or funny</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Two Cubans Combine Fishing, Farming for Better Food Production  (2023/10/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/two-cubans-combine-fishing-farming-for-better-food-production.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Cuba is undergoing economic crisis and shortages. This can make even simple efforts like fishing or farming complex.</p>
<p>That is why two young Cuban businessmen decided to turn to aquaponics to get better results and increase the amount of food available on the island nation.</p>
<p>Aquaponics is a practice that uses wastewater from fish farming to grow food plants in a soil-less environment. It brings together fishing and farming in a way that is both <strong>efficient</strong> and environmentally friendly.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Two Cubans Combine Fishing, Farming for Better Food Production" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e847-08dbc5b739c4_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Two Cubans Combine Fishing, Farming for Better Food Production</span></div>
<p>Joel Lopez, co-owner of JoJo Aquaponics, said the practice is a perfect fit for Cuba. "From fish to the production of food plants, everything is natural," he said while showing visitors the building where JoJo Aquaponics farms, outside of Havana, the capital of Cuba.</p>
<p>At the end of the month, the harvest includes both a protein from the fish, and a vegetable green – all without the use of expensive chemicals such as <strong>fertilizers</strong> and <strong>pesticides</strong>.</p>
<p>Cuba is facing its worst economic downturn in many years. Shortages of food, medicine and fuel have led the government to seek help from businesses in finding new solutions.</p>
<p>But businesses face a difficult environment in Cuba. The trade ban enforced by the United States makes doing business complex. And the Cuban government only recently permitted private businesses.</p>
<p>Jose Martinez is a co-owner of JoJo Aquaponics. He said aquaponics is costly and it has been difficult to raise money for the project. Martinez added that his business received some money from local government, though it was not enough.</p>
<p>Even with the barriers, many Cubans increasingly believe private businesses will succeed in a country where the average person earns less than $20 a month.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Alien Fernandez reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>efficient</strong>–<em>adj</em>. preventing waste</p>
<p><strong>fertilizer</strong>–<em>n</em>. a chemical substance added to increase fertility</p>
<p><strong>pesticide</strong>–<em>n</em>. a chemical or biological substance that protects from harmful organisms</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Uncertainty  (2023/10/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/grammar-and-uncertainty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Consider an unusual time in your life. Perhaps your country was having a financial crisis or a political crisis. Perhaps one of your family members became sick. In other words, you were facing an uncertain situation.</p>
<p>How do you talk about such situations?</p>
<p>That question will be the subject of today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>. You will learn about questions and answers. You will also learn about verbs and expressions used to express uncertainty.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1ddd-08dbc5a942b6_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>Let's start with some important terms and ideas.</p>
<p><strong>Questions about uncertain times </strong></p>
<p>Uncertainty means that something is doubtful or unknown. And, as the saying goes, life is full of uncertainties.</p>
<p>We often ask friends, family, coworkers, or even strangers about their thoughts and expectations during uncertain times.</p>
<p>There are two closely related questions we use in such situations. One involves "will" and the other involves "be going to." Although the questions have different wording, their meaning is the same. So, we have:</p>
<p><em>What do you think will happen?</em></p>
<p><em>What do you think is going to happen?</em></p>
<p>The structures of these questions are complex. We have the question word "what," the helping verb "do," the subject "you," the verb "think," and then the future marker – either "will" or "be going to" along with "happen."</p>
<p>We can also make our questions more exact by adding a noun or noun phrase after the word "to" near the end of the question.</p>
<p>So, you might ask:</p>
<p><em>What do you think will happen to______________?</em></p>
<p><em>What do you think is going to happen to _________________?</em></p>
<p>If your country has an uncertain financial situation, you might ask one of the following questions:</p>
<p><em>What will happen to the economy?</em></p>
<p><em>What is going to happen to the economy?</em></p>
<p>If your brother becomes sick, you might ask a doctor one of these questions:</p>
<p><em>What will happen to my brother?</em></p>
<p><em>What is going to happen to my brother?</em></p>
<p>These questions are open-ended. In other words, you are asking the person to give an answer that includes a lot of information.</p>
<p><strong>Answers about uncertainty </strong></p>
<p>We have explored questions about uncertainty. But how do we give answers? Answers could involve expressions, some <strong>specific</strong> verbs and adverbs, as well as <strong>phrasal verbs.</strong></p>
<p>In terms of expressions, a person might say:</p>
<p><em>I don't know.</em></p>
<p><em>I have no clue.</em></p>
<p>Verbs that we might use include hope, think, or doubt. Listen to these sentences.</p>
<p><em>I hope the economy turns around quickly.</em></p>
<p><em>I think the political disagreement will be solved quickly.</em></p>
<p><em>I doubt the economy will continue to fall apart.</em></p>
<p>And in the case of adverbs, we might use likely or unlikely, as in the flowing sentences:</p>
<p><em>It is likely that the economy will crash.</em></p>
<p><em>It is unlikely that the economy will crash.</em></p>
<p>With phrasal verbs, we might use "look like" - meaning to seem to be something because of appearances.</p>
<p>So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>It looks like the government is going to shut down.</em></p>
<p><em>It looks like that politician is going to win the election.</em></p>
<p>In the examples, "look like" suggests that the speaker has formed an idea about the situation. When you say, "It looks like something is going to happen," you are saying that you think something is likely to happen, even if the situation is uncertain.</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>The next time you read the news or watch a movie, pay careful attention to how speakers talk about uncertainty. Do the speakers use some of the terms and ideas we explored today? Or do they use different terms?</p>
<p>With time, you will notice that uncertainty – and discussions about uncertainty – make up a large part of our lives.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>specific</strong> <em>– adj. </em>special or particular</p>
<p><strong>phrasal verb</strong><em> – n.</em> a group of words that functions as a verb and is made up of a verb and another short word</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Finds AI Tools Help but also Hurt Worker Performance  (2023/10/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-finds-ai-tools-help-but-also-hurt-worker-performance.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An experiment involving hundreds of office workers has found that artificial intelligence (AI) tools can greatly help but also hurt worker performance.</p>
<p>AI tools designed to operate at human levels have greatly expanded in popularity over the past year. These include OpenAI's ChatGPT, Google's Bard and Microsoft's AI-powered search engine Bing.</p>
<p>Such tools, also known as chatbots or "generative AI," are computer-powered systems. They are designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing and creative work.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The ChatGPT logo and the words Artificial Intelligence are seen in this illustration image taken May 4, 2023. (Reuters)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8f88-08dbb92a42f0_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The ChatGPT logo and the words Artificial Intelligence are seen in this illustration image taken May 4, 2023. (Reuters)</span></div>
<p>In recent months, these tools have demonstrated an ability to produce high quality work. This has led some technology experts to warn that generative AI systems could end up replacing workers in many industries.</p>
<p>This year, researchers at Harvard Business School and other organizations carried out an experiment. It aimed to test how well AI tools could help workers perform their usual duties, or tasks. It involved more than 700 business advisors, called consultants, from Massachusetts-based Boston Consulting Group.</p>
<p>Harvard Business School recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4573321">published</a> results from the experiment in a "working paper." The main findings suggest that AI tools like ChatGPT can greatly improve worker performance.</p>
<p>For example, researchers found that, on average, workers who used OpenAI's latest ChatGPT 4 tool completed 12 percent more tasks than non-ChatGPT users. Tasks carried out with help from the AI technology were completed 25 percent faster. And the team found the quality of work performed by consultants using ChatGPT 4 increased about 40 percent.</p>
<p>Work tasks used in the study covered four main areas: creativity, <strong>analytical</strong> thinking, writing and persuasiveness. The team gave examples of worker tasks in each of these areas.</p>
<p>One example for creativity was: "Propose at least 10 ideas for a new shoe targeting an underserved market or sport." For writing, consultants were asked to "write a press release with marketing copy" for a new product. To show persuasiveness, workers were told to write a letter to employees that explained why a particular product would beat competitors.</p>
<p>Harvard Business School's Fabrizio Dell'Acqua was the paper's lead writer. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://venturebeat.com/ai/enterprise-workers-gain-40-percent-performance-boost-from-gpt-4-harvard-study-finds/">told</a> technology website VentureBeat he thinks the results were especially important because they showed that AI tools can help even highly educated, experienced workers.</p>
<p>"The fact that we could <strong>boost</strong> the performance of these highly paid, highly skilled consultants, from top, <strong>elite</strong> MBA institutions...I would say that's really <strong>impressive</strong>," Dell'Acqua said.</p>
<p>However, the paper also noted areas where the performance of consultants using ChatGPT 4 dropped. The researchers said this was especially true with tasks the AI tool was not good at completing.</p>
<p>Of tasks the AI was good at, the experiment showed it "significantly improved human performance," the paper <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.hbs.edu/ris/Publication%20Files/24-013_d9b45b68-9e74-42d6-a1c6-c72fb70c7282.pdf">said</a>. But for tasks ChatGPT 4 was not right for, "humans <strong>relied</strong> too much on the AI, and were more likely to make mistakes."</p>
<p>The researchers reported that consultants who used AI for tasks it was not well equipped for "were 19 percent less likely to produce correct solutions compared to those without AI."</p>
<p>The experiment also showed how consultants used the AI tool differently to improve their work. The researchers said some workers purposely divided the tasks with some being completely carried out by the AI tool and others the workers themselves carried out completely. Other workers chose to use AI for all tasks, while "continually interacting with the technology."</p>
<p>The team suggests one of the biggest barriers to companies effectively using AI is not knowing which tasks can be completed best with the technology. Finding this out will require businesses to carry out thoughtful research and training efforts in order to find the right mix of AI and human-level work.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Harvard Business School. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>analytical </strong><em>– adj. </em>examining the details of something carefully in order to understand or explain it</p>
<p><strong>impressive </strong><em>– adj. </em>making or attempting to make a marked impression</p>
<p><strong>boost –</strong>v. to lift or increase something</p>
<p><strong>elite </strong><em>– adj. </em>the richest, most powerful or best educated groups in a society</p>
<p><strong>rely </strong><em>– v. </em>to depend on</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Win Nobel Prize in Chemistry for Quantum Dots Discovery  (2023/10/5) | 三名科学家因发现量子点获得诺贝尔化学奖</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/three-win-nobel-prize-in-chemistry-for-quantum-dots-discovery.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Three scientists in the United States won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry on Wednesday. The three won for their discovery of quantum dots, a technology widely used today to make displays for electronic devices and medical imaging.<br/>
美国的三名科学家周三赢得了诺贝尔化学奖。 这三个人的获奖是因为发现了量子点，这是一项当今广泛运用于电子设备和医学成像显示的技术。</p>
<p>The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences awarded the prize to Moungi Bawendi of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Louis Brus of Columbia University in New York, and Alexei Ekimov of Nanocrystals Technology.<br/>
瑞典皇家科学院将该奖项授予了麻省理工学院的蒙吉·巴文迪，纽约哥伦比亚大学的路易斯·布鲁斯和美国纳米晶体科技公司的阿列克谢·伊基莫夫。</p>
<p>The academy said the three were honored for their work with particles that "have unique properties and now spread their light from television screens and LED lamps."<br/>
瑞典皇家科学院说，这三个人受到表彰是因为他们所研究的粒子“具有独特特性，现在它们从电视屏幕和LED灯中散发出了光”。</p>
<p>LED lights are electronic lights used all over the world, which use energy very effectively.<br/>
LED灯是世界各地使用的电子灯，它们非常节能。</p>
<p>Pernilla Wittung Stafshede, a member of the Nobel committee that awarded the prize, said, "We have displays on TVs, in your cellphone, that use quantum dots inside..."<br/>
负责颁发该奖项的一名诺贝尔委员会成员佩尔尼拉·维通·斯塔夫斯戴德说：“电视、手机的显示在其内部利用了量子点...”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are quantum dots?<br/>
什么是量子点？</span></p>
<p>Quantum dots are extremely small particles, called nanoparticles. They are said to be about 1/10,000 the width of a human hair. The dots glow blue, red, green or other colors when exposed to light. The color they give off depends on the size of the particles. Larger dots look red, and smaller dots look blue. The color change is caused by the behavior of electrons in these small spaces.<br/>
量子点是极小的颗粒，称为纳米颗粒。 据说它们大约是人头发粗细的一万分之一。 当它暴露于光线时会发出蓝色、红色、绿色或其他颜色。 它们散发的颜色取决于颗粒的大小。 较大的点看起来是红色的，较小的点看起来是蓝色。 颜色变化是由这些小空间中电子的行为引起的。</p>
<p>Physicists had predicted these color-change properties as early as the 1930s. However, it took 50 years of research and development to control the size of quantum dots correctly.<br/>
物理学家早在上世纪三十年代就预测了这些变色的特性。 但是，正确控制量子点的大小花了50年的研究和开发。</p>
<p>Ekimov and Brus were the early researchers of the technology. Bawendi is credited with developing the production of quantum dots being used today.<br/>
伊基莫夫和布鲁斯是该技术的早期研究人员。巴文迪被认为开发了当今正在使用的量子点的生产。</p>
<p>Bawendi used the words, "very surprised, sleepy, shocked, unexpected and very honored," to describe his feelings. Bawendi added he was not thinking about the possible uses of his work when he started researching quantum dots.<br/>
巴文迪使用了“非常惊讶，瞌睡，震惊，出乎意料和非常荣幸”等词语来描述他的感受。 巴文迪补充说，当他开始研究量子点时，他并没有考虑这项工作的可能用途。</p>
<p>"The motivation really is the basic science. A basic understanding, the curiosity of how does the world work? And that's what drives scientists and academic scientists to do what they do," he said.<br/>
他说：“我的动机确实是基础科学。基本理解就是对世界如何运作的好奇心？这就是促使科学家和学术科学家做他们所做事情的原因。”</p>
<p>Brus of Columbia University said he did not answer the phone call from the Swedish academy. He finally saw the news online when he got up in the morning.<br/>
哥伦比亚大学的布鲁斯说，他没有接到瑞典学院的电话。 早上起床时，他最终是在网上看到这一消息。</p>
<p>Brus said the practical uses of quantum dots, like creating the colors in TV screens, are something he was hoping for when he started the work many years ago.<br/>
布鲁斯说，量子点的实际用途，例如在电视屏幕上创建颜色，这是他多年前开始这项工作时所希望的。</p>
<p>"Basic research is extremely hard to predict exactly how it's going to work out," Brus said. "It's more for the knowledge base than it is for the actual materials. But in this case, it's both."<br/>
布鲁斯说：“基础研究很难准确地预测它将产生什么效果。它更多是用于知识基础，而不是用于实际材料。但是在这个案例中，这两者兼而有之。”</p>
<p>Ekimov is the former chief scientist at Nanocrystals Technology, a company based in New York where he started working in 1999. The Swedish academy credited him with showing how the size of nanoparticles affected the colors in glass.<br/>
伊基莫夫是美国纳米晶体科技公司的前任首席科学家，他于1999年开始为这家总部位于纽约的公司工作。瑞典皇家科学院认为他证明了纳米颗粒的大小如何影响玻璃中的颜色。</p>
<p>The three will receive 11 million Swedish crowns, about $1 million, and a gold medal when they collect their Nobel Prizes at the award ceremonies in December.<br/>
这三个人将在12月的颁奖典礼上领取诺贝尔奖时获得1100万瑞典克朗（约合100万美元）和一枚金牌。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Training Program in Pakistan Helps Afghan Women  (2023/10/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/training-program-in-pakistan-helps-afghan-women.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>In a small building in Peshawar, Pakistan, a group of Afghan women watch a teacher show them how to use a <strong>sewing</strong> machine.</p>
<p>The training program was established last year by Mahra Basheer who saw an increasing number of women coming from neighboring Afghanistan. Since the Taliban took over in 2021, women in Afghanistan have faced growing restrictions and an economic crisis.</p>
<p>Basheer created the program to provide choices for women to support themselves. She teaches sewing, <strong>digital</strong> skills and beauty treatments. And Basheer quickly found hundreds of women wanting to join the program.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Afghan women attend tailoring class at the Skills Academy for Needy Aspirants (SANA) in Peshawar, Pakistan July 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Fayaz Aziz)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-eba7-08dbc021a118_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Afghan women attend tailoring class at the Skills Academy for Needy Aspirants (SANA) in Peshawar, Pakistan July 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Fayaz Aziz)</span></div>
<p>"If we get assistance, I think we will be able to train between 250 and 500 students at one time, <strong>empowering</strong> women who can play an important <strong>role</strong> in the community," Basheer said.</p>
<p>Officials say hundreds of thousands of Afghans have traveled to Pakistan since the Taliban took over in 2021. Even before then, 1.5 million registered refugees were in the country. This is one of the largest such populations in the world, the United Nations refugee agency says.</p>
<p>More than a million others are estimated to live there unregistered.</p>
<p>Struggling with an economic crisis of its own, Pakistan's government is increasingly worried about the number of Afghan refugees. Many Afghans have been arrested in recent months. Lawyers and officials say they do not have the correct legal documents to live in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Basheer said that her main aim was expanding operations for Afghan women. But she has also included some Pakistani women in the program to increase their choices in the conservative area.</p>
<p>The training program lasts three months. When they complete the program, the women direct their attention to earning enough money to survive. Many women begin their own businesses.</p>
<p>Fatima, a nineteen-year-old from Afghanistan, completed the training program. She said she wants to open a beauty <strong>salon</strong> in Peshawar. It is currently banned in her home country just a few hours away.</p>
<p>"Right now my plan is to start a salon at home. Then to work very professionally so that I can <strong>eventually</strong> open a very big salon for myself," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Mushtaq Ali reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sew</strong>–<em>v</em>. make or repair clothes by hand</p>
<p><strong>digital</strong>–<em>adj.</em> electronic technology</p>
<p><strong>empower</strong>–<em>v</em>. to give authority or power to do something</p>
<p><strong>role</strong>–<em>n</em>. the part that a person or something plays in an activity or operation</p>
<p><strong>salon</strong>–<em>n</em>. a type of store for beauty products</p>
<p><strong>eventually</strong>–<em>adj</em>. in the end</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How A Rural US School System Makes Gains in Math  (2023/10/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-us-rural-school-system-gains-in-math.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many students across the United States fell behind in math during the COVID-19 pandemic. Many educators are seeking ways to bring students back up to usual math levels.</p>
<p>Such efforts paid off for a rural school system in the southern state of Alabama. It has shown major improvement.</p>
<p>A study called the Nation's Report Card shows that Alabama students led the nation in <strong>maintaining</strong> math learning during the pandemic. And the state's Piedmont City school system landed at the top in a comparison of scores from before and during the pandemic. Nationwide, students on average fell half a year behind in math, researchers say.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Piedmont math teacher Cassie Holbrooks helps a small group of fourth-grade students with a math problem in Piedmont, Ala., on Aug. 31, 2023. (Trisha Powell Crain/AL.com via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-d385-08dbba99dfc5_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Piedmont math teacher Cassie Holbrooks helps a small group of fourth-grade students with a math problem in Piedmont, Ala., on Aug. 31, 2023. (Trisha Powell Crain/AL.com via AP)</span></div>
<p>The Piedmont school system has about 1,100 students. Seven out of 10 children receive reduced-cost or free meals in the schools.</p>
<p>The school system has stuck with a policy it established before the pandemic: Teachers use test scores to learn where students are struggling and then target teaching to each child.</p>
<p>"We made a total <strong>transformation</strong> about five years ago," said Mike Hayes, the school system's chief. "We decided that we were going to let data make every decision."</p>
<p>Targeted <strong>instruction</strong> for small groups of students has years of research and evidence to back it up, said Rebecca Dreyfus of the educational nonprofit TNTP.</p>
<p>"The short answer is that using data effectively and efficiently to plan and <strong>monitor</strong> instruction is always going to make instruction better for kids," Dreyfus said.</p>
<p>Piedmont students were 35th in math skills for the state in 2017, when Hayes became the school system's leader. By spring 2022, Piedmont's students had moved to the 12th position.</p>
<p>"Once we made that decision and stuck to it and made changes and <strong>allowed</strong> our teachers time to look at the data and dive into the data, it paid off," Hayes said.</p>
<p><strong>Teachers go deep into data</strong></p>
<p>As part of the effort, the Piedmont school system made the school day longer. This permitted time every four weeks for "data days," when educators get together to study the numbers.</p>
<p>Cassie Holbrooks teaches fourth-grade math. She said the "data days" help teachers see where the weaknesses are and target instruction.</p>
<p>Sixth-grade teacher Lisa Hayes joined the school system five years ago. She said she was surprised to see how hard teachers worked during the data days.</p>
<p>"When I came here and we had a workday," she said, "you don't sit in your room. You're in here (the media center) most of the day, digging through test scores."</p>
<p>Teachers then use the information to decide how to divide the students into small groups for targeted instruction.</p>
<p>Grouping two to six students together to work on a specific skill has long been used for reading instruction and in younger grades. There is less research on the use of targeted small group instruction in math. But researchers like Dreyfus say it involves the same idea of identifying students who need extra help, rather than simply pulling out children who are "behind."</p>
<p><strong>Small groups and independent work</strong></p>
<p>While math teachers in Piedmont schools work with small groups, other students write in their math books, play learning games, or work on individual learning plans.</p>
<p>At first, when Piedmont expanded small group instruction in math, teachers said they did not have enough time to do the work well, Hayes said. So the schools expanded math and English language study time to between 80 and 120 minutes each day.</p>
<p>The longer math classes made a big difference, teacher Landon Pruitt said. "In a 52- or 53-minute class," he said, "there's no way you can <strong>consistently</strong> do (small groups) and work on getting through the <strong>standards</strong> that you have to cover."</p>
<p>The schools also had to help teachers <strong>adjust</strong> classroom management techniques as small groups and independent work would be done at the same time. Hayes said one solution was to give teachers a program to monitor each students' screen. The district wants to make sure teachers have the support and resources to do the job well, he added.</p>
<p>"I'm not sure we have a secret sauce or anything..." Hayes said. But, he noted that the teachers believe in learning data, and letting that data direct instruction.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Trisha Powell Crain reported this story for AL.COM and The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>maintain</strong> - v. to continue doing something</p>
<p><strong>transformation</strong> - n. a complete or major change</p>
<p><strong>instruction</strong> - n. action or process of teaching</p>
<p><strong>monitor</strong> - v. to watch, observe, listen, or check something for a period of time</p>
<p><strong>allow</strong> - v. to permit</p>
<p><strong>consistently</strong> - adv. doing something with the same quality</p>
<p><strong>standard</strong> - n. a level of quality</p>
<p><strong>adjust</strong> - v. to change in order to do better</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Professors Share Nobel Physics Prize for Study of Electrons  (2023/10/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/three-professors-share-nobel-physics-prize-for-study-of-electrons.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Three European physics professors won the Nobel Prize on Tuesday for their work on a system that permits scientists to study electrons.</p>
<p>Electrons are one of the three particles that make up atoms.</p>
<p>They are so small, however, and move so fast, that scientists had never been able to observe them.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This combo of pictures taken Tuesday, Oct. 3, 2023, shows from left, French scientist Pierre Agostini, Scientist Ferenc Krausz, and French-Swedish physicist Anne L'Huillier. The three scientists won the Nobel Prize in physics. (AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d94b2e64-0683-41b6-81bf-e6da211e1cd3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This combo of pictures taken Tuesday, Oct. 3, 2023, shows from left, French scientist Pierre Agostini, Scientist Ferenc Krausz, and French-Swedish physicist Anne L'Huillier. The three scientists won the Nobel Prize in physics. (AP)</span></div>
<p>However, the work of French-Swedish physicist Anne L'Huillier, French physicist Pierre Agostini and Hungarian-born physicist Ferenc Krausz solved that problem.</p>
<p>The professors carried out research that showed how <strong>ultra</strong>-fast light could permit scientists to "see" an electron for the first time.</p>
<p>"You can see whether it's on one side of a molecule or on the other," L'Huillier, 65, said. "It's still very <strong>blurry</strong>."</p>
<p>The system that came from their work creates light that shows the fast-moving electron in its orbit around the nucleus.</p>
<p>Krausz's team first created the short light pulses in the early 2000s. He said the system is similar to a camera with a fast <strong>shutter</strong> speed that permits a photographer to capture a Formula One race car as it crosses the finish line.</p>
<p>Using a special camera with light to see a clear image of a hummingbird's fast wing movements is another example.</p>
<p>But the speed of an electron is so fast that it could not be captured before the scientists produced experiments that showed it was possible to create a <strong>flash</strong> of light in one quintillionth of a second.</p>
<p>Mats Larsson of the Nobel Committee said the electrons are the "workforce" of the atom. "Once you can control and understand electrons, you have taken a very big step forward."</p>
<p>The method to study electrons should help scientists develop better electronic devices or study molecules for medical purposes.</p>
<p>L'Huillier is the fifth woman to receive the physics Nobel. She said her work is important because electrons are "how the atoms <strong>bind</strong> together," and where the chemical reactions happen.</p>
<p>She said she spent 30 years working on the project, and she wants other scientists to keep working on "<strong>fundamental</strong> science" no matter how it might be used in the future. It did not become clear how her work would be used in "the real world" until many years passed.</p>
<p>L'Huillier was in the middle of teaching a class at Lund University in Sweden when she got the news. "It's incredible," she said. She went back to teaching the class after being told of the prize.</p>
<p>Agostini is a retired professor at The Ohio State University. Krausz is a professor at the Max Planck Institute in Germany.</p>
<p>"I did not expect it," Krausz said. "I am <strong>overwhelmed</strong>," he added, asking if he was "in reality or it's just a long dream."</p>
<p>Agostini was in Paris when the news was announced but did not get a call from the Nobel Committee. He suggested the Nobel group was looking for him Columbus, Ohio, where Ohio State is located.</p>
<p>The 82-year-old said the prize was "good, but a bit late for me."</p>
<p>L'Huillier experimented with how a laser affects atoms in a gas causing electrons to produce light. Krausz worked on creating a system that could detect a single, very fast light <strong>pulse</strong>. Agostini was able to investigate a series of very fast pulses.</p>
<p>All the experiments showed that it would be possible one day to observe an image captured in an extremely small <strong>fraction</strong> of a second, known as an attosecond.</p>
<p>Physics is the second Nobel Prize of the week. Two scientists earned the medicine prize on Monday for their work on mRNA that led to COVID-19 vaccines.</p>
<p>Chemistry, literature, peace and economics come next.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on reports by the Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ultra </strong>–prefix; beyond the limit</p>
<p><strong>blurry </strong>–adj. unclear, not clearly seen</p>
<p><strong>shutter </strong>–n. a device in a camera that admits light for a set period of time to capture an image</p>
<p><strong>flash </strong>–n. a sudden burst of light</p>
<p><strong>bind</strong> –v. to combine</p>
<p><strong>fundamental </strong>–adj. something that serves as the support or basis of other things</p>
<p><strong>overwhelmed </strong>–adj. to be strongly affected by something</p>
<p><strong>pulse </strong>–n. a brief increase in electricity or light</p>
<p><strong>fraction </strong>–n. a part of a larger amount such as one half or one fourth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pope Opens Gathering to Discuss Future of Catholic Church  (2023/10/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/pope-opens-gathering-to-discuss-future-of-catholic-church.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Pope Francis on Wednesday is opening a gathering of bishops and others to discuss the future of the Roman Catholic Church. Some of the discussions include subjects that have never been considered before.</p>
<p>For the first time, women and non-clergy can vote alongside bishops in what is called a Synod of Bishops. The change reflects Francis' belief that the Church is more about its people than its leaders.</p>
<p>The gathering, called a synod, starts on October 4 and will end on the 29. It will be followed by a second gathering next year. The second synod is expected to put forward detailed proposals for Francis to consider in a future document.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pope Francis attends the prayer vigil in Saint Peter's square at the Vatican, September 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Remo Casilli)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9a99-08dbc28505bd_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pope Francis attends the prayer vigil in Saint Peter's square at the Vatican, September 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Remo Casilli)</span></div>
<p>The synod will have 365 voting members including the pope and 54 women. Their numbers are chosen by national bishops' organizations and religious orders.</p>
<p>In addition, there are around 100 experts and "<strong>facilitators</strong>," who will help move the discussion along. But they will not vote on a final document.</p>
<p><strong>What will be discussed?</strong></p>
<p>The working document for the gathering came after two years of listening to concerns from Catholics around the world. The aim has been to raise questions and start a debate.</p>
<p>For example, the document calls for specific steps to <strong>promote </strong>women to decision-making positions in the church. And it calls for church members to have more influence in church governance.</p>
<p>It also suggests the "inclusion" of LGBTQ+ Catholics and measures to prevent clergy from abusing their power.</p>
<p><strong>Conservative concerns</strong></p>
<p>Some conservatives have raised questions about the synod since Francis announced it three years ago. They said that those questions have already been settled by church teachings. And raising the questions only risks division among church members.</p>
<p>Just this week, five conservative cardinals from Europe, Asia, Africa, and the Americas made their disagreement with Pope Francis public.</p>
<p>In a letter, they put forward five questions, or "dubia," asking Francis to <strong>affirm</strong> church teaching on these issues, including homosexuality and female clergy. They said the synod was creating <strong>confusion</strong>.</p>
<p>Francis answered that changes in the world help the church to better understand and explain its teachings and that the synod is a way to find the path forward.</p>
<p>"With much sincerity, I tell you it's not good to be afraid of these questions," Francis told them.</p>
<p><strong>A closed synod</strong></p>
<p>For two years, the preparation for the synod has been open to the public. However, the synod itself will be closed to outsiders.</p>
<p>There will be no live stream of the gathering. Organizers say it will be a closed-door meeting and those taking part have been told not to speak to reporters. No daily briefings are planned as in earlier synods although five briefings are expected to take place over the time of the gathering.</p>
<p>Francis has defended the measures. The pope said he did not want "political <strong>gossip</strong>" leaking out with news of attendees arguing over disputed issues.</p>
<p>"This isn't a television show," he told reporters in August.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Nicole Winfield reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>facilitator</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a person who supports people involved in negotiations or discussions with the idea of making the talks easier</p>
<p><strong>promote</strong> <em>–v.</em> to move a person to a higher position</p>
<p><strong>affirm </strong>–v. to say that something is true; to support something already stated</p>
<p><strong>confusion</strong> –n. a condition of being unsure in which there is a lack of clarity or understanding</p>
<p><strong>gossip </strong>–n. repeated statements about the private lives of other people that might or might not be true</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Export Restrictions Causing Food Prices to Rise  (2023/10/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/export-restrictions-causing-food-prices-to-rise.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Important foods like grains and cooking oil again are growing more costly in many places around the world.</p>
<p>Observers say that is because countries have put export restrictions in place to protect food supplies at home. They also blame the price rise on weather conditions and the Ukraine war.</p>
<p>Caroline Kyalo is a 28-year-old who works at a hair <strong>salon</strong> in Kenya's capital Nairobi. She experienced the rising cost of food while planning meals for her two children. The price of onions has risen by 200 percent since neighboring Tanzania restricted agricultural exports. Kyalo tried a different kind of onion but those became too costly as well. Cooking oil and corn flour prices are increasing also.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="People buy onions at an open market in Nairobi, Kenya Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0086-08dbc070dd3f_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">People buy onions at an open market in Nairobi, Kenya Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga)</span></div>
<p>So, she said, "I just decided to be cooking once a day."</p>
<p>East Africa has fertile land and a large workforce. But the high cost of growing and transporting crops and a lack of rain have resulted in decreased local production. In the case of onions, the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization found that, in 2014, Kenya was getting half of its onions from Tanzania. Some traders have tried to get supplies from Ethiopia. Others have stopped selling onions altogether.</p>
<p>But Timothy Kinyua, who says prices have reached their highest level in seven years, promised he would sell the crop.</p>
<p>"It's something we can't cook without," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Spreading food restrictions</strong></p>
<p>Joseph Glauber is with the International Food Policy Research Institute in Washington. He said Tanzania's onion limits this year are one example of the spread of food restrictions. He called it a "contagion," or something that spreads like an infectious disease. His organization says that 19 countries have put 41 food export restrictions in place. The restrictions include bans or taxes.</p>
<p>India banned the export of some rice earlier this year cutting one fifth of the world's export market. Myanmar answered with its own export bans. India has also restricted onion exports. The action sent prices climbing in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Dry weather in Spain has hurt its olive crop causing European buyers to look to Turkey. But rising prices there led to export limits.</p>
<p>Morocco, which suffered a deadly earthquake recently, has also stopped exports of crops including onions, potatoes and tomatoes.</p>
<p><strong>‘The new normal'</strong></p>
<p>Over a period of years, food prices change sharply. In 2007 and 2008, rice and wheat prices doubled. Glauber, who also is a former economist from the Department of Agriculture, said changes are likely to continue.</p>
<p>"I think increased <strong>volatility</strong> is certainly the new normal," he said.</p>
<p>For example, both Russia and Ukraine are major suppliers of wheat, barely, sunflower oil and several other foods important to developing nations. The conflict between them interferes with production by both.</p>
<p>Changes in weather are also affecting agriculture, observers say. El Ni<i></i>241;o is a periodic warm current in the southern Pacific Ocean. It is linked to changes in weather in several places around the world. Some scientists say climate change could make the El Ni<i></i>241;o current more severe affecting weather everywhere.</p>
<p>For example, a lack of rain in India means export restrictions there might not end with the new rice harvest in October.</p>
<p><strong>Importers face added risk</strong></p>
<p>Most at risk from weather changes are nations that depend heavily on imported food. The World Banks, for example, notes that the Philippines imports 14 percent of its food. However, recent storms could mean further crop deficits. Rice prices there increased 8.7 percent in August. That is double the increase from the month before.</p>
<p>Since prices increased, Philippine food store owners say they are losing money. Thirty-two-year-old Charina Em owns a store in the Trabajo market in Manila.</p>
<p>"We cannot save money anymore. It is like we just work so that we can have food daily," she said.</p>
<p>Cynthia Esguerra is 66 years old and has several diseases. She said she has had to choose between medicines and food.</p>
<p>"I just don't worry about my sickness. I leave it up to God. I don't buy medicines anymore, I just put it there to buy food, or loans," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Aniruddha Ghosal, Evelyne Musambi and Jeoal Calupitan reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>salon</strong> <em>–n. </em>a business that cuts hair and offers beauty treatments</p>
<p><strong>volatility</strong> <em>–n.</em> the condition of changing sharply or unpredictably</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>FDA Health Advisors Vote Against ALS Treatment  (2023/10/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/fda-health-advisors-vote-against-als-treatment.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>United States health advisers voted against an experimental treatment for ALS disease last week. The vote came after years of efforts by ALS patients and their families in support of the unproven medical treatment.</p>
<p>ALS, or amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, is also known as Lou Gehrig's disease. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.ninds.nih.gov/health-information/disorders/amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-als">Patients with ALS</a> slowly lose the ability to control muscle movements, the ability to speak, eat, move and breathe. The U.S. National Institutes of Health says people can get the disease at any age. It most commonly develops between the ages of 55 and 75.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, a group of health advisors for the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) voted 17 to one against the treatment from BrainStorm Cell Therapeutics. The Israel-based company's treatment, NurOwn, uses stem cells. These are cells that can develop into many kinds of body cells. The group found the treatment was not effective for patients with ALS. A member of the group representing ALS patients was the only vote in favor. One expert did not register a vote.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A U.S. Food and Drug Administration building is seen behind FDA logos at a bus stop on the agency's campus in Silver Spring, Md., on Aug. 2, 2018. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-785c-08dbc0392150_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A U.S. Food and Drug Administration building is seen behind FDA logos at a bus stop on the agency's campus in Silver Spring, Md., on Aug. 2, 2018. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)</span></div>
<p>Lisa Lee, a health expert from Virginia Tech University voted against the treatment. She said, "Creating false hope can be considered a moral injury and the use of <strong>statistical</strong> magic or <strong>manipulation</strong> to provide false hope is problematic."</p>
<p>The FDA is not required to accept the group's vote. However, the agency's own scientists said earlier in the week that BrainStorm's treatment was "scientifically incomplete."</p>
<p>Brainstorm and the ALS community wanted to use the meeting to change the FDA's thinking about the NurOwn treatment.</p>
<p>Brainstorm's 200-patient study failed to show that NurOwn extended life, slowed the disease, or improved patients' ability to move. But the FDA agreed to bring outside advisers together after ALS patients and supporters submitted 30,000 signatures seeking a public meeting.</p>
<p>In the last year, the FDA has approved two new experimental drugs for ALS, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-new-treatment-option-patients-als">Relyvrio</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fda-approves-treatment-amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-associated-mutation-sod1-gene">Qalsody</a>. The approvals followed intense campaigns from the ALS community although there have been a limited number of scientific studies of the treatments.</p>
<p>The FDA has used the term "regulatory flexibility" when considering experimental treatments for some conditions, including ALS and Alzheimer's. But the agency appears unwilling to overlook the results of BrainStorm's approval effort. Important information about manufacturing and quality control was missing.</p>
<p>Dr. Kenneth Fischbeck of the National Institutes of Health said, "It really is a disease that needs a safe and effective treatment and there are a lot of other <strong>prospects</strong> out there that we need to <strong>encourage</strong>. Approving one like this would get in the way of that."</p>
<p>At last week's meeting, ALS patients, their family members and doctors spoke in support of BrainStorm's treatment. Several presented before-and-after videos that showed patients who had taken part in BrainStorm's study. The videos showed the patients walking, climbing stairs and doing other activities.</p>
<p>Mitze Klingenberg spoke for her son Matt Klingenberg who doctors found to have ALS in 2018. She said, "When Matt is on NurOwn it helps him, when he's off of it he gets worse."</p>
<p>The FDA is expected to issue its decision on the treatment by December 8.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from the Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>statistical</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj. </em>related to numbers used to provide information about people or things</p>
<p><strong>manipulation</strong> <em>–n.</em> the process of using or changing information in a way to gets a desired result</p>
<p><strong>prospect </strong><em>–n.</em> something or someone who is a candidate for a use or a position</p>
<p><strong>encourage </strong><em>–v.</em> to make something more likely to happen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Win Nobel Medicine Prize for COVID-19 Vaccine Research  (2023/10/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-win-nobel-medicine-prize-for-covid-19-vaccine-research.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Two scientists have won the Nobel Prize in Medicine for making molecule discoveries that helped create COVID-19 vaccines.</p>
<p>The Nobel Assembly at Sweden’s Karolinska Institute announced the winners Monday. They are Hungarian-American Katalin Kariko and American Drew Weissman.</p>
<p>Members of the assembly praised the two scientists for assisting in “the <strong>unprecedented</strong> rate of vaccine development during one of the greatest threats to human health in modern times."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this undated image provided by Penn Medicine, Katalin Karik&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/i&gt;243; and Drew Weissman pose for a photo at the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia. (Peggy Peterson Photography/Penn Medicine via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/sp/01000000-0aff-0242-a37a-08dbc377b7f1_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">In this undated image provided by Penn Medicine, Katalin Karik<i>&amp;#</i>243; and Drew Weissman pose for a photo at the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia. (Peggy Peterson Photography/Penn Medicine via AP)</span></div>
<p>Kariko and Weissman have long cooperated on research while working as professors at the University of Pennsylvania. The two centered on a technology called messenger RNA, or mRNA.</p>
<p>Technology companies such as Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna used mRNA to create their COVID-19 vaccines. The vaccines were deployed around the world to fight the disease.</p>
<p>The Nobel organization said the two scientists had changed "our understanding of how mRNA interacts with our <strong>immune system</strong>.”</p>
<p>Vaccine makers usually add elements of an inactive or weakened virus to the shot mixture. But with mRNA vaccines, scientists instead create a genetic material to direct the human body to produce <strong>antibodies</strong> and recognize and destroy the virus.</p>
<p>Research on mRNA has gone on for about 30 years. But no mRNA vaccine was developed and approved for use on people until the COVID-19 pandemic. In early experiments, researchers discovered that injecting laboratory-grown mRNA into animals usually led to a body reaction that destroyed it.</p>
<p>But Kariko and Weissman found a way to make a small change, or modification, to the building blocks of RNA that permitted it to survive immune defenses in the body. Their discovery was seen as breaking a major barrier because it showed that mRNA technology could be used as a treatment in humans.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old Kariko is the 13th woman to win the Nobel Prize in medicine. She was a vice president at BioNTech, which partnered with Pfizer to make one of the COVID-19 vaccines. She and the 64-year-old Weissman met by chance in the 1990s at the University of Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>Kariko noted that her husband was first to pick up the early morning call about the news. She said she then watched the announcement to make sure it was true. "I was very much surprised. But I am very happy.”</p>
<p>In reaction to his prize, Weissman said, “The future is just so incredible. We’ve been thinking for years about everything that we could do with RNA, and now it’s here.”</p>
<p>The two researchers have cooperated for many years, with Kariko centering on RNA and Weissman studying related immunology. “We educated each other,” Kariko said.</p>
<p>The prize comes with an award of $1 million. An award ceremony for all the Nobel awards, except the Peace Prize, is set for December 10 in Stockholm. The Peace Prize ceremony will take place in Norway’s capital, Oslo.</p>
<p>Other Nobel announcements will be made this week. The prize in physics will be announced Tuesday. Chemistry will be announced Wednesday, while literature will be awarded on Thursday. The Nobel Peace Prize is set to be announced Friday.</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>– adj. </em>never having happened before</p>
<p><strong>antibody </strong><em>– n. </em>a substance produced in the body to fight disease</p>
<p><strong>immune system </strong><em>– n. </em>the cells and tissues in the body that fight against infection</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Guinean Student Rides across Africa to Get to School  (2023/10/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/guinean-student-rides-across-africa-to-get-to-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mamadou Safaiou Barry lives in the West African nation of Guinea. He wanted to study Islamic <strong>theology</strong> at a top school in Cairo, Egypt.</p>
<p>Without money to pay for transport, Barry drew a map of Africa and headed out on a used <strong>bicycle </strong>for the trip across the continent.</p>
<p>Carrying only a change of clothes, a flashlight, and a small tool, the 25-year-old rode through jungles, deserts, and conflict areas in the hope of getting accepted to the school and finding a way to pay for it.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mamadou Safaiou Barry, a 25-year-old from Guinea, walks to the center where he studies Islam and the Koran, in El Marg district, east of Cairo, Egypt, September 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Fatma Fahmy)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e762-08dbc115313f_cx14_cy11_cw85_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mamadou Safaiou Barry, a 25-year-old from Guinea, walks to the center where he studies Islam and the Koran, in El Marg district, east of Cairo, Egypt, September 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Fatma Fahmy)</span></div>
<p>Four months and seven countries later, he is in Cairo with a full <strong>scholarship</strong> to Al-Azhar University. That is one of the world's oldest and most respected Sunni Muslim learning centers.</p>
<p>"If you have a dream, stay with it and be strong," Barry said. "God will help you."</p>
<p>Thousands of West Africans like Barry take risky journeys across the Sahara desert each year, searching for a better life. But many never make it. Nearly 500 people died or disappeared on West African migration routes last year, data from the International Organization for Migration shows.</p>
<p>Barry decided the risk was worth the <strong>reward</strong>.</p>
<p>"I had to fight," Barry said last August in Chad.</p>
<p>Barry rode about 100 kilometers each day. He rode through Mali, Burkina Faso, Togo, Benin, and Niger. He had to stop in N'Djamena, the Chadian capital because of the ongoing conflict in Sudan.</p>
<p>He said he had already been detained three times - twice in Burkina Faso and once in Togo. There, security forces held him for nine days without charge before releasing him for $56.</p>
<p>That was all of his money for the rest of the trip, he said.</p>
<p>"I often slept in the <strong>bush</strong> because I was afraid of people in the cities," Barry said. "I thought they would take my bike and hurt me."</p>
<p>Barry's luck changed again in Chad. There, a local <strong>philanthropist</strong>, who had read about his trip online, offered to fly him directly to Egypt and avoid the fighting in Sudan.</p>
<p>Barry arrived in Cairo on September 5 and days later received a full scholarship to Al-Azhar.</p>
<p>He intends to return to Guinea when his studies are complete, to spread the <strong>faith</strong> that has taken him so far.</p>
<p>"When I return to my country, I would like to be someone who teaches Islam and tells people how to do good things," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Reuters. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>theology </strong><em>— n. </em>the study of religious faith, practice, and experience</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>bicycle</strong><em>— n. </em>a 2-wheeled vehicle that a person rides by pushing on foot pedals</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scholarship </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that is given by a school, an organization, etc., to a student to help pay for the student's education</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reward </strong><em>— n. </em>to give money or another kind of payment to for something good that has been done</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>bush </strong><em>— n. </em>a large area that has not been cleared and that is not used for farming</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>philanthropist </strong><em>— n. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle">a wealthy person who gives money and time to help make life better for other people</p>
<p><strong>faith </strong><em>— n. </em>strong belief or trust in someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Southeast Asian Countries Consider Sharing Energy, Power  (2023/10/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/southeast-asian-countries-consider-sharing-energy-power.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Southeast Asian nations are increasingly looking to share power as a result of concerns about climate change.</p>
<p>Malaysia and Indonesia signed a deal in Bali, Indonesia in August to study 18 possible areas where cross-border power lines can be set up.</p>
<p>Those links could eventually create power equal to what 33 nuclear power plants would produce in a year. The links are economically and technically possible, and now are supported by <strong>regional</strong> governments, said Beni Suryadi a power expert at the ASEAN Center for Energy in Jakarta, Indonesia.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The Johor-Singapore Causeway lies empty in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, on Nov. 28, 2021. The urgency for Southeast Asian nations to switch to clean energy to combat climate change is reinvigorating a 20-year-old plan for the region to share power. (AP Photo/Vincent Thian, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/26e59f49-9886-45ab-888f-c5cd2a77560c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The Johor-Singapore Causeway lies empty in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, on Nov. 28, 2021. The urgency for Southeast Asian nations to switch to clean energy to combat climate change is reinvigorating a 20-year-old plan for the region to share power. (AP Photo/Vincent Thian, File)</span></div>
<p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations or ASEAN is a political and economic group of 10 countries across a large area. The group includes small countries such as Brunei and Singapore as well as larger ones such as Indonesia and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Cross-border power purchases accounted for just 2.7 percent of the region's<strong> capacity</strong> in 2017, says the Global Interconnection Journal. But those were between two countries, such as Thailand and Laos.</p>
<p>Now, more countries are looking at power sharing as a way to move their economies away from coal and other<strong> fossil fuels</strong>. Vietnam would like a regional<strong> grid</strong> so it could sell clean energy from offshore wind to its neighbors. And the Malaysian area of Sarawak is looking to sell its <strong>hydropower</strong> to neighboring Indonesia.</p>
<p>The plan for a regional grid between the 10 ASEAN members was developed twenty years ago, but progress has been slowed by problems including technical barriers and political mistrust.</p>
<p>The region now recognizes it must move faster. Climate change could reduce the region's economic growth by more than a third by the middle of the century, a report presented at the 2021 U.N. climate conference in Glasgow, Scotland says.</p>
<p>Demand for electricity is rising, and governments have realized the move away from fossil fuels requires an interconnected grid, Suryadi observed. "It has become a<strong> crucial</strong> need for every country," he said.</p>
<p>In the past, countries in the region paid more attention to energy security. They used fossil fuels and often built more capacity than they needed.</p>
<p>But renewable energy costs are falling, making hydroelectric, solar and wind power more affordable. All ASEAN countries apart from the Philippines have promised to stop adding carbon to the atmosphere by 2050.</p>
<p>So, arguments in favor of an interconnected grid appear to be winning.</p>
<p>But issues remain.</p>
<p>One of ASEAN's central policies is non-<strong>interference</strong>, which means members are less likely to do joint projects. Energy needs within a country sometimes conflict with the interests of an interconnected grid.</p>
<p>Nadhilah Shani, another expert at the ASEAN Center for Energy, said that this creates a difficult position for some countries. The countries could sell clean energy to neighbors for the region to move away from fossil fuels, or they could use those resources to meet their own climate targets.</p>
<p>The region's lack of a legal agreement for such things as setting submarine power cables is another difficult issue.</p>
<p>Not all the technical problems have been solved. <strong>Voltages</strong> used by each country can differ, as do the capacities of their grids. Even countries whose grids cross borders, like Thailand, need to upgrade them, said Harald Link, president of Thailand's Association of Private Power Producers.</p>
<p>"You need a huge amount of electricity— and they want it green. And where do you get it from? For some countries, it is more difficult to make it green," Link said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Aniruddha Ghosal and Victoria Milko reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>region</strong><em> – n. </em>a part of the world that is different or separate from other parts in some way</p>
<p><strong>capacity </strong><em>– n.</em> the amount of something that can be produced or managed</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong> a fuel such as coal, oil, or natural gas</p>
<p><strong>grid</strong><em> – n.</em> a network of electrical wires and equipment that supplies electricity to a large area</p>
<p><strong>hydropower</strong><em> – n. </em>electricity produced from machines that are run by moving water</p>
<p><strong>crucial </strong>–<em> adj.</em> extremely important</p>
<p><strong>interference </strong><em>– n. </em>involvement in the activities and concerns of other people</p>
<p><strong>voltage</strong><em> – n. </em>the force of an electrical current that is measured in volts</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA to Use Special Spacecraft to Deorbit Space Station  (2023/10/2) | 美国宇航局计划使用特制宇宙飞船让国际空间站脱轨回收</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/nasa-to-use-special-spacecraft-to-deorbit-space-station.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The American space agency NASA has a new plan for deorbiting the International Space Station (ISS). The plan involves developing a new spacecraft to safely guide the ISS during its final reentry through Earth's atmosphere.<br/>
美国宇航局制定了一项新的国际空间站脱轨计划。该计划包括开发一种新的航天器，安全引导国际空间站最后一次重返地球大气层。</p>
<p>NASA cooperates with four other space agencies on the station. These include the Canadian Space Agency, the European Space Agency, Japan's Aerospace Exploration Agency and Russia's Roscosmos.<br/>
美国宇航局在空间站上与其他四个航天机构合作。其中包括加拿大航天局、欧洲航天局、日本宇宙航空研究开发机构和俄罗斯航天局。</p>
<p>The ISS began serving as a space research center more than 22 years ago. It has been widely praised as a scientific success. But, NASA and its international partners say the ISS has a limited technical lifetime. NASA has said it will keep operating and sending astronauts to the ISS until 2030.<br/>
国际空间站于22年前开始作为一个空间研究中心。它被广泛赞誉为科学上的成功。但是，美国宇航局及其国际合作伙伴表示，国际空间站的技术寿命有限。美国宇航局表示，将继续运营国际空间站并派遣宇航员，直到2030年。</p>
<p>After that, the U.S. space agency plans to use privately developed space laboratories for its space research needs. NASA says this will permit it to pay space station operators only for the goods and services it needs.<br/>
之后，美国航天局计划使用私人开发的太空实验室来满足其太空研究需求。美国宇航局表示，这将允许其仅为其所需的商品和服务向空间站运营商支付费用。</p>
<p>NASA has already chosen several American companies to develop future space stations. These privately-operated stations will aim to serve the science needs of NASA, as well as other nations' space agencies and other organizations.<br/>
美国宇航局已经选择了几家美国公司来开发未来的空间站。这些私人运营的空间站将致力于满足美国宇航局、其他国家的航天机构和其他组织的科学需求。</p>
<p>In a report to the U.S. Congress last year, NASA established its plans for the ISS. The report said the agency aims to make the station's final years its most productive. Among the goals NASA declared: "To support deep space exploration and continue to return medical and environmental benefits to humanity."<br/>
在去年提交给美国国会的一份报告中，美国宇航局制定了国际空间站的计划。该报告称，该机构的目标是使空间站的最后几年成为最富有成效的几年。美国宇航局宣布的目标之一是：“支持深空探索，继续为人类带来医疗和环境效益。”</p>
<p>The agency recently announced its new deorbiting plan for the ISS after considering other options to retire it. A past plan, or option, involved the use of several Russian spacecraft. But NASA officials rejected that plan and decided a new, specially designed spacecraft would better serve the needs of the deorbiting operation.<br/>
在考虑了退役国际空间站的其他选择后，该机构最近宣布了其新的国际空间站脱轨计划。过去的计划或选择涉及使用几艘俄罗斯航天器。但美国宇航局官员拒绝了这一计划，并决定建造一艘新的、专门设计的航天器来更好地满足脱轨操作的需要。</p>
<p>Other options included a plan to take apart the space station in space and transport its pieces back to Earth. Another plan would have seen the ISS sent to a higher orbit, where it would remain out-of-service. A third option involved a non-controlled reentry operation. NASA said none of these met its requirements for safety and effectiveness.<br/>
其他选择包括在太空中拆除空间站并将其部件运回地球的计划。另一个计划是将国际空间站送往更高的轨道，在那里它将停止服务。第三种选择涉及非受控再入操作。美国宇航局表示，这些都不符合其安全性和有效性的要求。</p>
<p>The agency recently released a request for proposals to companies interested in building the new the spacecraft. NASA calls it the U.S. Deorbit Vehicle (USDV). It says it can be a completely new vehicle or an existing design that is changed to meet all needs of the deorbiting process. The agency said it is seeking proposals now because the effort "will take years to develop, test, and certify."<br/>
该机构最近向有兴趣建造这种新航天器的公司发布了一份征求建议书的请求。美国宇航局称之为美国脱轨飞行器。美国宇航局称它可以是一种全新的载运工具，也可以是一种现有的设计，可以进行改造以满足脱轨过程的所有需求。该机构表示，目前正在寻求提案，因为这项工作“需要数年的时间来开发、测试和认证”。</p>
<p>NASA has said when it is time to retire the ISS, it will begin taking the first steps to slowly lower its operating altitude. This part of the process can likely be carried out by the ISS and its systems, without the need for additional spacecraft.<br/>
美国宇航局表示，当国际空间站退役时，它将开始采取第一步，慢慢降低其运行高度。这部分过程可能由国际空间站及其系统进行，而不需要额外的航天器。</p>
<p>But the final part of the operation, reentry, will center on guiding the ISS though Earth's atmosphere to a pre-chosen target in an unpopulated area in the ocean. NASA says this final part "is expected to require a new or modified spacecraft using a large amount of propellant."<br/>
但行动的最后一部分，即重返大气层，将聚焦于引导国际空间站穿过地球大气层，到达海洋中无人区的预定目标。美国宇航局表示，这最后一部分操作“预计需要一种使用大量推进剂的全新或改进的航天器”。</p>
<p>The targeted landing spot has been identified as a place called Point Nemo in the South Pacific Ocean. This is a stretch of open water between New Zealand and the southernmost part of South America. The U.S. National Ocean Service identifies Point Nemo as the point in the ocean that is farthest from land.<br/>
目标着陆点已被确认为南太平洋的一处名为尼莫角的地方。这是新西兰和南美洲最南端之间的一片开阔水域。美国国家海洋局将尼莫角确定为海洋中距离陆地最远的点。</p>
<p>NASA predicts that most ISS equipment will burn up or vaporize during the intense heating that happens during atmospheric re-entry. But it says some denser or more heat-resistant elements are expected to survive and land in the targeted ocean area.<br/>
美国宇航局预测，国际空间站的大多数设备在重返大气层期间发生的剧烈加热过程中将会烧尽或汽化。但它表示，一些密度更大或更耐热的元素有望残存下来，并落入目标海域。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Research Shows Genetic Influence of Neanderthals, Denisovans  (2023/10/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/research-shows-genetic-influence-of-neanderthals-denisovans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Neanderthals live on within us.</p>
<p>These ancient human relatives, and others, called Denisovans, once lived alongside our early Homo sapiens ancestors. The groups mixed and had children. As a result, some of the Neanderthals and Denisovans live on in our genes. And science is starting to show just how much that shapes us.</p>
<p>Mary Prendergast, a Rice University archeologist, said, "We're now carrying the genetic <strong>legacies</strong> and learning about what that means for our bodies and our health."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A boy pats the head of a sculpture of a Neanderthal boy, inside the Smithsonian Hall of Human Origins, Thursday, July 20, 2023, at the Smithsonian Museum of Natural History in Washington.(AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2df9fea7-8037-4bd0-904c-1f9ae55e717b_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A boy pats the head of a sculpture of a Neanderthal boy, inside the Smithsonian Hall of Human Origins, Thursday, July 20, 2023, at the Smithsonian Museum of Natural History in Washington.(AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)</span></div>
<p>In the past few months, researchers have linked Neanderthal DNA to a serious hand disease, the shape of people's noses and other human<strong> traits</strong>. They even placed a gene carried by Neanderthals and Denisovans into mice to investigate its effects on biology. The researchers found that the gene gave the mice larger heads and an extra rib.</p>
<p>Much of the human story remains a mystery. But Dr. Hugo Zeberg of the Karolinska Institute in Sweden said new technologies and research are helping scientists begin to answer the questions: "Who are we? Where did we come from?"</p>
<p>And the answers point to a deep reality: We have far more in common with our ancient cousins than we ever thought.</p>
<p><strong>Neanderthal, Denisovan DNA </strong></p>
<p>Until recently, the genetic legacy from ancient humans was invisible. But there has been a number of discoveries from ancient DNA, an area of study developed by Nobel Prize winner Svante Paabo. He was first in creating a Neanderthal <strong>genome</strong>.</p>
<p>Research shows some African populations have almost no Neanderthal DNA, while those from European or Asian backgrounds have up to two percent. Denisovan DNA is rarely found in most parts of the world but makes up four to six percent of the DNA of people in Melanesia. The Pacific Ocean area extends from New Guinea to the Fiji Islands.</p>
<p>That may not sound like much, but it adds up: Even though only 100,000 Neanderthals ever lived, "half of the Neanderthal genome is still around, in small pieces <strong>scattered</strong> around modern humans," said Zeberg, who works closely with Paabo.</p>
<p>It is also enough to affect us in very real ways. Scientists studying the subject say the DNA can be both helpful and harmful.</p>
<p>For example, Neanderthal DNA has been linked to autoimmune diseases like Graves' disease and rheumatoid arthritis. When Homo sapiens came out of Africa, they had no immunity to diseases in Europe and Asia. But, Neanderthals and Denisovans already living there did.</p>
<p>Chris Stringer is a human evolution researcher at the Natural History Museum in London. Stringer said that by mating with Neanderthals and Denisovans, Homo sapiens "got a quick fix to our immune systems, which was good news 50,000 years ago." Stringer added, "The result today is, for some people, that our immune systems are oversensitive, and sometimes they turn on themselves."</p>
<p>In 2020, research by Zeberg and Paabo found that a major genetic risk factor for severe COVID-19 came from Neanderthals. "We compared it to the Neanderthal genome and it was a perfect match," Zeberg said.</p>
<p>The next year, they found a set of DNA <strong>variants</strong> along a single chromosome inherited from Neanderthals had the opposite effect: protecting people from severe COVID.</p>
<p>Much less is known about our genetic legacy from Denisovans – although some research has linked genes from them to fat processing and better performance at high altitudes. Maanasa Raghavan, a human genetics expert at the University of Chicago, said Tibetans carry an amount of Denisovan DNA. She noted that the population continues to live and do well in low-oxygen environments today.</p>
<p><strong>Human evolution </strong></p>
<p>John Hawks of the University of Wisconsin-Madison said that human evolution was not about "survival of the fittest and extinction." Instead, he suggested, it is about "interaction and mixture."</p>
<p>Researchers expect to learn more as the science continues to develop. Even when ancient bones are not available, scientists today can get DNA from soil where ancient humans once lived.</p>
<p>And there are less-explored places in the world where researchers hope to learn more. Zeberg said "biobanks" that collect biological materials will likely be established in more countries.</p>
<p>As researchers go deeper into humanity's genetic legacy, scientists expect to find even more evidence of how much we mixed with our ancient cousins and all they left us.</p>
<p>"Perhaps," Zeberg said, "we should not see them as so different."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar and Maddie Burakoff reported on this story for the Associated Press. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>legacy </strong><em>– n.</em> something that comes from someone in the past</p>
<p><strong>trait</strong><em> – n. </em>a quality that makes one person or thing different from another</p>
<p><strong>genome</strong><em> – n.</em> the complete set of genetic material present in an organism</p>
<p><strong>scatter</strong> –<em> v. </em>to cause (things or people) to go in different directions</p>
<p><strong>variant</strong><em> – n.</em> something that is different in some way from others of the same kind</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Women Drawn to Rickshaw Pulling  (2023/10/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/japanese-women-drawn-to-rickshaw-pulling.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Rickshaw comes from a Japanese word that means "human-powered vehicle." The vehicle was first used in 19th-century Japan and then in other Asian countries to transport passengers.</p>
<p>Rickshaw pullers are traditionally male. Through social media, some Japanese women are drawn to the profession. And now, they have developed a strong local and international following.</p>
<p>Yuka Akimoto is one of the women who have chosen to pull rickshaws in Tokyo.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rickshaw puller Akina Suzuki, 19, drives a rickshaw around Asakusa district in Tokyo, Japan, June 18, 2023. (REUTERS/Issei Kato)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4b5d-08dbbf85910b_cx7_cy16_cw81_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Rickshaw puller Akina Suzuki, 19, drives a rickshaw around Asakusa district in Tokyo, Japan, June 18, 2023. (REUTERS/Issei Kato)</span></div>
<p>"I don't deny it was extremely hard at the beginning," Akimoto said, as the rickshaw can weigh up to 250 kg. "I'm not athletic and the cart felt so heavy."</p>
<p>Now, she says she loves her job and wants to work as long as she is physically able. She wears a small sign that reads: "I don't want to give up."</p>
<p>Akimoto joined Tokyo Rickshaw two years ago. The company mainly operates in the Asakusa area, where many people visit. The company says about a third of their 90 pullers are now women. They are seeking more females to work for the company.</p>
<p>"The first girl who joined was cool," said Tokyo Rickshaw President Ryuta Nishio. "Since we posted videos of her on social media, many girls have followed... and joined us."</p>
<p>Nishio said he wants to create a place where women feel at ease and can be involved.</p>
<p>Rickshaw pullers wear special, traditional clothing on their feet. The pullers walk or run an average of 20km a day, no matter the weather.</p>
<p>In addition to being physically strong, rickshaw pullers must know a lot about Tokyo. They also need to communicate with visitors who want to see the city.</p>
<p>The most popular pullers earn over 1 million yen (about $6,700) a month. That is three times the national average. Tokyo Rickshaw noted that less than 10 percent of all applicants are offered a job.</p>
<p>The pullers actively use social media to increase their popularity. They want people to request them personally and repeat rides.</p>
<p>It was those social media posts that influenced college student Yumeka Sakurai to join Tokyo Rickshaw.</p>
<p>"I've watched many videos of women training hard and becoming rickshaw drivers themselves. They gave me confidence that I could do it too if I tried hard," the 20-year-old said.</p>
<p>Sakurai's friends and family disapproved of her choice. But after four months of training, she says she feels pleasure pulling passengers in her rickshaw.</p>
<p>Shiori Yano is 29 years old. She has been pulling rickshaws for nine years. She balances the demands of the job and her family.</p>
<p>She took a four-year break after having a child. She now works the rickshaw for eight hours a day, hurrying to pick up her daughter from childcare before going home to cook dinner and do housework.</p>
<p>"This job looked flashy from the outside but I've had some hard times, including when I was rejected in favor of a male driver," Yano said. Still, she says she will continue to work because she enjoys it.</p>
<p>Tokyo Rickshaw's Nishio said sometimes people are not satisfied women are doing such physically demanding work. Female pullers also sometimes face unwanted sexual behaviors or have their knowledge questioned by male riders, he added.</p>
<p>"We treat both male and female pullers completely equally," Nishio said. "The women say they want to be treated the same as the men, and in fact many of them are way tougher."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Mariko Katsumura reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cart</strong>–n. a vehicle designed for transport that has two wheels and is pulled by a person or animal</p>
<p><strong>athletic</strong>–adj. physically strong, fit and active</p>
<p><strong>cool</strong>–adj. pleasing, desired</p>
<p><strong>confidence</strong>–n. belief in oneself</p>
<p><strong>flashy</strong>–adv. desirable, fun</p>
<p><strong>tough</strong>–adj. strong</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Immigrants Are More Hopeful Than US-born Americans  (2023/10/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/why-immigrants-are-more-hopeful-than-us-born-americans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Immigrants in America are more hopeful about the future than citizens who were born in the United States.</p>
<p>That is what a recent opinion study<strong> </strong>of 3,358 immigrant adults found.</p>
<p>The study, or survey, aimed to find out what the immigrant adults thought about a number of issues.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Rita Guevara of the Philippines, center, takes a photo with her family following a naturalization ceremony, Sept. 15, 2023, in Miami. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-fa8c-08dbbb974d24_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Rita Guevara of the Philippines, center, takes a photo with her family following a naturalization ceremony, Sept. 15, 2023, in Miami. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)</span></div>
<p>Shannon Schumacher is a researcher at KFF, a nonprofit organization based in San Francisco that works with health policy. It was formerly known as the Kaiser Family Foundation.</p>
<p>She described what the immigrants told her this way: "They said, ‘You know, I face <strong>challenges</strong> here in the U.S., but it's far better than where I came from. And I have this belief that things will be better for my children.'"</p>
<p>Schumacher added, "Whether that's their education, their safety, their economic <strong>opportunities</strong>...they think that they're better off and their children are better off."</p>
<p>The survey was a partnership between KFF and the <em>Los Angeles Times</em> newspaper. The organizations carried out the study between April 10 and June 12, 2023.</p>
<p>The immigrants answered questions by telephone, mail, and online. The questions could be answered in any of the 10 most commonly spoken languages in the United States. They include English, Spanish, Chinese, Korean, Vietnamese, Portuguese, Haitian-Creole, Arabic, French and Tagalog.</p>
<p>Schumacher said it is the most complete survey of immigrants in the U.S. today.</p>
<p>"The survey can really help inform the public more about immigrants and really bring their voices to the <strong>forefront</strong>," she said. Schumacher added, "We don't actually hear about immigrants often in their own voices."</p>
<p>Immigrants make up 16 percent of adults in the U.S. They come from many different countries and are from many classes of people. Their belief in a better future remains although they face many difficulties.</p>
<p>Most of the immigrants in the survey have jobs. About half said they have experienced discrimination in the workplace. Three in 10 said they had been paid less for doing the same job or have had fewer opportunities to get a better job or increased pay, compared to their U.S.-born coworkers.</p>
<p>Health care can be another problem. One in five immigrants delayed or did not get health care in the past few years. Often the reason is lack of money or health <strong>insurance</strong>. And if they see a medical worker, the experience is not always good.</p>
<p>Schumacher said: "About one in four immigrants say they've been treated unfairly in a health care setting, such as being <strong>talked down to</strong>." She added that they might not have a health care provider explain things in a way they can understand. They also might not have had someone explain issues in their language.</p>
<p>The survey said that Black and Hispanic immigrants face the most discrimination.</p>
<p>Researchers worked with activist groups within the different immigrant communities to find people to talk to. The researchers said the English word "discrimination" was a problem because it does not always mean the same thing in different cultures and languages.</p>
<p>"People aren't sure what that means," Schumacher said. She added that they might use different words, "or they say something that maybe we as researchers would say, ‘Oh, that's discrimination,' but they call it <strong>bullying</strong> or someone just being mean."</p>
<p>To deal with possible miscommunication, researchers asked direct questions to identify experiences that they defined as discrimination. They did this even if the survey subject did not call the experience "discrimination." For example, the researcher might ask: "Have you ever been not paid for all the hours you've worked?" "Have you been <strong>harassed</strong> or threatened or been told to go back to your country?"</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>challenge </strong>– <em>n</em>. a difficult task or problem</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong><em>– n.</em> an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>forefront </strong>– <em>n</em>. the most important part or position</p>
<p><strong>insurance </strong><em>– n.</em> an agreement in which a person pays a company regularly so that the company will pay for part of, for example, a health care cost later on</p>
<p><strong>talk down to </strong>–v. (phrasal) to speak as though you are talking to a young child when you are not talking to a young child</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>– v.</em> to try to force people to do things by making threats</p>
<p><strong>harassed </strong><em>– v.</em> to annoy or bother (someone) in a repeated way over a period of time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Educators: Improving Teachers’ Math Skills Will Aid Students  (2023/10/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/educators-improving-teachers-math-skills-will-aid-students.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many elementary school teachers say they dislike the idea of teaching mathematics even at the most basic level. That is a cause for concern among educators.</p>
<p>Experts say it is <strong>critical</strong> for students to have a solid <strong>foundation</strong> in the subject because math skills build on each other. Research published by the National Institutes of Health (NIH) found that math is a common cause of <strong>anxiety</strong> for adults, especially for women. About 90 percent of elementary teachers in the U.S. are women. The NIH study suggested that, in the field of education, anxiety can have a harmful effect on learners.</p>
<p>International studies have found that U.S. students are behind many other democracies in math skills. In 2017, the OECD, an international economic research group, ranked the U.S. 30th among member countries.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Elementary math teacher Margie Howells teaches a fifth-grade class at Wheeling Country Day School in Wheeling, WV, on Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Gene J. Puskar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e09a75eb-78d7-4205-b5fb-8965169bf80b_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Elementary math teacher Margie Howells teaches a fifth-grade class at Wheeling Country Day School in Wheeling, WV, on Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Gene J. Puskar)</span></div>
<p>Since the worldwide COVID-19 pandemic, the math test scores in the U.S. suffered even more. Educators now say an important step to improving math skills after the pandemic is to increase the <strong>confidence</strong> of elementary school teachers.</p>
<p>The Erikson Institute in Chicago is a graduate school centered on child development. The school holds a yearly math conference where elementary teachers can ease their anxiety about math. Teachers find out how young children learn math and plan activities for the classroom.</p>
<p>Jennifer McCray is a research professor at Erikson. She said the best way to see how a child will perform in math up through eighth grade is to learn how the child did in math when they started <strong>kindergarten</strong>.</p>
<p>Teachers are worried that they will transfer their math fears to their students. Math specialists say this is a <strong>persistent</strong> issue in elementary school classrooms. Elementary school teachers are expected to teach every subject, often leading them to spend less classroom time on math.</p>
<p>During the Erikson Institute's summer meeting, teachers work with math concepts that they can use in the classroom. For example, the group built 10-sided shapes out of colored blocks. These exercises helped the teachers with their own math skills.</p>
<p>Lauran Solarski is a trainer with the Early Math Collaborative at Erikson. She told a group of educators, "There's a misbelief that in order to teach early childhood math, you don't really need to know math well."</p>
<p>Lisa Ginet is the director of operations at Erikson. She said that early childhood teachers do not necessarily need to be experts in complex math subjects like algebra and geometry. But they need to understand that many of the skills they are teaching are connected to mathematical thinking and to subjects that students will learn later in school.</p>
<p>Stacey Stevens works for the Kentucky Department of Education as the director of early childhood education training center. She said she changed her study major in college to early childhood education to avoid high level math. After she completed a yearlong class in math to improve her teaching, she finally started to understand how to teach the subject.</p>
<p>Stevens said she was <strong>passionate</strong> about teaching preschool because she did not want children to have the same struggles in math that she had growing up. "I wanted them to understand that four triangles make a square: to actually see it and do it and not just be told that a triangle is a fourth of a square."</p>
<p>Heather Peske is the president of the National Council on Teacher Quality (NCTQ), a research group based in Washington, D.C. She said colleges need to better prepare teachers to teach math before they get into the classroom.</p>
<p>The NCTQ studied teacher preparation programs in 2022. It found that most do not spend as much time on elementary math content as NCTQ thinks is necessary. The recommendations were based on studies that linked student <strong>achievement</strong> to teacher's math studies in college.</p>
<p>Peske said, "If we prepared them better, they would be stronger at both their math knowledge as well as their ability to teach math, and this would reduce their anxiety and improve student outcomes."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>Ariel Gilreath reported this story for The Hetchinger Report and The Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>anxiety</strong> <em>– n. </em>an emotional state of being worried or very concerned</p>
<p><strong>critical</strong> <em>– adj. </em>extremely important</p>
<p><strong>confidence </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling of trust or belief</p>
<p><strong>kindergarten </strong><em>– n. </em>a school or class for very young children</p>
<p><strong>passionate</strong> – <em>adv. </em>having, showing, or expressing strong emotions or beliefs</p>
<p><strong>achievement </strong><em>– n. </em>a thing that is completed successfully</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Boilerplate' Language Is All Business  (2023/10/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/boilerplate-language-is-all-business.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a type of writing -- boilerplate. Boilerplate language is the writing in documents such as contracts. The language is <strong>standardized</strong>. This means the words are well established and used by many people. The language is widely recognized as acceptable. It is not creative, nor does it change very much.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Pages from a Carlyle Group 2021 report on its financial risk from greenhouse gas emissions are photographed Tuesday, Sept. 20, 2022. Documents and contracts often contain what is called boilerplate language. (AP Photo/Jon Elswick)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-81c2-08dbc0e3960b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Pages from a Carlyle Group 2021 report on its financial risk from greenhouse gas emissions are photographed Tuesday, Sept. 20, 2022. Documents and contracts often contain what is called "boilerplate language." (AP Photo/Jon Elswick)</span></div>
<p>So, when it comes to things like business documents, legal contracts, and <strong>training manuals</strong>, boilerplate is a good thing. You don't need or want creative language in those sorts of documents.</p>
<p>However, in writing other kinds of stories, boilerplate has a different meaning.</p>
<p>If a piece of writing is not special or creative, we can call it boilerplate. The words <strong>hackneyed </strong>and <strong>trite</strong> have related meanings. Hackneyed or trite writing is commonplace and repeated too often. There is nothing special about boilerplate writing.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear boilerplate used in some examples.</p>
<p><em>I'm not signing any contract without my lawyer looking at it first. I don't care how boilerplate it is. </em></p>
<p><em>The writing in the novel was boilerplate. It showed no creativity. </em></p>
<p><em>The writing job was not difficult for the college student. It was mostly boilerplate type stories. </em></p>
<p><strong>Where did "boilerplate" come from?</strong></p>
<p>The website Meriam-Webster.com explains how the term "boilerplate" came to mean standard or non-creative writing.</p>
<p>Boilerplate comes from <strong>syndicated</strong> stories used especially by weekly newspapers. These stories were ready-to-print and required no additional writing.</p>
<p>Boilerplate stories were not usually hard news. They were stories that just filled space in the newspaper. So, the term boilerplate can mean ordinary, <strong>mediocre</strong> writing.</p>
<p>In the past, these stories were sent on flat, metal plates. These story plates looked like plates used to make steam boilers, devices used to make steam for heat or power. So, they were called "boiler plates." Soon, the term "boilerplate" came to mean the actual printed material on the plates as well as to the plates themselves.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Hopefully, you don't find our materials at VOA Learning English to be boilerplate.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>standardized </strong>–adj. to be regular, normal, and predictable because of similar language, spelling and usage rules</p>
<p><strong>training manual </strong><em>– n.</em> a book of instructions for a specific job or task</p>
<p><strong>hackneyed </strong><em>– adj. </em>lacking in freshness or originality because it is repeated often</p>
<p><strong>trite</strong> <em>– adj. </em>hackneyed or boring from much use,<strong> </strong>not fresh or original</p>
<p><strong>syndicate</strong> <em>– v.</em> to sell material for publication at the same time in many newspapers, periodical publications, or to broadcast on television or the radio</p>
<p><strong>mediocre </strong><em>– adj. </em>of medium or low quality, ordinary</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you have a similar expression in your language? In the Comments section, you can also practice using any of the expressions from the story. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Franklin D. Roosevelt: Powerful  (2023/10/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Franklin Delano Roosevelt. He was related to an earlier president with same last name, Theodore Roosevelt. Many Americans call Franklin Roosevelt by the first letter of each word in his full name: FDR.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7839e5c5-a69d-40ca-b953-5e64fe4efbf2_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt</span></div>
<p>When FDR took office, the United States was in a severe economic depression. The previous president, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-herbert-hoover/4037382.html">Herbert Hoover</a>, had tried to improve the economy, but his efforts had failed.</p>
<p>FDR defeated Hoover in the election of 1932. He won, in part, by promising what he called a "new deal" for Americans.</p>
<p>Voters did not know what FDR's "new deal" meant exactly, but many liked his message of hope.</p>
<p>Voters also did not know how much FDR would change the country. He remained in office for 12 years – the longest of any U.S. president – and led the country through the Great Depression and most of World War II.</p>
<p>Along the way, he changed the way government affected Americans' lives, and the job of the U.S. president.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Franklin Roosevelt was born on a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nps.gov/hofr/index.htm">large <strong>estate</strong></a> in New York, about 140 kilometers outside New York City. He was the only child of wealthy parents.</p>
<p>His mother and father made sure he had an excellent education. As a young man he attended a private high school, and then Harvard College in Massachusetts. He also studied law at Columbia University in New York.</p>
<p>Young FDR was not an excellent student, however. He was interested in many things outside the classroom, including politics and girls.</p>
<p>Two of FDR's interests came together in a young woman named Anna Eleanor Roosevelt, who went by the name Eleanor. She was the <strong>niece</strong> of a politician FDR greatly respected: President Theodore Roosevelt.</p>
<p>On the day when Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt were married, Theodore Roosevelt attended the ceremony. In fact, he walked with his niece in front of the guests to her future husband.</p>
<p>Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt went on to have six children, although one died as a baby.</p>
<p>While Eleanor Roosevelt raised the children, Franklin Roosevelt directed his attention to politics.</p>
<p>He left a job in a law office to serve in the New York state senate. In time, he was offered a job in the federal government as an assistant secretary of the Navy.</p>
<p>FDR enjoyed the job, but he continued seeking other political positions. He tried unsuccessfully for a seat in the U.S. Senate, but did get nominated by the Democratic Party to be its vice presidential candidate in 1920.</p>
<p>Although he and his partner lost the race, FDR seemed like he was in a good position for major political success.</p>
<p>But then something unexpected happened.</p>
<p><strong>Illness and return to politics</strong></p>
<p>When he was 39 years old, FDR suffered <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.cnn.com/2003/HEALTH/10/31/roosevelt.polio.reut/">major health problems</a>. One day he started to feel a pain in his back. The following day his legs grew tired. Then his skin became sensitive.</p>
<p>By the end of the week, both his legs were <strong>paralyzed</strong>. He could not move from the waist down. He remained paralyzed for the rest of his life.</p>
<p>The next years were difficult for the Roosevelts. Eleanor and the children helped care for FDR. And he worked hard to recover some of his strength and physical abilities, especially by exercising.</p>
<p>While he remained hopeful about his condition, FDR worried about his political career. He did not think the public would accept a leader who could not even walk by himself. So he took several measures.</p>
<p>He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://fdrlibrary.org/polio">created a small wheelchair</a> that would not get too much attention. It was made from a dining room chair, with wheels instead of legs.</p>
<p>He refused to let photographers take pictures of him being carried or struggling to move, and he found a way to appear as if he were walking. He used a cane or the arm of a partner to balance, and then he <strong>swung</strong> his hips to make his legs move forward.</p>
<p>Using this method, FDR "walked" to the <strong>stage</strong> at the 1924 Democratic National Convention. He used the event to nominate the governor of New York for president.</p>
<p>That man's bid did not succeed. But FDR showed himself to still be an able politician.</p>
<p>Four years later, FDR himself was elected governor of New York. He held the position in the early years of the country's economic crisis.</p>
<p>In 1932, FDR was a candidate for president. He took the unusual step of appearing in person at the Democratic convention to accept his party's nomination.</p>
<p>His campaign was such a success that the Democrats took not only the White House, but majorities in both the U.S. Senate and House of Representatives.</p>
<p>The strength of the Democratic Party in Congress would help FDR become one of the most powerful presidents the country had ever seen.</p>
<p>Next week we will continue our story of FDR and his presidency.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>______________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>estate</strong> - <em>n.</em> a large piece of land with a large house on it</p>
<p><strong>niece</strong> -<em> n. </em>a daughter of your brother or sister</p>
<p><strong>paralyzed</strong> - <em>adj.</em> unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
<p><strong>swing</strong> -<em> v. </em>to move backward and forward or from side to side while hanging from something</p>
<p><strong>stage</strong> - <em>n.</em> a raised platform in a theater or auditorium where the performers stand</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Paris Once Had Too Many Cars, Now It Has Too Many Bikes  (2023/9/30) | 曾经堵车严重的巴黎现在自行车严重拥堵</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/once-had-too-many-cars-now-paris-has-too-many-bikes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Paris mayor Anne Hidalgo has long worked to make her city less dependent on cars. She wanted to see more people using bicycles, or bikes, to get around.<br/>
巴黎市长安妮·伊达尔戈长期以来一直致力于减少城市对汽车的依赖。她希望看到更多的人骑自行车四处走动。</p>
<p>Over a number of years, the city government put in restrictions on cars and increased the amount of bike lanes from 200 kilometers to over 1,000 kilometers.<br/>
多年来，市政府对汽车进行了限制，并将自行车道的长度从200公里增加到1000公里以上。</p>
<p>Now, her effort seems to have paid off.<br/>
现在，她的努力似乎得到了回报。</p>
<p>This year, Parisians are not complaining about too much automobile traffic. Instead, they say there are too many bikes.<br/>
今年，巴黎人并没有抱怨汽车流量过大。相反，他们说自行车太多了。</p>
<p>Thibault Quere is a spokesperson for France's Federation of Bicycle Users. He said he remembered seeing "traffic jams all over the place" when he traveled by car as a child.<br/>
蒂伯·奎尔是法国自行车用户联合会的发言人。他说，他记得小时候乘车旅行时看到“到处都是交通堵塞”。</p>
<p>"Now, it's really like a bike traffic jam," he said. "It's kind of a good difficulty to have, especially when we think about what Paris used to be."<br/>
他说：“现在成了自行车交通堵塞，这是我们遇到的一个很大的困难，尤其是当我们想到巴黎曾经的样子时。”</p>
<p>Some famous roads along the River Seine are completely closed to cars. Now you see people riding bikes, running, and walking with their families along the river.<br/>
塞纳河沿岸的一些著名道路完全禁止汽车通行。现在你可以看到人们沿着河边骑自行车、跑步，以及跟家人一起散步。</p>
<p>In another part of Paris, a bike path on Sebastopol Boulevard is one of the busiest in Europe, after opening in 2019. In one week in early September, it recorded a record high of 124,000 riders.<br/>
在巴黎的另一个地区，塞瓦斯托波尔大道上的一条自行车道自2019年开通以来，是欧洲最繁忙的自行车道之一。在9月初的一周内，它创下了124000名骑手的历史新高。</p>
<p>Paris en Selle is a volunteer organization supporting cycling in the city. It says the French capital's bike paths are busier than some popular ones in London and almost as busy as some in Amsterdam. Amsterdam is known for its high bike usage.<br/>
Paris en Selle是一家支持城市自行车运动的志愿者组织。该组织称，法国首都巴黎的自行车道比伦敦的一些热门自行车道还要繁忙，它几乎和阿姆斯特丹的一些自行车道一样繁忙。阿姆斯特丹以自行车使用率高而闻名。</p>
<p>Experts say the revolution will continue. Instead of the honking of horns and pollutive gas from cars, Paris will become known for cyclists, they say.<br/>
专家表示，这场革命将继续下去。他们说，巴黎将以骑自行车而闻名，而不是喇叭声和汽车尾气污染。</p>
<p>The city will host the summer Olympics in 2024 and plans to add more bike lanes by then. Paris wants to reduce its pollution by half during the games, even as visitors from around the world will be in the city for the event. Organizers say all of the competition sites will be reachable by bike through a 60-kilometer network of bike lanes.<br/>
该市将于2024年举办夏季奥运会，并计划届时增加更多自行车道。巴黎希望在奥运会期间将污染减少一半，尽管来自世界各地的游客将到巴黎参加奥运会。组织者表示，所有比赛场地都将能通过60公里的自行车道网络骑自行车到达。</p>
<p>The change to Paris, however, has not been easy. With more people using bikes, more people are making mistakes. Some of them are new to cycling and disobey traffic rules.<br/>
然而，巴黎的改变并不容易。随着骑车的人越来越多，犯错的人也越来越多。他们中的一些人是自行车新手，不遵守交通规则。</p>
<p>Michel Gelernt rode through the Place de la Concorde in the central part of the city.<br/>
米歇尔·盖伦特骑车穿过了市中心的协和广场。</p>
<p>"Paris has become unlivable," he said. "No one can stand each other."<br/>
他说：“巴黎已经变得不适合居住了，没人能理解对方。”</p>
<p>Gelernt, who is retired and in his 70s, said he often used public transportation and for-hire motorized scooters. But he changed to cycling during the COVID-19 pandemic.<br/>
年过七旬、现已退休的盖伦特说，他经常使用公共交通工具和共享摩托车。但在新冠肺炎大流行期间，他改骑自行车。</p>
<p>He said he uses Paris' bike-sharing system for 80 percent of his trips. He still has complaints.<br/>
他说，他80%的出行都使用巴黎的共享单车系统。他仍然有怨言。</p>
<p>"Everyone behaves selfishly ... the traffic is a lot worse than it was," he said.<br/>
他说：“每个人的行为都很自私……交通比以前糟糕得多。”</p>
<p>But the environment may be improving. Cycling is good exercise and helps reduce pollution, which is still a problem for the large city. The French government blames atmospheric pollution for 48,000 early deaths in the country each year.<br/>
但环境可能正在改善。骑自行车是一种很好的锻炼，并且有助于减少污染，这对大城市来说仍然是一个问题。法国政府指责大气污染导致该国每年有4.8万人过早死亡。</p>
<p>Hidalgo was re-elected in 2020 and plans to keep making what she calls a "Paris that breathes." Her newest five-year bike plan includes over $250 million for more bike paths and bike parking. The new budget is an increase of over $100 million from her first five-year plan.<br/>
伊达尔戈于2020年再次当选，并计划继续打造她所说的“呼吸的巴黎”。她最新的五年自行车计划包括利用超过2.5亿美元修建更多自行车道和自行车停车场。这项新预算比她的第一个五年计划增加了1亿多美元。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Race to Help Largest, Rarest Tortoise  (2023/9/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/race-to-help-largest-rarest-tortoise.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The average life expectancy of North America's largest and rarest tortoise species is unknown. But scientists say the animals could live more than 100 years.</p>
<p>The Bolson tortoise is an endangered <strong>species</strong>. Saving it from <strong>extinction</strong> is a long-term project. But a conservation effort took a step toward that goal last week.</p>
<p>United States wildlife officials reached an agreement with the Turner Endangered Species Fund. The deal permits the release of Bolson tortoises on land owned by Ted Turner, a media industry leader.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gertie, an endangered Bolson tortoise, is shown to a group of state and federal wildlife officials during a trip to Ted Turner's Armendaris Ranch in Engle, N.M., on Friday, Sept. 22, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Montoya Bryan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-c2a4-08dbc0568c0e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Gertie, an endangered Bolson tortoise, is shown to a group of state and federal wildlife officials during a trip to Ted Turner's Armendaris Ranch in Engle, N.M., on Friday, Sept. 22, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Montoya Bryan)</span></div>
<p>The release of captive tortoises on the Armendaris Ranch is designed to create a free-<strong>roaming</strong> population. Last week, 20 adult tortoises were released on the property, which is already home to 23 of them. There are also many younger tortoises.</p>
<p>The tortoises usually spend about 85 percent of the time in their underground <strong>burrows</strong>, which in some cases can be about 20 meters long. The animals live long lives and are slow to reproduce.</p>
<p>Shawn Sartorius is with the Fish and Wildlife Service. He said the results of the <strong>breeding</strong> and restoration project will not be seen in his lifetime.</p>
<p>"What we're doing here is establishing a population here that can be handed off to the next generation," Sartorius said.</p>
<p>It is a step toward one day releasing the tortoises in more places in the Southwest. Conservationists are also pushing the federal government to consider creating a recovery plan for the species. The tortoise is part of a growing effort to find new homes for endangered species as they flee climate change and other threats to their natural <strong>habitats</strong>.</p>
<p>Wild Bolson tortoises are found only in the grasslands of north-central Mexico. The animal once lived in a much greater area that included the southwestern United States. <strong>Fossil</strong> records also show it was once present it the southern Great Plains, including parts of Texas and Oklahoma.</p>
<p>Scientists estimate the wild population of Bolson tortoises in Mexico is under 2,500. Experts say the animals are hunted as food and as pets. Their habitat is shrinking, as more desert grasslands become farmland.</p>
<p>The 1,450 square kilometer Armendaris Ranch appears to be a great area for the tortoises. In all, the Turner Endangered Species Fund and its partners have been able to grow the population from 30 tortoises to about 800, said Chris Wiese. She leads the project at the Armendaris Ranch.</p>
<p>"The releases are the <strong>essential</strong> step to getting them back on the ground and letting them be wild tortoises," she said.</p>
<p>The tortoises released last week will be able to live freely in the 6.6-hectare <strong>pen</strong>. They are given electronic trackers, and wildlife workers will check on them once a year.</p>
<p>Depending on weather and other factors, it can take a few years or more for a hatchling to reach just over 110 millimeters long. They can eventually grow to about 370 millimeters.</p>
<p>The species was unknown to science until the late 1950s and has not been studied closely.</p>
<p>The goal is to build a strong captive population that can be used as research for future releases into the wild — both in the U.S. and Mexico. That work will include getting state and federal permits to release tortoises outside Turner lands.</p>
<p>Those recently released hit the ground crawling. They wandered through grass and around desert plants as the Fra Cristobal mountain range appeared in the distance.</p>
<p>It was a moment that Wiese and her team have been working toward for years.</p>
<p>"We are not in the business of making pets," she said. "We're in the business of making wild animals and that means you have to let them go."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>species </strong><em>— n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extinction </strong><em>— n. </em>the state or situation that results when something has died out completely</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ranch </strong><em>— n. </em>a large farm especially in the U.S. where animals are raised</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>burrow </strong><em>— n. </em>a hole or tunnel in the ground that an animal makes to live in or for safety</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breed </strong><em>— v. </em>to keep and take care of animals or plants in order to produce more animals or plants of a particular kind</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fossil </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>essential </strong><em>— adj. </em>extremely important and necessary</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pen </strong><em>— n. </em>a small enclosed area for farm animals</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Teacher, Lecturer or Tutor?  (2023/9/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/teacher-lecturer-or-tutor.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between a "teacher," a "tutor," and a "lecturer."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello Teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Teacher, Lecturer or Tutor? " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9348-08dbc06138a2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Teacher, Lecturer or Tutor? </span></div>
<p>My name is Saddam, and I am from Uganda in Africa.</p>
<p>I request your help to differentiate between three words and their deep meanings: "teacher," "lecturer" and "tutor."</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>Saddam</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for this great question, Saddam. All three words are nouns used to describe educators. All three teach students in different ways and have different experiences and <strong>qualifications</strong>. Let's look at each word so we understand the differences.</p>
<p><strong>Teacher</strong></p>
<p>A teacher is a professional educator who teaches students.</p>
<p>When we think of a teacher, we see a smaller classroom with 15 to 25 students. A teacher might teach in front of the class or go around to work with individual students.</p>
<p>In the United States, we call those who teach students up to 12th-<strong>grade</strong> teachers. They teach all subjects in elementary school or specific subjects like math, English or history in middle or high school.</p>
<p>Teachers are usually required to have an advanced degree, such as a master's in education. They also must pass a certification or test in general teaching knowledge and specific subjects.</p>
<p><em>Ms. Leslie is a first-year elementary school teacher. She recently completed her certifications and spent many hours in a classroom helping another teacher. </em></p>
<p><strong>Lecturer </strong></p>
<p>A lecturer, or professor, is an educator who teaches in colleges or universities.</p>
<p>Lecturers often teach larger classes and stand in front of a big room. For one-on-one time with students, they meet outside the classroom during office hours.</p>
<p>Lecturers or professors usually have an advanced degree, like a Master's or Ph. D, in their subject or special field of study.</p>
<p><em>Angela is an economics lecturer at a university. She has a Ph.D., but this is her first year of full-time teaching. </em></p>
<p><strong>Tutor</strong></p>
<p>A tutor is an educator who specializes in a certain subject or content area. Tutors usually help students one-on-one or in small groups.</p>
<p>They do not need a degree. However, some professional tutors have at least a bachelor's degree.</p>
<p>High school students can be tutors to other students if they have advanced knowledge in a subject.</p>
<p>Tutors usually give study help to students at different times, like in the evening or on the weekends. They make lessons more personal and help students with specific problems.</p>
<p><em>I have a big English test coming up, so I am meeting with my tutor after school every day this week so I can be prepared. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Saddam.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>qualification </strong><em>– n. </em>a special skill or type of experience or knowledge that makes someone suitable to do a particular job or activity</p>
<p><strong>grade</strong>— n. a level of study that is completed by a student during one year</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Recover Genetic RNA from Extinct Tasmanian Tiger  (2023/9/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/scientists-recover-genetic-rna-from-extinct-tasmanian-tiger.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say they have recovered genetic material from the Tasmanian tiger, an Australian animal that has long been <strong>extinct</strong>. The discovery could help scientists learn more about these creatures before they disappeared from Earth.</p>
<p>The recovered material is called ribonucleic acid, or RNA. RNA is a group of molecules present in all living cells that is important for genetic activity. It is similar to DNA, the molecules that contain an organism's genetic instructions.</p>
<p>RNA carries genetic information it receives from DNA. RNA combines groups of proteins that organisms require to live and works to control cell <strong>metabolism</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The remains of an extinct Tasmanian tiger from a collection at the Swedish Museum of Natural History in Stockholm are seen in this undated handout image. (Emilio Marmol Sanchez/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0932-08dbbe9903b5_cx34_cy0_cw65_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The remains of an extinct Tasmanian tiger from a collection at the Swedish Museum of Natural History in Stockholm are seen in this undated handout image. (Emilio Marmol Sanchez/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The researchers said the recovered RNA came from skin and muscle from the remains of a Tasmanian tiger stored since 1891 in a museum in Stockholm, Sweden.</p>
<p>Scientists have in recent years taken DNA from different ancient animals and plants. But the team said it was the first time RNA has been recovered from an extinct animal.</p>
<p>Scientists believe the Tasmanian tiger once lived on the Australian continent and surrounding islands. It was a top <strong>predator</strong> at the time, hunting kangaroos and other animals. The last known Tasmanian tiger is believed to have died in a Tasmanian zoo in 1936.</p>
<p>Emilio Mármol Sánchez is with the Centre for Palaeogenetics in Stockholm. He was the lead writer of a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://genome.cshlp.org/content/early/2023/07/18/gr.277663.123.abstract">study</a> describing the research results. The study recently appeared in the publication <em>Genome Research</em>.</p>
<p>Sánchez told Reuters news service RNA material gives scientists "a taste of the real biology" involving the cells and tissues of the Tasmanian tigers before they went extinct.</p>
<p>Marc Friedl<i></i>228;nder of Stockholm University was a co-writer of the study. He said, "If we want to understand extinct species, we need to understand what gene <strong>complements</strong> they have and also what the genes were doing, and which were active."</p>
<p>Researchers have questioned how long RNA could survive at room temperature. The remains stored at the Swedish Natural History Museum were in a state of semi-<strong>mummification. </strong>This means<strong> </strong>skin, muscles and bones remained, but inside organs were lost.</p>
<p>"Most researchers thought that RNA would only survive for a very short time - like days or weeks - at room temperature," said evolutionary geneticist Love Dalén. He is with the Centre for Palaeogenetics. Dalén added that while this might be the case when remains are wet, it does not appear to be so when they are dried.</p>
<p>The Tasmanian tiger looked similar to a wolf, except for the tiger-like lines appearing on its back. When people arrived in Australia about 50,000 years ago, large animal population losses followed. The arrival of European colonizers in the 18<sup>th</sup> century destroyed the remaining populations around the island of Tasmania.</p>
<p>Private "de-extinction" programs have been launched with the aim of bringing back some extinct animals. These include the Tasmanian tiger, flightless dodo bird and wooly mammoth.</p>
<p>However, many researchers have warned about the difficulties of using genetic processes to actually recreate an extinct species. While Sánchez of the Centre for Palaeogenetics said he too has concerns about such processes, he noted that he does "<strong>advocate </strong>for more research on the biology of these extinct animals."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>not existing anymore</p>
<p><strong>metabolism </strong><em>– n. </em>all the chemical processes in the body, especially the ones that use food</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong><em>– n. </em>an animal that hunts and kills other animals for food</p>
<p><strong>complement </strong><em>– n. </em>something that makes something else seem good, appealing or complete</p>
<p><strong>mummify </strong><em>– v. </em>to preserve a dead body as a mummy: a dead body that is prevented from decaying by being treated with special substances before being covered in cloth</p>
<p><strong>advocate </strong><em>– v. </em>to publicly suggest or support an idea, development or way of doing something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indoor Food Growing Operations Face Uncertain Future  (2023/9/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/indoor-food-growing-operations-face-uncertain-future.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Indoor food growing operations are seeing both successes and failures in the United States. Some companies in the food industry are investing even as competitors fail.</p>
<p>California-based Plenty Unlimited this summer began work on a $300 million indoor plant, while Kroger announced that it will be increasing its availability of <strong>vertically</strong> farmed produce.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, two indoor farming companies that got strong backing — New Jersey's AeroFarms and Kentucky's AppHarvest — filed for <strong>bankruptcy </strong>reorganization. And a five-year-old company in Detroit, Planted Detroit, shut its doors this summer.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Aaron Fields looks at produce growing in vertical farm green house he manages at Eden Green Technology in Cleburne, Texas, Aug. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b4676747-ad10-4c54-a4a9-bf342401e533_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Aaron Fields looks at produce growing in vertical farm green house he manages at Eden Green Technology in Cleburne, Texas, Aug. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)</span></div>
<p>The industry changes do not worry Jacob Portillo, a grower with Eden Green Technology, an indoor farming company.</p>
<p>"The fact that other people are failing and other people are succeeding, that's going to happen in any industry you go to, but specifically for us, I think that ... the <strong>sustainable</strong> competitors ... are going to start winning," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Support and criticism of indoor farming </strong></p>
<p>Indoor farming brings growing inside in what experts sometimes call "controlled environment agriculture." There are different methods. One method called vertical farming involves <strong>stacking</strong> produce from floor to ceiling, often under artificial lights and with the plants growing in nutrient-enriched water. Other growers are trying very large greenhouses, indoor beds of soil in big buildings and using special robots for parts of the farming process.</p>
<p>Supporters say growing indoors uses less water and land and permits food to be grown closer to consumers, saving on transport. Indoor growing is also a way to protect crops from increasingly extreme weather caused by climate change. The companies often say their products are free of <strong>pesticides</strong>, although the foods are usually not marketed as <strong>organic</strong>.</p>
<p>But critics question the sustainability of operations that can require a lot of energy for artificial light. And they say paying for that light can make profitability impossible.</p>
<p>Tom Kimmerer is a plant expert who taught at the University of Kentucky. Kimmerer has followed indoor farming alongside his research into the growth of plants both outdoors and inside. He said his first thought on vertical farm companies — especially those that used a lot of artificial light — was, "Boy, this is a <strong>dumb</strong> idea," mainly due to high energy costs.</p>
<p>The industry has admitted those high costs. Some companies are seeking to push costs down by using solar power. But even the companies that use a lot of artificial light that does not come from renewables say they can be profitable by eventually producing a high volume of produce year-round.</p>
<p>But Kimmerer thinks there are better ways to provide food locally and extend the growing season — outdoors. He pointed to Elmwood Stock Farm outside Lexington, Kentucky. The farm can grow tomatoes and greens the whole year using tools like high tunnels, also known as hoop houses. These are greenhouse-like structures that protect crops while still being partially open to the outdoors.</p>
<p>He thinks investment flowing toward new versions of indoor farming would be better spent on solutions for outdoor farmers like special robots, or money support for <strong>regenerative practices</strong>.</p>
<p>Curt Covington of AgAmerica Lending, a private investment company centered on agriculture, is not convinced that indoor farming operations can work - except in special cases.</p>
<p>Given the high cost of indoor operations, Covington said, "It's just hard... to be very profitable."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Melina Walling and Kendria LaFleur reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vertically</strong><em> -- adv. </em> positioned up and down rather than from side to side</p>
<p><strong>bankruptcy</strong><em> -- n.</em> a condition of financial failure</p>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong><em>– adj.</em> involving methods that do not completely use up natural resources</p>
<p><strong>stack</strong> <em>– v.</em> to put things one on top of the other</p>
<p><strong>pesticide</strong><em> – n.</em> a chemical that is used to kill insects that damage crops</p>
<p><strong>organic </strong><em>– adj.</em> grown without the use of artificial chemicals</p>
<p><strong>dumb</strong><em> -- adj. </em>stupid or foolish</p>
<p><strong>regenerative practices</strong><em> – n. </em>a food production method that supports and nurtures soil health</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>School Shooting Survivor Develops Mental Wellness App  (2023/9/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/school-shooting-survivor-develops-mental-wellness-app.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Kai Koerber was a student at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Florida when a gunman murdered 14 students and three school workers there in February 2018. Seeing other students and himself struggle to return to normal, Koerber wanted to do something to help people deal with their emotions.</p>
<p>Some of his classmates from the school have <strong>advocated</strong> for gun control policies or entered politics. Some took time to heal and work on their studies. Koerber's background in technology led him in a different direction: to build a smartphone app.</p>
<p>The result was Joy: AI Wellness Platform. It uses artificial intelligence to suggest small mindfulness activities for people based on how they are feeling. The <strong>algorithm</strong> is designed to recognize how a person feels from the sound of their voice. It does not matter the words or language they speak.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kai Koerber poses for a photograph Thursday, July 27, 2023, in Berkeley, Calif. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;squez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-795d-08dbbe9d866e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kai Koerber poses for a photograph Thursday, July 27, 2023, in Berkeley, Calif. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V<i>&amp;#</i>225;squez)</span></div>
<p>Like many of his fellow students from Marjory Stoneman Douglas, Koerber said he suffered from <strong>post-traumatic stress disorder </strong>for a "very long time." Only recently has it eased a little.</p>
<p>Koerber started a research team at the University of California at Berkeley to build an AI tool to see if his idea was possible.</p>
<p>The idea was a platform that provides those struggling with a "wellness <strong>practice</strong> on the go that meets our emotional needs on the go."</p>
<p>He said it was important to offer quick activities. Sometimes the activities last just a few seconds and can be done anywhere the user might be.</p>
<p>Mohammed Zareef-Mustafa is a former classmate of Koerber's. He has been using the app for a few months.</p>
<p>"I use the app about three times a week, because the practices are short and easy to get into," Zareef-Mustafa said. "It really helps me quickly de-stress before I have to do things like job interviews."</p>
<p>To use Joy, the user simply speaks into the app over a phone or computer. The AI is supposed to recognize how you are feeling from your voice, then suggest short activities.</p>
<p>If the user is feeling "neutral," the app suggests several activities, like a 15-second exercise called "mindful <strong>consumption</strong>." It gets you to "think about all the lives and beings involved in producing what you eat or use that day."</p>
<p>Another activity calls for practicing how to make an effective apology. Another asks users write a letter to their future self. One suggestion asks sad users to track how many times they have laughed over a seven-day period. The user is supposed to count the laughs up at the end of the week to see what moments made them happy.</p>
<p>The iPhone app costs $8 a month. It is a work in progress. And like other AI tools, the more people use it, the better it becomes.</p>
<p>Many wellness apps on the market claim to help people with mental health issues, but it is not always clear whether they work, said Colin Walsh. He is a professor of biomedical informatics at Vanderbilt University and has studied the use of AI in suicide prevention.</p>
<p>The <strong>stakes</strong> also matter. Facebook, for instance, has faced some criticism in the past for its suicide prevention tool. It used AI as well as humans to identify users who may be considering suicide. If the technology is simply directing someone to spend some time outside, and the stakes are lower, it is unlikely to cause harm, Walsh said.</p>
<p>Koerber said people often forget, after mass shootings, that survivors do not "<strong>bounce</strong> back right away" from the experience<strong>.</strong> It takes years to recover, he said.</p>
<p>His work has also been slower and more thoughtful than tech business leaders of the past, he added.</p>
<p>"I guess young Mark Zuckerberg was very ‘move fast and break things,'" Koerber said. "And for me, I'm all about building quality products that ... serve social good in the end."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>advocate </strong><em>— v. </em>support or argue for a cause or policy</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>algorithm </strong><em>— n.</em> a step-by-step method for solving a problem (as finding the greatest common divisor) or accomplishing a goal</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>post-traumatic stress disorder </strong><em>— n. </em>psychological reaction to experiencing a highly stressing event (such as wartime combat, physical violence, or a natural disaster) that is usually characterized by depression, anxiety, flashbacks, recurrent nightmares, and avoidance of reminders of the event</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>practice </strong><em>— n. </em>a repeated or customary action</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>consumption </strong><em>— n.</em> use of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stakes </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is staked for gain or loss</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>bounce back </strong><em>—phrasal verb </em>to<em> </em>recover quickly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Discussing Alien Life  (2023/9/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/discussing-alien-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Over the last several months, there have been many news reports about possible <strong>alien</strong> life and strange objects in the skies, sometimes called UFOs. The stories have led to public discussion in the United States. Today, we have some English terms and structures to share that can help learners take part in the discussion, too.</p>
<p><strong>Do + believe</strong></p>
<p>Let's start with the basic yes/no question of, "Do you believe in aliens?"</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: Discussing Alien Life " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2a32-08dbbf752678_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: Discussing Alien Life </span></div>
<p>The verb "believe" is common to hear when talking about non-Earth life in the universe. To "believe" something means to accept something as true. Simple answers to this question are:</p>
<p><em>Yes, I believe in aliens.</em></p>
<p><em>No, I do not believe in them.</em></p>
<p>If you want to <strong>emphasize</strong> that you believe in aliens, you can use "do" before the main verb of "believe" in the positive form. This gives extra emphasis to the main verb. The stress would be on the verb "do" when you speak.</p>
<p><em>I do believe in aliens.</em></p>
<p><em>I do believe that we are not alone in the universe. </em></p>
<p><strong>Adverbs of possibility </strong></p>
<p>Another way we can express our opinion about aliens is through adverbs of possibility. Possibility is the likelihood of something happening.</p>
<p>There are adverbs to show a stronger chance of something happening, like the adverbs "definitely" or "certainly." And there are adverbs to show a weaker chance or probability of something occurring like "maybe," "probably" or "perhaps."</p>
<p>Let's look at short dialogue using these adverbs of possibility.</p>
<p><em>Carlos: Do you believe in aliens, Joy?</em></p>
<p><em>Joy: I certainly believe in aliens. I think they are definitely among us.</em></p>
<p><em>Carlos: So, you believe the sightings of UFOs are true?</em></p>
<p><em>Joy: Clearly! The UFOs are probably held in <strong>Area 51</strong>! </em></p>
<p><em>Carlos: Maybe, they are not enemies. Perhaps, they want to be friendly. </em></p>
<p>Joy uses three strong adverbs to express her opinion and show the chance of something happening.</p>
<p>The adverbs "certainly" and "clearly" are used to add emphasis and <strong>confidence</strong> to Joy's opinions about aliens. She uses the strong adverb "definitely" to show that she thinks there is a strong possibility that aliens might already live among humans.</p>
<p>Joy also uses a weaker adverb of "probably" to express that she thinks that UFOs might be held in Area 51.</p>
<p>Notice the placement of the adverbs. Typically, we place adverbs before the main verb in the sentence.</p>
<p><em>I certainly believe in aliens</em></p>
<p>But some adverbs like "maybe" and "perhaps" can be used in the beginning of sentences.</p>
<p><em>Carlos said, "Maybe, they are not enemies. Perhaps, they want to be friendly." </em></p>
<p>Next, we have the placement of adverbs with auxiliary verbs like "be" or "have." Adverbs always come after the auxiliary verb, but before the base verb, like in these examples:</p>
<p><em>I think they are definitely among us. </em></p>
<p><em>The UFOs are probably held in Area 51.</em></p>
<p>And lastly, adverbs can be used as interjections or at the beginning of sentences. Interjections are short statements that show more of a feeling and are grammatically independent from other sentences. They usually have an exclamation mark (!) as <strong>punctuation</strong>.</p>
<p>Joy uses the adverb "clearly" as an interjection to answer Carlos' question about UFO sightings.</p>
<p>Carlos then answers Joy using the adverbs "maybe" and "perhaps" to express his opinion about the chance that aliens are friendly. He uses the weaker adverbs here. "Maybe" and "perhaps" often come in the beginning of the sentence.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today we looked at how we can express our opinion of alien life. The verb "believe" is often used to express if we accept aliens as true. We can use the verb "do" in front of the main verb in the positive to give extra emphasis to our belief.</p>
<p>And we looked at the use of adverbs of possibility. We can use stronger adverbs such as "definitely" or "clearly" to say that there is a greater chance of something and to add emphasis to our opinions. Weaker adverbs such as "maybe" and "perhaps" can express that the likelihood of something is less. And finally, we looked at the placement of those adverbs within sentences.</p>
<p>Now it is your turn. Share your opinions of aliens using the expressions and grammar above. Do you believe in life outside of Earth? Are there aliens among us? Let us know in an email to learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>alien</strong> – n. a being that comes from somewhere other than the planet Earth; an extraterrestrial</p>
<p><strong>fiction </strong><em>– n.</em> a story that describes imaginary events and people</p>
<p><strong>emphasize </strong>– v. to place importance or call attention to</p>
<p><strong>Area 51</strong> – <em>n</em>. a once-secret military area in the state of Nevada where people think the United States government held beings from other planets</p>
<p><strong>confidence </strong><em>– n.</em> a feeling that you can do something correctly</p>
<p><strong>punctuation </strong><em>– n.</em> markings that make it clear how to separate sentences and parts of sentences, so reading is easier</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>ChatGPT Expands with Voice and Image Abilities  (2023/9/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/chatgpt-expands-with-voice-and-image-abilities.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The artificial intelligence (AI) tool ChatGPT has added new abilities that include voice and image recognition.</p>
<p>The changes permit some users to directly ask ChatGPT questions and receive voice answers. In addition, the tool can recognize images and provide information about what is in them.</p>
<p>ChatGPT is a chatbot, a computer-powered tool designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. The technology is also known as "generative AI."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The ChatGPT logo is seen in this illustration taken March 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1c54ef73-dc14-4b4b-bd14-52d1e08d3d6e_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The ChatGPT logo is seen in this illustration taken March 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>The creator of ChatGPT, OpenAI, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.rfi.fr/en/business-and-tech/20230925-chatgpt-ai-getting-chatty-with-voice-prompts">announced</a> the tool's latest additions, or upgrades, this week. Currently, the new voice and image upgrades are only available to users of ChatGPT's Plus and Enterprise services.</p>
<p>ChatGPT's main service, called GPT-3.5, is free for all users. ChatGPT Plus costs $20 per month. The Enterprise service is designed for individual companies, with costs tied to the services used by the business.</p>
<p>OpenAI explained that ChatGPT Plus and Enterprise users would be able to use the voice and image additions over the next two weeks. The upgraded tools would be made available to other groups of users, including developers, "soon after." The voice and image upgrades will also be added to devices using the iOS and Android systems in the near future.</p>
<p>The company said ChatGPT's new voice control is designed to provide a natural way for users to communicate with the AI tool in a way that is similar to speaking with a human. But it noted the chatbot can do more than answer questions. It can also tell a story to children or provide detailed <strong>instructions</strong> for making or building something.</p>
<p>Users can choose different voices they want the chatbot to use. The company said it worked closely with professional voice actors to make the interactions more realistic and personal.</p>
<p>The voice interaction ability of the ChatGPT upgrade already exists in many voice assistance systems. These include Amazon's Alexa, Alphabet's Google Assistant, Apple's Siri, and others. American software maker Microsoft added voice controls to its new ChatGPT-powered Bing search engine earlier this year.</p>
<p>Another notable change to the ChatGPT tool is image recognition. This permits users to upload a photo to the system and then get information about what is contained in the picture.</p>
<p>For example, the company says a user could take a picture of what is currently available in their <strong>refrigerator</strong>. After entering the photo into ChatGPT, the tool could suggest dinner possibilities based on what the person has. The system could also provide step-by-step instructions for preparing the meal.</p>
<p>Another example given is a parent who might take a picture of a child's math problem and then seek advice on how to explain to the child how to solve it. There is even a way for users to mark areas of the image – for example with a circle – to get more specific information or help with that element.</p>
<p>Along with its announcement, OpenAI issued another warning about how its ChatGPT tool can easily get things wrong. It noted that because the system is trained using massive amounts of publicly available information, it can return results that are false, outdated or discriminatory.</p>
<p>The company urged all its users to watch out for misinformation and to attempt to <strong>verify</strong> the information provided by chatbots.</p>
<p>OpenAI announced its AI technology is also being used by the digital music service Spotify. ChatGPT is being used to power a system designed to permit Spotify podcasters to <strong>translate</strong> their shows into different languages. The translations are completed in the podcasters' own voice in an effort to make them sound more natural, OpenAI said.</p>
<p>Spotify says the first languages to be added in the coming weeks will be Spanish, French and German.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from OpenAI, Reuters and Agence France-Presse. </em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>instructions </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> directions for carrying out a task or on how to do something</p>
<p><strong>refrigerator </strong><em>– n. </em>a device used to keep things (such as food and drinks) cold</p>
<p><strong>verify </strong><em>– v. </em>to confirm or prove that something is true</p>
<p><strong>translate </strong><em>– v. </em>to change from one language to another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
