<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>What Led to the Resignation of an Ivy League President?  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-led-to-the-resignation-of-an-ivy-league-president.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The presidents of three well-known American universities recently spoke to members of the U.S. Congress about antisemitism on college <strong>campuses</strong>.</p>
<p>Antisemitism is the word used to describe a hatred of Jewish people.</p>
<p>The House's Committee on Education called Liz Magill of the University of Pennsylvania, Claudine Gay of Harvard and Sally Kornbluth of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) for a five-hour hearing in Washington, D.C.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - University of Pennsylvania President Liz Magill testifies before a House Education and The Workforce Committee hearing titled Holding Campus Leaders Accountable and Confronting Antisemitism on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Ken Cedeno)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/803e2aa7-6c8a-4cf3-93a4-430d15d63ba2_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - University of Pennsylvania President Liz Magill testifies before a House Education and The Workforce Committee hearing titled "Holding Campus Leaders Accountable and Confronting Antisemitism" on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Ken Cedeno)</span></div>
<p>The Republican-led committee chose the three leaders because their schools "have been at the center of the rise in antisemitic protests," a committee spokesperson said in a statement.</p>
<p>The protests are related to the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas. On October 7, Hamas fighters launched a surprise attack in Israel and killed over 1,200 Jewish people. Since then, the conflict has led to the deaths of more than 18,000 people in the Palestinian territory of Gaza.</p>
<p>Protesters who supported Palestine used the word "intifada," an Arabic word for resistance, and the phrase "from the river to the sea." Some people believe the phrase is a call for the death of all Jews.</p>
<p><strong>"Yes or no?"</strong></p>
<p>Representative Elise Stefanik is a Republican lawmaker from New York state. Stefanik, who went to Harvard, asked each university leader about how their school would react to calls to kill a large number of Jews, something described as <strong>genocide</strong>.</p>
<p>Stefanik asked Magill: "Does calling for the genocide of Jews violate Penn's rules or <strong>code of conduct</strong>? Yes or no?"</p>
<p>Magill did not answer "yes" or "no." Instead, she said the university only considers if "speech turns into conduct." By that, she meant the university respects an individual's right to free speech. But if the speech became "directed and severe, <strong>pervasive,</strong>" as the president said, it would then be considered more serious. In response to a question about whether a student would be punished for their speech, Magill said it depended on "<strong>context</strong>."</p>
<p>When faced with the same questions from Stefanik, Gay of Harvard and Kornbluth of MIT also did not say "yes" or "no."</p>
<p>Gay answered that it depended on the context. She added that when "speech crosses into conduct, that violates our policies." And Kornbluth answered that she had not "heard calling for the genocide of Jews on our campus."</p>
<p><strong>Criticism and questions of free speech</strong></p>
<p>The answers brought serious criticism from national and state political leaders, students, and members of the college community.</p>
<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, a Democrat, said Magill's answer was "unacceptable." He said talk of genocide against any group of people "is all in the wrong... She needed to give a one-word answer."</p>
<p>A spokesman for President Joe Biden criticized the three college presidents' answers. In a statement, he said they did not go far enough to condemn antisemitism on campuses. And calls for genocide go against "everything we represent as a country."</p>
<p>All three university presidents later apologized for not speaking out against Jewish genocide. Magill called for a review of Penn's policies which she said have long been guided by the U.S. Constitution. Gay wrote that "calls for violence or genocide against the Jewish community, or any religious or ethnic group are <strong>vile</strong>, they have no place at Harvard."</p>
<p>Free speech experts say the college presidents' answers at the hearing did follow the current understanding of the Constitution's right to free speech.</p>
<p>Suzanne Nossell is the leader of the nonprofit PEN America, a free-expression organization. She said the First Amendment of the U.S. Constitution protects "even deeply hateful speech."</p>
<p><strong>The outcome</strong></p>
<p>The congressional hearing took place on December 5.</p>
<p>By December 9, Magill resigned under pressure from wealthy donors and <strong>alumni</strong>. The pressure had started earlier this autumn when the university permitted a meeting on campus despite charges that some speakers had shown antisemitic views in other comments.</p>
<p>At MIT, the school's leadership group, called the MIT Corporation, announced its support for Kornbluth, who is Jewish, two days after the hearing. It said in a statement, "She has done excellent work in leading our community, including in addressing antisemitism, Islamophobia, and other forms of hate ..."</p>
<p>Gay faced pressure from Harvard's donors and alumni to step down. But more than 600 Harvard professors voiced their support for her leadership. They say that the school should not be influenced by political pressure.</p>
<p>Laurence Tribe is a well-known law professor at Harvard. He was critical of Gay's answer at the hearing. But he supported her continued leadership. Tribe said that "it is dangerous for universities to be... <strong>bullied</strong> into <strong>micromanaging</strong> their policies."</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Harvard leadership group announced that it would stand behind Gay and she would continue as the university's president.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>campus </strong><em>–n. </em>the physical location of a college or university's buildings</p>
<p><strong>genocide </strong><em>–n.</em> the deliberate killing of people who belong to a particular racial, political, or cultural group</p>
<p><strong>code of conduct </strong><em>–n.</em> rules on how to participate in a group, such as how to be a student at a university</p>
<p><strong>pervasive </strong><em>–adj.</em> spreading to all parts of something</p>
<p><strong>context </strong><em>–n.</em> the words that are used with a certain word or phrase and that help to explain its meaning</p>
<p><strong>vile </strong><em>–adj.</em> evil, immoral, unpleasant</p>
<p><strong>alumni </strong><em>–n.</em> the people who graduated from a school or university</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>–v.</em> to frighten, hurt, or threaten (a smaller or weaker person) : to act like a bully toward (someone)</p>
<p><strong>micromanage </strong><em>–v.</em> to try to control all parts of something usually in a way that is not wanted</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you think the universities dealt properly with their presidents?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>When Does a Problem 'Snowball'?  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/when-does-a-problem-snowball.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>If you live in a part of the world that is experiencing winter right now, it might be snowing.</p>
<p>But even if you do not live in a snowy <strong>climate</strong>, try to image cold, snowy weather. Imagine having a snowball fight with your friends. A snowball is, of course, a ball of snow. But not all snow makes good snowballs. If the snow is too light and dry, it will not hold together. It is <strong>powdery</strong>. Wetter snow makes for great snowballs. You can pack it into a tight ball, which is great for throwing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Snowballs fly during a snowball fight organized by the DC Snowball Fight Association, on the National Mall in the snow, Monday, Jan. 3, 2022, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/E81E4789-5EA7-4E37-9AAE-5573AD054F7B_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Snowballs fly during a snowball fight organized by the DC Snowball Fight Association, on the National Mall in the snow, Monday, Jan. 3, 2022, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)</span></div>
<p>A snowball might hurt a bit, but it would not cause a lot of damage. But imagine that snowball rolling down a hill. As it rolls, it picks up more and more snow. It gets bigger and bigger until it crashes into something and causes damage!</p>
<p>And that gives us "snowball" as a verb.</p>
<p>Dictionary.com defines the verb "snowball" as becoming "larger, greater, more <strong>intense</strong>..." very quickly.</p>
<p>If something like a project, campaign, or business snowballs, its progress rapidly increases and grows. For example, after a photographer posted a picture on Instagram of a m<i><i>onkey</i></i> protecting a human baby, her followers snowballed to over 1 million within a week!</p>
<p>However, when we use this expression the ending results are usually not good. Something that snowballs in a bad way <u>goes downhill</u> quickly. For example, when we do not take care of small problems, they can snowball into bigger ones.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear an example using the verb "snowball."</p>
<p><em>A: I have a friend who lied about knowing sign language on her <strong>r</strong></em><strong><em>e</em></strong><strong><em>sum</em></strong><strong><em>e</em></strong><em>. She thought no one would ask her to actually prove she knew sign language. But her boss asked her to. In fact, he set up a big meeting with the deaf community and assigned her to act as <strong>translator</strong>. She lied about why she could not attend the event. But her boss surprised her with an unplanned meeting. That is when he found out that she did not know how to sign. Her lie on her r</em><em>e</em><em>sum</em><em>e</em><em> quickly snowballed into a workplace drama that got her fired from her job. </em></p>
<p>Next, let's talk about the expression <u>snowball effect</u>.</p>
<p>A <u>snowball effect</u> is a situation where one action or event causes many other similar actions or events. And these actions or events grow and grow bigger and more problematic – just like a snowball rolling down a hill.</p>
<p>A snowball effect is similar to a <u>chain of events</u>. However, with a chain of events, one thing leads to another. But these events do not necessarily intensify or grow bigger.</p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Hopefully, using resources on VOA Learning English is having a snowball effect on your English studies ... in a good way!</p>
<p>Until next time, I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>climate </strong><em>– n. </em>a region with specified weather conditions<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>powdery </strong><em>– adj. </em>resembling or consisting of matter in a finely divided state</p>
<p><strong>intense </strong><em>– adj. </em>existing in an extreme degree</p>
<p><strong>r</strong><strong>e</strong><strong>sum</strong><strong>e </strong><em>– n. </em>a short account of one's career and qualifications</p>
<p><strong>translator </strong><em>– n. </em>to turn into one's own or another language</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you have a similar expressions in your language? Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html" target="_blank" title="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Bill Clinton: Survivor  (2023/12/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-bill-clinton.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>
VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about William Jefferson Clinton – better known as Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Clinton took office in 1993, and was re-elected in 1996. In many ways, historians consider his time in office a success. The economy expanded, and the country was largely at peace.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Bill Clinton" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7493e0cb-7da8-4433-85f3-39609c1945f0_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Bill Clinton</span></div>
<p>But Clinton had some notable failures, too. He could not persuade Congress to accept a plan to reform the nation's health care system.</p>
<p>And, in his second term, the House of Representatives took steps to remove him from office. But the Senate decided not to act.</p>
<p>Clinton finished his second term with high approval ratings. Yet he is also remembered for being only the second U.S. president to be <strong>impeached</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Bill Clinton came from a town with a memorable name: Hope. He grew up there, and in another nearby town in the Southern state of Arkansas.</p>
<p>For most of his early life, Bill was raised by his grandmother and his mother, both nurses. His father had died in a car accident before he was born.</p>
<p>People who knew Bill as a young man remember him as very intelligent, charming with people, and talented in music. His mother told him he would be president one day.</p>
<p>Sure enough, Clinton pursued activities that would lead to a political career. He attended college at Georgetown University in Washington, DC, where he studied international affairs; led student government groups; and took a position as a <strong>clerk</strong> in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>He went on to study at Oxford University in England on a prestigious Rhodes Scholarship.</p>
<p>Then he graduated from law school at Yale University. There, he met another student who would be his wife, Hillary Rodham. The two went on to have one child together, a daughter named Chelsea.</p>
<p>After finishing his studies, Clinton returned to his home state of Arkansas and pursued political office. At 32, he became one of the youngest governors ever in the country.</p>
<p>Two years later, he was voted out of office, and -- as historian Russell Riley notes -- he became the youngest <em>former</em> governor.</p>
<p>And that is how a good deal of Clinton's political career continued: in a pattern of successes and failures.</p>
<p>His successes often came as a result of his <strong>centrist</strong> policies, which appealed to people of different political beliefs. He also was an effective public speaker and, to many, a likable, charismatic person who seemed to care deeply about others.</p>
<p>But, his critics pointed out, Clinton also appeared to make many decisions simply for political advantage. And he sometimes tried to please so many people that he pleased no one.</p>
<p>Following a series of increasingly national roles – as well as a series of setbacks – Clinton campaigned for president in 1992. At first, he did not do well in the campaign. He was young and not well-known. He also suffered from reports that he had relationships with women who were not his wife.</p>
<p>But in time, Clinton began winning primary contests. Reporters called him the "Comeback Kid." He earned a public image as a politician who could survive problems.</p>
<p>In the general election, Clinton competed against the sitting president, Republican George H.W. Bush. The two men also faced an unusually strong third-party candidate named Ross Perot.</p>
<p>On Election Night, Clinton prevailed. Because Americans had split their votes among three major candidates, Clinton earned less than 50% of the popular vote. But he won enough electoral votes to become the next U.S. president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>The people who worked on Bill Clinton's presidential campaign adopted an informal motto. They said, "It's the economy, stupid." In other words, campaign officials believed that most Americans cared primarily about how a president's policies would affect their financial concerns.</p>
<p>So, President Clinton quickly set about making a series of economic changes. They included raising taxes on wealthier Americans and cutting spending to help poorer Americans.</p>
<p>In a few years, the U.S. budget deficit was gone, the federal government had a surplus, and the country's financial situation was strong and healthy – although not everyone approved of the steps Clinton took to get there, or believed he should get all the credit.</p>
<p>Early in his first term, Clinton sought an additional reform he believed would help voters' financial concerns: affordable health insurance for all Americans. Most people in the U.S. either bought private health insurance or did not have any insurance to help pay for medical costs. Clinton wanted to find a way for the U.S. government to support Americans' health-related expenses.</p>
<p>He appointed his wife, first lady Hillary Clinton, to lead a healthcare reform effort. Hillary Clinton, a lawyer, had led a similar effort to reform education in Arkansas when her husband was governor there.</p>
<p>But some lawmakers in Congress – as well as some voters – rejected her efforts. The reform effort failed.</p>
<p>Clinton also struggled in some early foreign policy moves. He withdrew American troops from Somalia after their humanitarian efforts there turned into a bloody military struggle.</p>
<p>He was also criticized for failing to intervene quickly in the genocide in Rwanda, where hundreds of thousands of people were killed.</p>
<p>Later, Clinton won praise for some of his foreign policy. His government helped restore the elected president in Haiti after a coup. It also helped negotiate peace agreements in Bosnia and Ireland. And it cooperated with NATO to intervene in the Kosovo area and stop attacks on Albanians there.</p>
<p>In general, Clinton believed the U.S. had an important role to play in maintaining peace and protecting human life around the world. At the same time, he did not want to use too many American resources to do so. He aimed to cooperate with other nations, and to set moderate goals.</p>
<p>As usual, Clinton adopted an approach that was not too extreme on one side or another.</p>
<p><strong>Impeachment</strong></p>
<p>During most of his time as president, Clinton had been under investigation. Federal judges had appointed a special counsel, named Kenneth Starr, to find out if the president had committed any crimes related to financial investments before he took office.</p>
<p>During the investigation, Starr learned that the president had been having a sexual relationship with a young woman who worked in the White House. Starr asked Clinton about the affair under oath.</p>
<p>Later, Starr accused Clinton of lying about his relationship with the woman. Starr said that Clinton had also tried to prevent others from telling the truth about some of his activities.</p>
<p>In time, the president publicly admitted the relationship, and he apologized to voters and his family. But he said he had not lied or told anyone else to lie for him.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the House of Representatives did not accept Clinton's defense. They advanced two articles of impeachment.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the U.S. Senate then considered the case. It is their job to examine the evidence and decide whether to remove a president from office. A majority did not believe the actions Clinton was accused of were serious violations against the country. They voted to acquit Clinton of the charges and permit him to continue as president.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>In the U.S., a president can serve only two full terms. After his second, Bill Clinton and his wife settled in a town outside New York City. In time, Hillary Clinton became the U.S. senator from New York, as well as a secretary of state and the Democratic Party's candidate for president.</p>
<p>Bill Clinton, like many other U.S. presidents, wrote about his experiences and helped develop his presidential library. He also worked on humanitarian, health, and economic issues with his family's organization, the Clinton Foundation.</p>
<p>For many, Clinton's time in office is remembered as a mixed experience. The economy was at one of its strongest in U.S. history. Most people could find jobs, and many Americans bought homes for the first time. In the mid-1990s especially, the Internet and other new developments created a technology boom.</p>
<p>In addition, Clinton was an effective public speaker, and he inspired new groups of people to support his Democratic Party. Many voters approved of his appointments of women and minorities to positions of power in his government. They also liked the steps he took to reduce the use of handguns, protect the environment, and provide paid time off work for some people to care for themselves or their families.</p>
<p>But both Democrats and Republicans found fault with some of Clinton's efforts. And even his supporters note that the president had to spend much of his time in office answering charges of wrongdoing.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impeach</strong> - <em>v. </em>to charge (a public official) with a crime done while in office</p>
<p><strong>clerk</strong> - <em>n. </em>a person whose job is to keep track of records and documents for a business or office</p>
<p><strong>centrist </strong>- <em>adj.</em> having political opinions that are not extreme; having beliefs fall between those of liberals and conservatives</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Did People Search for in 2023?  (2023/12/16) | 谷歌发布2023年度热搜榜</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/what-did-people-search-for-in-2023.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span style="font-size: 9pt;">Google, the most popular internet search engine, releases its "Year in Search 2023" this week.</span><p>
互联网最热门搜索引擎谷歌本周公布了“2023年热搜榜”。</p>
<p>Around the world, Google says the "war in Israel and Gaza" was the top search for news. The ongoing war topped searches for "Titanic submarine," which imploded in June, and February's "Turkey earthquake," which killed at least 50,000 in Turkey and Syria.<br/>
谷歌表示，在世界各地，“以色列和加沙战争”是新闻热搜榜首。这场正在进行的战争超过了对今年6月内爆的“泰坦尼克号潜艇”和2月在土耳其和叙利亚造成至少5万人死亡的“土耳其地震”的搜索。</p>
<p>Damar Hamlin was Google's top trending person on search this year. He is an American football player who collapsed as his heart stopped suddenly during a game in January. People also searched for Travis Kelce. In case you have not heard, Kelce is another American football player who is dating singer Taylor Swift.<br/>
达马尔·哈姆林是谷歌今年搜索量最高的人物。他是一名美式橄榄球运动员，在一月份的一场比赛中因心脏骤停而倒下。人们也在搜索特拉维斯·凯尔斯。为了防止你没有听过，凯尔斯是正在与歌手泰勒·斯威夫特约会的另一位美式橄榄球运动员。</p>
<p>Among those who passed away, people want to know about Matthew Perry, a well-known actor in the American television show Friends. Singers Tina Turner of the United States and Sinéad O'Connor from Ireland rounded out the top three.<br/>
在逝者当中，人们想要了解美国电视节目《老友记》中的著名演员马修·佩里。美国歌手蒂娜·特纳和爱尔兰歌手希妮德·奥康娜跻身前三。</p>
<p>In the world of movies, Barbie and Oppenheimer were not only the top Hollywood money-makers but also the top searches for the year. The two films topped Jawan, an Indian movie seen by millions on the streaming service Netflix.<br/>
在电影界，《芭比》和《奥本海默》不仅是好莱坞的赚钱机器，也是今年的热门搜索对象。这两部电影超过了在流媒体服务Netflix上有数百万观众观看的印度电影《战士》。</p>
<p>Yoasobi's "アイドル (Idol)" was the most searched song on Google this year. The Japanese musical group is made up of producer Ayase and singer Ikura. Inter Miami CF, the new home of Argentine soccer player Lionel Messi, led Google's sports teams search. And Bibimbap, a Korean meal of rice, vegetables, egg and protein, was the top search for a recipe.<br/>
夜游乐队的《偶像》是今年谷歌搜索量最高的歌曲。这个日本乐队由制作人Ayase和歌手几田莉拉组成。阿根廷足球运动员莱昂内尔·梅西的新东家迈阿密国际足球俱乐部在谷歌的运动队搜索中排名第一。由大米、蔬菜、鸡蛋和蛋白质组成的韩国餐石锅拌饭在搜索食谱时排名第一。</p>
<p>Google says information on the top search results came from January 1 through November 27 of this year. Search results are presented worldwide as well as individually for nearly 50 countries.<br/>
谷歌表示，排名第一的搜索结果信息来自今年1月1日至11月27日。搜索结果显示在全球范围内以及近50个国家/地区。</p>
<p>In India, the top news search was for Chandrayaan-3, the spacecraft that touched down on the moon in August. The successful landing made India only the fourth country to land on the moon.<br/>
在印度，最热门的新闻搜索是“月船3号”，这是今年8月登陆月球的航天器。这次成功着陆使印度成为第四个登上月球的国家。</p>
<p>Typhoon Kanun and Jeon Cheongjo were the top news searches in South Korea. And Ashura and Güllac, national dishes often made during religious celebrations, were the top recipes in Turkey.<br/>
台风卡努和全清道是韩国最热门的新闻搜索。在土耳其，经常在宗教庆祝活动中制作的民族菜肴阿舒拉和古拉克是最受欢迎的食谱。</p>
<p>To mark the search engine's 25th birthday, Google also released top search data "of all time" across several areas. Since 2004 (when the company's search data first became available worldwide), the most-Googled Grammy winner of all time has been Beyoncé. Portuguese soccer great Cristiano Ronaldo is the highest-searched athlete, and the most-searched movie or television program is Harry Potter.<br/>
为了纪念该搜索引擎25周年，谷歌还发布了几个领域“有史以来”的热门搜索数据。自2004年（该公司的搜索数据首次在全球范围内公布）以来，有史以来谷歌搜索次数最多的格莱美奖得主是碧昂斯。葡萄牙足球巨星克里斯蒂亚诺·罗纳尔多是搜索量最高的运动员，而搜索量最高的电影或电视节目是《哈利·波特》。</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'The Gift of the Magi,' by O. Henry  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-gift-of-the-magi-o-henry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Karen Leggett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p><em>Editor's Note: We are pleased to share a traditional holiday story with you, 'The Gift of the Magi' by O. Henry. </em><em>Karen Leggett adapted this story for VOA Learning English. Your storyteller was Shep O'Neal. The producer was Lawan Davis.</em></p>
<p>One dollar and eighty-seven cents. That was all. And sixty cents of it in the smallest pieces of money - pennies. Pennies saved one and two at a time by <strong>negotiating</strong> with the men at the market who sold vegetables and meat. Negotiating until one's face burned with the silent knowledge of being poor. Three times Della counted it. One dollar and eighty-seven cents. And the next day would be Christmas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Gift of the Magi" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/36fb8ef4-a6ec-4ed7-a573-0924aaa83d0d_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Gift of the Magi</span></div>
<p>There was clearly nothing to do but sit down and cry. So Della cried. Which led to the thought that life is made up of little cries and smiles, with more little cries than smiles.</p>
<p>Della finished her crying and dried her face. She stood by the window and looked out unhappily at a gray cat walking along a gray fence in a gray back yard. Tomorrow would be Christmas Day, and she had only one dollar and eighty-seven cents to buy her husband Jim a gift. She had been saving every penny she could for months, with this result.</p>
<p>Jim earned twenty dollars a week, which does not go far. Expenses had been greater than she had expected. They always are. Many a happy hour she had spent planning to buy something nice for him. Something fine and rare -- something close to being worthy of the honor of belonging to Jim.</p>
<p>There was a tall glass mirror between the windows of the room. Suddenly Della turned from the window and stood before the glass mirror and looked at herself. Her eyes were shining, but her face had lost its color within twenty seconds. Quickly she pulled down her hair and let it fall to its full length.</p>
<p>Now, Mr. and Mrs. James Dillingham Young had two possessions which they valued. One was Jim's gold time piece, the watch that had been his father's and his grandfather's. The other was Della's hair.</p>
<p>Had the Queen of Sheba lived in their building, Della would have let her hair hang out the window to dry just to reduce the value of the queen's jewels.</p>
<p>So now Della's beautiful hair fell about her, shining like a brown waterfall. It reached below her knees and made itself almost like a covering for her. And then quickly she put it up again. She stood still while a few tears fell on the floor.</p>
<p>She put on her coat and her old brown hat. With a quick motion and brightness still in her eyes, she danced out the door and down the street.</p>
<p>Where she stopped the sign read: "Madame Sofronie. Hair Goods of All Kinds." Della ran up the steps to the shop, out of breath.</p>
<p>"Will you buy my hair?" asked Della.</p>
<p>"I buy hair," said Madame. "Take your hat off and let us have a look at it."</p>
<p>Down came the beautiful brown waterfall of hair.</p>
<p>"Twenty dollars," said Madame, lifting the hair with an experienced hand.</p>
<p>"Give it to me quick," said Della.</p>
<p>The next two hours went by as if they had wings. Della looked in all the stores to choose a gift for Jim.</p>
<p>She found it at last. It surely had been made for Jim and no one else. It was a chain -- simple round rings of silver. It was perfect for Jim's gold watch. As soon as she saw it she knew that it must be for him. It was like him. Quiet and with great value. She gave the shopkeeper twenty-one dollars and she hurried home with the eighty-seven cents that was left.</p>
<p>When Della arrived home she began to repair what was left of her hair. The hair had been ruined by her love and her desire to give a special gift. Repairing the damage was a very big job.</p>
<p>Within forty minutes her head was covered with tiny round curls of hair that made her look wonderfully like a schoolboy. She looked at herself in the glass mirror long and carefully.</p>
<p>"If Jim does not kill me before he takes a second look at me," she said to herself, "he'll say I look like a song girl. But what could I do--oh! what could I do with a dollar and eighty-seven cents?"</p>
<p>At seven o'clock that night the coffee was made and the pan on the back of the stove was hot and ready to cook the meat.</p>
<p>Jim was never late coming home from work. Della held the silver chain in her hand and sat near the door. Then she heard his step and she turned white for just a minute. She had a way of saying a little silent prayer about the simplest everyday things, and now she whispered: "Please God, make him think I am still pretty."</p>
<p>The door opened and Jim stepped in. He looked thin and very serious. Poor man, he was only twenty-two and he had to care for a wife. He needed a new coat and gloves to keep his hands warm.</p>
<p>Jim stopped inside the door, as <strong>immovable</strong> as a dog smelling a bird. His eyes were fixed upon Della. There was an <strong>expression</strong> in them that she could not read, and it frightened her. It was not anger, nor surprise, nor fear, nor any of the feelings that she had been prepared for. He simply looked at her with a strange expression on his face. Della went to him.</p>
<p>"Jim, my love," she cried, "do not look at me that way. I had my hair cut and sold because I could not have lived through Christmas without giving you a gift. My hair will grow out again. I just had to do it. My hair grows very fast. Say 'Merry Christmas!' Jim, and let us be happy. You do not know what a nice-- what a beautiful, nice gift I have for you."</p>
<p>"You have cut off your hair?" asked Jim, slowly, as if he had not accepted the information even after his mind worked very hard.</p>
<p>"Cut it off and sold it," said Della. "Do you not like me just as well? I am the same person without my hair, right?</p>
<p>Jim looked about the room as if he were looking for something.</p>
<p>"You say your hair is gone?" he asked.</p>
<p>"You need not look for it," said Della. "It is sold, I tell you--sold and gone, too. It is Christmas Eve, boy. Be good to me, for it was cut for you. Maybe the hairs of my head were numbered," she went on with sudden serious sweetness, "but nobody could ever count my love for you. Shall I put the meat on, Jim?"</p>
<p>Jim seemed to awaken quickly and put his arms around Della. Then he took a package from his coat and threw it on the table.</p>
<p>"Do not make any mistake about me, Dell," he said. "I do not think there is any haircut that could make me like my girl any less. But if you will open that package you may see why you had me frightened at first."</p>
<p>White fingers quickly tore at the string and paper. There was a scream of joy; and then, alas! a change to tears and cries, requiring the man of the house to use all his skill to calm his wife.</p>
<p>For there were the combs -- the special set of objects to hold her hair that Della had wanted ever since she saw them in a shop window. Beautiful combs, made of shells, with jewels at the edge --just the color to wear in the beautiful hair that was no longer hers. They cost a lot of money, she knew, and her heart had wanted them without ever hoping to have them. And now, the beautiful combs were hers, but the hair that should have touched them was gone.</p>
<p>But she held the combs to herself, and soon she was able to look up with a smile and say, "My hair grows so fast, Jim!"</p>
<p>Then Della jumped up like a little burned cat and cried, "Oh, oh!"</p>
<p>Jim had not yet seen his beautiful gift. She happily held it out to him in her open hands. The silver chain seemed so bright.</p>
<p>"Isn't it wonderful, Jim? I looked all over town to find it. You will have to look at the time a hundred times a day now. Give me your watch. I want to see how it looks on it."</p>
<p>Instead of obeying, Jim fell on the couch and put his hands under the back of his head and smiled.</p>
<p>"Dell," said he, "let us put our Christmas gifts away and keep them a while. They are too nice to use just right now. I sold my gold watch to get the money to buy the set of combs for your hair. And now, why not put the meat on."</p>
<p>The <strong>magi</strong> were wise men--wonderfully wise men--who brought gifts to the Baby Jesus. They invented the art of giving Christmas gifts. Being wise, their gifts were wise ones. And here I have told you the story of two young people who most unwisely gave for each other the greatest treasures of their house. But in a last word to the wise of these days, let it be said that of all who give gifts, these two were the wisest. Everywhere they are wisest. They are the magi.</p>
<p><em>Download activities to help you understand this story <a class="wsw__a" href="https://docs.voanews.eu/en-US-LEARN/2014/12/23/802e047a-0721-4918-b463-4bf5926937b0.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>.</em></p>
<p><em>Now it's your turn. Write to us in the Comments section or on <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com" target="_blank">51VOA.COM</a> about a very special gift you received</em></p>
<p></p><p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><small><big>Words in This Story</big></small></h2>
<p><strong>negotiate</strong> - <em>v.</em> to discuss something formally in order to make an agreement</p>
<p><strong>immovable</strong> - <em>adj. </em>not able to be moved <strong>:</strong> firmly fixed in place</p>
<p><strong>expression</strong> - <em>n. </em> the way someone's face looks that shows emotions and feelings</p>
<p><strong>magi </strong>- <em>n.</em> the wise men, generally assumed to be three in number, who paid homage to the infant Jesus. Matt. 2:1–12.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indigenous Women Bring Amazon Tribe Back from Near Extinction  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/indigenous-women-bring-amazon-tribe-back-from-near-extinction.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Juma are native people of the Amazon rain forest area in Brazil. In the 1990s, there were only four people remaining in the tribe.</p>
<p>They were Aruká, the father, and his three daughters – Boreá, Mandeí and Maytá.</p>
<p>In 2021, Aruká died from COVID-19. The news appeared around the world. The <em>New York Times</em> newspaper wrote the "last man of his tribe" was gone and many people believed the tribe would go <strong>extinct</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Juma Indigenous sisters Mandei Juma, from left, Mayta Juma and Borea Juma pose for a picture at their community, near Canutama, Amazonas state, Brazil, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Andre Penner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1acf682b-c57a-41bf-88fa-e863222f2c27_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Juma Indigenous sisters Mandei Juma, from left, Mayta Juma and Borea Juma pose for a picture at their community, near Canutama, Amazonas state, Brazil, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Andre Penner)</span></div>
<p>The tribe, in the past, was built upon the idea that men had to be in charge. Once the last man died, the tribe would no longer exist.</p>
<p>But the daughters had a different idea. Before Aruká died, he and his daughters started thinking about a way to keep the tribe alive by choosing a female leader.</p>
<p>Mandeí said her sisters and father wanted her to take the position. So, Mandeí became the first woman chief in the area.</p>
<p>Earlier in their lives, the Juma sisters married men from other tribes to make sure their family line could continue.</p>
<p>Over many years, the number of Juma people has grown. In the area that is now Juma territory, there is a lot of activity. Children play in the river. People catch fish. Women work to make flour from the cassava root. Others hunt in the forest.</p>
<p>They also gather at a community building called a maloca, to eat, take care of animals, rest, and use their phones. The building has mobile phone signal equipment.</p>
<p>Aruká, the last Juma male leader, is buried under the maloca.</p>
<p>Mandeí recently retired as leader. Her older sister, Boreá, is chief now.</p>
<p>Mandeí said she found leadership difficult, at first. She said other people did not treat the Juma with respect because the tribe was so small. People also opposed her leadership because she is female, she said.</p>
<p>It hurt her but did not stop her. "I <strong>adapted</strong> to seek solutions for our people," she said.</p>
<p>The Juma territory needs a strong leader. It is about the size of a large city, similar to Las Vegas, Nevada. Old-growth forest covers the land. A Juma leader's main job is to protect the territory and its natural wealth from outsiders.</p>
<p>People come and cut down the trees. They then use the cleared land to plant grasses that are used to raise animals.</p>
<p>The changes are damaging to the traditional life of native people. Developers plan to build a road nearby. The Juma say that will bring more people and industry to the area. Mandeí says the environment is already changing.</p>
<p>"The river doesn't fill with water as it used to ... The water shouldn't dry up so much like this. It's much hotter, it wasn't like this before. Our concern is: Why is this happening? Because of deforestation," she said.</p>
<p>The Juma people work to protect their land – they move around the territory by boat and even use <strong>drones</strong> to view their land from above.</p>
<p>Mandeí's nephew, Puré, is one of the guards. He said he is proud to be a Juma and protect the land.</p>
<p>He said he broke the rules and followed his mother's lineage. "If I don't identify myself as Juma, who else will?"</p>
<p>Puré's mother married a man from another tribe. When he was born, he was registered as a member of his father's tribe. But at 15, he decided to add the Juma name, his mother's name, to his name. He had to visit Brazil's indigenous people's office to make the change.</p>
<p>Two of his cousins also added Juma to their names.</p>
<p>There were not many Juma people to begin with. Experts on Brazil's native people say before non-indigenous people made contact with the Juma, there were probably a few thousand. The Juma fought the invaders and suffered major losses in battle. A book by a German Christian clergyman<strong> </strong>says the last attack on the Juma came in 1964. Over 30 people were killed, including Aruká's father.</p>
<p>Later, when Mandeí became the leader, she asked for help in saving the Juma language. In 2019, she invited a language expert to visit and help create a dictionary for use with mobile phones. They also created digital records of the language with stories, speeches, and songs in the Juma language.</p>
<p>Wesley dos Santos went to Brazil to work on the project. He is a graduate student at the University of California – Berkeley. He said the language, Kawahiva, is endangered. It is only used by 560 people. One of its variations is Juma, and there are seven others.</p>
<p>Mandeí said she is concerned that the language and the people who speak it will disappear one day. There are only 24 people living in the Juma village. The three sisters are still trying to decide how to pass down the Juma traditions to the people who come after them.</p>
<p>"The largest responsibility I share with my sisters is not to lose Juma culture as taught by our father," Mandeí said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>–n.</em> no longer existing</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong><em>–v.</em> to change based on new information</p>
<p><strong>drone</strong><em>–n.</em> a small flying robot that often has a camera</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wondering About Wonder?  (2023/12/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/wondering-about-wonder.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the word "wonder" as a noun and a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-36f1-08dbfc22883a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am one of your followers from Iran.</p>
<p>I have question about the word "wonder."</p>
<p>How can I use it as a noun and a verb in a sentence in various ways?</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>Ali</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, especially for the month of December, Ali. We sometimes describe Christmas as "the most wonderful time of the year." The expression comes from a song by Andy Williams.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>"Wonderful" mean full of wonder. But what exactly is "wonder?"</p>
<p>In today's Ask a Teacher will we answer your question by looking at "wonder" as a noun and a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Wonder as a noun</strong></p>
<p>"Wonder" is the feeling of surprise and <strong>amazement</strong> usually caused by something that is new, strange, unexpected or different. It can also be something that people can <strong>admire</strong> or love and want to protect.</p>
<p><em>The <strong>roaming</strong> cats of Old San Juan are one of the wonders of Puerto Rico.</em></p>
<p>You may have heard people say, "no wonder." This is another way of saying "it is not surprising." For example:</p>
<p><em>It is no wonder that the meeting started late. Everyone was stuck in traffic!</em></p>
<p>Now let's look at "wonder" as a verb.</p>
<p><strong>Wonder as verb</strong></p>
<p>"Wonder" can mean to be in a state of surprise.</p>
<p><em>I always wonder at Amaury Guichon's life-size chocolate <strong>sculptures</strong> of things like dragons and giraffes!</em></p>
<p>It can also mean to think about something because it interests you.</p>
<p><em>I wonder what the economy will be like after inflation.</em></p>
<p><em>Jessica wondered where her next vacation would be: Scotland or Thailand?</em></p>
<p>We can also use "wonder" to make <strong>formal</strong> and polite requests.</p>
<p><em>I wonder if you could pick me up at the train station next week.</em></p>
<p>"Wonder" can also be used as an adjective. We use "wonder" to describe something that is extraordinary.</p>
<p><em>Wonder Woman has superhuman strength and the ability to fly!</em></p>
<p><em>There were many wonder drugs developed in the 20<sup>th</sup> century, including penicillin and insulin.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Ali.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>amazement </strong>– n. a feeling of being very surprised or shocked</p>
<p><strong>admire</strong> – <em>v</em>. to feel respect or approval of someone</p>
<p><strong>roam</strong><em> </em>— <em>v. </em>to go to different places without having a particular purpose or plan</p>
<p><strong>sculpture</strong> – n. a form of art in which hard materials are worked into object that has width, height, and depth</p>
<p><strong>formal </strong>–<em> adj. </em>serious and official</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mobile App Helps People Seeking Money from Strangers  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/mobile-app-helps-people-seeking-money-from-strangers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Do you still leave home with money in your <strong>pocket</strong>?</p>
<p>Now that many stores have gone "cashless" and most people do not have money in their pocket, those who once depended on <strong>handouts</strong> from strangers often end the day empty-handed.</p>
<p>Many people without homes or jobs say they are not able to get much money from strangers anymore.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A vendor selling Street Sense holds up her sign saying she can accept donations from cashless apps like Venmo and CashApp, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d2b79979-0c18-45d9-b926-870c16882d31_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A vendor selling Street Sense holds up her sign saying she can accept donations from cashless apps like Venmo and CashApp, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)</span></div>
<p>John Littlejohn is 62 years old and lives in Washington, D.C. He said he has been homeless for 13 years. In recent years, he said, people would tell him they left home without any money.</p>
<p>"I would be out here for six or seven hours and wouldn't get more than $12 to $15," he said.</p>
<p>People can use <strong>apps</strong> on their mobile phones to pay for most things, so they do not leave home with bills or coins. For a while, those without homes and <strong>charities</strong> that depended on <strong>spare</strong> change suffered.</p>
<p>But they are using technology, too.</p>
<p>Littlejohn sells copies of a newspaper called <em>Street Sense</em>. It is published by a nonprofit organization that says it helps homeless people. Now people who want to buy the newspaper can use an app. The money goes directly to the seller. Littlejohn is able to pay for an apartment with the money he gets from selling <em>Street Sense</em> and also other jobs he does.</p>
<p>Some people who stand outside public places such as subway stations and ask for money are called panhandlers. Sylvester Harris is one of them. He talked to a reporter near a subway station close to a large sports center in Washington, D.C. He said people often look like they want to give him money, but they do not have coins or bills.</p>
<p>"Everybody just has (credit cards) or their phones now," he said.</p>
<p>Homeless people often do not have bank accounts, credit cards or real identification that would permit them to use a mobile phone app to get money.</p>
<p>The cashless society also used to be a problem for a charity organization called the Salvation Army. The group is known for sending people to stand in busy places with a big red cooking pot, known as a kettle. People walk past the kettle and drop a dollar or a few coins inside.</p>
<p>However, as more people started using their phones and credit cards to make payments, the Salvation Army was receiving less money.</p>
<p>Now, the organization permits people to make donations by <strong>tapping</strong> their phones on the red kettle.</p>
<p>Michelle Wolf is with the Salvation Army in Washington. She said the technology is only available in a few places around the city, but it already has brought in more money.</p>
<p>Most people give $5 and often people give $20, she said.</p>
<p>The head of <em>Street Sense</em> said he started to see a problem about 10 years ago. Those who sold his newspapers said people did not have money to buy them.</p>
<p>"We were losing sales," said Brian Canmore. "Times were changing, and we had to change with them."</p>
<p>He heard that a similar newspaper in Vancouver, Canada created a payment app. Now the newspaper in Washington uses the same technology.</p>
<p>Thomas Ratliff also works for <em>Street Sense</em>. He is in charge of the 100 sellers around Washington. He said a big problem started in 2020 when many workers stayed home because of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>He said people who came to Washington for work were the main buyers of the newspaper. Many of those people are still not coming into the city. Now the sellers take the subway to busier areas outside of Washington, D.C. in Maryland and Virginia to sell the papers.</p>
<p>Ratliff noted that some payment apps that do not require a bank account -- Venmo and Cash App – still require a steady mobile phone number. But the sellers often change their number and then they have trouble getting paid.</p>
<p>There is a way for homeless people without jobs to get money in the cashless society. They can use the Samaritan app. It permits people to give money to someone just by <strong>scanning</strong> a special <strong>code </strong>– a QR code – with their phone. People who scan the code can read a story about the person and donate money that is meant to be used for buying food or clothing.</p>
<p>Jon Kumar started the Samaritan app. Charities pay him to use his technology for their work. He said it is hard to walk past a person when you know their story. His app, he said, "personalizes the person in need."</p>
<p>The people who use the app to ask for money must meet with a case manager to claim their money. The manager can also help the person with services, such as directing them to counseling or drug <strong>rehabilitation</strong>.</p>
<p>None of the apps or new technology will solve every problem for homeless people. Many people do not have the ability to sell newspapers, for example. Others are too old to work so they depend on asking people for money. Not everyone has a mobile phone.</p>
<p>Kumar said some people are "not a great fit" for this kind of intervention. He said some people need more support than a phone app can offer.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pocket <i></i>173;</strong>–n. a small cloth container sewed into some clothing</p>
<p><strong>app (application) </strong>–n. a computer application.</p>
<p><strong>charity</strong>—n. a not-for-profit organization that aims to do some good in society</p>
<p><strong>spare </strong>–adj. something that is extra</p>
<p><strong>tap </strong>–v. to lightly touch</p>
<p><strong>scan </strong>–v. to use a machine to take a picture to record an image of something like a document or other media</p>
<p><strong>code (QR) </strong>–n. a special sign that can be scanned and which directs the scanning device to a website that provides additional information</p>
<p><strong>rehabilitation </strong>–n. the process of trying to bring someone back to normal or health after an illness, drug problem or similar difficulty</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indonesian Bird Could Face New Threat from Capital City Development  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/indonesian-bird-could-face-new-threat-from-capital-city-development.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>An endangered bird in Indonesia could face new threats from development linked to the country's new capital city.</p>
<p>The bird is the maleo, a tall animal with black feathers and a pink chest. It is native to Indonesia's Sulawesi island and a few neighboring ones.</p>
<p>The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) considers the maleo to be "critically endangered." The environmental group's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/">Red List</a> identifies wildlife across the world currently facing threats. The IUCN estimates only 8,000 to 14,000 adult maleos remain in the wild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A pair of maleos look for a spot to lay an egg in Mamuju, West Sulawesi, Indonesia, Friday, Oct. 27, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a648-08dbfa7eeb88_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A pair of maleos look for a spot to lay an egg in Mamuju, West Sulawesi, Indonesia, Friday, Oct. 27, 2023. (AP Photo/Dita Alangkara)</span></div>
<p>West Sulawesi has been set up as a "support" area for building activities. The Indonesian government plans to move the nation's capital from Jakarta to a new city on Borneo island. West Sulawesi and Borneo are separated by an ocean passageway called the Makassar Strait and are just a six-hour boat trip apart.</p>
<p>Support work will take place in areas around West Sulawesi's capital, Mamuju. The development is expected to include the building of new roads and seaports to be used to transport materials to the new capital, named Nusantara, on Borneo.</p>
<p>Activities include tree clearing, digging, and removing stones. The process already has changed the forest environment on West Sulawesi and is harming maleo <strong>nesting</strong> areas near the beach.</p>
<p>These latest changes follow others to the birds' general environment, or habitat, linked to human activities in the area. These changes have made the trip for maleos to lay their eggs increasingly more difficult.</p>
<p>The maleo is considered "critically endangered because the next step is <strong>extinction</strong>," said biologist Marcy Summers. She directs the Alliance for Tompotika Conservation, a non-governmental organization working to support maleo <strong>conservation</strong> in the area. Summers noted that maleo populations had decreased by more than 80 percent since 1980.</p>
<p>Experts do not know how many maleos still live around Mamuju or across West Sulawesi island. The West Sulawesi Forestry Agency was only able to record the presence of nesting grounds in 23 villages based on reports from locals in the area. But of those, only 18 are considered active nesting areas.</p>
<p>"As far as I know, maleo birds are in <strong>decline</strong>," said Andi Aco Takdir, chief of the West Sulawesi Forestry Agency. He pointed to several reasons for the decline, including destruction of beach areas, and expanding human development activities.</p>
<p>Takdir said the government has been warning people in the area to stop establishing palm oil operations and to halt all other development around maleo nesting grounds.</p>
<p>Officials said the government is committed to keeping the birds even with massive development to support the new capital city.</p>
<p>Another problem has been thieves, also called poachers. The Associated Press reports that poachers steal maleo eggs from the sand where their parents have hidden them.</p>
<p>Poachers sell the eggs for about $1 to people as food. The eggs are a traditional gift for many people in Mamuju and other parts of Sulawesi.</p>
<p>Muhammad Idris is a local official in West Sulawesi. He told the AP that government officials there are prepared to take steps to protect the maleos even with the new capital development.</p>
<p>Idris said, "Nature conservation must be used as an <strong>achievement </strong>and (projects) must not be built leaving behind problems."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nest </strong><em>– v. </em>a home built by birds for their eggs and by some other creatures to live in</p>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>no longer existing on Earth</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>decline </strong><em>– v. </em>to go down in amount, importance, quality, etc.</p>
<p><strong>achievement </strong><em>– n. </em>something good that you achieve: to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boston Common: America’s First Public Park  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/boston-common-america-s-first-public-park.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Almost 400 years ago, America's early European colonists voted to tax each household in Boston about $70 in today's money. The money was used to buy a local farm. The plan was to use it as a common area for the public.</p>
<p>That is how Boston Common, in the state of Massachusetts, became America's first public <strong>park.</strong></p>
<p>Liz Vizza is president of the Friends of the Public Garden, an organization that supports Boston Common. She noted that Bostonians did not have backyards – private outdoor spaces behind their homes. Boston Common, she said, became "their front yard and backyard and common ground. It was a place that everybody owned."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Oldest Public Park" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d371-08dbf4d37028_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Oldest Public Park</span></div>
<p>On any given day, colonists walking though Boston Common would see soldiers setting up camp or their neighbors taking walks. They may also have seen public punishments. Presidents George Washington and John Adams also visited the park.</p>
<p>Visitors would have seen cows, because everyone had the right to keep one cow per household in the area.</p>
<p>Today, visitors will find dogs instead of cows in the 20-hectare park. The cows became outlawed in 1830 as Boston Common became more of a place for <strong>recreation</strong>.</p>
<p>Friends of the Public Garden estimates that Boston Common sees 7 million visitors each year.</p>
<p>"Boston Common is a central stage of <strong>civic</strong> life in Boston and it's been that center stage of civic life for hundreds of years, ever since it began as a park in 1634," Vizza said. "America's oldest park is a place where we come to celebrate, we come to protest, we come to find a place alone," she added.</p>
<p>Boston Common is home to several large pieces of art. They include "The Embrace," a <strong>sculpture </strong>that shows civil rights leader Martin Luther King, Jr. holding his wife, Coretta Scott King. The Brewer Fountain was the park's first public piece of art. It won the top award at the 1855 World's Fair in Paris, France.</p>
<p>The pieces of art found on the Common may soon change to include a wider selection of subjects.</p>
<p>Vizza said, "We want people to look at it with new eyes and just have a deeper understanding and respect and <strong>awareness</strong> of the history."</p>
<p>That history includes the native Massachusett tribe, the first people to live where the Common is now. The state of Massachusetts is named after the Massachusett people.</p>
<p>Vizza said, "People have lived on this land for 12,000 years. So, we do want to think about colonial America because that's a <strong>fascinating</strong> story for us. But what's an even more fascinating story is to <strong>peel</strong> those layers open to think about the Native Americans living here."</p>
<p>Vizza's team is working with tribal members to develop a piece to recognize the Massachusett tribe. They hope to have something in place by 2026, when America will celebrate its 250th birthday.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>park </strong>– <em>n</em>. a piece of public land in or near a city that is kept free of houses and other buildings and can be used for pleasure and exercise</p>
<p><strong>recreation </strong>– <em>n</em>. something people do to relax or have fun: activities done for enjoyment</p>
<p><strong>civic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to a city or town or the people who live there</p>
<p><strong>sculpture </strong>– <em>n</em>. a piece of art that is made by carving or molding clay, stone, or metal</p>
<p><strong>landscape </strong>– <em>n</em>. a picture that shows a natural scene of land or the countryside</p>
<p><strong>awareness </strong>– <em>adj</em>. knowing that something (such as a situation, condition, or problem) exists</p>
<p><strong>fascinating </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very interesting or appealing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar for a Gift-giving Season  (2023/12/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/grammar-for-a-gift-giving-season.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>We are entering a major gift-giving season in the United States. People purchase goods and services for their loved ones, friends, coworkers, and others.</p>
<p>But how do we talk about giving gifts? How do we use subjects, verbs, and objects to describe gift giving?</p>
<p>Those questions will be the subject of today's Everyday Grammar.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0d3b-08dbfcbb1c81_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start with some important terms and ideas.</p>
<p><strong>Elements </strong></p>
<p>In <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-for-giving-gifts/7377191.html" target="_blank">a recent Everyday Grammar lesson</a>, we explored questions about gifts – asking what others might want in terms of a gift.</p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will talk about statements we might make after we purchase the gift.</p>
<p>Before we continue with the lesson, we need to identify the key elements of a sentence.</p>
<p>The simplest way to divide a sentence is into two parts: the subject and the <strong>predicate</strong>.</p>
<p>The subject is generally a noun, noun phrase, or pronoun.</p>
<p>The predicate, on the other hand, says something about the subject. The predicate contains a verb, objects, indirect objects, and so on.</p>
<p>Now that we have our basic building blocks of language, we should explore how to put them together.</p>
<p><strong>Putting elements together </strong></p>
<p>We will start with the predicate. Why? Because the predicate is central to today's lesson.</p>
<p>The language we use in the predicate to describe a gift purchase often falls into a simple <strong>pattern</strong>: transitive verb + noun <strong>phrase</strong> 1+noun phrase 2.</p>
<p>A transitive verb is one that takes a direct object. A direct object is the receiver of the verb's action.</p>
<p>So, in the pattern we just learned about, we can say that the transitive verb takes a noun phrase that acts like the direct object.</p>
<p>Finally, we might have a second noun phrase that acts like the indirect object – the person who receives the direct object.</p>
<p>Please note that the direct object does not always appear directly next to the verb, as we will see.</p>
<p>Some examples will clarify this explanation.</p>
<p><strong>Examples </strong></p>
<p>When we talk about gift giving, we often use three transitive verbs: get, buy, and give.</p>
<p>The direct object is the gift. The indirect object is the person receiving the gift.</p>
<p>So, let's imagine we have a friend named Mary. We might say the following about Mary's gift-giving decision:</p>
<p><em>Mary got her son a book.</em></p>
<p>In our example, the subject is Mary. The predicate is "got her son a book."</p>
<p>The direct object is "a book." What did Mary get? She got a book. Who is going to receive the book? Her son. In this case, "her son" is the indirect object.</p>
<p>So, in the sentence "Mary got her son a book," we can say that the structure is subject + transitive verb + noun phrase 1 + noun phrase 2.</p>
<p>Here are two other examples. Let's use the transitive verbs "buy" and "give":</p>
<p><em>Jonathan bought his mother a sweater.</em></p>
<p><em>Felicia gave her friend a painting.</em></p>
<p>All of these examples are in their past forms. But we can also use these verbs in other forms as well.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Create a sentence using the following elements:</p>
<p>The subject is "My father."</p>
<p>The predicate consists of the verb "get," the noun phrase "a <strong>vase</strong>," and the noun phrase "my mother."</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here is one possible answer:</p>
<p><em>My father got my mother a vase.</em></p>
<p>The order of the sentence is subject + transitive verb + indirect object + direct object.</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>Today we explored one pattern we often use to describe gift giving. To be clear: we use other patterns as well.</p>
<p>One of these makes use of the prepositions "to" and "for." But that will have to be the subject of a future lesson.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>predicate</strong><em> – n. grammar:</em> the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
<p><strong>pattern</strong><em> – n.</em> the regular and repeated way in which something happens</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
<p><strong>vase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a container that is used for holding flowers or for decoration</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>At COP28, Nations Agree to Move away from Fossil Fuels  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/at-cop28-nations-agree-to-move-away-from-fossil-fuels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Nearly 200 countries agreed on Wednesday to move away from using planet-warming fossil fuels. The deal came after two weeks of intense negotiations at the 2023 United Nations Climate Change Conference, also known as COP28.</p>
<p>World leaders gathered in Dubai for the meeting. The agreement was meant to send a powerful message that the world is united in its desire to break with fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Scientists say the agreement is the last best hope to prevent climate <strong>catastrophe</strong>. But nations have not always followed climate agreements made in the past.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="U.N. Climate Chief Simon Stiell, from left, COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber and Hana Al-Hashimi, chief COP28 negotiator for the United Arab Emirates, pose at the end of the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, on Dec. 13, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e0edc700-fd42-4143-8e3b-fb56d1f79cb9_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">U.N. Climate Chief Simon Stiell, from left, COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber and Hana Al-Hashimi, chief COP28 negotiator for the United Arab Emirates, pose at the end of the COP28 U.N. Climate Summit, on Dec. 13, 2023, in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)</span></div>
<p>COP28 President Sultan al-Jaber called the deal "historic." He added that its true success would be in taking action. "We are what we do, not what we say," he said. "We must take the steps necessary to turn this agreement into... actions."</p>
<p>Norway's Minister of Foreign Affairs Espen Barth Eide said, "It is the first time that the world unites around such a clear <strong>text</strong> on the need to <strong>transition</strong> away from fossil fuels."</p>
<p>More than 100 countries had pushed for strong language in the COP28 agreement to "<strong>phase out</strong>" oil, gas, and coal use. However, they faced powerful opposition from the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC). The organization controls nearly 80 percent of the world's proven oil reserves as well as about one-third of worldwide oil output. The group, led by Saudi Arabia, said the world can cut emissions without rejecting <strong>specific</strong> fuels.</p>
<p>That dispute had some observers worried that an agreement would not come together.</p>
<p>The lead negotiator for the Alliance of Small Island States, Anne Rasmussen, criticized the deal as not strong enough. But she did not officially object to the agreement. Her speech in Dubai drew a standing <strong>applause</strong> that lasted nearly two minutes.</p>
<p>Danish Minister for Climate and Energy Dan Jorgensen noted one reason the deal was impressive. "We're standing here in an oil country, surrounded by oil countries, and we made the decision saying let's move away from oil and gas," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Transitioning away from fossil fuels</strong></p>
<p>The deal does not call for "phasing out" fossil fuels. It calls for "transitioning away" from fossil fuels to reach "net zero by 2050 in keeping with the science."</p>
<p>In some ways, that language describes what is already happening. Some governments have enacted policies in recent years to move to a greener economy.</p>
<p>Europe and the United States have retired some coal-fired power plants. And many countries have policies meant to increase sales of electric vehicles.</p>
<p>The deal calls on governments to move even faster in several areas. They include increasing renewable energy by three times by 2030, speeding up efforts to reduce coal use, and developing technologies such as carbon capture.</p>
<p>German climate diplomat Jennifer Morgan said there was not much difference between "phasing out" and "transitioning away." She said, "I think the ‘phase-out' was about sending a clear signal. And I think the ‘just transition away from' is a way of phrasing the phase-out" for poorer nations who cannot act as quickly as richer ones.</p>
<p>Li Shuo of the Asia Society told the Associated Press that when the two phrases are <strong>translated</strong> into Mandarin or Japanese, there is almost no difference.</p>
<p>The Reuters news agency reported that a source familiar with Saudi Arabia's position described the deal as "a menu where every country can follow its own pathway."</p>
<p>China, the world's biggest carbon polluter today, suggested that industrialized countries should take the lead.</p>
<p>Zhao Yingmin is China's vice environment minister. He said after the deal was approved, "Developed countries have...historical responsibilities for climate change."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>catastrophe</strong> - n. a terrible disaster</p>
<p><strong>text</strong> - n. words on a writing or document</p>
<p><strong>transition</strong> - n. change from one state to another</p>
<p><strong>phase out</strong> - v. to stop something gradually over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>specific</strong> - adj. special or particular</p>
<p><strong>applause</strong> - n. cheer</p>
<p><strong>translate</strong> - v. to change words from one language to another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Jury Rules Google App Store Operates as Monopoly  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/jury-rules-google-app-store-operates-as-monopoly.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American jury has found that Google's app store operates as an illegal <strong>monopoly</strong>.</p>
<p>The decision came in a lawsuit brought by video game company Epic Games. The jury reached the decision this week in California after a four-week trial.</p>
<p>Epic had argued Google uses business methods that block competition against its Google Play Store. That is where users can download <strong>apps</strong> for smartphones and other devices using the Android operating system (OS). Google owns the Android OS. Epic uses Google Play and other app stores to sell its popular game Fortnite and others.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This March 23, 2010, file photo shows the Google logo at the Google headquarters in Brussels, Belgium. (AP Photo/Virginia Mayo, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/03190000-0aff-0242-5ad4-08da3e6b9459_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This March 23, 2010, file photo shows the Google logo at the Google headquarters in Brussels, Belgium. (AP Photo/Virginia Mayo, File)</span></div>
<p>Experts predict that if the ruling stands, it could cost Google billions of dollars in business. It could also change the way all app stores do business in the future. Google condemned the court's decision and said it will appeal the ruling.</p>
<p>Android holds by far the largest share of the mobile OS market worldwide. Online data researcher Statista <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272698/global-market-share-held-by-mobile-operating-systems-since-2009/">estimated</a> in October that Android had a market share of 70.5 percent. The next closest competitor, Apple, held a market share of 28.8 percent.</p>
<p>Other companies, such as Apple, also operate app stores. Epic brought a similar lawsuit against Apple in 2021. In it, Epic argued Apple used methods in its app store that created a monopoly that blocked competition. A federal judge ruled mostly in Apple's favor in that case. Epic has appealed that ruling.</p>
<p>One of the biggest issues in both cases was whether Google and Apple have the right to require developers to use the app store's payment systems. Such systems can take up to 30 percent of a sale in <strong>commissions</strong> from app developers.</p>
<p>In the case of Epic vs. Apple, the judge mostly sided with Apple. But the judge did find that Apple had used some unfair business methods which violated California law. The judge ordered Apple to permit developers across the United States to add their own links to process payments within iPhone apps.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency reported that Google's appeal will take place in the same court in San Francisco that decided Epic's case against Apple. Epic's appeal of the Apple decision is currently before the U.S. Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The jury in the Epic vs. Google legal case debated for about three hours before giving its decision on Monday. It decided that Google's control of its Play Store amounted to an illegal monopoly. The monopoly covered both Google's app selling system and its payment processing method within the app, the jury found. Epic did not ask the court for financial damages.</p>
<p>Epic chief Tim Sweeney praised the court's decision on X, formerly known as Twitter. "Victory over Google!" Sweeney <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1734370774830797210">wrote</a>. In a company statement, Epic called the <strong>verdict</strong> "a win for all app developers and <strong>consumers</strong> around the world."</p>
<p>Google's vice president of government affairs and public policy, Wilson White, confirmed the company's plan to appeal the ruling. In a statement, he said, "We will continue to defend the Android business model and remain deeply committed to our users, partners, and the broader Android <strong>ecosystem</strong>."</p>
<p>White added his opinion that the Google Play Store currently offers "more choice and openness" than any other major mobile provider.</p>
<p>Depending on how the court's ruling is enforced, Google could lose billions of dollars yearly in commissions on sales through the Play Store. But the company's main source of earnings, online advertising, would not be directly affected by the court's decision.</p>
<p>The case now goes back to the judge in the trial, U.S. District Judge James Donato. He will hear arguments on both sides about how Google should change its business operations to improve fair competition. The judge has suggested this process could begin in the second week of January.</p>
<p>During those hearings, Google will be able to argue against the changes proposed by Epic. In addition, any orders established by the judge at the end could be appealed. These processes, technology experts say, could result in the case extending for many months, or possibly years.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this report for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse.</em></p>
<p><span>___________________________________________________</span></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>monopoly </strong><em>– n. </em>complete control of the entire supply of goods or of a service in a certain area or market</p>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device</p>
<p><strong>commission </strong><em>– n. </em>a payment made to someone who sells goods that is directly related to the amount sold</p>
<p><strong>verdict </strong><em>–n. </em>the decision of a jury in a trial in a court of law</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who buys goods or services<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong><em>– n. </em>all the things that are part of a particular environment or situation</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do You Say That Name Again?  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-do-you-say-that-name-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>News reporters, politicians and public <strong>figures</strong> have had trouble saying some of the words that relate to the top stories of the year year. Last week, the online language learning company Babbel released its lists of the most <strong>mispronounced</strong> words in the United States and Britain.</p>
<p>The two lists are a reminder of the year's news on everything from scientific discoveries to politics.</p>
<p>Babbel teacher Malcolm Massey noted the <strong>diversity</strong> of the words. This year's words come from several different languages.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - SZA arrives at the 64th annual Grammy Awards, April 3, 2022, in Las Vegas. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c42f-08dbfa9cb107_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - SZA arrives at the 64th annual Grammy Awards, April 3, 2022, in Las Vegas. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)
</span></div>
<p>"I think a lot of it is due to how close our cultures have become because of how <strong>globalized</strong> things are," Massey said.</p>
<p><strong>Singers, actors and politicians</strong></p>
<p>A popular singer who spells her name S-Z-A is on the U.S. list. Babbel notes her name is pronounced SIZ-uh,[short I sound].</p>
<p>The first name of another entertainer is also on the list. Cillian Murphy is an Irish actor who starred in this summer's hit as physicist J. Robert Oppenheimer. His first name is pronounced KI-lee-uhn.</p>
<p>Other pronunciations on the U.S. list include the name of biotech businessman Vivek Ramaswamy, who is a Republican presidential candidate. The correct way to say his name is Vih-VAKE Rah-mah-SWAH-me.</p>
<p>Two volcanoes were also on the list — Mexico's Popocatepetl, (Poh-poh-kah-TEH-peh-til), and Hawaii's Kilauea, (Kee-lou-EY-uh).</p>
<p>The winning word at this year's Scripps National Spelling Bee also made the U.S. list. That word was psammophile (SAM-uh-file.) It means any animal or plant that prefers sandy soils or areas.</p>
<p>The <strong>coronation</strong> of King Charles in May helped put the Stone of Scone, (Stown uhv Skoon), on Britain's list. The holy stone rests beneath the Coronation Chair where a new king first receives his crown.</p>
<p>Kristie Denlinger teaches <strong>linguistics</strong> at the University of Texas in Austin. She said hearing an unfamiliar word often enough can help someone master it.</p>
<p>"Anything that is kind of different from what a speaker is used to, they can learn how to pronounce things in different ways than what they're used to, it just takes more <strong>exposure</strong>," Denlinger said.</p>
<p><strong>A personal choice</strong></p>
<p>Massey said that as one learns a new pronunciation, it is important to "not stress perfection but progress over time, so practicing these words again and again."</p>
<p>In some cases, the correct pronunciation is just a matter of personal choice. Earning a place on the U.S. list was the last name of Travis Kelce, the Kansas City Chiefs' American football player. Whether Kelce should be pronounced with one or two syllables, Kels or KEL-See, has been a subject even his own family talks about.</p>
<p>Both Travis and his brother, Philadelphia Eagles center Jason Kelce, say their last name as KEL-see. On a <strong>podcast</strong>, they discussed with their father, Ed Kelce, how that pronunciation came to be.</p>
<p>"I got tired of correcting people," said Ed Kelce, who said that his co-workers always called him KEL-see.</p>
<p>Jason Kelce then asks: "Should we go by Kels or KEL-see?" His father answers: "Do whatever you want. I did."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jamie Stengle reported on this story for the Associated Press. Jill Robbins adapted this story for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>figure – </strong><em>n</em>. a person who is well-known and important in some way.</p>
<p><strong>mispronounced</strong> – <em>adj.</em> not said in a correct way</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong>– <em>n.</em> containing many very different elements</p>
<p><strong>globalized </strong>– <em>adj.</em> when people from one country link with people</p>
<p>from another country in order to work or communicate with them</p>
<p><strong>coronation</strong> – <em>n.</em> the ceremony at which a king or queen is crowned</p>
<p><strong>linguistics</strong> – <em>n.</em> the science of language</p>
<p><strong>exposure</strong> – <em>n.</em> publicity, being seen or heard</p>
<p><strong>podcast</strong> – <em>n. </em>an audio file similar to a radio broadcast, that can be listened to on a website or app on your phone or computer</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gates Foundation Takes on Poverty in US  (2023/12/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/gates-foundation-takes-on-poverty-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>In recent years, city leaders in Grand Island, Nebraska, observed that many workers and students were walking or riding long distances to their jobs or schools. So when city administrator, Laura McAloon, learned of a chance to study the development of a bus system to meet those transportation needs, she took it.</p>
<p>The study received support from the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation along with the International City/County Management Association.</p>
<p>It sent McAloon to Washington, D.C. along with other local leaders to learn about policies to lift people in their community out of poverty.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Laura McAloon, Grand Island City Administrator, poses for a photo on Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Grand Island, Nebraska. (AP Photo/John Peterson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6817-08dbfa6e13bc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Laura McAloon, Grand Island City Administrator, poses for a photo on Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023, in Grand Island, Nebraska. (AP Photo/John Peterson)</span></div>
<p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation announced last week that it will donate $100 million to expand its work on reducing poverty in the U.S. The commitment is part of the $460 million the foundation said in 2022 it would donate over four years to this area of need. The foundation says it is looking to quicken the speed at which its gifts have an <strong>impact</strong>.</p>
<p>Ryan Rippel is a founding director for economic strategy at the Gates Foundation. He said the large donations represent an important change in its strategy and give <strong>grantees</strong> more power in directing their own work.</p>
<p><strong>Goal to help 50 million Americans</strong></p>
<p>The investment is a small part of the foundation's overall budget, which was $7 billion last year. But it has quickly grown. The expansion of their work, Rippel said, depends on whether they meet their goal of improving economic <strong>mobility</strong> for 50 million people in the U.S. who are just above the poverty level with a yearly <strong>income</strong> of $29,160.</p>
<p>The foundation will give money to organizations working to expand support for local government using evidence -based policies that improve economic mobility. That includes policies that connect people with skills without college degrees to jobs, helping people receive government <strong>benefits</strong> and pushing businesses to change working conditions to improve work-life balance.</p>
<p>The grantees include Opportunity@Work, Families and Workers Fund, Prosperity Now, Pacific Community Ventures, Results for America and the Urban Institute.</p>
<p>At a meeting in Washington, D.C., in May, the Urban Institute introduced the tools and research they have developed to help cities and counties understand barriers to economic mobility. There, McAloon from Grand Island realized that her city of 53,000 needed to collect more information.</p>
<p>By the end of the meeting, they had changed their objectives and launched a data collective and analysis project. That included <strong>surveying</strong> local citizens and working with the human resources departments of major local employers.</p>
<p>What the city learned is that transportation had been a problem for workers. But when the meatpacking plant and other manufacturers raised wages after the pandemic, many households were able to pay for cars. Now the problem, the employers said, was housing.</p>
<p>At the close of Grand Island's research study this fall, McAloon said they found it would not be possible to set up a bus system under federal rules. Instead, they are exploring a transportation <strong>pool</strong> that is partially paid for by employers and the state.</p>
<p>The study led to new communication and cooperation across agencies, schools and local organizations. And McAloon's office learned that a lack of plumbers and electricians was holding up new housing developments. So, she reached out to the community college, which is now setting up a technical training program in high schools.</p>
<p>"It was a matter of a couple of emails," she said. "And they're already working on ... making an impact on that issue that's keeping us from building more houses."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>impact </strong><em>— n. </em>a powerful or major influence or effect</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grant </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that is given to someone by a government, a company, etc., to be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mobility </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability or tendency to move from one position or situation to another usually better one</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>income </strong><em>— n. </em>money that is earned from work, investments, business, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>benefit </strong><em>— n. </em>a good or helpful result or effect</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>survey </strong><em>— n. </em>an activity in which many people are asked a question or a series of questions in order to gather information about what most people do or think about something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pool </strong><em>— n. </em>a group of people who do the same job or activity together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Will Europe’s New Artificial Intelligence Rules Affect the World?  (2023/12/13) | 欧盟新版人工智能规定将如何影响全球？</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-will-europe-s-new-artificial-intelligence-rules-affect-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>European nations reached an agreement on rules for artificial intelligence (AI) last week. Some experts say the regulations will affect people around the world.<br/>
欧洲国家上周就人工智能规定达成协议。一些专家表示，这些规定将影响到世界各地人们。</p>
<p>Here are some of the details of the agreement reported by the Associated Press:<br/>
以下是美联社报道的一些协议细节：</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">The AI Act and how it works:<br/>
《人工智能法案》及其运作方式：</span></p>
<p>The AI Act aims to regulate or establish guidelines for AI technology that has the potential to cause problems if misused.<br/>
《人工智能法案》旨在规范或制定人工智能技术的指导方针，如果滥用，人工智能技术可能会引发问题。</p>
<p>AI systems that recommend online material, or those that check email messages, would be less regulated. But technology that concerns healthcare or medical decisions would have higher requirements.<br/>
推荐在线材料或检查电子邮件的人工智能系统将受到较少的监管。但涉及医疗保健或医疗决策的技术将有更高的要求。</p>
<p>Some AI systems will be banned except in some cases. They include systems that scan people's faces in public and systems that make predictions about future behavior such as whether a person will commit a crime.<br/>
除某些情况外，一些人工智能系统将被禁止。它们包括在公共场合扫描人们面部的系统，以及预测未来行为（如一个人是否会犯罪）的系统。</p>
<p>The new AI Act will not take effect until two years after a vote from European lawmakers. The vote is planned for the first part of next year. The soonest it would be in place is sometime early in 2026.<br/>
新的《人工智能法案》要到欧洲立法者投票两年后才能生效。投票计划在明年上半年进行。它最快将在2026年初生效。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">How will the Act affect the world?<br/>
该法案将如何影响世界？</span></p>
<p>Some experts say the guidelines could become a global standard. That has happened before. One recent European decision caused U.S. company Apple to stop using its lightning data cable in favor of a more widely used cable.<br/>
一些专家表示，这些指导方针可能会成为一项全球标准。这种情况以前也发生过。欧洲最近的一项决定导致美国苹果公司停止使用其闪电接口数据线，转而使用一种更广泛使用的数据线。</p>
<p>Experts say Europe's rules might be used as a blueprint in other parts of the world. Anu Bradford is a professor at Columbia University in New York City. She called Europe's act "comprehensive" and "a game-changer." Bradford noted the European rules will "show the world AI can be governed."<br/>
专家表示，欧洲的规定可能会被用作世界其他地区的蓝图。阿努·布拉德福德是纽约哥伦比亚大学的教授。她称欧洲的法案是“全面的”和“游戏规则的改变者”。布拉德福德指出，欧洲的规定将“向世界表明人工智能是可以治理的”。</p>
<p>Rights groups complained that Europe's decision to not completely ban the use of facial recognition "is a missed opportunity." Amnesty International noted that Europe did not ban exports of AI technology that covers social scoring. Social scoring systems permit governments to record how well citizens follow rules.<br/>
人权组织抱怨说，欧洲没有完全禁止使用面部识别的决定是“错过了一个机会”。大赦国际指出，欧洲没有禁止出口涵盖社会评分的人工智能技术。社会评分系统允许政府记录公民遵守规则的程度。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are the U.S. and China doing?<br/>
美国和中国在做什么？</span></p>
<p>In the United States, President Joe Biden signed an executive order in October on AI. Biden required AI technology companies to share test results and other information with the government. Government organizations will create requirements for AI tools that must be followed before systems are released for public use.<br/>
在美国，乔·拜登总统于10月签署了一项关于人工智能的行政命令。拜登要求人工智能技术公司与政府共享测试结果和其他信息。政府组织将对人工智能工具提出要求，在系统发布供公众使用之前必须遵守这些要求。</p>
<p>China released rules for AI tools that create material such as photos, text and videos. The rules are only short-term guidelines. President Xi Jinping also called for an open and fair environment for AI development around the world.<br/>
中国发布了创建照片、文本和视频等材料的人工智能工具的规定。这些规定只是短期的指导方针。习主席还呼吁为世界各地人工智能技术发展创造公开、公正的环境。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Will Europe's rules change ChatGPT?<br/>
欧洲的规定会改变ChatGPT吗？</span></p>
<p>The rise of ChatGPT, an AI tool based in the U.S., is one of the reasons for Europe's new set of rules. Europe's rules include guidelines for chatbots and other AI systems that can do jobs such as writing, creating video and writing computer code.<br/>
总部位于美国的人工智能工具ChatGPT的兴起是欧洲制定新规则的原因之一。欧洲的规则包括针对聊天机器人和其他人工智能系统的指导方针，这些系统可以完成写作、创建视频和编写计算机代码等工作。</p>
<p>Systems must clearly show where the material that went into training the bots came from. They also must show how much energy was used to train the systems, or models. They should be open about how they control the data that comes from their tool's users. And they need to observe the EU's copyright property protection laws.<br/>
系统必须清楚地显示用于训练机器人的材料来自哪里。他们还必须显示有多少能源用于训练系统或模型。他们应该公开如何控制来自工具用户的数据。他们还需要遵守欧盟的版权保护法。</p>
<p>High technology systems or risky uses of AI are required to follow stricter rules. Those include systems that create basic pieces of information, such as computer code, that others will then use to create other AI systems.<br/>
高科技系统或人工智能的高风险使用需要遵守更严格的规则。其中包括创建基本信息的系统，如计算机代码，然后其他人将使用这些信息创建其他人工智能系统。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Bird Flu Kills Hundreds of Seals, Sea Lions in Brazil  (2023/12/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/bird-flu-kills-hundreds-of-seals-sea-lions-in-brazil.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Brazilian officials say bird flu has killed nearly 1,000 seals and sea lions in the country's south.</p>
<p>As of December 11, the southern state of Rio Grande do Sul had confirmed 942 sea mammal deaths. The animals were infected with Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza, also known as bird flu.</p>
<p>The first cases of the sickness were reported in Brazil in 2023. During past outbreaks in Europe and America, agriculture industries have killed hundreds of millions of farm animals to try to contain the disease.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Oceanologist Liane Dias photographs a dead porpoise on the coast of the Atlantic Ocean, during an outbreak of Bird Flu, in Sao Jose do Norte, in the State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Diego Vara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d71a-08dbfa9e7dd3_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Oceanologist Liane Dias photographs a dead porpoise on the coast of the Atlantic Ocean, during an outbreak of Bird Flu, in Sao Jose do Norte, in the State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Diego Vara)</span></div>
<p>Officials at Brazil's Agriculture Ministry said preventive measures were put in place after the first report of bird flu in May. This action made it possible to avoid an outbreak on <strong>poultry</strong> farms. That kind of outbreak, officials say, would have likely led to a ban on such exports from Brazil, the world's top chicken exporter.</p>
<p>Silvina Botta studies oceans and sea life at Brazil's Rio Grande Federal University. She told Reuters news agency the remains of dead animals need to be buried or burned as soon as possible to prevent further disease spread.</p>
<p>Scientists have found some sea mammals <strong>convulsing</strong> along local beaches, as the virus attacks their nervous system, Reuters reported. Botta said that under government health rules, the animals must be killed immediately to prevent their suffering.</p>
<p>Botta added that the first case of bird flu-related sea mammal deaths in the area came in September. That is when local scientists first became aware of a large increase in disease deaths. Three towns in the state still have active bird flu outbreaks.</p>
<p>Botta said the spread among sea mammals appears to have started in Peru and then reached the South American continent. The disease has also affected wildlife in Chile, Argentina, and Uruguay.</p>
<p>Brazil's Agriculture Ministry has reported 148 bird flu outbreaks in the country, mostly along the coast. Officials have declared a health emergency to contain the disease, which it says "is not yet considered <strong>endemic</strong> in Brazil."</p>
<p>The virus has also affected other animal populations in the country. In addition to the outbreaks among seabirds, seals and sea lions, researchers have collected remains of dead porpoises and penguins found on beaches. Officials say they have not yet confirmed those deaths were also from bird flu.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>poultry </strong><em>– n. </em>chicken and other birds that people breed for meat and eggs</p>
<p><strong>convulse </strong><em>– v. </em>cause to shake violently with sudden uncontrolled movements</p>
<p><strong>endemic </strong><em>– adj. </em>regularly found or commonly affecting a particular group or specific area</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Student Learning Decreased in Math, Reading Worldwide  (2023/12/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/study-student-learning-decreased-in-math-reading-worldwide.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Students around the world suffered historic <strong>setbacks</strong> in reading and math during the COVID-19 pandemic. That information comes from results of the latest Program for International Student Assessment (PISA).</p>
<p>The PISA is an international comparative study of the <strong>scores</strong> of 15-year-old students on tests in reading, math and science. Nearly 700,000 students took part in the study.</p>
<p>PISA is administered every three years. The latest results showed an "unprecedented drop in performance" since 2018.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Math teacher Doug Walters sits among empty desks as he takes part in a video conference with other teachers to prepare for at-home learning at Twentynine Palms Junior High School in Twentynine Palms, Calif., Aug. 18, 2020. (AP Photo/Gregory Bull, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/49553d60-b3f0-4e33-a7b8-306e857e52db_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Math teacher Doug Walters sits among empty desks as he takes part in a video conference with other teachers to prepare for at-home learning at Twentynine Palms Junior High School in Twentynine Palms, Calif., Aug. 18, 2020. (AP Photo/Gregory Bull, File)</span></div>
<p>The PISA 2022 study was supposed to happen in 2021. But it was postponed because of the pandemic. The 2022 results were released on December 5. It is the first extensive study with data on how the pandemic has affected student performance around the world.</p>
<p>The study looked at 81 education systems. They include 37 member countries of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD). OECD has been administering the test since 2000.</p>
<p><strong>Decreasing scores</strong></p>
<p>The study found decreasing test scores in both rich and poor countries.</p>
<p>Andreas Schleicher is the director for education and skills at OECD. He said, "The world is no longer divided between rich and well-educated countries and poor and badly educated countries."</p>
<p>The study found the average international math score fell by 15 points since 2018. Reading scores across <strong>participating</strong> countries fell by 10 points. The OECD considers 20 points to be equal to one year of learning. Scores did not change in a major way in science.</p>
<p>Albania saw the biggest decrease in math scores, with a massive 69-point decrease. That means Albanian students lost more than three years of learning. Many countries fell by more than one year's worth of learning in math, including Germany, Iceland and the Netherlands.</p>
<p><strong>Some Good News</strong></p>
<p>Four places did improve their performance between PISA 2018 and 2022 in all three subjects: Brunei, Cambodia, the Dominican Republic and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Six East Asian education systems outperformed all other countries in math. Scores in Singapore were measurably higher than all other countries in all three subjects.</p>
<p>The math scores for U.S. students were about even with the international average. Science and reading were slightly higher.</p>
<p><strong>Effects of the pandemic</strong></p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic was a major reason for the worldwide score drops. But science and reading scores were dropping even before the pandemic. This suggests there are other reasons for the decrease.</p>
<p><strong>Factors</strong> such as the level of investment in education, the social value and pay levels of teachers, and educational beliefs of students have all influenced educational results, the OECD's Schleicher said.</p>
<p><strong>Purpose of PISA</strong></p>
<p>The PISA tests explore how well students can solve complex problems, think critically and communicate effectively.</p>
<p>The goal of PISA is to provide useful information to educators and policymakers on the strengths and weaknesses of their country's education system.</p>
<p>OECD Secretary-General Mathias Cormann released the latest PISA results in Paris. He said, "PISA 2022 helps to identify the comparative strengths of education systems that have performed well <strong>despite</strong> recent shocks."</p>
<p>Policymakers can use such information to consider reforms to education systems for a brighter, more financially successful future, Cormann added.</p>
<p>The study also reported on the fast-changing influence of technology on educational performance. The results found that moderate use of electronic devices in school is connected to higher performance.</p>
<p><strong>Test your skills</strong></p>
<p>Khan Academy is a popular test prep web site. It offers a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.khanacademy.org/test-prep/oecd-pisa" target="_blank">free PISA quiz</a>. You can see example questions and compare your math skills against the 15-year-old students from around the world who took the PISA 2022.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for VOA Learning English using sources from the Associated Press, PISA, OECD, and others.</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">___________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>setback</strong>–<em>n</em>. an event that delays progress</p>
<p><strong>score</strong>–<em>n</em>. a piece of information, usually a number, that demonstrates the performance level of a skill</p>
<p><strong>participating</strong>–<em>adj</em>. taking part in</p>
<p><strong>factor</strong>–<em>n</em>. something that contributes to a result</p>
<p><strong>despite</strong>—<em>prep</em>. without being affected by</p>
<p><strong>quiz</strong>–<em>n</em>. a short, informal quiz</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Approves Two Treatments for Sickle Cell Disease  (2023/12/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-approves-two-treatments-for-sickle-cell-disease.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>United States health officials last week approved two gene treatments for sickle cell disease. Doctors hope that the treatments will provide a cure for the painful genetic blood disorder.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) said the one-time treatments can be used for patients 12 and older with severe forms of the disease.</p>
<p>One treatment is made by Vertex Pharmaceuticals and CRISPR Therapeutics. The other is made by Bluebird Bio.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This photo provided on Oct. 25, 2023 by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows crescent-shaped red blood cells from a sickle cell disease patient in 1972. (Dr. F. Gilbert/CDC via AP, File )" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-23ba-08dbe70ba37f_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This photo provided on Oct. 25, 2023 by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows crescent-shaped red blood cells from a sickle cell disease patient in 1972. (Dr. F. Gilbert/CDC via AP, File )</span></div>
<p>"Sickle cell disease is a... life-threatening blood disorder with significant unmet need," the FDA's Dr. Nicole Verdun said in a statement announcing the approvals. "We are excited to <strong>advance</strong> the field especially for individuals whose lives have been severely disrupted by the disease."</p>
<p>Sickle cell disease (or SCD) affects millions of people worldwide. The disease is common in places with high cases of malaria, like Africa and India. Scientists believe being a carrier of SCD helps protect against severe malaria.</p>
<p>It is more common among Black Americans, Africans, and Middle Easterners than other population groups. The World Health Organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.afro.who.int/health-topics/sickle-cell-disease">said</a> many children with the most severe form of the disease die before the age of five, usually from an infection or severe blood loss.</p>
<p><strong>The new treatments</strong></p>
<p>A genetic change, or mutation, causes blood cells to become defective in people with sickle cell disease. The unhealthy blood cells result in blockages, called blood clots. The clots cause pain and damage to bones and organs in the human body.</p>
<p>The Vertex treatment is called Casgevy. Its goal is to help the body go back to producing healthy blood cells that are present at birth. It uses CRISPR, the gene editing tool, to <strong>knock out</strong> a gene in stem cells collected from the patient.</p>
<p>Bluebird's treatment, called Lyfgenia, aims to add copies of a modified gene. The modified gene helps red blood cells to produce a protein that prevents or <strong>reverses</strong> unhealthy cells.</p>
<p>The two gene treatments are the first approved in the U.S. for sickle cell disease. Vertex is already approved in Britain and Bahrain.</p>
<p>The new treatments are costly. The cost for Bluebird Bio is $3.1 million and for Vertex, $2.2 million. To help cover the cost, the U.S. Centers for Medicare and Medicaid says it plans to create partnerships with state Medicaid agencies and drug companies.</p>
<p>Even with the high cost, many patients say they would consider the gene treatment because of the seriousness of the disease.</p>
<p>Jalen Matthews of Louisville, Kentucky, was diagnosed with sickle cell at birth. She had her first pain <strong>episode</strong> at age 9. Three years later, the disease led to a spinal cord stroke that left her with some <strong>paralysis</strong> in her left arm and leg.</p>
<p>"I had to learn how to walk again, feed myself, clothe myself, basically learn how to do everything all over again," said Matthews, who is now 26.</p>
<p>Today, she deals with the disease by having <strong>blood</strong> <strong>transfusions</strong>. About every two months, the treatment replaces five units of her blood with healthy cells. She said she plans to ask her doctor about the new treatments.</p>
<p>"This one-time kind of cure is very much needed," Matthews said.</p>
<p>Studies testing the treatments suggest they work well. Of 31 people treated in the Vertex study with enough follow-up, 29 were free of pain episodes for at least a year. In the Bluebird study, 28 of 32 patients had no severe pain or organ damage between six and 18 months after the treatment.</p>
<p>But doctors note there are possible side effects. They also say the long-term results are unknown. For both treatments, the required chemotherapy comes with risks such as infertility, hair loss and serious infections.</p>
<p>With the Bluebird treatment, blood cancer has happened. The FDA said it will include a "black box warning" about that risk.</p>
<p>With the Vertex therapy, some scientists worry that CRISPR brings the possibility of "off-target effects." These are unexpected changes to a person's genome.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English with reporting from The Associated Press and other sources.</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">_________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advance</strong> - v. to move forward</p>
<p><strong>knock out</strong> - phrasal verb, to cause something to stop working</p>
<p><strong>reverse</strong> - v. to return to an earlier state</p>
<p><strong>episode</strong> - n. a short time of an illness</p>
<p><strong>paralysis</strong> - n. a condition in which you are unable to move</p>
<p><strong>blood transfusion</strong> - n. a medical treatment in which someone's blood is put into the body of another person</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan’s Ohtani Gets $700 Million, Biggest Team Sports Deal  (2023/12/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/japan-s-ohtani-gets-700-million-biggest-team-sports-deal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Everyone expected Japan's Shohei Ohtani to receive the biggest deal in baseball history. Over the weekend, the two-time Most Valuable Player award-winner received the biggest deal in team sports<em> </em>history.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the Japanese star announced that he had agreed to a 10-year contract with the Los Angeles Dodgers valued at $700 million.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://olympics.com/en/news/ohtani-shohei-mega-deal-top-10-richest-contrcts-mbappe-messi-ronaldo">Olympics.com</a> says the amount is higher than the $679 million for France's Kylian Mbappe with Paris Saint-Germain in 2022, $674 million for Lionel Messi with Barcelona in 2017, and Cristiano Ronaldo's $500 million agreement with Al Nassr.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Japan's Shohei Ohtani, of the Los Angeles Angels acknowledges the crowd after receiving the trophy for leading vote-getter during the MLB All-Star baseball game in Seattle, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Lindsey Wasson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e4b3-08dbfa71d442_cx18_cy10_cw80_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Japan's Shohei Ohtani, of the Los Angeles Angels acknowledges the crowd after receiving the trophy for leading vote-getter during the MLB All-Star baseball game in Seattle, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Lindsey Wasson)</span></div>
<p>The total is also higher than the largest American football contract of $450 million given to Patrick Mahomes of the Kansas City Chiefs. It far exceeds the baseball deals of $426.5 million given to Mike Trout of the Los Angeles Angels and the $360 million given to Aaron Judge of the New York Yankees.</p>
<p>Under the contract, Ohtani's average yearly salary of $70 million is well above the <strong>previous</strong> high of about $43 million that pitchers Max Scherzer and Justin Verlander struck with the New York Mets. His average yearly <strong>salary</strong> is also higher than the combined salary of all players with the Baltimore Orioles or the Oakland A's this year.</p>
<p>Ohtani's agent, Nez Balelo, called it "a <strong>unique</strong>, historic contract for a unique, historic player." Another sports agent, Leigh Steinberg said, "He's rocketed into a <strong>stratosphere</strong> all his own."</p>
<p><strong>Is he worth it?</strong></p>
<p>Ohtani started in Major League Baseball with the Los Angeles Angels in 2018. He is the sport's best two-way player. He is one of the best hitters and also one of the best <strong>pitchers</strong> in baseball. He is the only player in baseball history to appear as both a pitcher and a hitter in the All-Star games in 2021 and 2023. He was unanimously named the Most Valuable Player twice in 2021 and 2023.</p>
<p>But the $700 million deal was more than most baseball fans imagined. And many wonder why the Dodgers made that kind of investment in one player.</p>
<p>Mike Lewis teaches marketing and sports business at Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia. He said, "Baseball has sometimes struggled to gain national attention, but he's the kind of guy who attracts millions...and not just from the U.S."</p>
<p>Lewis compared the Dodgers' signing of Ohtani to Inter Miami's signing of Lionel Messi in Major League Soccer. Interest in American soccer, especially on social media, greatly increased around the U.S. and the world. As of Sunday morning, the Dodgers' Instagram account had 3.2 million followers. Ohtani on his own has 6.3 million.</p>
<p>No baseball player has received more interest internationally than Ohtani, especially in his native Japan. Japanese companies paid for top advertising spaces in Anaheim when Ohtani was playing with the Angels. His Angels <strong>uniform</strong> is the best-selling one among baseball players in 2023. Ohtani's uniform is expected to sell well, and many more Dodgers' tickets are expected to be sold, too.</p>
<p>When Ohtani was negotiating with different baseball teams for a new contract, fans were following his movements and posting information online. The interest was similar to the level around popular singer Taylor Swift.</p>
<p>Steinberg, the sports agent, believes every baseball team interested in Ohtani has already estimated how much money he would bring to the team. If the Dodgers were willing to pay $700 million to sign him, then Steinberg believes they made a good decision.</p>
<p>"He's handsome and he's a huge <strong>box office draw</strong>," Steinberg told the <em>Associated Press</em>. "There are very few players who can match that. He has appeal to all."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English based on reporting from The Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>previous</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj. </em>taking place earlier; before the present</p>
<p><strong>salary</strong> <em>–n.</em> pay or wages in money</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong> <em>–adj.</em> unlike anything else</p>
<p><strong>stratosphere </strong><em>–n.</em> a high level of the atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>pitcher </strong><em>–n. (baseball)</em> the player who throws the ball to the batter: the pitcher's action starts every play in baseball</p>
<p><strong>uniform </strong><em>–n.</em> the clothing worn by a team which is also sold to fans and the public</p>
<p><strong>box office draw </strong><em>–expression (entertainment)</em> a popular perform who many people are willing to pay money to see</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Nickel Mine, Environmental Activists Exist Together in Michigan  (2023/12/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/nickel-mine-environmental-activists-exist-together-in-michigan.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>About 20 years ago, the international mining company Rio Tinto said it would open a nickel mine in the far northern part of the American state of Michigan.</p>
<p>Rio Tinto promised good jobs for people in the area close to Canada.</p>
<p>But environmental activists had concerns. They were worried about industrial pollution from the metal, the mining byproducts and <strong>contaminated</strong> water runoff into rivers and lakes.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This May 8, 2014, photo shows the opening to the Eagle Mine in western Marquette County, Michigan. (AP Photo/John Flesher)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7124-08dbe6170e3b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This May 8, 2014, photo shows the opening to the Eagle Mine in western Marquette County, Michigan. (AP Photo/John Flesher)</span></div>
<p>Many observers expected a long legal fight between the two sides. Some did not believe the mine would ever open.</p>
<p>But the Eagle mine has been open for more than 10 years. There have been no accidents or pollution problems.</p>
<p>People in the area who once protested the mine have found a way to exist with the mine.</p>
<p>Maura Davenport is one of those people. She is one of the top leaders of the Superior Watershed Partnership (SWP), an environmental interest group.</p>
<p>"I was fiercely opposed to the mine, and I changed," she said.</p>
<p>Davenport's group was invited to act as a "watchdog" for the mine. Rio Tinto asked the group to oversee pollution testing that has higher <strong>standards</strong> than <strong>regulators</strong> require.</p>
<p>The cooperation between the environmental group and the mining company may be an example for other mines around the world.</p>
<p>Many new mines are opening in order to provide minerals needed to make <strong>items</strong> used by the green energy economy. These items include <strong>batteries</strong>, electrical wire and magnets.</p>
<p>If countries around the world are to meet the climate goals set in Paris in 2015, there needs to be a 400-percent increase in the production of these minerals. The International Energy Agency said there needs to be an increase of 19 times in nickel production alone.</p>
<p>Davenport said the Eagle mine proposal "divided our community." Other mines in northern Michigan had opened in the 1800s and closed in the 1930s. The mining companies left behind large open holes and environmental damage. Water that ran from the mine polluted Lake Superior, one of the Great Lakes in the northern Midwest.</p>
<p>Simon Nish worked for Rio Tinto when the Eagle mine was proposed. He said he understands the "<strong>dilemma</strong>" that communities face. They need jobs and an economic <strong>benefit</strong>, he said, but "don't want long-term environmental consequences."</p>
<p>Residents do not trust the big mining companies he said, so it makes it easier to say no to proposals.</p>
<p>He worked in Australia in the 1990s when mining companies wanted to use land where native Aboriginal people lived. He said he learned that businesses need to "understand the interests of both sides" if they want long-term success.</p>
<p>When Nish arrived in Michigan in 2011, the mine was under <strong>construction</strong>. But it faced several legal disputes. In order to find a way for the mine to open, Nish considered looking for a partner.</p>
<p>Nish said the Superior Watershed Partnership was already testing water around the area. He asked if they would consider running an environmental testing program for the mine.</p>
<p>Over a few months, Rio Tinto and the SWP made a plan for testing. The group required open <strong>access</strong> to the mine. It would also test groundwater in the surrounding area. And it required permission to test a processing center 30 kilometers away. Rio Tinto was required to pay for the work.</p>
<p>The agreement launching the Community Environmental Monitoring Program was signed in 2012. More than 10 years later, no major pollution problems have turned up.</p>
<p>But some environmental groups are still concerned. Rochelle Dale is head of the Yellow Dog Watershed Preserve. She said Eagle mine and the testing program are doing good work.</p>
<p>But, she said, "a lot of the sulfide mines in the past haven't really had a problem until after closure. It's something that our grandchildren are going to <strong>inherit</strong>."</p>
<p>As more mines open up to help meet the world's demand for new minerals, mining companies are starting to understand how important local support is to their success.</p>
<p>The partnership in Northern Michigan gives large mining companies a "<strong>road map</strong>." But, although it has been successful so far, there is no guarantee that an accident will not happen that pollutes the area in the future.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>VOA's Steve Baragona wrote this story. Dan Friedell adapted it for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>contaminated </strong><em>– adj. </em>something that is no longer pure because an outside element has dirtied it or made it harmful</p>
<p><strong>standard </strong><em>– n. </em>something set up by authority or by general consent as a rule for measuring or as a model</p>
<p><strong>item </strong><em>– n. </em>an object of attention, concern, or interest</p>
<p><strong>regulator </strong><em>– n. </em>a person or group that establishes rules and makes sure they are followed</p>
<p><strong>battery </strong><em>– n. </em>an electric cell or connected electric cells for providing electric current</p>
<p><strong>dilemma </strong><em>– n. </em>a difficult decision or question</p>
<p><strong>benefit </strong><em>– n. </em>something that produces good or helpful results or effects</p>
<p><strong>construction </strong><em>– n. </em>the building work that must be done to create something new</p>
<p><strong>access </strong><em>– n. </em>the ability to walk into an otherwise restricted area</p>
<p><strong>inherit </strong><em>– v. </em>to receive something when a person dies</p>
<p><strong>road map</strong><em>– n. </em>guidelines or directions proven successful in meeting a goal</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Free Toy Store Helps Needy Families  (2023/12/12) | 慈善商店帮助有需要家庭</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/free-toy-store-helps-needy-families.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Four years ago, country music star Brad Paisley and his wife, actress Kimberly Williams-Paisley, helped create a free food store in Nashville, Tennessee. Their goal was to give families in need the ability to choose their own food in a place that felt like a normal store. They named it The Store.<br/>
四年前，乡村音乐明星布拉德·佩斯利和他的妻子、演员金伯利·威廉姆斯-佩斯利在田纳西州纳什维尔市帮助创建了一家免费食品店。他们的目标是让有需要的家庭能够在一个感觉像普通商店的地方自行挑选食物。他们把它命名为The Store。</p>
<p>The Store is a partnership with Nashville's Belmont University, where Paisley earned his degree.<br/>
The Store是纳什维尔市贝尔蒙特大学的合作伙伴，佩斯利在该校获得了他的学位。</p>
<p>The Store is turning into a free toy store ahead of the Christmas holiday. The event began Friday. For two days, chosen families could pick out new toys, video games, stuffed animals, makeup and other gifts.<br/>
圣诞节假期前，The Store将变成一家免费的玩具店。该活动于周五开始。在为期两天的时间里，被选中的家庭可以挑选新玩具、电子游戏、毛绒玩具、化妆品和其它礼物。</p>
<p>Paisley said, "The emotional aspect of being able to give your child something your child wanted versus just something to sort of get you through the holidays...that's such a load off the minds of somebody who maybe didn't think they were going to be able to do that."<br/>
佩斯利说：“能够给孩子一些他们想要的东西，而不仅仅是度过假期的东西的这种情感，对于那些可能认为自己无法做到这一点的人来说，这是他们思想上的沉重负担。”</p>
<p>Paisley and Williams-Paisley brought the idea of a free food store to Nashville after seeing a similar effort in California. The Store launched in early 2020. Its opening came just weeks after a powerful tornado hit the area and shortly before the start of the COVID-19 pandemic. The pandemic made food access an urgent problem.<br/>
佩斯利和威廉姆斯-佩斯利在加利福尼亚州看到类似措施后，将免费食品店的想法带到了纳什维尔市。该店于2020年初开业。它刚好赶在一场强大的龙卷风袭击了该地区的几周后，也是新冠肺炎大流行开始前不久。新冠疫情使食品供应成为一个紧迫的问题。</p>
<p>The Store changed its methods to meet people's needs. It turned into a food delivery service for older people. It delivered one million meals in its first year of operation.<br/>
The Store转变了方式来满足人们的需求。它变成了为老年人提供的送餐服务。它在运营的第一年就送出了100万份餐食。</p>
<p>Along with the food store, Belmont University also offers additional services to families in need. They include financial education and music therapy.<br/>
除了这家食品店，贝尔蒙特大学还为有需要的家庭提供额外的服务。其中包括金融教育和音乐治疗。</p>
<p>"People come on hard times and we want this to be a safe, welcoming place for everybody, whether you're volunteering or whether you're needing the services," Williams-Paisley said. "It's just a community and we're all in it together."<br/>
威廉姆斯-佩斯利说：“人们在困难时期到来，我们希望这里对每个人来说都是一个安全、受欢迎的地方，无论你是在做志愿者还是需要服务。这只是一个社区，我们都在其中。”</p>
<p>For this year's toy store event, The Store received about 2,000 donated objects and raised $20,000. Volunteers and workers from Belmont University in Nashville spent hours opening and organizing all of the donated toys into different areas.<br/>
在今年的玩具商店活动中，The store收到了大约2000件捐赠物品，并筹集了20000美元。纳什维尔市贝尔蒙特大学的志愿者和工作人员花了几个小时将所有捐赠的玩具打开并整理到不同的区域。</p>
<p>Parents will be able to drop off their kids at a religious center nearby, where they can play and drink a hot chocolate. The adults can pick out gifts at the same time.<br/>
家长们可以把孩子送到附近的宗教中心，在那里他们可以玩耍并喝一杯巧克力热饮。与此同时成年人可以挑选礼物。</p>
<p>Paisley said Christmas is his favorite time of year. He said he might even visit The Store dressed as Santa Claus, the make-believe person who brings gifts for children on Christmas.<br/>
佩斯利说圣诞节是他一年中最喜欢的时间。他说，他甚至可能打扮成圣诞老人的样子去The Store，圣诞老人是一个在圣诞节给孩子们派送礼物的虚构人物。</p>
<p>"I live for this time of year," Paisley said. "Ever since we've had children and possibly even before, I kind of go all out."<br/>
佩斯利说：“我盼着每年的这个时候。自从我们有了孩子，甚至可能在此之前，我就有点不遗余力。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Make Surprising Discovery about Ancient Mosquitoes  (2023/12/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/researchers-make-surprising-discovery-about-ancient-mosquitoes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of people worldwide are killed every year by malaria and other diseases that are spread through mosquito bites.</p>
<p>Female mosquitoes are responsible for these deadly bites because they have a special mouth design that male mosquitoes do not have.</p>
<p>But it has not always been that way. Researchers said they have discovered the oldest-known fossils of mosquitoes - two males located in pieces of an ancient orange-colored substance known as amber.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An undated handout image of a view from below of the head of a fossilized male mosquito, including elongated sucking-piercing mouthparts, trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago. (Dany Azar/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ab739397-aa09-4907-a4a1-f87eb8f5d3b6_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An undated handout image of a view from below of the head of a fossilized male mosquito, including elongated sucking-piercing mouthparts, trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago. (Dany Azar/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The male mosquitoes date to 130 million years ago. They were found near the modern town of Hammana in Lebanon. To researchers' surprise, the male mosquitoes had long mouthparts seen now only in females.</p>
<p>Dany Azar is a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Sciences' Nanjing Institute of Geology and Paleontology and Lebanese University. Azar said they were clearly blood-eaters. The lead writer of the study, recently published in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(23)01448-3" target="_blank">Current Biology</a>, added, "This discovery is a major one in the <strong>evolutionary</strong> history of mosquitoes."</p>
<p>The two fossilized mosquitoes, both representing the same species that has died off, are similar in size and appearance to modern mosquitoes. However, the mouthparts used for getting blood are shorter than in today's female mosquitoes.</p>
<p>Study co-writer André Nel of the National Museum of Natural History of Paris described the finding as "quite surprising."</p>
<p>The special<strong> anatomy</strong> of the two mosquitoes was beautifully saved in the fossils. Both insects had sharp and triangle-shaped jaw anatomy and a long structure with tooth-like elements.</p>
<p>The researchers said they suspect that mosquitoes evolved from insects that did not consume blood. They think that the mouthparts that were developed for getting blood meals were originally used to <strong>pierce</strong> plants to get nutritious fluids.</p>
<p>Plant evolution may have affected the differences in feeding between male and female mosquitoes. At the time when these two mosquitoes became stuck in tree <strong>sap</strong> that eventually became amber, flowering plants were beginning to spread for the first time.</p>
<p>From the findings, Azar said that all early mosquitoes, both male and female, were bloodsucking. And male mosquitoes lost the ability later.</p>
<p>The researchers said while these are the oldest mosquito fossils, mosquitoes probably appeared millions of years earlier. They noted that molecular evidence suggests mosquitoes developed from about 200 million to 145 million years ago.</p>
<p>There are more than 3,500 species of mosquitoes worldwide, found everywhere except Antarctica. Some species spread diseases such as malaria, yellow fever, Zika fever, dengue and others. The World Health Organization says more than 400,000 people die annually from malaria - a parasitic infection - mostly children under age 5.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong>–<em> n.</em> something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times</p>
<p><strong>evolution</strong> <em>– n.</em> an idea that the differences between plants and animals are because of changes that happened by a natural process over a very long time</p>
<p><strong>species</strong><em> – n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>anatomy </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>the parts that form a living thing</p>
<p><strong>pierce </strong><em>-- v. </em>to make a hole in or through something</p>
<p><strong>sap</strong><em> – n.</em> a watery juice inside a plant that carries the plant's food</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Discover Six Planet System Orbiting in ‘Perfect Harmony’  (2023/12/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/scientists-discover-six-planet-system-orbiting-in-perfect-harmony.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have identified six planets orbiting a nearby star "in perfect <strong>harmony</strong>" in our Milky Way galaxy. The solar system appears to be untouched by outside forces since it was created, likely billions of years ago.</p>
<p>The rare discovery was made by observations from a pair of space telescopes – the European Space Agency's Cheops, and Tess, operated by the American space agency NASA. The find is expected to provide astronomers with new data to help them learn more about how solar systems form and develop.</p>
<p>The six planets sit in the northern sky constellation of Coma Berenices, about 100 light-years from Earth. A light year is the distance light travels in a year – about 9.5 trillion kilometers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration depicts the six planets of the HD110067 system, which scientists say interact perfectly in gravitational synchronization. (image Credit: Thibaut Roger/NCCR PlanetS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-129a-08dbf811e6b1_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration depicts the six planets of the HD110067 system, which scientists say interact perfectly in gravitational synchronization. (image Credit: Thibaut Roger/NCCR PlanetS)</span></div>
<p>The star the planets are orbiting is known as HD110067. It is about 20 percent smaller in mass than our sun. The six planets are about two to three times the size of Earth. But they are believed to have densities closer to gas giants in our own solar system, such as Jupiter and Saturn.</p>
<p>The scientists say the planets are considered "sub-Neptunes." This is a common kind of planet found within our Milky Way galaxy. These planets are generally much larger than Earth but smaller than Neptune.</p>
<p>The orbits range from nine days to 54 days. This puts them closer to their star than Venus is to our sun. It also makes the planets intensely hot. The researchers say that while only six planets were discovered, there could be more.</p>
<p>An international team of astronomers recently described the findings <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06692-3">in a study</a> that appeared in the publication <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>The researchers reported the six planets were in a rare condition called orbital resonance. This is when two or more moons line up with their parent planet at regular times and <strong>interact</strong> gravitationally. In this case, the team described the solar system as completely "synchronized" in a gravitational formation. Synchronized means happening at the same time and speed.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>The scientists say it is likely these synchronized orbits have been happening since the system formed about 4 billion years ago. The planets were identified by observing small drops in the star's brightness when a planet passed in front of the star.</p>
<p>Hugh Osborn, of the University of Bern in Switzerland, helped lead the research. He said the resonance interactions demonstrate "the mathematical beauty" of the system. Osborn added that the newly discovered system could possibly "unlock the secrets of these mysterious sub-Neptune planets, which we know so little about."</p>
<p>The lead writer of the study was Rafael Luque. He is an astronomer from the University of Chicago. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://news.uchicago.edu/story/scientists-discover-rare-6-planet-system-moves-strange-synchrony?utm_source=WWW&amp;utm_medium=NewsModule">said</a> the discovery will likely become a very useful tool to study sub-Neptunes.</p>
<p>Scientists have long wondered whether sub-Neptunes might be rocky planets with thick atmospheres of hydrogen and helium. They have also suggested the planets might be made of rock and ice, with warm and water-rich atmospheres.</p>
<p>Luque said the synchronized nature of the discovered system is highly rare and requires further study. "We think only about one percent of all systems stay in resonance, and even fewer show a <strong>chain</strong> of planets in such <strong>configuration</strong>," he said. "It shows us the <strong>pristine</strong> configuration of a planetary system that has survived untouched."</p>
<p>Enric Palle is a researcher at the Institute of Astrophysics in the Canary Islands. He told the Associated Press that while astronomers know of 40 to 50 in-sync solar systems, none have as many planets in such perfect synchronization as the newly discovered one.</p>
<p>The University of Bern's Osborn said he was surprised but pleased when the orbital periods of the planets came close to what scientists predicted. "My <strong>jaw</strong> <strong>was on the floor</strong>," he said. "That was a really nice moment."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, NASA, The University of Chicago and the University of Geneva. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>harmony </strong><em>– n. </em>a situation in which people are peaceful and agree with each other</p>
<p><strong>interact </strong><em>– v. </em>if two things interact, they have an effect on each other</p>
<p><strong>chain </strong><em>– n. </em>a series of things strung together in a line</p>
<p><strong>configuration </strong><em>– n. </em>the arrangement or pattern a group of related things appear in</p>
<p><strong>pristine </strong><em>– adj. </em>in very good condition</p>
<p><strong>jaw</strong> <strong>on the floor </strong><em>– phr. </em>a phrase used to express deep shock or surprise</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How to Grow Mushrooms Indoors  (2023/12/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-to-grow-mushrooms-indoors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mushrooms are not only tasty. They are also filled with healthy nutrients, like calcium and potassium, and vitamins, like D and B.</p>
<p>Some people not only enjoy eating mushrooms. They also like to collect them in the wild. But that is not for everyone. While some people are knowledgeable enough to collect mushrooms in the woods and eat them, many people are not. Eating the wrong mushroom can make you sick or even ... dead.</p>
<p>Therefore, buying them is the easier and safer choice. However, there is another one: You can grow mushrooms yourself inside your own home.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by North Spore shows a variety of cultivated mushrooms in a cardboard box in Portland, Maine. (North Spore via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-048e-08dbf7ee9eb5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by North Spore shows a variety of cultivated mushrooms in a cardboard box in Portland, Maine. (North Spore via AP)</span></div>
<p>In a recent article for <em>The Associated Press</em>, plant expert Jessica Damiano explains there are two ways to do this. You can buy a set of materials from a garden store called a "grow kit" or you can put them together yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Grow kits</strong></p>
<p>Grow kits are a great way for beginners to try growing mushrooms. These grow kits include partly-grown mushroom starters, called "spawn." The spawn is set in soil and is contained in its own grow box. You put the spawn in water overnight. Then you return it to the box and open it to fresh air. <strong>Spray</strong> it with water two times a day.</p>
<p>Within two or three weeks, you will be eating mushrooms with more on the way. Damiano says it is a fun, easy activity. And people will likely ask you about it.</p>
<p><strong>Putting them together yourself</strong></p>
<p>If you are more serious about growing mushrooms and want a larger harvest, Damiano says it costs less to put the materials together yourself. It is easy, she says.</p>
<p>For starters, you will need a wooden, metal, or plastic box or container. It needs to be about 15 centimeters deep and large enough to hold your harvest.</p>
<p>You will also need a growing substance -- soil mixed with compost and other materials. The materials depend on the mushrooms. White button mushrooms grow better in a half-and-half mix of compost and <strong>well-rotted manure</strong>. Oyster mushrooms do well in oat or wheat straw. Shiitakes, another kind of mushroom, like sawdust.</p>
<p>Finally, you will need <strong>fungal spores</strong>: Think of them as seeds. You can purchase these online or at specialty stores.</p>
<p>Clean your hands well. Avoid bringing bacteria, <strong>mold,</strong> or non-mushroom fungi into the box. Fill the box with your growing substance (soil and materials) leaving about 25 millimeters at the top. Put the spores evenly over the soil substance and gently wet it. Spray it with water twice daily. Keep it wet but not too wet.</p>
<p>To grow quickly and effectively, the spore-topped soil material should be kept away from direct sunlight. It should be kept at or close to 21 degrees Celsius. If you cannot keep a room in your home at that temperature, set the box or tray on a heating <strong>pad</strong> set to 21 degrees but no higher (warmer temperatures can kill the spores). A soil thermometer can help make sure the soil does not get too warm.</p>
<p>Put a piece of cloth lightly over the top of the box to keep <strong>moisture </strong>in. But do not seal it tightly.</p>
<p>Soon, a white coating will form on the surface of the soil. That is mycelium, a network of fungal threads from which your mushrooms will grow.</p>
<p>When the soil is completely coated with mycelium, top it off with a bit more of the soil mixture. Remove any heating elements. And move the tray to a cooler spot – 12 to 15 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>Mushrooms usually grow, or "fruit," within a week or two. They nearly double in size daily until they are finished growing. Depending on the kind of mushroom, they will be ready to harvest, with their tops fully open. That will be in roughly three to four weeks. Use a sharp, clean knife to cut them at soil level to avoid disrupting nearby growth.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for the Associated Press. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>spray </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to scatter or apply lightly and in small amounts</p>
<p><strong>well-rotted </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to decay due to the action of fungi or bacteria to high degree</p>
<p><strong>manure </strong><em>– n. </em>bodily waste from birds and animals in stables and barnyards with or without litter</p>
<p><strong>fungal </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>of, relating to, or having the characteristics of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/fungi">fungi</a></p>
<p><strong>spores </strong><em>– n.</em> a primitive usually unicellular often environmentally resistant dormant or reproductive body produced by plants, fungi, and some microorganisms and capable of development into a new individual either directly or after fusion with another spore</p>
<p><strong>mold </strong><em>– n. </em>a superficial often woolly growth produced especially on damp or decaying organic matter or on living organisms by a fungus</p>
<p><strong>pad </strong><em>– n. </em>a thin flat mat or cushion</p>
<p><strong>moisture </strong><em>– n. </em><strong> </strong>liquid diffused or condensed in relatively small quantity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>College Board Changes AP Black History Class  (2023/12/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/college-board-changes-ap-black-history-class.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>High school students in the United States can earn college credits by taking and passing Advanced Placement (AP) <strong>courses</strong>. The classes, developed by The College Board, cover many subjects, including English, history, math, and sciences among others.</p>
<p>This week, the non-profit organization released a new set of ideas and skills, called a framework, for its AP African American Studies course. The latest version comes months after the organization was criticized for discussing course requirements with conservative critics.</p>
<p>Changes include more attention to ideas such as the Tulsa Race Massacre, Black culture's influence on film and sports, and discrimination in housing, known as <strong>redlining</strong>. The latest version will be used when the class officially launches at the start of the next school year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Emmitt Glynn teaches to a group of Baton Rouge Magnet High School students, Jan. 30, 2023, in Baton Rouge, La. The College Board released an updated framework for its new Advanced Placement African American Studies course. (AP Photo/Stephen Smith, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7ac5e685-efb3-49bd-9579-dbeb7fa8861b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Emmitt Glynn teaches to a group of Baton Rouge Magnet High School students, Jan. 30, 2023, in Baton Rouge, La. The College Board released an updated framework for its new Advanced Placement African American Studies course. (AP Photo/Stephen Smith, File)</span></div>
<p>The AP African American History course gained national attention earlier this year. At that time, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, currently a Republican presidential candidate, said he would ban the course in his state because it pushed political issues. Florida released a list of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/CommMannyDiazJr/status/1616565048767385601">concerns</a> it had with the pilot, an early version of a course.</p>
<p>In February, the College Board released its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/college-board-changes-to-black-studies-unrelated-to-politics/6950243.html">first official version</a> of the AP course. It did not contain several subjects on the list of Florida's concerns, including Black Lives Matter, slavery <strong>reparations</strong> and several important Black writers.</p>
<p>The board was then widely criticized for giving in to political pressure. The new changes pay attention to some of that criticism.</p>
<p><strong>Changes in the latest version</strong></p>
<p>The latest version includes several important Black writers that were excluded, and written works about feminism and intersectionality. Intersectionality is the idea that race, gender, and class combine to create different levels of discrimination and <strong>privilege </strong>in society.</p>
<p>The College Board did not add back every subject that was removed earlier. The Black Lives Matter movement is still not included in the final test for the course. However, it is mentioned along with other examples and listed among subjects that schools could choose from for further discussion.</p>
<p>Nelva Williams is a member of the course's development committee. She has been a teacher for more than 40 years. She also taught a pilot class of AP African American Studies in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>Williams said, "The updates are based on teacher <strong>recommendations</strong>, and changes <strong>coincide</strong> with the latest scholarship and resources used at the collegiate level."</p>
<p>Rashad Shabazz teaches several courses related to race at Arizona State University. He said the course provides students with the basics to understand the field of African-American studies. But it does not contain in-depth theoretical discussions that are more common at the college level.</p>
<p>Next year, the AP course will be available to all schools in the U.S. But it remains unclear how many will offer it. Holly Stepp, a spokesperson for the College Board, said they are pleased with the interest that has been expressed in the course.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Cheyanne Mumphrey reported this story for the Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>course</strong>—<em>n</em>. a plan of study on an exact subject that includes many classes and usually leads to a test</p>
<p><strong>redlining</strong>—<em>n</em>. discrimination in housing<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>reparations</strong><em>–n.</em> something given, usually money, in recognition of loss, suffering, abuse or injury</p>
<p><strong>privilege</strong>—<em>n</em>. a special right or better position given or available only to an identified person or group</p>
<p><strong>recommendation</strong>—<em>n</em>. suggestion</p>
<p><strong>coincide</strong>—<em>v</em>. happen during the same time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US College Closings Worry Educators  (2023/12/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-college-closings-worry-educators.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>American higher education experts are concerned that small colleges closed at a high rate in 2023. They say college closures can prevent students from finishing their study programs and take away some of the country's <strong>unique</strong> education offerings.</p>
<p>The website HigherEd Dive notes 26 American colleges and universities either closed or announced their plans to close in 2023. About half that number closed or announced their closing in 2022.</p>
<p>The colleges that closed this year were privately <strong>funded</strong> and mostly small. They were facing a loss of money and a drop in student numbers. Some schools closed completely, while others combined with nearby schools. Most offered students a chance to finish their study programs or move on to another school nearby.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Jimmy Fallon attends the College of Saint Rose graduation in 2009. The college will close in May 2024 after years of financial struggles, officials said. (AP Photo/Hans Pennink, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fb5af0fc-a7f1-4b08-b4e7-0b520dabdc3d_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Jimmy Fallon attends the College of Saint Rose graduation in 2009. The college will close in May 2024 after years of financial struggles, officials said. (AP Photo/Hans Pennink, File)</span></div>
<p>Although the schools made efforts to assist their students, professors and others who worked at the colleges lost their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>A small college in New York</strong></p>
<p>Alliance University in New York state is one of the schools that closed this year.</p>
<p>The university was started by Christian <strong>missionaries</strong> in New York City in 1880. It offered mostly religious study programs until the 1960s and 1970s, when it expanded to offer programs in education and business.</p>
<p>At one point, the university had close to 3,000 students. But the publication Inside Higher Ed reports that the number had dropped below 2,000 in recent years.</p>
<p>The school had a budget shortfall of many millions of dollars that it could not make up. After an <strong>accreditor</strong> reviewed the school's situation last summer, the university announced its plan to close. An accreditor is a group that permits colleges and universities to operate.</p>
<p>Heather Garcia worked at the school for many years. She also took classes and earned two science degrees there. She said the university asked the accreditor for more time to improve its finances. However, the group decided the school's plan was not strong enough.</p>
<p>She said the school was going "deeper into debt each year." Garcia also noted that the student population continued to drop after the start of the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020.</p>
<p>The school knew it was in trouble. It had started new professional training programs in an effort to attract more students. It had also tried to cut spending. But the decision still came as a surprise.</p>
<p>Some students were able to finish their study programs over the summer. But others needed to move to new schools. Garcia said she felt <strong>especially</strong> bad for new students and for those who had come to play on the school's sports teams.</p>
<p>The school's last day was August 31.</p>
<p><strong>Concerns for the future</strong></p>
<p>The State Higher Education Executive Officers Association, or SHEEO, <strong>advocates</strong> for higher education in the U.S. Last year, the organization produced a report that looked at students affected by college closures. The report covered 467 schools that closed between 2004 and 2020.</p>
<p>The major concern of SHEEO is that students whose studies get interrupted by a closure often do not go on to graduate. More than half of students do not continue with their studies. Among those who do, only about 37 percent finish their degree.</p>
<p>In some cases, students do not get their school fees returned. In other cases, students have trouble getting their school records to send to other universities.</p>
<p>SHEEO's report asked that states require colleges to help with these concerns if they close, and said colleges should avoid sudden closures.</p>
<p>In 2021, The Hechinger Report noted that students whose schools combine with others also face similar problems.</p>
<p>Observers will be watching what happens with the College of Saint Rose in Albany, New York. The small school recently announced a plan to close in May 2024. An accreditation group said it was concerned about the college's finances for the 2024-2025 school year.</p>
<p>The school has been losing money since 2013. It lost $11 million in 2020. Cuts to study programs and changes in leadership did not put the school on a better path.</p>
<p><strong>What comes next?</strong></p>
<p>Bryan Alexander is a writer and researcher whose work centers on the future of higher education.</p>
<p>He said the small school closures could lead to a "one-size fits all" style of higher education. That style, he said, may not be suitable for students who have learning troubles or special interests in art, music or language.</p>
<p>Alexander said a government push for Americans to go to college that started in the 1980s, combined with a large population of college-aged young adults, helped many small colleges stay open. But now, he said, the costs of college are high, there are fewer college-aged people, and some people are questioning the value of college.</p>
<p>The first signs that a college is in danger come when there are reductions in study programs and changes "behind the scenes." Alexander was asked if this year's high number of closures is cause for alarm in higher education.</p>
<p>"I think, within higher ed, the alarm has already been sounded. Presidents, Deans, Provosts. This is the stuff that keeps them up at nights."</p>
<p>Alexander noted that the U.S. is unusual when compared to the rest of the world. The country has a lot of small schools with special study programs. He noted Oberlin College in Ohio and Wesleyan University in Connecticut, but there are many more.</p>
<p>In many other countries, universities are generally not smaller than 10,000 students.</p>
<p>"You know, all these little small colleges, and they're really special. They're <strong>delightful</strong>. But they're <strong>fragile</strong>. They don't have economies of scale."</p>
<p>Economy of scale is a reference to the lower cost of a service per person at a large university when compared to a small college. The cost to provide a study program is much higher per student at a small college.</p>
<p>Large American universities with financial problems, such as West Virginia University, are usually able to make changes and continue to stay open. That is because they receive government support.</p>
<p>"State governments don't want to close the state university," Alexander said. "When we see that happen, that will be <strong>a big deal</strong>."</p>
<p>Garcia, who worked at and attended Alliance, said observers may not see her school closing as a large loss in the same way they would if a famous school closed. But for the people who went to school and worked there, she said: "it is deeply painful."</p>
<p>"It really just felt special. It felt like we had just this little special <strong>niche</strong> there in the bottom corner of New York City...and that what we were doing was making an impact on the whole world because we would send, you know, we have <strong>alumni</strong> all over the world."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>unique </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>something different from everything else</p>
<p><strong>fund</strong> <em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to provide money for something</p>
<p><strong>missionary </strong><em>– n. </em>a religious worker who travels to talk about and convert people to their religion</p>
<p><strong>accreditor </strong><em>– n. </em>an organization that checks the credentials of a school and determines if they have permission to operate</p>
<p><strong>especially </strong><em>– adv. </em>a word used to indicate that something deserves extra attention</p>
<p><strong>advocate </strong><em>– n. </em>a person or organization that supports a cause</p>
<p><strong>delightful </strong><em>– adj. </em>a word used to describe something that is special, fun or exciting</p>
<p><strong>fragile </strong><em>– adj. </em>something easily hurt or broken</p>
<p><strong>a big deal </strong><em>– n. </em>something that is very important or hard to believe</p>
<p><strong>niche </strong><em>– n. </em>something that has a unique position, unlike others</p>
<p><strong>missionary </strong><em>– n. </em>a religious worker who travels to talk about and convert people to their religion</p>
<p><strong>alumni </strong><em>– n. </em>(plural) people who attended a schoo</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI, Hallucinate, Authentic or Rizz for Word of the Year  (2023/12/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/ai-hallucinate-authentic-or-rizz-for-word-of-the-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>As the year 2023 comes to a close, English language dictionary publishers are announcing their choices for word of the year. The words usually come from popular usage, news events, or things that are on people's minds.</p>
<p><strong>AI</strong></p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.collinsdictionary.com/woty"><em>Collins</em></a>, a British publisher, has named "AI" as its word of the year for 2023. AI, short for artificial intelligence, is a term that describes "the modeling of human mental functions by computer programs."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - AI (Artificial Intelligence) letters are placed on a computer motherboard in this illustration taken, June 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f867-08dbefab3987_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - AI (Artificial Intelligence) letters are placed on a computer motherboard in this illustration taken, June 23, 2023. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>AI is increasingly becoming a part of everyday life. Just this year, the Beatles released a song with help from AI. The American toy company Mattel now uses AI to design new toy cars. A Kuwaiti news organization used AI to create "Fedha", a female presenter to read the news. AI has also been used to identify an asteroid that could one day present a threat to Earth.</p>
<p>One of the best-known AI programs is ChatGPT. The program can have a discussion with people, write books, and create images. The program learns from a large database of books, online materials, and other media.</p>
<p>It can produce human-like writing. But, sometimes, its writings are not correct or do not make sense. When artificial intelligence produces such information, people say that the program has "hallucinated."</p>
<p><strong>Hallucinate</strong></p>
<p>The British dictionary publisher <a class="wsw__a" href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/editorial/woty"><em>Cambridge</em></a> chose "hallucinate" as its word of the year. It says the word "gets to the heart of why people are talking about AI."</p>
<p>To "hallucinate" means to seem to see, hear, feel, or smell something that does not exist. But when used in connection to AI, it means to produce false information.</p>
<p><em>Cambridge</em> says, "generative AI is a powerful tool but one that we're all still learning how to interact with safely and effectively." The publisher adds that "AI hallucinations remind us that humans still need to bring their critical thinking skills to use these tools."</p>
<p><strong>Authentic</strong></p>
<p>The American publisher <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/wordplay/word-of-the-year"><em>Merriam-Webster</em></a><em> </em>chose "authentic" as its word of the year.</p>
<p><em>Merriam-Webster</em> says it has seen a major rise in searches for "authentic" in 2023. The publisher says the searches are driven by "stories and conversations about AI, <strong>celebrity</strong> culture, identity, and social media."</p>
<p>Authentic has several meanings, including "not false," "true to one's own personality" and "made or done the same way as an <strong>original</strong>."</p>
<p>With the rise of artificial intelligence, <em>Merriam-Webster </em>says the line between "real" and "fake" has become increasingly unclear.</p>
<p>Other words <em>Merriam-Webster </em>considered include "deepfake," "<strong>coronation</strong>," "<strong>indict</strong>" and "rizz."</p>
<p><strong>Rizz</strong></p>
<p>The editors of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://corp.oup.com/news/rizz-crowned-oxford-word-of-the-year-2023/"><em>Oxford</em></a> dictionary left the selection for Word of the Year to language lovers.</p>
<p>Over 30,000 people voted and selected four finalists for word of the year. They were "Swiftie" (fans of Taylor Swift), "situationship" (an informal romantic or sexual relationship), "prompt" (an instruction given to an artificial intelligence program), and "rizz."</p>
<p>If you are not familiar with "rizz," it is time to learn its meaning. It is <em>Oxford</em>'s word of the year. "Rizz" is believed to come from the word "charisma." <em>Oxford</em> says it means having "style, charm or attractiveness." It can also mean the "ability to attract a romantic or sexual partner." The word is popular among Generation Z -- people born during the late 1990s and early 2000s.</p>
<p>"Rizz" can be used as a verb, too. To "rizz up" means "to attract, <strong>seduce</strong>, or chat up (a person)."</p>
<p><em>Oxford </em>editors said they chose "rizz" as "an interesting example of how language can be formed, shaped, and shared within communities, before being picked up more widely in society."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>any of the small rocky celestial bodies found especially between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter</p>
<p><strong>celebrity</strong> <em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>a famous or celebrated person</p>
<p><strong>original </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to or being the origin or beginning</p>
<p><strong>coronation </strong><em>– n. </em>accession to the highest office</p>
<p><strong>indict </strong><em>– v. </em>to charge with a crime by the finding or presentment of a jury (such as a grand jury) in due form of law</p>
<p><strong>seduce </strong><em>– v. </em>to persuade to do wrong : to persuade to have sexual intercourse</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Works to Build World’s Largest Renewable Energy Project  (2023/12/9) | 印度致力于打造全球最大可再生能源项目</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/india-works-to-build-world-s-largest-renewable-energy-project.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>India is planning to launch the world's largest renewable energy project near the country's border with Pakistan.<br/>
印度正计划在该国与巴基斯坦边境附近启动世界上最大的可再生能源项目。</p>
<p>The term renewable describes energy produced from natural sources, such as sunlight or wind. These sources are considered renewable because they are continually produced in nature.<br/>
“可再生能源”一词是指由自然资源（如阳光或风能）产生的能源。这些资源被认为是可再生的，因为它们是在自然界中不断产生的。</p>
<p>The Indian effort would be so huge it could be seen from space. Officials say it will use solar and wind equipment to produce electricity.<br/>
该印度项目将是如此巨大，以至于可以从太空中看到。官方称其将使用太阳能和风能设备发电。</p>
<p>The project is named the Khavda Renewable Energy Park, after the closest village in the area.<br/>
该项目以该地区最近的村庄命名为“卡夫达可再生能源园区”。</p>
<p>Reporters from The Associated Press recently visited the project area. They reported that thousands of workers are taking part in building activities. Some workers placed pillars in the ground to hold panels to capture sunlight. The large pillars can be seen rising into the distance for as far as the eye can see.<br/>
美联社记者最近参观了该项目区域。他们报道说，成千上万的工人正在从事建筑活动。一些工人把柱子安装在地上，用来固定太阳能电池板以获取阳光。这些大柱子延伸至目光所能及的远方。</p>
<p>Other workers prepared parts of the ground to support large wind collectors, called turbines. Others were seen transporting building materials or running wiring over many kilometers.<br/>
其他工人在准备用于支撑大型涡轮机的基础部分。还能看到其他人在数公里外运输建筑材料或布线。</p>
<p>When completed, the project will be about the size of Singapore, spreading over 726 square kilometers. The Indian government estimates it will cost at least $2.26 billion.<br/>
该项目建成后占地726平方公里，相当于新加坡的面积。印度政府估计，这将花费至少22.6亿美元。</p>
<p>Leaders meeting at the COP28 climate conference in Dubai have said an expansion of renewable energy will be important as the world seeks to meet future environmental targets. Some leaders have said any final climate agreement must call for a tripling of renewable energy worldwide.<br/>
在迪拜举行的第二十八届联合国气候变化大会上，各国领导人表示，随着世界寻求实现未来的环境目标，扩大可再生能源将非常重要。一些领导人表示，任何最终的气候协议都必须要求全球可再生能源增加三倍。</p>
<p>In addition, environmental activists say major cuts must be made in the use of non-sustainable planet-warming energies, such as coal, oil and natural gas.<br/>
此外，环保活动人士表示，必须大幅削减煤炭、石油和天然气等不可持续、能导致全球变暖的能源的使用。</p>
<p>The Khavda project is being built in the middle of the Rann of Kutch, in India's western Gujarat state. The Rann is an extreme environment containing a salt desert and wetlands.<br/>
卡夫达项目正在印度西部的古吉拉特省库奇兰恩中部建造。库奇兰恩是一处包括盐沙漠和湿地的极端环境。</p>
<p>When AP reporters visited, two days of unseasonal heavy rains had left the ground muddy and wet. The only escape for water in the area is through evaporation. The rainy conditions made the jobs harder for the workers, the AP reported.<br/>
当美联社记者访问时，两天的非季节性暴雨使地面泥泞潮湿。该地区水的唯一出路是蒸发。据美联社报道，下雨的天气使工人们的工作更加困难。</p>
<p>An estimated 4,000 workers and 500 engineers have been living in camps over the past year to try to get the project up and running.<br/>
在过去的一年里，估计有4000名工人和500名工程师住在营地里，试图让项目启动并运行。</p>
<p>Once completed, it will supply 30 gigawatts of renewable energy each year. This would be enough to power nearly 18 million Indian homes.<br/>
一旦建成，它将每年提供30千兆瓦的可再生能源。这将足以为近1800万户印度家庭供电。</p>
<p>India is mostly powered by carbon fuels, especially coal. Coal produces about 70 percent of the nation's electricity. Renewable energy currently makes up just 10 percent of India's electricity needs.<br/>
印度主要依靠碳燃料，尤其是煤炭提供电力。煤炭生产的电力约占全国电力的70%。可再生能源目前仅占印度电力需求的10%。</p>
<p>The country is currently the third-largest polluter of planet-warming gases, behind China and the United States.<br/>
印度目前是全球变暖气体的第三大污染国，仅次于中国和美国。</p>
<p>KSRK Verma is the project leader for Adani Green Energy Limited. The Indian government has contracted with the company to build 20 gigawatts of the project. Verma has 35 years of experience in the industry. He called the Khavda project one of the most difficult he has ever led.<br/>
维尔马是阿达尼绿色能源有限公司的项目负责人。印度政府已与该公司签订合同建造其中20千兆瓦的项目。维尔马拥有35年的行业经验。他称卡夫达项目是他负责过的最困难的项目之一。</p>
<p>"It's not at all (an) easy site to work at," he said. He noted the area's severe conditions, including high winds, heavy rains and earthquake activity.<br/>
他说：“这不是一个容易工作的地方。”他提到了该地区的恶劣条件，包括大风、暴雨和地震活动。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rock Group Ends Live Concerts, Becomes Computerized Avatars  (2023/12/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/rock-group-ends-live-concerts-becomes-computerized-avatars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Recently, members of the American rock band Kiss closed out their final performance. The group's "The End of the Road" <strong>concert</strong> series ended in New York City's famous Madison Square Garden.</p>
<p>But as it turns out, fans will still be able to enjoy Kiss performances for years to come.</p>
<p>The band formed in 1973. It is currently made up of founders Paul Stanley and Gene Simmons, as well as Tommy Thayer and Eric Singer. Towards the end of Saturday's show, the band members left the stage and <strong>revealed</strong> computerized likenesses of themselves. The computerized <strong>avatars</strong> launched into a performance of the song "God Gave Rock and Roll to You."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gene Simmons, left, Tommy Thayer and Paul Stanley of KISS perform during the final night of the Kiss Farewell Tour on Saturday, Dec. 2, 2023, at Madison Square Garden in New York. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7ab7da4f-f61f-4895-8da8-93c4dcd6ee61_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Gene Simmons, left, Tommy Thayer and Paul Stanley of KISS perform during the final night of the "Kiss Farewell Tour" on Saturday, Dec. 2, 2023, at Madison Square Garden in New York. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>After 50 years of Kiss, the band now hopes to be remembered forever.</p>
<p>The avatars were created by George Lucas' special-effects company Industrial Light &amp; Magic. The company also worked with Pophouse Entertainment Group. Bjorn Ulvaeus, a member of the Swedish musical group ABBA, is its founder.</p>
<p>The two companies recently came together for the "ABBA Voyage" show in London. Fans there could enjoy a full concert by the Swedish band as performed by the computerized avatars.</p>
<p>Per Sundin is chief executive officer of Pophouse Entertainment. He said the new technology lets Kiss continue its history for "<strong>eternity</strong>."</p>
<p>He said the band was not on stage during the computerized performance. He added, "Kiss could have a concert in three cities in the same night across three different continents. That's what you could do with this."</p>
<p>In order to create their computerized avatars, Kiss performed in equipment that followed their movement. This equipment is called motion capture suits.</p>
<p>Experimentation with this kind of technology has become increasingly common in the music industry. In October, K-pop star Mark Tuan partnered with Soul Machines to create a computerized version of himself called "Digital Mark." The technology lets fans have one-on-one talks with Digital Mark. Tuan is the first famous person to attach their likeness to OpenAI's GPT artificial intelligence technology.</p>
<p>Aespa is a K-pop girl group. The group often performs alongside their computerized avatars. In fact, the four-member band is meant to be seen as a group of eight.</p>
<p>Another girl group, Eternity, is made up entirely of computerized performers. No humans are necessary.</p>
<p>Kiss performer Paul Stanley told reporters that what they have done "... has been <strong>amazing</strong>, but it's not enough. The band<strong> deserves</strong> to live on because the band is bigger than we are."</p>
<p>"We can be forever young and forever <strong>iconic</strong> by taking us to places we've never dreamed of before," Kiss performer Gene Simmons added. "The technology is going to make Paul jump higher than he's ever done before."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Sherman reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>concert </strong>– <em>n</em>. a public performance of music</p>
<p><strong>revealed </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make (something) known</p>
<p><strong>avatar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a small picture that represents a computer user in a game or on the Internet</p>
<p><strong>eternity </strong>– <em>n</em>. time without an end</p>
<p><strong>amazing </strong>– <em>adj</em>. causing great surprise or wonder</p>
<p><strong>deserve </strong>– <em>v</em>. used to say that someone or something should or should not have or be given something</p>
<p><strong>iconic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. being a famous person or thing that people admire and see as a symbol of a particular idea or way of life</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ability or Capability?  (2023/12/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/ability-or-capability.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the difference between the words "ability" and "capability."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA <em>Ask a Teacher</em>,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9123-08dbf73fdce2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am Lyla from China. I am <strong>confused</strong> about "ability" and "capability." I looked them up in the dictionary, but I still can't tell them apart.</p>
<p>Can you explain the difference?</p>
<p>Thanks, and best regards,</p>
<p>Lyla</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for your question, Lyla. The words are so similar that their use can even trouble native English speakers! Generally, ability describes special skills and qualities now in use. "Capability" speaks more to the possible power or use of those skills and qualities.</p>
<p>Let's take a closer look at each.</p>
<p><strong>Ability</strong></p>
<p>"Ability" is a noun that comes from the adjective "able." If you are "able," you can do something. You can carry out an action. "Ability" means a quality, skill, or <strong>aptitude</strong> that you have that makes it possible for you to do something. Compare these sentences:</p>
<p><em> I have the ability to speak Russian and English. </em></p>
<p><em>Courtney's disabilities are the result of a car accident. </em></p>
<p><em>Henry's cooking abilities increased over years of practice in his own home.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "capability."</p>
<p><strong>Capability</strong></p>
<p>"Capability" is the quality or state of being capable. "To be capable" means having qualities or skills to successfully perform some future action. Your "capability" depends more on the situation, environment, or your desire to do something rather than just your ability to do it.</p>
<p><em>He has the capability of lifting very heavy weights, but he injured himself last year, so he chooses to lift light weights while he recovers. </em></p>
<p>"Capability" also can mean a skill set that can be further developed.</p>
<p><em>The new employees have strong capabilities in marketing. They just need more experience in the business world. </em></p>
<p>Finally, "capability" is the possibility to be affected by use or treatment.</p>
<p><em>The movie Oppenheimer is about the development of the United States' nuclear capabilities and eventual use of those weapons.</em></p>
<p><em>Critics question the administration's capability to compromise on a solution.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Lyla.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>confused</strong> –adj. lost or unsure of something</p>
<p><strong>aptitude</strong> <em>— n</em>. the ability to learn something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Technology Industry Divided over How to Govern AI Development  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/technology-industry-divided-over-how-to-govern-ai-development.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Technology leaders have shown major support for laws to govern artificial intelligence use. At the same time, they are seeking to guarantee that any future AI rules work in their favor.</p>
<p>The technology industry is increasingly divided about how to govern AI. One side supports an "open science" method to AI development; the other supports a closed method.</p>
<p>Facebook parent Meta and IBM recently launched a new group called the AI Alliance. The group supports the "open science" method of AI development. On the other side are companies such as Google, Microsoft and ChatGPT-maker OpenAI.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai speaks about Google DeepMind at a Google I/O event in Mountain View, Calif., May 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9928c3fd-329b-4073-8655-13e3ea0dc824_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai speaks about Google DeepMind at a Google I/O event in Mountain View, Calif., May 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)</span></div>
<p>Safety is at the heart of the debate. But, tech leaders are also arguing about who should profit from AI developments.</p>
<p><strong>What is open-source AI?</strong></p>
<p>The term "open-source" comes from a common method of building software in which the code is widely available at no cost. Anyone can examine and make changes to it.</p>
<p>Open-source AI involves more than just code. Computer scientists differ on how to define "open source." They say the identifications are dependent on which parts of the technology are publicly available and if there are restrictions on use.</p>
<p>Some computer scientists use the term "open science" to describe the wider philosophy.</p>
<p>IBM and Meta lead the AI Alliance. Members include Dell, Sony, chipmakers AMD and Intel, and several universities and smaller AI companies. The alliance is coming together to say "that the future of AI is going to be built ... on top of the open scientific exchange of ideas and on open <strong>innovation</strong>, including open source and open technologies," said Darío Gil of IBM. Gil made the comment in a discussion with The Associated Press.</p>
<p><strong>Concerns about open-source AI</strong></p>
<p>Part of the confusion about open-source AI is that the company that built ChatGPT and the image-generator DALL-E is called OpenAI. But its AI systems are closed.</p>
<p>"There are near-term and commercial <strong>incentives </strong>against open source," said Ilya Sutskever, OpenAI's chief scientist and co-founder, in a video with Stanford University in April.</p>
<p>But there is also a longer-term worry about the open development method. Sutskever noted one worry is that an AI system with powerful abilities could be too dangerous to make available to the public.</p>
<p>For example, he described a possible AI system that could learn how to start its own biological laboratory.</p>
<p>Even current AI models present risks. They could create disinformation campaigns, for example, said David Evan Harris of the University of California, Berkeley. Such campaigns could<strong> disrupt</strong> democratic elections, he said.</p>
<p>"Open source is really great in so many <strong>dimensions</strong> of technology," but AI is different, Harris said.</p>
<p>The Center for Humane Technology, a longtime critic of Meta's social media activities, is among the groups drawing attention to the risks of open-source or leaked AI models.</p>
<p>"As long as there are no <strong>guardrails</strong> in place right now, it's just completely irresponsible to be deploying these models to the public," said the group's Camille Carlton.</p>
<p><strong>Benefits and dangers</strong></p>
<p>An increasingly public debate has appeared over the good and bad of using an open-source method to AI development.</p>
<p>Meta's chief AI scientist, Yann LeCun, this fall criticized OpenAI, Google, and Anthropic on social media for what he described as "massive corporate lobbying." Le Cun argues that the companies are trying to write rules in a way that help their high-performing AI models and could help them hold their power over the technology's development. The three companies, along with OpenAI's key partner Microsoft, have formed their own industry group called the Frontier Model Forum.</p>
<p>LeCun said on X, formerly Twitter, "Openness is the only way to make AI platforms reflect the entirety of human knowledge and culture."</p>
<p>For IBM, the dispute feeds into a much longer competition that began before the AI boom. IBM was an early supporter of the open-source Linux operating system in the 1990s.</p>
<p>Chris Padilla leads IBM's international government affairs team. The companies are trying to raise fear about open-source innovation as they have in the past, he suggested.</p>
<p>He added, "I mean, this has been the Microsoft model for decades, right? They always opposed open-source programs that could compete with Windows or Office. They're taking a similar approach here."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Matt O'Brien reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>innovation</strong> <em>– n.</em> the act of introducing new ideas, devices, or methods</p>
<p><strong>incentive</strong> <em>– n.</em> something that encourages a person to do something</p>
<p><strong>disrupt</strong> <em>– v.</em> to interrupt the normal progress or activity of something</p>
<p><strong>dimension</strong> <em>– n.</em> a part of something</p>
<p><strong>guardrail</strong> <em>– n.</em> a protective device along the side of a road that prevents vehicles from driving off the road (can be used metaphorically)</p>
<p><strong>lobby</strong><em> – v.</em> to try to influence government officials to make decisions for or against something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Hanukkah Is Celebrated around the World  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-hanukkah-is-celebrated-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hanukkah (also written as Chanukah) is Judaism's "<strong>festival</strong> of lights." On eight straight nights, Jews come together with family and friends at the end of daylight to light one additional <strong>candle</strong> in the menorah.</p>
<p>A menorah is a lamp or candle holder used in Jewish religious ceremonies. It usually has eight branches, with a ninth place for the candle called shamash from which all the others are lit.</p>
<p>In Hebrew, Hanukkah means "<strong>dedication</strong>."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An Ultra-Orthodox Jewish man stands in front of a menorah on the third eve of Hanukkah, at the Western Wall, Judaism's holiest site in Jerusalem's old city on December 13, 2009. (AP Photo/Sebastian Scheiner, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/91867a88-114c-467a-a11f-6be7ffeb1480_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An Ultra-Orthodox Jewish man stands in front of a menorah on the third eve of Hanukkah, at the Western Wall, Judaism's holiest site in Jerusalem's old city on December 13, 2009. (AP Photo/Sebastian Scheiner, File)</span></div>
<p>The holiday marks the rededication of the Temple in Jerusalem about 2500 years ago. That was the time a small group of Jewish fighters took it back from occupying foreign forces. The fighters found a very small supply of oil in the religious building, or temple, and used it to keep a menorah lit for eight days. Their practice of lighting a nightly candle and cooking foods like potato pancakes called latkes, serve to remember the event.</p>
<p><strong>When is Hanukkah 2023?</strong></p>
<p>The dates of the holiday are based on the Hebrew month of Kislev, which usually falls sometime in November or December in the Gregorian calendar.</p>
<p>This year, Hanukkah is being celebrated from December 7 through December 15.</p>
<p><strong>Do Hanukkah celebrations differ?</strong></p>
<p>There are different branches of Judaism, like Reform, Conservative and Orthodox. But they all celebrate the holiday by bringing light into the darkness and remembering that even a small and unlikely-to-succeed effort can make great change.</p>
<p>The Talmud is Judaism's central religious book. Within it, there is a dispute over the order of lighting. But even with that dispute, most start with one candle and increase the lighting by one more candle each night while saying religious <strong>blessings</strong>.</p>
<p>The candles are added from right to left, but lit from left to right on the menorah, thus always starting with the newest light.</p>
<p>The tradition calls for candles with a real<strong> flame</strong>. But some also use electric ones in public areas, such as in hospitals, for safety reasons.</p>
<p><strong>How is Hanukkah celebrated?</strong></p>
<p>A menorah is lit in each household and traditionally is placed where it can be seen from the outside, such as a doorway or near a window. It represents the spreading of God's light to all nations.</p>
<p>The lighting of menorahs in city streets and public areas, like parks or areas of interest, has become more common in recent years in countries around the world.</p>
<p>In addition to menorah lightings, giving money to those in need and social works are also part of the celebration for many. This comes out of the belief that the Jewish people are called by God to help make the world better for all.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Giovanna Dell'Orto</em><em> reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>festival </strong>– <em>n</em>. a special time or event when people gather to celebrate something</p>
<p><strong>candle </strong>– <em>n</em>. wax that has been formed into a stick or another shape and has a string in the middle that can be burned</p>
<p><strong>dedication </strong>– <em>v</em>. to officially make (something) a place for honoring or remembering a person or event</p>
<p><strong>blessing </strong>– <em>n</em>.<strong> </strong>a short prayer</p>
<p><strong>flame </strong>– <em>n</em>. the hot, glowing gas that can be seen when a fire is burning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Studies Possible Change to Safer Nuclear Fuel  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-studies-possible-change-to-safer-nuclear-fuel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Documents show that a U.S. research program is making progress on its goal to use a safer kind of fuel for nuclear-powered Navy submarines and military ships. But the program's governmental financial support is at risk.</p>
<p>The aim of the research is to change from using highly-<strong>enriched</strong> uranium, which can be used to make bombs, to a safer choice.</p>
<p>Since 2018, the U.S. government has been exploring how to use low-enriched fuel that cannot be used as an explosive in weapons. It is doing this to help decrease the proliferation risks of keeping stores of highly-enriched uranium.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The U.S. nuclear-powered submarine USS Annapolis is anchored at a naval base on Jeju Island, South Korea, July 24, 2023. (The Defense Ministry/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e78e1538-b8cb-4e91-8af0-48022f351059_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The U.S. nuclear-powered submarine USS Annapolis is anchored at a naval base on Jeju Island, South Korea, July 24, 2023. (The Defense Ministry/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>Proliferation means a fast increase in the amount of something. Nuclear proliferation is the spread of nuclear weapons or materials that can be used to make nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>The National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) sent a report to the U.S. Congress last year. It said the research program progressed from a planning stage to an experimental campaign stage during the 2021 <strong>fiscal</strong> year. It added that early findings represent progress in what could be a 20- to 25-year design effort.</p>
<p>The documents were recently seen by Reuters reporters.</p>
<p>The issue of highly-enriched uranium is critical because of a defense technology partnership between the U.S., Australia and Britain. The $245-billion partnership, called AUKUS, permits the sale of U.S. nuclear-powered submarines. It also permits the sharing of nuclear-<strong>propulsion</strong> technology with Australia. The partnership is in answer to China's growing power in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Non-proliferation experts say sending submarines to Australia that use highly-enriched uranium could lead to other countries using the fuel.</p>
<p>The NNSA document said the low-enriched uranium fuel program seeks to meet certain U.S. Navy requirements. The document added that the fuel development process would be long and costly. Success, it said, is not guaranteed.</p>
<p>The document also noted a 2016 report's findings that it could cost more than $1 billion to develop <strong>alternative</strong> fuel. That report also said low-enriched fuel would hurt <strong>reactor</strong> strength, ship costs and operational effectiveness.</p>
<p>The NNSA's 2022 report warned the costs could take away from the higher aim of non-proliferation and naval propulsion research and development.</p>
<p>Still, head of the NNSA Jill Hruby said in the document she was pleased with progress the program has made in this difficult effort.</p>
<p>NNSA did not immediately respond to questions about the documents when asked by Reuters.</p>
<p>Congress has given the program $100 million since 2016. But governmental financial support is in question after a group in the Republican-controlled House of Representatives this year voted to stop it. The Senate has approved financial support and the Senate and House of Representatives are expected to work together to decide on any <strong>funding</strong>.</p>
<p>Alan Kuperman is a professor at the University of Texas at Austin. He works at the Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Project. He has pushed the government to accept low-enriched uranium for Navy ships.</p>
<p>Kuperman also looked at the documents from NNSA. He said the documents make three things clear. First, the program is very important in preventing the spread of nuclear weapons. Second, it is making quick progress. And third, it will go into use only if it can keep the current performance of U.S. Navy ships.</p>
<p>He said the possible $1-billion cost for the fuel was small compared to trillions of dollars spent on all the Navy's nuclear ships.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Timothy Gardner reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>enrich </strong>– <em>v</em>. to improve the quality of (something)</p>
<p><strong>fiscal </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to money and especially to the money a government, business, or organization earns, spends, and owes</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong>– <em>n</em>. the force that moves something forward</p>
<p><strong>alternative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not usual or traditional</p>
<p><strong>reactor </strong>– <em>n</em>. a large device that produces nuclear energy</p>
<p><strong>fund </strong>– <em>v</em>. to provide money for (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reviewing Pet Descriptions  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/reviewing-pet-descriptions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A few weeks ago, we asked our readers and listeners to describe their pets. We asked them to practice using <strong>multiple</strong> adjectives in a certain order. One reader, Maria from Argentina, wrote to us about her dog, Ceferina.</p>
<p>In this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will <strong>review</strong> Maria's message describing her dog. And we will give some grammar suggestions.</p>
<p><strong>Maria's Message about her Pet</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5e22-08dbf6776a4c_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p><em>I have five dogs, three cats and one<strong> rooster</strong>. I love animals very much but I am going to describe only one of them. My female dog called Ceferina. She is a senior big dog. </em></p>
<p><em>I meet her at the street. She was very ill and sad. Now is a <strong>cute</strong> dog. </em></p>
<p><em>Her colors is black and her eyes brown. She is a friendly dog. She looks like brave but she is lovely dog. </em></p>
<p><strong>Review of Maria's message</strong></p>
<p>Let's start with the first two sentences.</p>
<p><em>I have five dogs, three cats and one rooster. I love animals very much but I am going to describe only one of them.</em></p>
<p>These two sentences are almost perfect. Maria uses number adjectives to describe how many pets she has. Maria has nine pets total! She then says that she will only choose one.</p>
<p>We suggest adding "my" before "animals" because Maria then refers to her animals as "them" in the second half of the sentence. The choice "my" is a more specific choice. We also suggest adding a comma before "but" to separate the two clauses.</p>
<p><em>I love my animals very much, but I am going to describe only one of them.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto the next two sentences.</p>
<p><em>My female dog called Ceferina. She is a senior big dog. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, Maria describes the <strong>gender </strong>of the dog. We recommend adding "is" before "called." This is a <strong>passive</strong> sentence, so we must use a form of "be" plus the verb in the past participle form.</p>
<p><em>My female dog is called Ceferina.</em></p>
<p>The next sentence has two adjectives: "senior" and "big." This is where we should pay attention to the order of adjectives. When we use two or more adjectives from different categories, we must order them a certain way in the sentence.</p>
<p>The order of the adjective categories is as follows: quantity, opinion, size, age, shape or length, color, <strong>origin, </strong>material, and purpose.</p>
<p>We recommend changing the order of the adjectives "senior" and "big" based on the order of adjectives rule. Size adjectives come before age adjectives.</p>
<p><em>She is a big senior dog.</em></p>
<p>Note that we do not need a comma between the adjectives because these are cumulative adjectives. In other words, they build on each other. They are from different adjective categories so they cannot be separated by a comma.</p>
<p>Let's look at the next few sentences.</p>
<p><em>I meet her at the street. She was very ill and sad. Now is a cute dog. </em></p>
<p>First, instead of "meet," you can use the verb "find" to say that you first discovered or saw your dog. You should use the past tense of "find" because you are talking about a time in the past.</p>
<p>Next, we suggest changing the preposition "at" to either the preposition "in" or "on."</p>
<p>"In the street" means that you found her in the middle of the street. "In" is used for talking about an enclosed space. "On the street" means that you found her somewhere along the street. "On" is used for general location.</p>
<p>Maria did a great job separating the adjectives "ill" and "sad" with the conjunction "and." These are opinion adjectives and carry equal importance in the sentence. This makes them coordinating adjectives, so we can use "and" or only a comma to separate them. We can also change their order and keep the same meaning.</p>
<p>In the next sentence, we need a subject. We can use the pronoun "she." We also suggest adding a comma after "now."</p>
<p><em>I found her on the street. She was very ill and sad. Now, she is a cute dog. </em></p>
<p>And finally, we have the last three sentences.</p>
<p><em>Her colors is black and her eyes brown. She is a friendly dog. She looks like brave but she is lovely dog. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, we have some subject-verb agreement issues. Since Maria's dog is black, "color" can be singular.</p>
<p>We need the verb "are" in the second half of that sentence to go after "eyes."</p>
<p><em>Her color is black and her eyes are brown. </em></p>
<p>Finally, in the last sentence we suggest a different word for "brave." We want another word that is the opposite of "lovely." We could say that Ceferina looks "fierce," which is like "brave" and "intense" combined.</p>
<p>We can also remove "like" because we are not making a comparison, just a contrast. And finally, we need to add the indefinite article "a" before dog.</p>
<p><em>She looks fierce, but she is a lovely dog. </em></p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today, we looked at Maria's message about her dog, Ceferina. We talked about the order of adjectives, commas, and subject verb agreement. We learned about coordinating and cumulative adjectives and their connection to the order of adjectives.</p>
<p>Thank you, Maria, for telling us about Ceferina! We are happy she found such a loving home.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Mateo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in the Story</h2>
<p><strong>rooster</strong> – <em>n.</em> an adult male chicken</p>
<p><strong>cute </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having a pleasing, youthful appearance</p>
<p><strong>gender </strong>– <em>n.</em><strong> </strong>the state of being male or female</p>
<p><strong>passive </strong><em>– adj. the quality of not being active or not taking action and letting things happen</em></p>
<p><strong>origin </strong>–<em> n. </em>the place that a person or thing comes from</p>
<p><strong>clause </strong>– <em>n</em>. (grammar) a part of a sentence that has its own subject and verb</p>
<p> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: 2023 Would Be Warmest Year on Record  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/scientists-2023-would-be-warmest-year-on-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>European Union scientists said on Wednesday that 2023 would be the warmest year on record. The average world temperature for the first 11 months of the year hit the highest level on record, 1.46 degrees Celsius above the 1850 to 1900 average.</p>
<p>The record comes as governments are in negotiations at the COP28 meeting in Dubai. Governments are deciding whether to gradually stop the use of coal, oil and gas, the main source of warming <strong>emissions</strong>.</p>
<p>The temperature for the January to November period was 0.13 degrees higher than the average for the same period in 2016, currently the warmest calendar year on record. That information comes from the Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S).</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A person rests under an umbrella as the sun sets, Sept. 12, 2023, in Newport Beach, Calif. European Union scientists said 2023 would be the warmest year on record. (AP Photo/Ryan Sun, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9a496d05-7fb3-43ad-a654-d987de31a7e9_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A person rests under an umbrella as the sun sets, Sept. 12, 2023, in Newport Beach, Calif. European Union scientists said 2023 would be the warmest year on record. (AP Photo/Ryan Sun, File)</span></div>
<p>November 2023 was the warmest November on record worldwide. The average surface air temperature was 14.22 degrees, 0.85 degrees above the 1991 to 2020 average for November. It was 0.32 degrees above the previous warmest November, in 2020, C3S added.</p>
<p>Samantha Burgess is deputy director of C3S. She said in a statement that the "November temperatures, including two days warmer than 2C above <strong>preindustrial</strong>, mean that 2023 is the warmest year in recorded history."</p>
<p>The autumn in the Northern Hemisphere from September to November was also the warmest on record by a large amount. The average temperature was 15.3 degrees, 0.88 degrees above average, EU scientists said.</p>
<p>The 2015 Paris climate agreement set a goal of limiting worldwide temperature rise to 1.5 degrees above pre-industrial times. Above that limit, scientists warn of severe effects on weather, health and agriculture.</p>
<p>Diplomats, scientists, activists and others have been meeting in Dubai to find ways to limit warming to those levels. But the planet is not cooperating. They say Earth is on its way to reach 2.7 to 2.9 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial times.</p>
<p>C3S records go back to 1940. United States government records go back to 1850. Using information from ice cores, tree rings and corals, scientists have said this is the warmest 10-year period Earth has seen in about 125,000 years. That dates back to the time before human civilization.</p>
<p>Scientists say there are two driving forces behind the six straight months of record hot temperatures. One is human-caused climate change from the burning of coal, oil and gas. And El Nino, the natural warming of surface waters in the Pacific, is making it worse.</p>
<p>"2023 is very likely to be a cool year in the future unless we do something about our dependence on <strong>fossil fuels</strong>," Burgess said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters and The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>preindustrial </strong><em>— adj. </em>relating to a time before industrialization</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>— n. </em>a fuel such as coal, oil, or natural gas that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>System Tested in US Can Charge Electric Vehicles as they Drive  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/system-tested-in-us-can-charge-electric-vehicles-as-they-drive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Officials in the American city of Detroit, Michigan, have equipped a piece of road with technology designed to charge electric vehicles (EVs) on the path.</p>
<p>The roadway is meant to serve as a demonstration project for the technology, which could be expanded to larger road systems. Leaders of the project say it is believed to be the country's first public wireless charging roadway built for EVs.</p>
<p>The system uses a series of copper wires placed underneath the road. These wires have the ability to send electricity through a magnetic field to charge an EV's battery. Charging can happen while the car is driving or sitting above the equipment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An electric van drives past a visible in-road wireless charging coil to be installed in a street in Detroit, Wednesday, Nov. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2fbd-08dbf4fc2697_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An electric van drives past a visible in-road wireless charging coil to be installed in a street in Detroit, Wednesday, Nov. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)</span></div>
<p>The technology was created by an Israeli company called Electreon, a developer of wireless charging solutions for EVs. The company currently has contracts to build similar roadways in Israel, Sweden, Italy and Germany.</p>
<p>Stefan Tongur is Electreon's vice president of business development. He told <em>The Associated Press</em> EVs require special equipment to receive the wireless signal. "The technology is smart," Tongur said, and "knows who you are..."</p>
<p>The system was recently demonstrated to the public at a technology development center in Detroit. The center seeks solutions to transportation issues facing cities. The effort, which includes several development projects, is where Ford Motor Company is building a factory to develop self-driving vehicles.</p>
<p>The electrified road stretches about one half-kilometer. It will be used to test and improve the technology in preparation for wider releases, said Michigan's Department of Transportation (<strong>DOT</strong>)<strong>.</strong></p>
<p>Tongur said the project aims to "demonstrate how wireless charging unlocks widespread EV <strong>adoption</strong>, addressing limited range, <strong>grid</strong> limitations, and battery size and costs."</p>
<p>He looks forward to a future in which, in his words, "EVs are the <strong>norm</strong>, not the exception."</p>
<p>Electreon says the electric road system is safe for people and animals walking over it and does not harm drivers.</p>
<p>Michigan's DOT signed a five-year agreement with Electreon to develop the roadway charging system. Officials have said they plan to build another electrified stretch of road in another part of the city.</p>
<p>American President Joe Biden is seeking to build a nationwide network of EV charging stations in the United States. His administration plans to establish at least a half-million sites along highways in the United States by 2030.</p>
<p>Michigan transportation officials say the wireless-charging roadway project has helped position the state and city of Detroit as national leaders in EV technology. "In Michigan, we want to stay <strong>ahead of the curve</strong>," Michigan DOT Director Bradley C. Wieferich told the <em>AP</em>. He added, "We want to lead the curve."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>adopt </strong><em>– v. </em>to accept or start using something</p>
<p><strong>grid </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of connected wires used to supply electrical power to large areas</p>
<p><strong>norm </strong><em>– n. </em>the usual way that something happens</p>
<p><strong>ahead of the curve </strong><em>– phr. </em>to have a deeper or developing understanding of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Venezuela’s Claims on Guyana’s Territory Raise Concerns  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/venezuela-s-claims-on-guyana-s-territory-raise-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Venezuela has increased pressure on its claim that the territory of Essequibo belongs to the country. However, the government of President Nicolás Maduro has little to no support from neighbors or intergovernmental organizations for the claim.</p>
<p>Essequibo is an area that makes up most of the South American country of Guyana, the neighbor to the east of Venezuela.</p>
<p>On Sunday, the Venezuelan government held a vote asking the Venezuelan people if they believed the country should declare Essequibo a Venezuelan state.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - View of Kaieteur, the world's largest single drop waterfall, located in the Potaro-Siparuni region of Guyana, on April 12, 2023. (Photo by Mart&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;237;n SILVA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d9356fc8-312b-4b83-be36-d00db18c681c_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - View of Kaieteur, the world's largest single drop waterfall, located in the Potaro-Siparuni region of Guyana, on April 12, 2023. (Photo by Mart<i>&amp;#</i>237;n SILVA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Despite media reports that showed nearly empty voting centers and other signs of low voter turnout, the Maduro government claimed that 10.5 million people voted. That is more than the last presidential election. Of those, it said 95 percent agreed in declaring Essequibo part of Venezuela.</p>
<p>The claim has been criticized by governments in both South America and the Caribbean. And there have been warnings from the International Court of Justice.</p>
<p>Last week, the court ruled that Venezuela must avoid taking any action which would change Guyana's current control of the territory.</p>
<p>In recent months, Venezuela has further increased <strong>tensions</strong> by deploying its military to the border with Guyana. And it has announced that it has plans to install a landing for planes in the area to provide support for the development of Essequibo.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, Guyana President Mohamed Irfaan Ali said his country does not plan to surrender any territory to Venezuelan control. And he called on the Maduro government to moderate its behavior.</p>
<p>Ali said to his countrymen, "I want to advise Venezuela that this is an <strong>opportunity</strong> for them to show <strong>maturity</strong>, an opportunity for them to show responsibility, and we call upon them once more [to] join us in ..." permitting the rule of law to work and to decide the outcome of these tensions.</p>
<p><strong>Publicity stunt gone wrong</strong></p>
<p>Christopher Sabatini works for Latin America at the London-based foreign policy group Chatham House. He told VOA that the vote in Venezuela had all the signs of a <strong>publicity stunt </strong>that got out of control. And it now threatens to turn into serious conflict.</p>
<p>Sabatini told VOA that the vote was mostly for those within the country, but the Maduro government has started something "... and we don't know where it's going to go."</p>
<p><strong>Roots of the dispute</strong></p>
<p>Essequibo is an area of 160,000 square kilometers with little development. It makes up the western two-thirds of Guyana, a country on South America's northern Atlantic coast.</p>
<p>The Venezuelan government has long claimed Essequibo. That is despite the fact that the area has been recognized by the international community, first as part of British Guiana and then as part of present-day Guyana, for more than 100 years.</p>
<p>The Venezuelan claim is largely based on the fact that during the colonial period, Essequibo and Venezuela were both administered by Spain. As part of a settlement reached by an international group, Essequibo was ruled to be part of British territory. All of modern-day Guyana gained independence in 1966.</p>
<p>The International Court of Justice is currently considering Venezuela's claim in a request brought forward by the Maduro government in 2018. But it is believed to be years away from issuing a decision.</p>
<p>The border dispute gained importance in 2015. That was after oil company ExxonMobil proved that there are billions of <strong>barrels </strong>worth of oil that could be reached off the coast of Essequibo in Guyana's territorial waters.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Rob Garver reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tension </strong>– <em>n</em>. a state in which people, groups, or countries disagree with and feel anger toward each other</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>– <em>n</em>. an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>maturity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the state of being fully developed in the body or the mind</p>
<p><strong>publicity stunt </strong>– <em>n</em>. something done just to get the attention of the public</p>
<p><strong>barrel </strong>– <em>n</em>. a unit of measurement of volume equal to 159 liters of oil</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Agency Aims to Remove Stray Cats from Puerto Rico’s Historic Fortress  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/agency-aims-to-remove-stray-cats-from-puerto-rico-s-historic-fortress.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The US National Park Service recently announced a plan to remove hundreds of <strong>stray</strong> cats that <strong>wander</strong> historic Old San Juan on the island of Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Local people and <strong>tourists</strong> consider the cats a joy, but some are bothered by them while others worry about disease.</p>
<p>There are about 200 cats that live on about 30 hectares surrounding the old <strong>fortress</strong> at the San Juan Historic Site. The U.S. federal agency operates the site because Puerto Rico is a territory of the United States.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A stray cat sits on a wall in Old San Juan, Puerto Rico, Wednesday, Nov. 2, 2022. The U.S. National Park Service has announced a plan to remove them. (AP Photo/Alejandro Granadillo, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/154d77e2-3cf5-4849-895f-21a7265619ab_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A stray cat sits on a wall in Old San Juan, Puerto Rico, Wednesday, Nov. 2, 2022. The U.S. National Park Service has announced a plan to remove them. (AP Photo/Alejandro Granadillo, File)</span></div>
<p>The park service said it will pay an animal <strong>welfare </strong>organization to remove the cats. If the organization does not remove the cats within six months, the park service said it will have the cats removed.</p>
<p>Cat lovers are disappointed with the plan. However, the agency said that the cats can spread diseases to humans. The plan said that the removal will be of value to visitors by reducing the possibility of disease.</p>
<p>Ana Maria Salicrup works for the nonprofit group Save a Gato. "Gato" is the Spanish word for "cat." The group has helped care for the cats for years and hopes the agency will choose it to do the work. However, Salicrup said that the six-month time limit is not realistic.</p>
<p>"Anyone who has worked with cats knows that is impossible. They are setting us up for failure," Salicrup said.</p>
<p>There are many different kinds of cats with different behaviors that wander along the fortress known as "El Morro" which was built in the 1500s. The fortress is by the ocean and the island's capital, San Juan.</p>
<p>The cats are believed to have come from the time when Puerto Rico was a colony of Spain. But some were brought to the capital to kill rats in the mid-1900s by Mayor Felisa Rincon de Gautier, the first female mayor elected in the Americas.</p>
<p>The cats have since increased in number over the years. Visitors to Old San Juan often take pictures with the cats, and residents and volunteers with Save a Gato take care of them. The group feeds, <strong>sterilizes</strong>, and places them for <strong>adoption</strong>.</p>
<p>Federal officials said two years ago that area was overpopulated with cats. The smell of waste and the behavior of the cats was "inconsistent with the cultural landscape," the agency said.</p>
<p>Last year, the National Park Service offered two possibilities during a public meeting: remove the animals or do nothing.</p>
<p>Those in attendance rejected removing the cats. One man described the cats as "one of the wonders of Old San Juan." The local people have even created a statue of the cats in the historic area.</p>
<p>Danna Wakefield works in the solar industry and moved to Puerto Rico in 2020. She visits the cats weekly. She told the Associated Press, "These cats are <strong>unique</strong> to San Juan. Me and many other people love that walk because of the cats."</p>
<p>In the removal plan, the agency said that cat feeding areas are to be removed unless they are used to trap cats. It said that feeding the cats is not permitted and attracts rats. Feeding the cats also causes people to leave their own unwanted cats in the area because they know their cats will be fed.</p>
<p>The plan says that the animal welfare organization that is chosen will be responsible for deciding whether the cats will be adopted, placed in a temporary home, kept in a shelter or destroyed.</p>
<p>The National Park Service said that the six-month time limit to trap the cats might be extended if progress is made. If that does not happen, then the current plan would end, and the service would pay for a removal agency.</p>
<p>Salicrup said finding a home for so many cats is difficult. Save a Gato has talked with animal shelters on the U.S. mainland. They are unwilling to take the cats.</p>
<p>"The response always is, 'You cannot bring 100 cats here,'" she said.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>Danica Coto <em>reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stray </strong>– <em>adj. </em>to describe going in a direction that is away from a group or from the place where you should be</p>
<p><strong>wander </strong>– <em>v. </em>to move from one place to another without a particular direction or destination</p>
<p><strong>tourist </strong>–n. a person who travels for pleasure and not for business</p>
<p><strong>fortress </strong>–n. a structure for defense against military attack</p>
<p><strong>welfare </strong><em>– n. </em>the state of being happy, healthy, or successful; well-being</p>
<p><strong>sterilize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make a living thing unable to produce children or offspring</p>
<p><strong>adopt </strong>–v. to legally take another person's child or pet as your own</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong><em> </em>– <em>adj</em>.<em> </em>used to say that something or someone is unlike anything or anyone else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Growing Plants to Save Australia's Koalas  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/growing-plants-to-save-australia-s-koalas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Lucy was rescued from a rural property in New South Wales, Australia, two years ago. She was suffering from chlamydia, a disease widespread among koalas.</p>
<p>Today, she is one of the lucky animals living in tree <strong>corridors</strong> that have been created to protect koalas and other animals by saving their quickly shrinking habitat, or natural environment.</p>
<p>The corridors, planted by the local conservation group Bangalow Koalas, are made up of large systems of plants. They are a lifeline for koalas and other animals like the glossy black cockatoo, gliders, possums, and wallabies. All of them are endangered, or at risk of becoming <strong>extinct</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Lucy, an adult female Koala sits in a eucalyptus tree planted by Bangalow Koalas in Australia. (Saul Goodwin/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a24f4482-d48d-424c-b0e6-3c2c373822c7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Lucy, an adult female Koala sits in a eucalyptus tree planted by Bangalow Koalas in Australia. (Saul Goodwin/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The corridors provide a safe path across the koala's increasingly broken habitat. This permits increased genetic mixing and protection from human threats.</p>
<p>"Our corridors are actually trying to get them away from humans, from cars, from dogs," said Linda Sparrow, president of Bangalow Koalas. "They can safely move across the <strong>landscape</strong> and not have to put up with us humans."</p>
<p>The koala is predicted to be extinct in the wild in New South Wales by 2050. Some of the biggest threats include wildfires and habitat loss through land clearing for development. Koalas have already been declared endangered in several Australian states.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019, Bangalow Koalas has planted over 336,000 trees on 119 properties, helping koala conservation and improving the local ecosystem. The group, which depends on community volunteers, aims to plant 500,000 trees by 2025.</p>
<p>"The neighbor would want to join and then another neighbor will want to join," Sparrow said, describing increasing the number of people involved in the corridor.</p>
<p>Volunteer Lindy Stacker, who has been planting trees for over five years, said the activity is good for mental health and has brought the community together.</p>
<p>A recent report by the Australian Koala Foundation said the animal was worth an estimated $3.2 billion per year to the <strong>tourism</strong> industry.</p>
<p>However, the World Wildlife Fund-Australia reported concerning declines in koala populations in Australian states, with a 50 percent drop in Queensland and a 62 percent drop in New South Wales since 2001.</p>
<p>Sparrow remains committed to the cause.</p>
<p>"I can't imagine a world where there's no koalas in the wild," she said.</p>
<p>"We're going to do everything we can possibly to make sure that doesn't happen."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Jill Gralow reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>corridor</strong>–<em>n</em>. land that connects and provides a way through</p>
<p><strong>extinct</strong>–<em>adj</em>. no longer existing</p>
<p><strong>landscape</strong>–<em>n</em>. the qualities that you can see in an area of land</p>
<p><strong>tourism</strong>–<em>n</em>. travel for vacation or pleasure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some US Schools Operate outside State Education System  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/some-us-schools-operate-outside-state-education-system.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Nearly 9,000 private schools in the American state of Louisiana do not need state approval to give high school <strong>diplomas</strong>.</p>
<p>Public schools, formal homeschooling programs and traditional private schools all need state approval. Nearly all of the schools lacking approval were created to serve a single homeschooling family. But some have buildings, classrooms, teachers and many students.</p>
<p>A small percentage of Louisiana's students have ties to unapproved schools. The schools are being called Louisiana's <strong>off-the-grid</strong> school system. Some observers say they are a growing example of the nation's continuing effects of COVID-19 because families appear to be leaving traditional education.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Salutatorian Alasia Baker, 17, center, and Khyli Barbee, 15, following Baker, leave a graduation ceremony for Springfield Preparatory School at Victory in Christ church in Holden, La., Saturday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Matthew Hinton)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-12ae-08dbf4e6e30f_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Salutatorian Alasia Baker, 17, center, and Khyli Barbee, 15, following Baker, leave a graduation ceremony for Springfield Preparatory School at Victory in Christ church in Holden, La., Saturday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Matthew Hinton)</span></div>
<p>U.S. public school <strong>enrollment</strong> fell by more than 1.2 million students in the first two years of the pandemic. Many families sent their children to private school or told their state they were homeschooling. But the Associated Press (AP) and its partners say thousands of other students are unaccounted for.</p>
<p>The students in Louisiana's "off-the-grid" school system are not missing. But there is no way to know what kind of education they are getting.</p>
<p>The AP and <em>The Advocate</em>, a Louisiana newspaper, say that over 21,000 students are enrolled in the state's unapproved schools. That is nearly double the number from before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Supporters of the system want to avoid state <strong>oversight</strong>. They say Louisiana's unapproved schools are an extension of the idea of parental rights in education.</p>
<p>One such school in Louisiana is Springfield Preparatory School. The school calls itself an <strong>umbrella</strong> school for Christian homeschoolers. Most students there attend the school to get an education through classes or <strong>tutoring</strong>.</p>
<p>However, school leader Kitty Sibley Morrison is also willing to give a diploma to anyone whose parents say they were homeschooled, even years earlier.</p>
<p>"Sometimes it takes two or three times to explain to them that they are free," Sibley Morrison said. "Their parents are in charge of them, not the state."</p>
<p><strong>A different choice for homeschooling</strong></p>
<p>Sibley Morrison said she is not selling diplomas; she is selling lifetime services for homeschooling families.</p>
<p>"We're not here to make money," she said.</p>
<p>Yet a list of prices is placed on the front window of the school building: $250 for diploma services, a $50 application fee, $35 for a diploma cover and $130 to take part in a ceremony.</p>
<p>The number of students in unapproved schools like Springfield has nearly doubled. State records show there were 11,600 students in the 2017 to 2018 school year and over 21,000 in 2022 to 2023.</p>
<p>There is little information available about these schools. The state calls them "nonpublic schools not seeking state approval." To start one, an adult must only report their school's name and address, their contact information and how many students they have.</p>
<p>Most of the schools are small, single-family home schools. However, last year, 30 of Louisiana's unapproved schools reported they had at least 50 children enrolled.</p>
<p>Laura Hawkins says there is no way for the government to know whether the schools are safe, good, or even whether they exist. Hawkins is a former official of the Louisiana Department of Education who worked on its school choice efforts until 2020.</p>
<p>The department warns parents on its website that it cannot confirm whether these organizations even meet the legal definition of a school.</p>
<p>Louisiana has two <strong>options</strong> for homeschooling.</p>
<p>Parents who want their child to receive a state-recognized high school diploma can <strong>apply</strong> for the official home study program. They must apply using test scores or copies of the student's work. The work must show their child has received 180 days of schooling of the same quality as a public school's.</p>
<p>The state-recognized diploma is more widely accepted by colleges. It also permits students to be considered for a popular in-state scholarship program.</p>
<p>Families can also choose to set up their own private school without asking for state approval. There are no requirements to prove a child is getting an education. The schools do not even have to provide the names of students who are attending.</p>
<p>At least two unapproved schools have had abuse <strong>scandals</strong>. But the state Department of Education says it has no legal power to do anything.</p>
<p>Today, over 12 states permit families to open a private school as a form of homeschooling, including California, Illinois and Texas. Around half the states require those schools to teach basic subjects such as math and reading. Louisiana is not one of them.</p>
<p><strong>‘I take their word for it'</strong></p>
<p>Springfield Preparatory occupies two buildings on Springfield's main street. State records say 250 students attend, but Sibley Morrison said the school does not keep the number.</p>
<p>Some homeschooling families come for art or science. Others attend services like career guidance, test preparation and "explanation and support in their parental rights," said Sibley Morrison. Some, such as Arliya Martin, go straight for a diploma.</p>
<p>Martin was expelled from high school in 10th grade after getting in a fight. She tried a military-style program for at-risk youths but finished without her GED. The GED test provides what is equal to a high school diploma.</p>
<p>"At 17, I was already by myself. I had my son at 18, and it was just work, work, work," she said.</p>
<p>Within days of meeting Sibley Morrison, Martin visited her office and got a diploma.</p>
<p>The document was backdated to 2015, when she would have graduated high school. It also said she had completed a program for graduation "approved by the Louisiana Board of Education," which is not true. After questions from AP, Sibley Morrison said there had been a mistake and that the document would be corrected.</p>
<p>Signs at the school advertise "state-approved" diplomas although the state has not approved the school. Sibley Morrison said she can use those words because she pushes families in her program to also sign up for the state-approved home study program.</p>
<p>After learning that her diploma is not approved by the state and might not be accepted by some colleges, Martin said she did not feel bad. Friends and family members have gotten diplomas from the same school and have gone on to college and successful careers, she said.</p>
<p>Sibley Morrison said parents are the only people who can decide if and when someone is properly educated.</p>
<p>"When parents say, ‘My child is ready to go into the real world' — I take their word for it," Sibley Morrison said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Sharon Lurye reported this story for the Associated Press. Charles Lussier contributed to it. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>off-the-grid </strong><em>— adj. (informal) </em>not connected to a formal or official system</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enrollment </strong><em>— adj. </em>the process of getting accepted to an institution such as a school or college and providing all necessary documents</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>oversight </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of overseeing and activity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>umbrella </strong><em>— adj. </em>describing a group that includes many other groups that might be quite different or in different places<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>option </strong><em>— n. </em>a choice or possibility to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor </strong>–v. to teach only one or a very small group of students</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diploma </strong><em>— adj. </em>a document that is given to people who complete their classes and course of study at a high school, college or university</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scandal </strong>–n. something that happens because it is shocking, morally or legally wrong</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>COP28 Meeting in Dubai Centers on ‘Phase Out’ or ‘Phase Down’ of Fossil Fuels  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/cop28-meeting-in-dubai-centers-on-phase-out-or-phase-down-of-fossil-fuels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The world's climate negotiators are meeting this month in Dubai for the COP28 United Nations Climate Conference. Activists, scientists and U.N. officials want the representatives to make plans to "<strong>phase</strong> out" the use of fossil fuels as an energy source.</p>
<p>However, some representatives are using the term "phase down" instead.</p>
<p>To "phase out" means to end something slowly through a planned series of steps. But to "phase down" means to slowly reduce the use of something instead of stopping completely.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="International leaders at the United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP28), in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Thaier Al-Sudani)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/efc339a4-e39a-4965-948d-3abf41b78707_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">International leaders at the United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP28), in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Thaier Al-Sudani)</span></div>
<p>The concern, say climate scientists, is that the time for a "phase down" is over.</p>
<p>Bill Hare is a climate scientist and the CEO of Climate Analytics. He said unless the result of the meeting is a "phase out," there is unlikely to be an "improvement in temperature."</p>
<p>The COP28 meeting runs until December 12. During last year's COP27 event, negotiators agreed to plans that would limit <strong>global</strong> temperature warming to only 2.4 degrees Celsius over pre-industrial times.</p>
<p>But a recently updated report found that the world is going in the wrong direction. The report, called the Climate Action Tracker, found that the world is on target for a 2.5-degree rise. It added that several nations, including Indonesia and Iran, have increased their use of fossil fuels. These increases are part of why the world is warming more quickly.</p>
<p>Adnan Amin is the leader of COP28. He is former Director-General of the UN's International Renewable Energy Agency. He said the negotiators have so far produced a "pretty <strong>comprehensive</strong>" <strong>draft</strong> for a central outline of the meeting. The draft is called the Global Stocktake. He said he expects a "very intensive <strong>engagement</strong> process" between the negotiators during the next week of meetings.</p>
<p>The draft is 24 pages long and covers a number of issues. However the greatest concern is the choice between a "phasedown of ... coal power" or "an orderly and just phase out of fossil fuels."</p>
<p>Amin noted that, coming into the event, he did not believe it would be possible to even include "phase out" language in the document. He said some countries are not prepared to agree to a phase out because they require fossil fuel energy to grow their economies.</p>
<p>Critics and activists note that some countries signed on to last year's plan but moved forward with expanding their use of fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Ana Missirliu is an <strong>analyst</strong> at the New Climate Institute. She said she has seen "worrying announcements" in the last year. She pointed to the host nation of COP28 – the United Arab Emirates – announcing a $150-billion expansion of its oil and gas industry. She also pointed to expansions in the United States, Britain and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Several protest groups are in Dubai. They are holding up signs in "action zones" near the UN event. The protesters are asking the representatives to push for a "phase out."</p>
<p>Although there may be some nations pushing for language that does not require a "phase out," many countries are planning to increase their use of renewable energy. More than 100 countries say they will <strong>triple</strong> their ability to create clean energy and double their energy <strong>efficiency</strong> by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>phase </strong>(out or down)<strong> </strong>–v. to introduce something slowly</p>
<p><strong>global </strong>–adj. having to do with the whole world</p>
<p><strong>comprehensive </strong>–adj. including many, or most, things</p>
<p><strong>draft </strong>–n. writing or a document that is the first version of something, not the final</p>
<p><strong>engagement </strong>–n. the act or state of being involved with something</p>
<p><strong>analyst </strong>–n. a person who studies a topic and then makes a recommendation</p>
<p><strong>triple </strong>–v. to increase something by 300 percent or three times</p>
<p><strong>efficiency </strong>–n. the ability to do something or produce something without wasting resources</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More Rohingya Refugees Fleeing Bangladesh by Boat This Year  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/more-rohingya-refugees-fleeing-bangladesh-by-boat-this-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The number of Rohingya taking risky boat trips to flee refugee camps in Bangladesh is rising even higher than last year. Human rights groups and aid agencies told VOA that those numbers could keep rising.</p>
<p>The Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, UNHCR, said in a statement that a boat with 150 Rohingya on board landed in western Indonesia Saturday morning. Amnesty International's Indonesia office told VOA it had confirmed the landing as well.</p>
<p>That brings the total number of Rohingya fleeing across the Andaman Sea by boat to 3,722 so far this year, says the UNHCR.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Children of newly-arrived Rohingya refugees are seen at a beach on Sabang island, Aceh province, Indonesia, on December 2, 2023. (Photo by CHAIDEER MAHYUDDIN / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4c7d951a-6c71-446b-a217-38cd71bcf74b_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Children of newly-arrived Rohingya refugees are seen at a beach on Sabang island, Aceh province, Indonesia, on December 2, 2023. (Photo by CHAIDEER MAHYUDDIN / AFP)</span></div>
<p>In its statement, the refugee agency said it had also received several reports of two more boats with broken engines <strong>stranded </strong>in the Andaman Sea. Those boats hold 400 or more people. The agency issued an <strong>urgent</strong> search and rescue call to countries in the area.</p>
<p>In 2022, the UNHCR counted 3,705 Rohingya who tried to flee. That was the most for any year since 2015.</p>
<p>December is a time when the waters are somewhat calm. And it is the time when most Rohingya try to leave. UNHCR spokesperson Babar Baloch noted, "We can't <strong>predict</strong> what is going to happen in December, but if we look at last year, 2022, the last three months were the ... busiest."</p>
<p><strong>More to come</strong></p>
<p>The Rohingya is a mostly Muslim minority from Buddhist-majority Myanmar. Nearly 1 million currently live in several large refugee camps in eastern Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Most arrived in 2017, fleeing what the U.N. calls a campaign of "<strong>genocidal intent</strong>" by the Myanmar military.</p>
<p>Now, some try to flee by boat to Malaysia or Indonesia, both Muslim-majority countries. Several hundred have died attempting to flee on old and overcrowded boats. Entire boats filled with refugees are believed to have been lost at sea.</p>
<p>Chris Lewa is with the Arakan Project, a group that closely follows the issue. She told VOA, "I believe there will be a lot more people on the way, but to [give] a <strong>figure</strong> ... is impossible."</p>
<p><strong>Reasons for the increase</strong></p>
<p>Aid groups and the Rohingya blame worsening conditions in the camps in Bangladesh for the increase in attempts to flee. The refugees complain of rising <strong>gang</strong> violence, a lack of jobs and schools, and little food.</p>
<p>The U.N. World Food Program is the main source of food aid for the refugees. In June, it reduced the amount of monthly food aid, for the second time, to $8 per person per month. The agency blamed lack of <strong>donor </strong>support for the cuts.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Rohingya are losing hope that they will be able to return safely to Myanmar where they are mostly denied citizenship.</p>
<p>Mohammed Rezuwan Khan is a Rohingya refugee. He said, "...All these things [are] driving the people to take the dangerous sea <strong>journeys</strong>." Khan said his sister and niece knew the risks but still fled by boat last year. They made it to Indonesia.</p>
<p>In years past, the boats carried mostly single men and women. But the UNHCR says more families with children are now traveling together. This year nearly a third of those making the dangerous trip are children.</p>
<p><strong>Losing their lives</strong></p>
<p>UNHCR spokesperson Babar Baloch says Indonesia is the only country willing to take in the Rohingya. A 2016 presidential decision in Indonesia ordered officials to aid any boats at risk in the country's waters and to let them land.</p>
<p>However, that may be starting to change. Last month, a boat that reached Aceh in Indonesia was reportedly pushed back out to sea twice. On the third try, it made it to land.</p>
<p>A representative of Amnesty International blamed this on the national government's failure to assist local officials in their efforts to help the refugees.</p>
<p>Should Indonesia stop helping, experts say more Rohingya will die when they cannot reach land at all. The UNHCR counted 348 dead or missing among those who set out in 2022 and 225 so far this year.</p>
<p>Baloch said, "We saw last year the <strong>consequences</strong> of not having a safe port or a safe place to <strong>disembark</strong>. These people risk losing their lives."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Zsombor Peter reported on this story in Bangkok, Thailand for VOA News. Anna Matteo adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stranded </strong><em>– v. </em>left without the means to move from somewhere.</p>
<p><strong>urgent</strong> <em>– adj.</em> calling for immediate attention</p>
<p><strong>predict</strong> <em>– v. </em>to declare in advance <strong>: </strong>foretell on the basis of observation, experience, or reasoning</p>
<p><strong>genocidal </strong><em>– adj.</em> the deliberate and systematic destruction of a racial, political, or cultural group<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>intent </strong><em>– n. </em>a usually clearly formulated or planned</p>
<p><strong>figure </strong><em>– n. </em>a number symbol</p>
<p><strong>gang</strong> <em>– n. </em>a group of persons associated together to do something illegal</p>
<p><strong>donor </strong><em>– n. </em>one that give money or other resources</p>
<p><strong>journey </strong><em>– n.</em> an act or instance of traveling from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>consequence </strong><em>– n. </em>something produced by a cause or necessarily following from a set of conditions</p>
<p><strong>disembark </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove to shore from a ship</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Extreme Sleep Behavior of Antarctic Penguins  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/extreme-sleep-behavior-of-antarctic-penguins.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Almost all new parents struggle to get enough sleep while caring for their newborns. For some penguin parents, though, periods of sleep are especially short.</p>
<p>Penguins are birds that cannot fly but use their wings for swimming. They live in or near the Antarctic.</p>
<p>Researchers recently found that Chinstrap penguins only sleep for about four seconds at a time in order to protect their eggs and newborn chicks. They do this thousands of times throughout the day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Won Young Lee shows wild chinstrap penguins on King George Island, Antarctica. (Won Young Lee via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/34b8efbd-95d2-4db8-abcc-fa3ddcd07ff8_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Won Young Lee shows wild chinstrap penguins on King George Island, Antarctica. (Won Young Lee via AP)</span></div>
<p>A study on the findings recently appeared in the publication <em>Science.</em></p>
<p>The short "microsleeps" total around 11 hours each day. The microsleeps appear to be enough to keep the parents going for many weeks.</p>
<p>Niels Rattenborg is a sleep researcher at the Max Planck Institute for Biological Intelligence in Germany. He helped write the new study. He said these penguins <strong>blink</strong> "... their eyes open and <strong>shut</strong>, and they do it 24/7 for several weeks at a time."</p>
<p>"What's surprising is that they're able to function okay and successfully raise their young," he said.</p>
<p>Chinstrap penguins usually lay their eggs in November in <strong>nests</strong> made up of small rocks. As with many other kinds of penguins, mated pairs share parenting responsibilities. One parent usually watches the eggs and chicks alone while the other goes off fishing for family meals.</p>
<p>Adult penguins do not face many natural <strong>predators</strong> in the mating season. But large birds called brown skuas eat the penguin eggs and small chicks. Other adult penguins may also try to steal the small rocks from nests. So, penguin parents must always be on guard.</p>
<p>For the first time, scientists followed the sleeping behavior of Chinstrap penguins in an Antarctic mating colony. They did this by attaching devices that measure brain waves. They collected data on 14 adults over 11 days on King George Island off the coast of Antarctica.</p>
<p>Won Young Lee is a biologist at the Korean Polar Research Institute. He thought of the idea for the study when he saw mating penguins often blinking their eyes and possibly sleeping during his long days of field observations. But the team needed to record brain waves to confirm the animals were sleeping.</p>
<p>"For these penguins, microsleeps have some <strong>restorative </strong>functions," he said. He added that they would not survive without it.</p>
<p>The researchers did not collect sleep data outside the mating season. But they suspect that the penguins may sleep for longer periods at other times of the year.</p>
<p>Paul-Antoine Libourel is a sleep researcher at the Neuroscience Research Center of Lyon in France. He also helped write the study. He said scientists do not yet know if the gains from microsleep are the same as gains from longer periods of time. Scientists also do not know if other kinds of penguins sleep in such short periods.</p>
<p>Researchers have documented a few other animals with special sleeping <strong>adaptations</strong>. For example, frigatebirds can sleep with one half of their brain at a time while flying.</p>
<p>But researchers say the Chinstrap penguin microsleeps appear to be a new extreme.</p>
<p>Daniel Paranhos Zitterbart studies penguins at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study. He noted that penguins mate in crowded colonies and their predators are around at the same time. He described microsleeping as "an <strong>amazing </strong>adaptation" that permits the penguins to be nearly always on guard.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>blink </strong>– <em>v</em>. to close and then open your eyes very quickly</p>
<p><strong>shut </strong>– <em>v</em>. to close (something)</p>
<p><strong>nest </strong>– <em>n</em>. the place where a bird lays its eggs and takes care of its young</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong>– <em>n</em>. an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals: an animal that preys on other animals</p>
<p><strong>restore </strong>– <em>adj</em>. large in amount, size, or number</p>
<p><strong>adaptation </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having the ability to make a person feel strong or healthy again</p>
<p><strong>amazing </strong>– <em>adj</em>. causing great surprise or wonder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Africa, Colombia Aim to Get Lower-Cost Drugs for TB, HIV  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/south-africa-colombia-aim-to-get-lower-cost-drugs-for-tb-hiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>South Africa and Colombia are among the countries aiming to push drug companies to permit low-cost versions of drugs for deadly diseases. The drugs are for people with drug-resistant versions of tuberculosis (TB) and with HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>One target is the drug bedaquiline. It is used for treating people with drug-resistant tuberculosis. In South Africa, TB was blamed for the deaths of more than 50,000 people in 2021, making it the country's leading cause of death.</p>
<p>Johnson &amp; Johnson is a U.S.-based drug and medical technology company. The company owns a patent for the drug bedaquiline. Patents legally protect a company's right to manufacture and sell a product that it developed or owns for a limited time. The legal protection prevents other companies from making the same drug without permission.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Scientists conduct reserach at an Afrigen Biologics and Vaccines facility in Cape Town, South Africa, Tuesday Oct. 19, 2021. (AP Photo/Jerome Delay, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-9336-08dbf1b3d2d3_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Scientists conduct reserach at an Afrigen Biologics and Vaccines facility in Cape Town, South Africa, Tuesday Oct. 19, 2021. (AP Photo/Jerome Delay, File)</span></div>
<p>In recent months, activists have protested efforts by Johnson &amp; Johnson to protect its patent. In March, TB patients asked the Indian government to make a lower cost copy of bedaquiline. The government agreed, saying Johnson &amp; Johnson's patent could be broken.</p>
<p>In July, the time limit for Johnson &amp; Johnson's patent on the drug ran out in South Africa. The company extended the patent until 2027 under South African law. However, activists became angry and accused Johnson &amp; Johnson of trying to make a lot of money from the drug.</p>
<p>The South African government then began investigating the company's pricing policies. South Africa had been paying about $282 per treatment course: a full group of treatments. This was more than twice as much as poor countries involved in the Swiss-based Stop TB Partnership paid.</p>
<p>In September, about a week after South Africa's investigation began, Johnson &amp; Johnson announced it would not enforce its patent in more than 130 countries. This would permit other drug makers in those countries to copy the drug.</p>
<p>Christophe Perrin is a TB expert at Doctors Without Borders. He called the decision "a big surprise." He said protecting patents is central to how most drug companies plan their businesses.</p>
<p>In October, Colombia announced that it would permit a third party to make the HIV drug dolutegravir without permission from the drug's patent-holder, Viiv Healthcare. The decision came after more than 120 groups asked the government to let more people use the drug, which is supported by the World Health Organization (WHO).</p>
<p>Peter Maybarduk is with the Washington, D.C., non-profit group Public Citizen. He thinks the Colombian government is trying to take control of its treatment of HIV after not having enough vaccines for COVID-19. He noted that Brazilian activists are pushing their government to do the same.</p>
<p><strong>More changes needed</strong></p>
<p>However, some experts say more needs to change before poor countries can produce their own medicines.</p>
<p>Petro Terblanche is managing director of the biotechnology company Afrigen Biologics based in Cape Town, South Africa. She said African countries produced less than one percent of all vaccines made around the world when the COVID-19 pandemic hit. But, Terblanche said, Africa used more than half of the world's supply.</p>
<p>Afrigen Biologics is part of a WHO-supported effort to produce a COVID vaccine using the same mRNA technology as those made by U.S.-based drug makers Pfizer and Moderna.</p>
<p>Terblanche also noted that African countries need to improve their ability to <strong>deliver</strong> vaccines. "If we can't get (vaccines and medicines) to the people who need them, they aren't useful," she said.</p>
<p>Lynette Keneilwe Mabote-Eyde is a health care activist who has ties to the nonprofit Treatment Action Group based in New York City. She noted that South Africa has no clear law permitting the government to take legal action against a patent or a patent extension.</p>
<p>The South African department of health did not answer questions from the Associated Press about patents.</p>
<p><strong>Fighting tuberculosis</strong></p>
<p>In its yearly report on TB released in November, the WHO said there were more than 10 million people sickened by the disease in 2022 and 1.3 million deaths.</p>
<p>After COVID-19, tuberculosis is the world's deadliest infectious disease. It is also now believed to be the main cause of death of people with HIV. The WHO says only about 40 percent of people with drug-resistant TB are being treated.</p>
<p>Zolelwa Sifumba, a South African doctor, found she had drug-resistant TB in 2012. She went through 18 months of treatment, taking about 20 pills every day in addition to daily injections. These left her in severe pain and resulted in some hearing loss. Bedaquiline was not a standard treatment in South Africa until 2018.</p>
<p>"I wanted to quit (treatment) every single day," she said. Since her recovery, Sifumba has been pushing for better TB treatment. She said it makes little sense to charge poor countries, which have more cases of TB, high prices for necessary medicines.</p>
<p>She questioned why poor countries would have to pay a lot for medicine. "If the lower income countries can't get it, then what's the point? Who are you making it for?" she said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Gerald Imray and Maria Cheng wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>deliver </strong><em>–v.</em> to take something from one place to the place where it is supposed to go</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Biden to US Congress: Ukraine Is 'Out of Money, Out of Time'  (2023/12/5) | 拜登督促国会批准尽快对乌克兰援助</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/biden-to-us-congress-ukraine-is-out-of-money-out-of-time.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The administration of American President Joe Biden warned lawmakers Monday against rejecting a military aid proposal for Ukraine.<br/>
美国总统乔·拜登政府星期一警告议员不要否决对乌克兰军事援助的提案。</p>
<p>Shalanda Young is the director of the United States Office of Management and Budget. She sent an open letter to the leaders of the U.S. Senate and House of Representatives.<br/>
莎兰达·杨是美国管理和预算办公室主任。她向美国参众两院领导人发出了一封公开信。</p>
<p>Young said if the current budget measure is rejected, U.S. military aid to Ukraine would be gone by the end of the year.<br/>
杨说，如果目前的预算提案被否决，美国对乌克兰的军事援助将在今年年底前不复存在。</p>
<p>The aid permits Ukraine to buy weapons for its defense against Russia.<br/>
这项援助允许乌克兰购买武器抵抗俄罗斯。</p>
<p>Young noted that the U.S. also provides financial aid to the Ukrainian economy, and that money is already gone. She wrote: "If Ukraine's economy collapses, they will not be able to keep fighting...."<br/>
杨指出，美国还向乌克兰经济提供财政援助，这些钱已经花光了。她写道：“如果乌克兰经济崩溃，他们将无法继续战斗……”</p>
<p>With less than one month to go in 2023, she added: "We are out of money – and nearly out of time."<br/>
距离2023年还有不到一个月的时间，她补充道：“我们没有钱了，而且几乎没有时间了。”</p>
<p>Biden has asked Congress for more than $100 billion in aid that would go to Ukraine, Israel and others. Some lawmakers oppose the measure unless there are conditions attached. They say the Biden administration must find solutions to the migrant problem at the U.S. southern border.<br/>
拜登已要求国会向乌克兰、以色列和其他国家提供1000多亿美元的援助。一些立法者反对这项提案，除非有附加条件。他们说，拜登政府必须找到解决美国南部边境移民问题的办法。</p>
<p>The House of Representatives already approved a military assistance bill for Israel. The Senate has not.<br/>
众议院已经批准了一项对以色列的军事援助法案。参议院没有。</p>
<p>The U.S. sent $111 billion to Ukraine in 2023. About $67 billion went to military needs. Another $27 billion went toward economic and civil assistance and $10 billion supported humanitarian aid.<br/>
2023年，美国向乌克兰提供了1110亿美元。大约670亿美元用于军事需求。另有270亿美元用于经济和民事援助，还有100亿美元用于人道主义援助。</p>
<p>Only three percent of the fund remains, Young wrote. She urged lawmakers to approve more money.<br/>
杨写道，这笔专款只剩下3%。她敦促议员们批准更多资金。</p>
<p>"This isn't a next year problem. The time to help a democratic Ukraine fight against Russian aggression is right now. It is time for Congress to act," the letter reads.<br/>
这份公开信写道：“这不是明年的问题。帮助民主乌克兰对抗俄罗斯侵略的时机就是现在。国会是时候采取行动了。”</p>
<p>The letter followed a closed meeting on November 29 among U.S. congressional, military and national security officials. The security officials told the lawmakers that Ukraine aid needed to continue. Biden's recent proposal includes $61 billion for Ukraine.<br/>
这封信是在11月29日美国国会、军方以及国家安全官员举行非公开会议后发出的。安全官员告诉议员们，对乌克兰援助需要继续。拜登最近的提案包括向乌克兰提供610亿美元。</p>
<p>Chuck Schumer attended the meeting. He is the Majority Leader of the U.S. Senate and a Democrat. He said the American military experts "were clear that Ukraine needs the aid soon."<br/>
查克·舒默出席了会议。他是美国参议院多数党领袖以及民主党人。他说，美国军事专家“清楚乌克兰很快需要这笔援助。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US States Push to End Food Waste  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-states-push-to-end-food-waste.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>When Sean Rafferty first worked in a food store 40 years ago, anything that was not sold got thrown out.</p>
<p>But on a recent day at his store near the New York City area, he was preparing boxes of bread, vegetables, and milk products to be picked up by a food bank. It is part of a program in New York State requiring larger businesses to donate food, and, if possible, reusing small, leftover pieces of food.</p>
<p>New York is among a growing number of states trying to limit food waste. They are concerned that it is taking up space in landfills and adding to <strong>global warming</strong>. A landfill is a place for putting <strong>garbage</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Driver Carlos Quezada loads rice on a pallet for distribution at Feeding Westchester in Elmsford, N.Y., Wednesday, Nov. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e9cc-08dbf0f79b38_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Driver Carlos Quezada loads rice on a pallet for distribution at Feeding Westchester in Elmsford, N.Y., Wednesday, Nov. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>Food waste including meat and vegetables releases methane gas after being put in a landfill. And saving unwanted food helps to feed hungry families.</p>
<p>Worldwide, about a third of food is wasted. In the United States, it is 40 percent. The U.S. spends about $218 billion each year growing and producing food that is wasted. About 57 million metric tons goes to waste, including 47.5 million metric tons that ends up in landfills.</p>
<p>"What's shocking to people often is not only how much we waste ... but also the <strong>impact</strong>," said Emily Broad Leib. She is a Harvard University professor and director of the school's Food Law and Policy Clinic. "Food waste causes about 8 percent to 10 percent of global <strong>greenhouse gas emissions</strong>."</p>
<p>In 2015, the U.S. Department of Agriculture and the Environmental Protection Agency announced a goal of 50 percent food waste reduction by 2030.</p>
<p>That has led to a number of state government efforts, along with smaller, nonprofit efforts.</p>
<p>Ten American states and Washington, D.C. have passed legislation or created policies to reduce, <strong>compost</strong> or donate waste.</p>
<p>The states of California and Vermont have programs for turning people's food waste into compost or energy. Connecticut requires businesses, including larger food sellers and <strong>supermarkets</strong>, to reuse food waste. Farmers in Maryland can get a tax credit of up to $5,000 per farm for food they donate.</p>
<p>Several states have joined New York in creating systems for food donation. Rhode Island requires food sellers servicing schools and universities to donate any unused food to food banks. And Massachusetts limits the amount of food that businesses can send to landfills.</p>
<p>As of late October, New York had sent 2.3 million kilograms of food, about 4 million meals, through its Feeding New York State program. The program supports the state's 10 area food banks and is hoping to double that number next year.</p>
<p>"Certainly, we should be reducing the amount we waste to start with, but then we should be feeding people before we throw food away..." said Sally Rowland. She is with the New York Department of Environmental Conservation.</p>
<p>Despite New York's success, some worry not enough is being done to meet the 2030 goal. Broad Leib and others have called for a national effort to <strong>coordinate</strong> the various state and local policies.</p>
<p>Kathryn Bender is a University of Delaware assistant professor of economics. She said donation programs are helpful. But she worries they might put the responsibility on nonprofits, instead of businesses.</p>
<p>"The best solution for food waste is to not have it in the first place," Bender said. "If we don't need to produce all that food, let's not put all the resources into producing that food."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>global warming </strong><em>— n. </em>the recent increase in the world's temperature that is believed to be caused by the increase of certain gases in the atmosphere</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>garbage </strong><em>— n. </em>things that are no longer useful or wanted and that have been thrown out</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>impact </strong><em>— n. </em> the act or force of one thing hitting another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>greenhouse gas </strong><em>— n.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>compost </strong><em>— n. </em>a decayed mixture of plants that is used to improve the soil in a garden</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>supermarket </strong><em>— n. </em>a store where customers can buy a variety of foods and usually household items</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coordinate </strong><em>— n. </em>to make arrangements so that two or more people or groups of people can work together properly and well</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Continues Mars Helicopter Experiments, Tests New Design on Earth  (2023/12/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/nasa-continues-mars-helicopter-experiments-tests-new-design-on-earth.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>As the American space agency NASA continues to carry out tests of its Ingenuity helicopter on Mars, it is also testing a future aircraft design on Earth.</p>
<p>NASA's Ingenuity has been making test flights on the Red Planet for the past two-and-a-half years. The experimental helicopter arrived on Mars along with NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover, in February 2021.</p>
<p>Both the rover and helicopter have been collecting images and data as they explore an area known as Jezero Crater. The goal of the exploration effort is to search for signs of ancient life on Mars.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-05e9-08dbf1ebe005_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Ingenuity made history on Mars</strong></p>
<p>Ingenuity made history in April 2021 by becoming the first aircraft to complete a powered, controlled flight on another planet. NASA officials have said the helicopter has performed far above expectations. Agency engineers planned on Ingenuity completing just five experimental flights on Mars. But the helicopter has so far performed 66 flights. It has provided NASA with valuable data on building future aircraft to fly in space.</p>
<p>Travis Brown is Ingenuity's chief engineer at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in California. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-uses-two-worlds-to-test-future-mars-helicopter-designs">said</a> in a statement that with nearly every flight, the helicopter has progressed in new ways. Brown noted that over the past nine months, Ingenuity had doubled its top speed and height records. In addition, the aircraft's operating speed and landings improved.</p>
<p>Most Ingenuity flights only last two to three minutes. This is because the helicopter has energy and temperature limitations.</p>
<p>NASA engineers say they have also been careful not to try to fly Ingenuity too fast because this can cause problems with its <strong>navigation</strong> system. The helicopter uses a camera to identify rocks and other things on the surface as it travels. If the aircraft goes too fast, it might not be able to navigate the best way forward.</p>
<p>Controllers on the ground have said that to help with this issue, they have sent commands to Ingenuity to fly at higher levels. This way the aircraft has less chance of losing its way because surface objects stay in view longer.</p>
<p>NASA says Ingenuity established a new height record, on flight 61, of 24 meters as it examined Martian wind conditions. On flight 62, the helicopter set a new speed record of 10 meters per second. During this flight Ingenuity also identified a new place for the Perseverance rover to carry out science experiments.</p>
<p><strong>Testing new helicopter design on Earth</strong></p>
<p>As that testing continues on Mars, teams on the ground have been experimenting with new <strong>rotor blades</strong>. These could be used in the future with a new generation of Mars helicopters. During the tests, engineers reported the rotor blades had reached speeds nearly equal to Mach 1, the speed of sound.</p>
<p>The blades tested on Earth are made of carbon material and are more than 10 centimeters longer than Ingenuity's. The blades were designed to be both faster and stronger. NASA has said such rotor blades should be able to support bigger, more complex helicopters. The team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-uses-two-worlds-to-test-future-mars-helicopter-designs">said</a> in a statement the helicopter design must reach the right balance. If the blades spin too fast, this causes control issues that can increase the risk of crashes.</p>
<p>The Earth-based tests were carried out in September inside a space <strong>simulator</strong> at NASA's JPL. For these experiments, the simulator aimed to establish a Mars-like environment. The team was measuring tests of the rotor blades with sensors, cameras and other equipment. Many different speeds were tested and the blades were repeatedly repositioned to observe the best results.</p>
<p>"We spun our blades up to 3,500 rpm, which is 750 revolutions per minute faster than the Ingenuity blades have gone," said Tyler Del Sesto, a leader of the JPL testing. "These more <strong>efficient</strong> blades are now more than a <strong>hypothetical</strong> exercise. They are ready to fly," he added.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>navigate </strong><em>– v. </em>to find the right direction to travel in by using maps of other equipment</p>
<p><strong>rotor blade </strong><em>– n. </em>thin, flat pieces of material that spin to make aircraft lift off the ground and travel</p>
<p><strong>simulator </strong><em>– n. </em>a machine used to practice operating a vehicle or piece of equipment without having to actually use those things</p>
<p><strong>efficient </strong><em>– adj. </em>working well and not wasting time or energy</p>
<p><strong>hypothetical </strong><em>– adj. </em>a situation or idea has been suggested but does not yet really exist or has not been proven to be true</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
