<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Moon Is 40 Million Years Older than First Believed  (2023/10/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-moon-is-40-million-years-older-than-first-believed.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists say a mineral found in moon dust suggests Earth's moon is 40 million years older than scientists had believed.</p>
<p>The finding was made by researchers who examined moon <strong>samples</strong> gathered by astronauts from the lunar surface in 1972 – the last time humans walked on the moon. The samples were part of a collection of 110 kilograms of dust and rock returned to Earth for scientific study.</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/moon/facts/">says</a> the leading theory on how the moon formed involves a huge crash. NASA says a Mars-sized object likely crashed into Earth and released material from both objects, which formed the moon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, the crescent Earth rises above the lunar horizon in this undated NASA handout photograph taken from the Apollo 17 spacecraft in lunar orbit during the final lunar landing mission in the Apollo program in 1972. (REUTERS/NASA/Handout)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6db4-08dbd671e44f_cx0_cy18_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, the crescent Earth rises above the lunar horizon in this undated NASA handout photograph taken from the Apollo 17 spacecraft in lunar orbit during the final lunar landing mission in the Apollo program in 1972. (REUTERS/NASA/Handout)</span></div>
<p>But the exact timing of when the moon was created has been difficult to identify. A new study based on the 1972 samples suggests the moon formed about 4.46 billion years ago.</p>
<p>The research was led by a team from the Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago, Illinois. The findings were recently published <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.geochemicalperspectivesletters.org/article2334/">in a study</a> in <em>Geochemical Perspective Letters</em>.</p>
<p>The study examined small <strong>crystals</strong> found in the lunar dust. The team said the crystals contained a mineral called zircon. The zircon is believed to have formed when the lunar surface cooled after being in a melting state after the crash.</p>
<p>The method used to estimate the age of the dust sample is called atom probe tomography. This method had not been developed when the sample was collected 51 years ago, said Philipp Heck. He is the lead writer of the study and the senior director of research at the Field Museum of Natural History.</p>
<p>NASA said the lunar sample was collected from an area known as the Taurus-Littrow valley on the near side of the moon. The near side of the moon is the side that always faces Earth. The sample had been stored at NASA's Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>Heck noted that zircon is a very strong mineral that can "survive the breakdown of rocks during weathering."</p>
<p>The new study followed an earlier one carried out in 2021. In that study, researchers examined how many atoms of uranium and lead were contained in the zircon crystals. They then estimated the age of the mineral based on differences in the <strong>decay</strong> of the radioactive uranium to lead over time.</p>
<p>But the purpose of the new study was to confirm the earlier study's results, which were not considered <strong>conclusive</strong>. The examinations of the sample material were carried out atom-by-atom with very sensitive instruments, the researchers <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fieldmuseum.org/about/press/crystals-brought-back-by-astronauts-show-that-the-moon-is-40-million-years-older">said</a>.</p>
<p>Jennika Greer is a researcher in the School of Geographical and Earth Sciences at the University of Glasgow in Scotland. She helped lead the study. Greer told Reuters news agency the finding is "a great example of what the nanoscale, or even atomic <strong>scale</strong>, can tell us about big-picture questions."</p>
<p>Heck, from the Field Museum, said the huge crash that formed the moon was a major event that changed Earth's rotational speed. He added, "The formation date of the moon is important as only after that Earth became a <strong>habitable</strong> planet."</p>
<p>Greer said she hopes the team's finding can be a basis for answering many remaining questions about the moon. "It's amazing being able to have proof that the rock you're holding is the oldest bit of the Moon we've found so far." She added, "When you know how old something is, you can better understand what has happened to it in its history."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and the Field Museum of Chicago reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– v. </em>a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>crystal </strong>–n. a mineral that has formed into a regular shape because of the physical qualities of what it is made of</p>
<p><strong>decay </strong><em>– v. </em>to become weak or destroyed over time, often because of natural causes like bacteria or age</p>
<p><strong>conclusive </strong><em>– adj. </em>proving that something is true</p>
<p><strong>scale </strong><em>– n. </em>the size or level of something</p>
<p><strong>habitable </strong><em>– adj. </em>having the ability to support life</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Most American Schools Not Prepared to Identify Math Disabilities  (2023/10/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/most-american-schools-not-prepared-to-identify-math-disabilities.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many American education experts are concerned about students' performance in the subject of mathematics.</p>
<p>Scores on <strong>standardized tests</strong> are falling, students are having trouble learning high-level math in college and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/educators-improving-teachers-math-skills-will-aid-students-/7258594.html">some teachers</a> do not feel prepared to teach math to young people.</p>
<p>Laura Jackson's daughter was nine years old when she discovered that she was having a learning problem that her school was not prepared to deal with.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Preschool students practice math using manipulatives at a public school in Boston in 2016. (Lillian Mongeau/The Hechinger Report via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1a36256a-b5e8-44ab-8bb9-fca954e1d466_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Preschool students practice math using manipulatives at a public school in Boston in 2016. (Lillian Mongeau/The Hechinger Report via AP)</span></div>
<p>Jackson said she started to worry about her daughter when she was having problems with math in third grade. She said other students had no trouble doing <strong>multiplication</strong> problems, but her daughter still used her fingers to count.</p>
<p><strong>Discovering dyscalculia</strong></p>
<p>At that point, the girl asked her mother if she was "stupid." She was still having trouble with math although she had been working with a special math teacher.</p>
<p>Then Jackson heard about a learning problem from a friend. It is called dyscalculia. She looked up the learning disability and found that the learning problem prevents children from understanding numbers and learning math.</p>
<p>"I was like, ‘Oh my <strong>gosh</strong>, this is my kid'," Jackson said.</p>
<p>Around the U.S., hundreds of thousands of students might have a math-learning problem such as dyscalculia. However, most schools are not prepared to deal with the condition.</p>
<p><strong>Easier to find reading problems</strong></p>
<p>Schools are getting better at discovering learning problems. States passed laws that require testing young students for problems such as dyslexia, a common reading disability. But schools are not yet required to test for problems with numbers. One study, published by the National Library of Medicine in 2019, said between three and seven percent of the population has dyscalculia.</p>
<p>Karen Wilson is a neuropsychologist who tests children for learning problems. "There's not as much research on math disorders," when compared to reading problems, she said.</p>
<p>Math test scores have been decreasing in the U.S. for years, but the numbers got worse after the COVID-19 pandemic changed the way students learned. Few teachers say anyone has tested their students for dyscalculia.</p>
<p>Education experts say the kind of slow and repetitive math teaching that helps students with dyscalculia might also help other students.</p>
<p>Sandra Elliott currently works for TouchMath, an education company that sells a math teaching program. She used to be a special education teacher. She said schools that change their teaching to help students who have "severe disconnections and slower processing speeds," will also help other students get better at math.</p>
<p>Some schools, such as the one Jackson's daughter attended, do not always believe students have a serious math learning problem when they do well in other subjects.</p>
<p>Jackson researched dyscalculia on her own and decided to write a book about her family's problems. She found many schools do not know about the problem.</p>
<p>She said parents think schools will let them know if their child is having trouble, "but that's just not how it works."</p>
<p><strong>How to help students</strong></p>
<p>Lynn Fuchs is a professor in special education and human development at Vanderbilt University in Tennessee. She said students with math learning problems need "<strong>systematic</strong> and <strong>explicit</strong>" teaching. That means they need math teachers who have learned how to help students who have a math disability. Most do not have enough training. For example, some states require teachers to get dyslexia awareness training in order to renew their teaching permit. But no such requirement exists for dyscalculia.</p>
<p>Amelia Malone is a director at the National Center for Learning Disabilities. She said there are not enough high-level degrees in education that center on math learning disabilities "with any level of...depth, quality or <strong>rigor</strong>."</p>
<p>In addition, most schools do not have specialists who can work with math learning problems. Jackson said she took it upon herself to learn how to teach students with dyscalculia and started giving her daughter extra help.</p>
<p>In New York City, some schools do look for math problems among their students. In 2015 and 2016, the city spent $6 million to introduce a math program with games, art projects and songs. However, most school systems do not do that.</p>
<p>Some education experts say students, such as Jackson's daughter, could improve if schools used different methods to teach math to young people. These could include games, wooden blocks, body motions and songs.</p>
<p>After spending time working with her daughter, Jackson said the girl returned to classes and as her education continued, she started getting good grades in Algebra.</p>
<p>She said students need to understand they are not "bad at math." They need help learning and can then succeed in the subject.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this piece for Learning English based on story by the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://hechingerreport.org/disabilities-in-math-affect-many-students-but-get-little-attention/" target="_blank">Hechinger Report</a> and republished by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>standardized test </strong><em>–n.</em> a test that is the same for everyone which aims to measure a student's ability in one or more subjects</p>
<p><strong>multiplication </strong><em>–n.</em> repeated addition of a number by one or more other numbers or values</p>
<p><strong>gosh </strong><em>–interjection</em> an expression of surprise</p>
<p><strong>systematic </strong>–adj. a method that follows a system and is not disordered or impossible to explain</p>
<p><strong>explicit </strong><em>–adj.</em> clearly stated; openly shown</p>
<p><strong>rigor </strong>–n. a quality of being exact, strict and careful</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Birds of a Feather ...'  (2023/10/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/birds-of-a-feather.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples and sometimes notes on usage.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Young brown pelicans flock together in their nest as terns fly overhead on Raccoon Island, a Gulf of Mexico barrier island in Chauvin, Louisiana, May 17, 2022. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01460000-0aff-0242-733e-08da702d34f5_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Young brown pelicans flock together in their nest as terns fly overhead on Raccoon Island, a Gulf of Mexico barrier island in Chauvin, Louisiana, May 17, 2022. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)</span></div>
<p>Have you ever found yourself in a group of people with similar ways of thinking and interests to yours? They understand you. They really get you. They may even be wearing similar clothing to yours.</p>
<p>We have a great expression for this: <u>Birds of a feather <strong>flock</strong> together</u>. This means people of the same kind or with the same tastes and interests often find each other.</p>
<p>Artists may spend time with other artists. Lawyers often talk about legal issues or court cases with other lawyers. And people who love languages like to discuss grammar and words with other language-loving people.</p>
<p>We have many similar expressions, and many of them use the word "mind" or "brain."</p>
<p>If someone thinks like me, I can say we are <u>like-minded.</u> I can also say we <u>are of like mind</u> or <u>of the same mind</u>.</p>
<p>There is also something called a <strong><u>hive</u></strong><u> mind</u>. In a beehive, the bees all work together to achieve the same goal. People who are part of a <u>hive mind</u> have similar thoughts, ideas, and opinions. They often work together to discuss an issue or solve a problem.</p>
<p>And sometimes, I can joke that I share <u>the same brain</u> with those who share my thinking and <strong>attitudes</strong>.</p>
<p>If you a spiritual kind of person, you can call them your <strong><u>kindred</u></strong><u> spirits</u>. If you are more of a science person, you can say you are <u>on the same <strong>wavelength.</strong> </u></p>
<p>And if you are a person who likes to make things, you can use these two expressions: <u>cut from the same cloth,</u> <strong><u>cast</u></strong><u> from the same <strong>mold</strong>.</u></p>
<p>All these expressions mean the same thing -- you feel a strong connection to someone and feel very similar to them.</p>
<p>We have another expression that can also be used in this situation. But we only use it when we have a similar idea with another person: <u>great minds think alike</u>.</p>
<p>If you often listen to VOA Learning English, you belong to a community of <u>like-minded</u> people: People who want to practice their English.</p>
<p>Welcome to our family!</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>flock </strong><em>– v. </em>to gather or move in a crowd<em> </em>:<em> – n. </em>a group of animals (such as birds or sheep) assembled or herded together</p>
<p><strong>attitude </strong><em>– n. </em>a position assumed for a specific purpose</p>
<p><strong>hive </strong><em>– n. </em>a container for housing honeybees : a colony of bees</p>
<p><strong>kindred </strong><em>– n.</em> of a similar nature or character</p>
<p><strong>wavelength </strong><em>– n. </em><strong> </strong>the distance (as from crest to crest) in the line of advance of a wave from any one point to the next corresponding point <strong>: </strong>a certain line of thought or behavior that reveals a common understanding</p>
<p><strong>cast </strong><em>– v. </em>to give a shape to (a substance) by pouring in liquid or plastic form into a mold and letting harden without pressure</p>
<p><strong>mold </strong><em>– n. </em>the frame on, around, or in which something is constructed or shaped</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>John Kennedy: Young  (2023/10/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/americas-presidents-john-kennedy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about John Fitzgerald Kennedy. He was also known as Jack Kennedy, or by the letters JFK.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - John F. Kennedy" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2145b47f-b40b-482b-9a06-bf2f4c5cc4e3_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - John F. Kennedy</span></div>
<p>When he took office in 1961, Kennedy was 43 years old. He was the youngest elected president in United States' history.</p>
<p>Kennedy was also the first Catholic to be elected U.S. president.</p>
<p>Kennedy's youth and religion raised questions in the minds of some Americans that Kennedy could lead the country. They wondered if he would always follow the policies of the Roman Catholic Church.</p>
<p>But Kennedy became well-known as a statesman, and popular with people around the world. He was intelligent, funny and good-looking. For many, Kennedy was a sign of new energy and hope.</p>
<p>The public was shocked, then, when the president's term was violently cut short.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>John F. Kennedy was born in 1917 near Boston, Massachusetts. He was the second of nine children.</p>
<p>Both his parents were Catholic, with ancestors from Ireland. Many years ago, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/sep/12/america-history-of-hating-catholics">Irish Catholics often faced discrimination</a> in the United States. But the Kennedy family was also politically powerful and wealthy.</p>
<p>As a result, young Jack Kennedy grew up in big, beautiful houses and received a top quality education. His family did not suffer during the Great Depression, as many Americans had. Instead, the Kennedy children swam, sailed boats and played sports.</p>
<p>Jack also enjoyed reading books and following the news. His older brother Joe wanted to enter politics, but Jack said he might become a teacher or writer. When he was a college student at Harvard, Jack wrote a long paper about Britain in the years leading up to World War II. A version of it was published in 1940 as a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.amazon.com/Why-England-Slept-John-Kennedy/dp/4871877671">book</a>.</p>
<p>The war changed Jack's thinking about his future plans. During World War II, both Jack and his older brother joined the U.S. Navy. In the Pacific, Jack became a hero. He won medals for leading some of his troops to safety after a Japanese warship struck a boat they were on.</p>
<p>But Joe was killed. In 1944, his airplane exploded over Europe.</p>
<p>When the war ended, Jack's father urged him to follow his brother's dream of succeeding in politics. Jack agreed, and he set his sights on becoming the country's first Catholic president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>Kennedy was nominated as the Democratic Party's candidate, and he was elected in 1960.</p>
<p>He easily defeated Vice President Richard Nixon, the Republican candidate, in the Electoral College. But Kennedy won only narrowly in the popular vote.</p>
<p>Though he was young, Kennedy brought experience to the job. In addition to being a naval officer, Kennedy had been a member of the U.S. House of Representatives as well as a senator from Massachusetts.</p>
<p>He also published a Pulitzer Prize-winning book called "Profiles in Courage."</p>
<p>And he had become a husband and father. He married a wealthy, well-educated woman who had been working as a newspaper photographer. Her name was <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/jacquelinekennedy">Jacqueline Bouvier</a>, but she was sometimes called Jackie.</p>
<p>She became pregnant five times, but only two of her children would survive: a daughter named Caroline, and a son, John F. Kennedy, Junior.</p>
<p>The family of four moved into the White House in January 1961. On the day he was sworn-in, Kennedy gave a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.gilderlehrman.org/history-by-era/sixties/essays/john-f-kennedy%E2%80%99s-inaugural-address">speech</a> that many people still remember today. It celebrated the "new generation of Americans," and promised to "pay any price" for liberty.</p>
<p>Supporters of the new president loved his energy and sense of hope. In his most famous line, Kennedy said, "Ask not what your country can do for you – ask what you can do for your country."</p>
<p>Many young people remembered that line when they volunteered for a program Kennedy created in 1961: the Peace Corps.</p>
<p>Other Americans remembered the line when they watched two Apollo 11 astronauts walk on the moon in 1969. Kennedy strongly supported the country's space program. He promised that Americans would land on the moon by the end of the 1960s, and they did.</p>
<p>Kennedy also supported efforts to improve civil rights across the U.S., although his administration moved slowly. Calls to end legalized racism were growing stronger during Kennedy's time in office, particularly because of the leadership of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/peace/laureates/1964/king-bio.html">Martin Luther King, Junior</a>.</p>
<p>In June of 1963, King spoke to hundreds of thousands of people at a civil rights protest called the March on Washington. He told the crowd that he dreamed "my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin, but by the <strong>content</strong> of their character."</p>
<p>The March on Washington, among other events, showed the power of the civil rights movement. In late 1963, President Kennedy sent a civil rights bill to Congress and spoke to Americans about the injustice that remained in the country.</p>
<p>The Peace Corps, the Space Race, and civil rights are all part of Kennedy's <strong>legacy</strong>.</p>
<p>Kennedy is also remembered for several troubling international events. In one, known as the Bay of Pigs, Americans supported Cuban refugees in an effort to oust the government of Fidel Castro. Not only did the refugees fail, but Kennedy's government was found to be lying about their support of the effort.</p>
<p>And Kennedy faced off with the leader of the Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev. In 1962, American leaders learned that the Soviets had hidden nuclear weapons in Cuba. The missiles would be able to reach the U.S. mainland easily.</p>
<p>Kennedy ordered a blockade of Cuba. People around the world held their breath as they waited to see if the U.S. and the Soviet Union would launch a nuclear war. They did not. After several very tense weeks, Kennedy and Khrushchev reached an agreement that ended the crisis.</p>
<p>Kennedy went on to reach an agreement with the Soviet Union and Britain to limit nuclear weapons testing. He said the agreement was one of the presidential acts of which he was most satisfied.</p>
<p>Historians still debate Kennedy's actions, and what else might have happened during his presidency. They wonder especially what he would have done about the increasing conflict in Vietnam.</p>
<p>But Kennedy did not live to finish his first term.</p>
<p><strong>Death</strong></p>
<p>By November 22, 1963, Kennedy had been president for just under three years. The next election was still a year away, but it was time to start campaigning again.</p>
<p>So the president and his wife went to Dallas, Texas to connect with voters. They were riding in a car with other official vehicles that drove slowly through the center of the city. Jack, Jackie, and the Texas governor and his wife sat in a convertible – an automobile without protection over the seats.</p>
<p>The president was waving at the crowd. Suddenly, several gunshots were fired. The president was struck twice.</p>
<p>The governor was also hit and injured.</p>
<p>Kennedy was hurried to a hospital, but doctors were unable to help him. News reporters announced his death to a stunned public.</p>
<p>Hours later, Jackie Kennedy appeared next to the former vice president – now president – Lyndon Johnson. She still wore the clothes with her husband's blood on them.</p>
<p>The events remain intense in the minds of many Americans who were alive at the time. The images remain easily recognizable parts of American history. The pictures of Kennedy's family at his funeral are especially memorable. In one, three-year-old John holds up his arm and salutes his father's <strong>casket</strong>.</p>
<p>Attention quickly turned to the gunman. It was reportedly a 24-year-old man named <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/retropolis/wp/2017/10/25/jfks-assassin-lee-harvey-oswalds-eerie-calm-the-day-before-he-pulled-the-trigger/?hpid=hp_no-name_hp-in-the-news%3Apage%2Fin-the-news&amp;tid=sm_tw&amp;utm_term=.511aa2475a9e">Lee Harvey Oswald</a>. Shortly after the president and the governor were shot, Oswald shot a policeman who questioned him.</p>
<p>Oswald was eventually detained. Officials planned to bring him to court for the death of the president and the policeman. But on the way from the police station to the jail, a local <strong>night-club</strong> owner shot and killed Oswald.</p>
<p>As a result, the case never came to trial. Many Americans believe the reason for the attack has yet to be clarified.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy </strong></p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/kennedy/impact-and-legacy">Historians have a mixed reaction</a> to Kennedy's years as a president, although their opinions are generally <strong>positive</strong>.</p>
<p>His image with the public suffered some years after his death because of reports that he had romantic relationships with women other than Jackie throughout his marriage.</p>
<p>In time, the public also learned about Kennedy's health problems. He suffered from severe back pain and Addison's disease. He often used strong medicine to help control the conditions. The health problems are <strong>at odds</strong> with Kennedy's image of health and love of sports.</p>
<p>Yet even with these new details, Kennedy is still one of the country's best-remembered leaders. He was a <strong>charismatic</strong> man whose career influenced many other Americans to enter public service.</p>
<p>Americans also remember his stylish, cultured wife. Jackie Kennedy compared the Kennedy years at the White House to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.livescience.com/28992-camelot.html">Camelot</a>, the legendary court of King Arthur.</p>
<p>Their remains, along with those of two of their children, are buried at <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.arlingtoncemetery.mil/Explore/Monuments-and-Memorials/President-John-F-Kennedy-Gravesite">Arlington National Cemetery</a>, across the Potomac River from Washington. They are honored there with an <strong>eternal flame</strong> – one designed so the fire will never go out.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>________________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>content</strong> -<em> n. </em>the things that are in something</p>
<p><strong>legacy</strong> -<em> n.</em> something that happened in the past or that comes from someone in the past</p>
<p><strong>casket</strong> - <em>n. </em>coffin</p>
<p><strong>nightclub</strong> - <em>n.</em> a place that is open at night, has music, dancing, or a show, and usually serves alcoholic drinks and food</p>
<p><strong>positive</strong> - <em>adj.</em> showing or expressing support, approval, or agreement</p>
<p><strong>at odds</strong> -<em> n.</em> not agreeing with each other : in a state of disagreement</p>
<p><strong>charismatic</strong> -<em> adj. </em>having great charm or appeal : filled with charisma</p>
<p><strong>eternal </strong>-<em> adj.</em> having no beginning and no end in time : lasting forever</p>
<p><strong>flame</strong> - <em>n.</em> the hot, glowing gas that can be seen when a fire is burning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Right Whale Number Decrease Slowing, But Threats Remain  (2023/10/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/right-whale-number-decrease-slowing-but-threats-remain.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The North Atlantic right whale is one of the world's most endangered large whale <strong>species</strong>.</p>
<p>Its population loss appears to be slowing. But scientists warn that the large sea animals still face threats from getting caught in fishing equipment, being struck by ships, and warming oceans.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A North Atlantic right whale feeds on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/74e35c76-344c-467e-935b-85c58896f2e5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A North Atlantic right whale feeds on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)</span></div>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/species/north-atlantic-right-whale/overview">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</a> (NOAA) says that by the early 1890s, <strong>commercial</strong> whalers almost destroyed the species. They got their name from being the "right" whales to hunt because they floated when they were killed.</p>
<p>Commercial whale fishing is no longer a threat, but its population has never fully returned. They have been protected under United States law for many years now.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic right whale is about 16 meters long and weighs more than 63,000 kilograms. The whales can probably live for 70 years. However, female North Atlantic right whales are now only living to around 45 years old. Such reduced <strong>lifespans</strong> are caused by human activities, not old age.</p>
<p>The NOAA estimates that fewer than 350 right whales are remaining off the U.S. East Coast. From 2010 to 2020, their population fell by about 25 percent.</p>
<p>This week, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.narwc.org/">North Atlantic Right Whale Consortium</a> (NARWC) said the population decrease appears to have leveled off. A strong birthing year in 2021, when 18 baby whales, or calves, were born, kept whale population numbers up, the NARWC said.</p>
<p>However, the organization warned that the high number of deaths faced by whales from getting caught in fishing equipment or struck by ships remains a major problem for the whales.</p>
<p>"The news is less bad than it has been. My heart is a little less heavy, but certainly not light or hopeful," said Philip Hamilton. He is a member of NARWC and a senior scientist at the Anderson Cabot Center for Ocean Life at the New England Aquarium. "It shouldn't be dependent on the whales to give birth to enough calves to <strong>reverse</strong> what we're doing to them."</p>
<p>Scientists say another reason why whale numbers are decreasing is warming oceans and climate change. The whales eat very small ocean organisms called copepods. They travel from calving grounds off the coasts of Florida and Georgia to feeding grounds off New England and Canada every year.</p>
<p>As waters have warmed, the whales must travel outside of protected areas of the ocean in search of food. That has left them open to strikes with large ships and getting trapped in commercial fishing equipment. Those are the biggest causes of early death.</p>
<p>Many fishermen have opposed proposed fishing restrictions that they fear would hurt their business rather than help whales. Dave Cousens, a past president of the Maine Lobstermen's Association, has called the proposed rules "<strong>nonsensical</strong>."</p>
<p>But environmental groups want new federal rules to save the species, including one to make ships slow down for whales.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Garance Burke and Matt O'Brien reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong><em>– adj.</em> related to or used in the buying and selling of goods and services</p>
<p><strong>lifespan </strong><em>– n. </em>the amount of time that a person or animal actually lives</p>
<p><strong>reverse </strong><em>– v.</em> to change (something) to an opposite state or condition</p>
<p><strong>nonsensical </strong><em>– adj. </em>very foolish or silly</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Beatles Song Created with a Little Help from AI  (2023/10/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/new-beatles-song-created-with-a-little-help-from-ai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A "new" song from the Beatles, with help from artificial intelligence, comes out next week.</p>
<p>The song, called <em>Now And Then</em>, will be available on November 2. It is part of a single along with <em>Love Me Do</em>. In 1962, <em>Love Me Do</em> came out as the first Beatles single.</p>
<p><em>Now And Then </em>comes from the same group of unreleased recordings written by Beatle John Lennon, who died in 1980. His former bandmates used some of the media to build the songs <em>Free As a Bir</em>d and <em>Real Love</em> released in the mid-1990s.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this Aug. 23, 1966 file photo, The Beatles, from left, Ringo Starr; Paul McCartney; John Lennon; and George Harrison appear at a press conference in New York. (AP Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ab9e-08dbd66f9b40_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this Aug. 23, 1966 file photo, The Beatles, from left, Ringo Starr; Paul McCartney; John Lennon; and George Harrison appear at a press conference in New York. (AP Photo)</span></div>
<p>Paul McCartney, Ringo Starr and George Harrison worked on <em>Now And Then</em> at the same time. But, technological limitations blocked their progress. George Harrison died in 2001.</p>
<p>With the help of artificial intelligence (AI), movie director Peter Jackson was able to solve those tech problems. He used AI to "separate" Lennon's voice from the sound of the piano used in the late 1970s recording. The much clearer vocals permitted the surviving members, McCartney and Starr, to complete the song last year.</p>
<p>The new single contains guitar work that Harrison had recorded almost 30 years ago. Drummer Starr provided new sound along with McCartney's bass, piano and guitar. McCartney and Starr also sang with Lennon.</p>
<p>McCartney also added a string instrument piece written with the help of Giles Martin, son of the late Beatles producer George Martin.</p>
<p>And, they weaved in background singing<strong> </strong>from the first Beatles recordings of <em>Here, There and Everywhere</em>, <em>Eleanor Rigby</em> and <em>Because</em>.</p>
<p>"There it was, John's voice, <strong>crystal</strong> clear," McCartney said in the announcement of the new song. "It's quite emotional. And we all play on it," he added.</p>
<p>Harrison's <strong>widow</strong>, Olivia, said "he would have wholeheartedly" joined Paul and Ringo in completing the song now if he were still alive.</p>
<p>Next Wednesday, the day before the song's release, a 12-minute film that tells the story of the new recording will be made public.</p>
<p>Later in the month, expanded versions of the Beatles' albums <em>1962-1966</em> and <em>1967-1970, </em>will be released. The later years' collection will get the addition of the song <em>Now And Then</em>.</p>
<p>The surviving Beatles have skillfully released new projects. They made remixes of old albums. They also worked with director Jackson's 2021 documentary series, <em>The Beatles</em>: <em>Get Back</em>.</p>
<p>This year is the big <strong>finale</strong> of new Beatles music.</p>
<p>"This is the last track, ever, that you'll get the four Beatles on the track. John, Paul, George, and Ringo," Starr said in a recent interview with the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>David Bauder of the Associated Press wrote this report. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>crystal </strong><em>– n. </em>something resembling crystal in transparency and colorlessness</p>
<p><strong>widow </strong><em>– n. </em><em> </em>a woman who has lost her spouse or partner by death and usually has not remarried</p>
<p><strong>finale </strong><em>– n. </em>the close or termination of something: such as</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>This and That  (2023/10/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/this-and-that.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the use of "this, that, these, those."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5d19-08dbd649089c_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Please, how should I use the pronouns "this, that, these, those" beyond the <strong>notion</strong> of near or far?</p>
<p>Thanks a lot,</p>
<p>Odilon</p>
<p><strong>Answer </strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Odilon. This is an excellent question!</p>
<p>We know that the words "this, that, these, those" have many meanings and uses in English.</p>
<p>One meaning of "this/these" is to note someone or something is near in physical distance. "That/those" can note someone or something that is far in physical distance. Here are two examples:</p>
<p><em>You can say, "<u>This</u> book is mine" while holding it in your hand. </em></p>
<p><em>And you can say, "<u>That</u> book is yours" while pointing at one on the table across the room. </em></p>
<p><strong>Time </strong></p>
<p>Near and far can also demonstrate time. "This" can mean now or current, and "that" can mean before or earlier. For example,</p>
<p><em>The solar <strong>eclipse</strong> will not happen again <u>this</u> year. </em></p>
<p><em>The last supermoon came in September. At <u>that</u> time, the moon's orbit brought it closer than usual to Earth. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, "this" notes the current year. In the second sentence, "that" refers to a time in the past.</p>
<p><strong>Preference </strong></p>
<p>We can also use "this/that" to show preference or a desirable choice. "This" can demonstrate a more desirable choice, and "that" can demonstrate a less desirable choice. Here are two examples:</p>
<p><em><u>This</u> is my favorite restaurant. </em></p>
<p><em><u>That</u> doesn't sound very fun. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, "this" shows the restaurant is the best choice, and "that" in the second sentence demonstrates the idea is not a desirable one.</p>
<p><strong>Focus, or attention </strong></p>
<p>"This/these" also has an additional use. We can use "this/these" for focus, or attention, to establish new information. Using "this/these" can direct the reader's or listener's attention to important information. Here is an example.</p>
<p><em>And <u>this</u> is one major concern about the use of artificial intelligence: ownership. </em></p>
<p>"This" directs the reader to pay attention to the new information that is coming in the sentence. The important information in the sentence is a major concern. Ownership is the major concern.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Odilon.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>notion</strong>–<em>n</em>. idea or belief</p>
<p><strong>eclipse</strong>–<em>n</em>. an event in which the sun is blocked by the moon, or when the moon passes through the Earth's shadow</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>China Sends Its Youngest-ever Crew, Enters New Space Race  (2023/10/27) | 中国将最年轻航天员乘组送入空间站</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/china-sends-its-youngest-ever-crew-enters-new-space-race.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>China launched its youngest-ever crew for its orbiting space station Thursday. The launch is part of the country's plan to put astronauts on the moon before 2030.<br/>
中国周四将其有史以来最年轻的航天员送上了轨道空间站。此次发射是中国在2030年前将航天员送上月球计划的一部分。</p>
<p>The Shenzhou 17 spacecraft lifted off from the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in northwestern China at 03:14 UTC. The China Manned Space Agency said the average age of the three-member crew is the youngest since the launch of the space station. Their average age is 38, state media China Daily said.<br/>
神舟十七号宇宙飞船于协调世界时03:14从中国西北部的酒泉卫星发射中心升空。中国载人航天局表示，这3名机组人员的平均年龄是天宫空间站发射以来最年轻的。据官方媒体《中国日报》报道，他们的平均年龄为38岁。</p>
<p>The three astronauts are Tang Hongbo, Tang Shengjie, and Jiang Xinlin. They will replace a crew that has been on the station for six months.<br/>
这三名航天员分别是汤洪波、唐胜杰和江新林。他们将接替已经在空间站工作了六个月的航天员乘组。</p>
<p>The new crew will perform experiments in space medicine, space technology, and other areas during their mission. And they will help to place and do possible repairs to equipment inside and outside the station, the agency said.<br/>
这个新的航天员乘组将在任务期间进行太空医学、太空技术和其他领域的实验。该机构表示，他们将帮助安装空间站内外的设备，并对其进行可能的维修。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">New space race<br/>
新太空竞赛</span></p>
<p>China also has plans to place astronauts on the moon before the end of 2030 in competition with the United States in space exploration. This follows other competition for influence between the world's two largest economies in the technology, military, and diplomatic fields.<br/>
中国还计划与美国在太空探索方面展开竞争，在2030年底前将航天员送上月球。此前，世界上最大的这两个经济体在技术、军事和外交领域展开了其他影响力竞争。</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, the Chinese space agency also announced plans to send a new telescope to look deep into the universe. Chinese state broadcaster CCTV said the telescope would permit for mapping of the sky, but no timeline was given for when it would be placed.<br/>
周三早些时候，中国航天局还宣布计划发射一台新望远镜深入探索宇宙。中国国家广播公司CCTV表示，该望远镜将允许绘制天空地图，但没有给出任何具体的时间表。</p>
<p>In 2022, the Chinese government built its own space station after it was not permitted to join the U.S.-led International Space Station.<br/>
在未被允许加入美国领导的国际空间站后，中国政府于2022年建造了自己的空间站。</p>
<p>China's first manned space mission in 2003 made it the third country after the former Soviet Union and the U.S. to put a person into space using its own resources.<br/>
2003年，中国首次执行载人航天任务，成为继前苏联和美国之后第三个利用本国资源将航天员送入太空的国家。</p>
<p>The American space program is believed to be far ahead of China at this time. But, China has made some important steps. They include bringing back samples from the moon's surface for the first time in many years and landing a vehicle on the less explored far side of the moon.<br/>
据信，美国的太空计划目前远远领先于中国。但是，中国已经取得一些重要的进展。其中包括多年来首次从月球表面带回样本，以及将一辆运载工具降落在探索较少的月球背面。</p>
<p>The U.S., meanwhile, aims to put astronauts back on the moon's surface by the end of 2025. It is aided by private American companies like SpaceX and Blue Origin.<br/>
与此同时，美国的目标是在2025年底前让航天员重返月球表面。它得到了像太空探索技术公司和蓝色起源公司这样的美国私营公司的帮助。</p>
<p>In addition to their moon, or lunar, programs, the two countries have also separately landed vehicles on Mars. And China plans to follow the U.S. in landing a spacecraft on an asteroid.<br/>
除了月球计划外，两国还分别在火星上着陆了运载工具。中国计划效仿美国，将一艘宇宙飞船降落在小行星上。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Detect Ancient Energetic Burst  (2023/10/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/researchers-detect-ancient-energetic-burst.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Astronomers have<strong> detected</strong> radio waves coming from what looks like a joining of galaxies from about 8 billion years ago. The discovery is the oldest-known example of an event that is difficult to explain: a fast radio<strong> burst</strong>.</p>
<p>In less than a <strong>millisecond</strong>, this burst released the amount of energy our sun releases in thirty years, scientists said.</p>
<p>The Australian SKA Pathfinder, a radio telescope in the state of Western Australia, detected the burst. And the European Southern Observatory's Very Large Telescope in Chile, one of the most powerful telescopes, found the <strong>location</strong> of the burst.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This artist's impression, not to scale, illustrates the path of a fast radio burst from the distant galaxy where it originated all the way to Earth in this handout picture obtained on October 20, 2023. (ESO/M. Kornmesser/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/83ec49f4-4a01-4776-b8b8-ae0be83e4262_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This artist's impression, not to scale, illustrates the path of a fast radio burst from the distant galaxy where it originated all the way to Earth in this handout picture obtained on October 20, 2023. (ESO/M. Kornmesser/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>A fast radio burst, or FRB, is a kind of radio-frequency electromagnetic radiation. It lasts less than a millisecond but outshines most other sources of radio waves in the universe. Radio waves have the longest wavelengths in the electromagnetic spectrum.</p>
<p>Ryan Shannon, an astronomer at Swinburne University of Technology in Australia, was a co-leader of the study published recently in Science.</p>
<p>He said radio waves in FRBs are similar to those used in microwave ovens. And he added that this FRB had the same amount of energy needed to microwave "a bowl of popcorn twice the size of the sun."</p>
<p>Until now, the oldest-known such burst dated to 5 billion years ago, making this one 3 billion years older. The universe is about 13.8 billion years old. For comparison, Earth is about 4.5 billion years old.</p>
<p>In seeing objects and events from long ago, researchers look across large distances, making this burst also the farthest of any FRB ever detected.</p>
<p>"We now know that fast radio bursts have been around for more than half the age of the universe," said study co-leader Stuart Ryder of Macquarie University in Australia.</p>
<p>Researchers first discovered fast radio bursts in 2007.</p>
<p>The most likely source is a special kind of "<strong>neutron star</strong>, called a magnetar. These stars ... are some of the most extreme objects in the universe, which you would need to produce such extreme bursts," Shannon said.</p>
<p>"There are more energetic events in the universe, associated with <strong>stellar</strong> explosions or a black hole <strong>shredding</strong> a star apart. But FRBs are <strong>unique</strong> in that they produce all their energy in radio waves, with nothing seen in other bands - optical light or X-rays for example - and that the signals are so short," Shannon added.</p>
<p>They also are more common, Shannon explained, with around 100,000 thought to happen somewhere in the universe daily. Far fewer have been detected, Shannon said, and only around 50 - including this one - have been <strong>traced</strong> back to the galaxy where they began.</p>
<p>The scientists said that studying these bursts can help to detect and measure the large amount of matter believed to populate the large distances of space between galaxies.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>detect </strong><em>-- v. </em> to discover or notice the presence of something</p>
<p><strong>burst </strong><em>– n.</em> a short period of producing or doing something that begins suddenly</p>
<p><strong>millisecond </strong><em>– n.</em> one-thousandth of a second</p>
<p><strong>location</strong><em> -- n. </em>a place or position</p>
<p><strong>neutron star </strong><em>– n.</em> a small and very dense kind of stellar object</p>
<p><strong>stellar </strong><em>– adj.</em> of or relating to the stars</p>
<p><strong>shred </strong><em>– v.</em> to cut or tear (something) into long pieces</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong><em> -- adj. </em>used to say that something or someone is unlike anything or anyone else</p>
<p><strong>trace </strong><em>-- v. </em> to follow something back to its cause or beginning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Program Could Permit Visa Holders to Renew in US  (2023/10/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/us-program-could-permit-visa-holders-to-renew-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. State Department is working on a test program that would permit some work visa holders to <strong>renew</strong> their documents in the United States.</p>
<p>The pilot program would involve holders of H-1B visas. This kind of visa permits highly skilled foreigners to enter the U.S. for work purposes for at least three years.</p>
<p>Currently, H-1B visa holders are required to travel to an American diplomatic office outside the U.S. to seek renewals</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A visa application center of VFS Global is seen in Istanbul, Turkey, Aug. 25, 2022. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c0a3-08db896660c8_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A visa application center of VFS Global is seen in Istanbul, Turkey, Aug. 25, 2022. </span></div>
<p>A State Department spokesperson told VOA the pilot program aims to improve "the <strong>uncertainty</strong> often experienced by U.S. companies" that temporarily employ H-1B workers. The official communicated by email. The official spoke to VOA on the condition that they not be identified.</p>
<p>The official said that the State Department would judge whether the policy change would improve the availability and speed of visa approvals worldwide.</p>
<p>Immigration lawyers have long urged the administration of President Joe Biden to bring back U.S. visa renewals that were ended in 2004. They say the current renewal process can make it difficult for U.S.-based foreign employees to get appointments at U.S. diplomatic offices abroad. And the travel linked to those appointments can be very costly.</p>
<p>The spokesperson said the State Department is hoping to begin accepting renewal documents by the end of this year. The program is to begin with officials inviting a small number of visa holders to take part.</p>
<p>But the spokesperson said the program must first go through a rule-making process, which will start at the White House. Once those rules are decided, the State Department will seek public comments and consider any necessary changes. The proposal will then go back to the White House for final review.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Aline Barros reported this story for VOA News. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>renew </strong><em>– v. </em>to arrange to continue an official agreement that is set to end soon</p>
<p><strong>uncertainty </strong><em>– adj. </em>not sure or not able to decide about something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Halloween  (2023/10/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/grammar-and-halloween.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An interesting holiday in the United States is coming up soon. Halloween happens on the last day of October. If you have lived in the U.S., you have probably noticed many changes in the month or so before Halloween. Let's hear about some of them and explore the vocabulary and expressions you might hear this time of year.</p>
<p><strong>‘Trick-or-treat'</strong></p>
<p>First, you should know about trick-or-treating. Children <strong>dress</strong> <strong>up</strong> in special clothes, or costumes, to look like frightening creatures. They might dress up as little <strong>vampires</strong>, <strong>ghosts</strong> and <strong>witches </strong>or superheroes. Then their parents walk with them to the homes of neighbors, where the children knock at the door and call out, "Trick or treat!"</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-4cc8-08dbd581255f_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Some people believe the custom goes back to an old Celtic celebration in which people went from door to door asking for firewood. The Celts believed that the spirits of the dead would return to their homes on October 31, the day of the autumn feast. The Celts would build large fires to frighten away evil spirits on that night.</p>
<p>In modern-day Halloween, the children ask for candy. That's the "treat" part. The "trick" part is what happens if you do not give them something.</p>
<p>Before Halloween, communities might create a "<strong>haunted</strong> house" in an old house or an open field. Visitors can walk through the place and be frightened and surprised by unusual noises and people dressed up like ghosts or spirits.</p>
<p>Fear plays a big part in Halloween celebrations. The words we use to talk about fear include "scary," an adjective to show something causes fear and "afraid" an adjective that describes the person who feels fear. We might say, "I'm scared of ghosts," to say we are afraid of ghosts.</p>
<p>Another word we use to describe things that cause fear is "<strong>spooky</strong>." Little people trying to look like ghosts might say, "Boo!" to frighten others. Let's put some of these expressions together to see how they work.</p>
<p><em>Greg has a really scary costume this year. He said "Boo!" to me and I jumped!</em></p>
<p><em>Caty's house looks really spooky with all those skeletons and spider webs that she put out in her yard.</em></p>
<p><em>I'm not afraid of ghosts but seeing people dressed up as witches scares me!</em></p>
<p>You will see that stores begin offering many kinds of candies in small packages. We call these "individually wrapped" treats. They are meant for handing out to children as part of trick-or-treating. Some candy makers call these small packages "fun-sized" treats.</p>
<p><strong>Halloween decorations</strong></p>
<p>People put some strange things on and around their homes for Halloween. People hang toy spiders, skeletons and other scary <strong>decorations</strong> on trees and bushes. You will see pumpkins everywhere. People often empty the pumpkins and make scary faces on them. Then they place a candle inside so the pumpkin face shines in the night. We call these "jack-o-lanterns."</p>
<p>The custom of carving scary faces into vegetables is believed to come to us from the Irish. They had an old story about a wandering soul named Stingy Jack. They carved faces in turnips to frighten him away. When they came to America, they found the pumpkin was widely available. So, they carved faces into pumpkins, and made what we call the jack-o-lantern today. Now, children carry plastic buckets made to look like a carved pumpkin. They fill them with candy as they trick-or-treat around their neighborhood.</p>
<p>We close with a usual conversation around Halloween in the U.S. See how many traditions and customs you can spot.</p>
<p><em>A: Are you going to any Halloween parties this year?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No, I have to take my kids trick-or-treating. Then I'm too tired to dress up and go out to a party. Are you going?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Yes, I'm going to be a vampire this year. My block has a great party with a haunted house every year.</em></p>
<p><em>B: Oh, I wish I could go. Hey, will you help me carve these pumpkins? I want to put them out front.<br/>
B: Sure, I love carving jack-o-lanterns. Can I have some of that candy while I'm working?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Of course. Help yourself to those fun-sized Hershey bars. I only have a hundred of them.</em></p>
<p>Does your culture have any celebrations where you dress up or give out treats? Write to us in the comments to tell us about them!</p>
<p>And that's Everyday Grammar for Halloween. Boo!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dress up </strong><em>– v.</em> to wear a special kind of clothing for a festival or event</p>
<p><strong>vampire – </strong><em>n. </em>a dead person who leaves the grave at night to bite and suck the blood of living people</p>
<p><strong>ghost – </strong><em>n. </em>the soul of a dead person thought of as living in an unseen world or as appearing to living people</p>
<p><strong>witch – </strong><em>n. </em>a woman who is thought to have magic powers</p>
<p><strong>candy – </strong><em>n. </em>a sweet food made with sugar or chocolate</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI Tool Aims to Predict Virus Variants before They Appear  (2023/10/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/ai-tool-aims-to-predict-virus-variants-before-they-appear.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have created an artificial intelligence (AI) tool that aims to predict different virus versions, called variants, before they appear.</p>
<p>Creators of the tool say it works by estimating the likelihood that a variant will permit it to escape the body's own <strong>immunity</strong> defenses.</p>
<p>The tool is called EVEscape. It works by processing collected data on the development, or evolution, of a virus over time. The system also considers detailed biological and structural information related to the virus.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by The National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases shows the SARS-CoV-2 virus. (NIAID-RML via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3874-08dbd580cc27_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">
This image provided by The National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases shows the SARS-CoV-2 virus. (NIAID-RML via AP)</span></div>
<p>The method is a form of "generative AI," a term describing technology tools designed to operate at human levels. EVEscape was developed by researchers from Britain's University of Oxford and Harvard Medical School in Boston, Massachusetts. The team's findings recently appeared <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06617-0">in a study</a> in the publication <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>Many viruses repeatedly <strong>mutate</strong> in an effort to stay alive and strong. This requires viruses to infect living organisms. Once inside the body, viruses continue to reproduce and spread.</p>
<p>The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/variants/index.html">explains</a> that repeated mutating creates new variants. Some of these mutations permit the virus "to spread more easily or make it resistant to treatments or vaccines," the CDC said.</p>
<p>The researchers built on previous work involving a tool they created called EVE. This tool was designed to study gene mutations that can cause human disease. In a past study, the team said it successfully used EVE to identify mutations linked to conditions like cancer and heart disease.</p>
<p>During the COVID-19 pandemic, the scientists said they recognized a good chance to "rebuild" EVE into a new tool "for the purpose of predicting viral variants."</p>
<p>To do this, the team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://hms.harvard.edu/news/ai-tool-can-help-forecast-viral-outbreaks">explained</a> it "turned the clock back to January 2020, just before the COVID-19 pandemic started." The researchers asked the EVEscape tool to predict what mutations would develop from the SARS-CoV-2 virus that causes COVID-19.</p>
<p>The researchers reported the tool correctly predicted which SARS-CoV-2 mutations would appear and which would become most common, or dominant.</p>
<p>The team also <a class="wsw__a" href="https://hms.harvard.edu/news/ai-tool-can-help-forecast-viral-outbreaks">said</a> the tool predicted which antibody-based treatments "would lose their efficacy as the pandemic progressed and the virus developed mutations to escape these treatments."</p>
<p>The study noted EVEscape can make predictions more quickly and effectively than lab-based methods. This is because the tool does not need "to wait for <strong>relevant</strong> antibodies to arise in the population and become available for testing."</p>
<p>The team said the system was able to examine tens of thousands of new virus variants appearing each week and identified the ones most likely to become problematic.</p>
<p>Sarah Gurev is a student in the Electrical Engineering and Computer Science program at the Massachusetts Institute of Technoology (MIT). She was a leader of the research. Gurev said that by quickly identifying the threat level of new variants, "we can help inform earlier public health decisions."</p>
<p>The team said it continuously uses the system to examine real-time data about the development of new variants of SARS-CoV-2. It then shares this information with the public and international agencies such as the World Health Organization (WHO).</p>
<p>The researchers said their experiments also showed the EVEscape tool could successfully predict mutating behaviors for other common viruses, including HIV and the flu.</p>
<p>Debora Marks is a professor of systems biology at Harvard Medical School's Blavatnik Institute. She was a lead writer of the study. She said the researchers would continue to improve the tool's ability to predict new variants for a number of viruses. "Because if we can, that's going to be extremely important for designing vaccines and <strong>therapies</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Oxford University, Harvard Medical School and Nature. </em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>immunity </strong><em>– n. </em>bodily power to resist an infectious disease</p>
<p><strong>mutate </strong><em>– v. </em>to cause a gene to change and create an unusual characteristic in a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>efficacy</strong> <em>– n. </em> the ability to produce a desired result</p>
<p><strong>relevant </strong><em>– adj. </em>related or useful to what is happening or being talked about</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong><em>– n. </em>a treatment method for disease</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Part of Antarctica to Experience ‘Unavoidable’ Melt  (2023/10/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-part-of-antarctica-to-experience-unavoidable-melt.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new study says that no matter how much the world cuts back on carbon <strong>emissions</strong>, a large and important part of Antarctica is expected to disappear.</p>
<p>Researchers used computer models to predict the future melting of protective ice around Antarctica's Amundsen Sea in western Antarctica. They said the "unavoidable" melting will take hundreds of years. It will slowly add nearly 1.8 meters to sea levels. And it will be enough to reshape where and how people live in the future.</p>
<p>The study was published recently in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/nclimate/"><em>Nature Climate Change</em></a>. It found that even if future warming was limited to just a few tenths of a degree more, it would have "limited power to prevent ocean warming that could lead to the collapse of the West Antarctic Ice Sheet."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by British Antarctic Survey, shows the North Cove, in Antarctic. (Michael Shortt/British Antarctic Survey via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b89651bb-aab0-4e18-8706-f5c8bfa0a0ce_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/>
<br/>
<span class="imagecaption">
This undated image provided by British Antarctic Survey, shows the North Cove, in Antarctic. (Michael Shortt/British Antarctic Survey via AP)</span></div>
<p>Many scientists say the goal of just a few tenths of a degree of warming is unlikely to be met.</p>
<p>"Our main question here was: How much control do we still have over ice <strong>shelf</strong> melting? How much melting can still be prevented by reducing emissions?" said study lead writer Kaitlin Naughten. She is an expert on oceans at the British Antarctic Survey.</p>
<p>She said their research suggests that Earth is set on the path to a quick increase in the rate of ocean warming and ice shelf melting over the rest of the century.</p>
<p>While past studies have talked about how serious the situation is, Naughten was the first to use computer modeling to study how warm water from below will melt the ice.</p>
<p>The study looked at four different cases in how much carbon emissions the world produces. In each case, ocean warming was just too much for this area of the ice to survive, the study found.</p>
<p>Naughten looked at melting, floating areas of ice that hold back <strong>glaciers</strong>. Once these areas of ice melt, there is nothing to stop the glaciers behind them from flowing into the sea.</p>
<p>The study also looked at what would happen if future warming was limited to 1.5 degrees Celsius over mid-19th century levels: the international goal. They found the <strong>runaway</strong> melting process in this case as well.</p>
<p>The world has already warmed about 1.2 degrees Celsius since pre-industrial times and much of this summer went past the 1.5 degrees mark.</p>
<p>Naughten's study looked at the part of the West Antarctic Ice Sheet that is most at risk from melting from below, near the Amundsen Sea. It includes the very large Thwaites ice shelf that is melting so fast it is called "the Doomsday Glacier."</p>
<p>That part of Antarctica "is <strong>doomed</strong>," said University of California Irvine ice scientist ice scientist Eric Rignot. He was not part of the study. He added, "The damage has already been done."</p>
<p>Naughten does not like to use the word "doomed," because she said 100 years from now, the world might not just stop but drive back carbon levels in the air and climate change. But she said what is happening now on the ground is a slow collapse that cannot be stopped, at least not in this century.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>emission </strong>– <em>n</em>. the act of producing or sending out something (such as energy or gas) from a source</p>
<p><strong>shelf </strong>– <em>n</em>. a flat area of rock, sand, or ice, especially underwater</p>
<p><strong>glacier </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very large area of ice that moves slowly down a slope or valley or over a wide area of land</p>
<p><strong>runaway </strong><em>– adj.</em> operating, running, or increasing in a fast and dangerous way that cannot be controlled</p>
<p><strong>doom </strong>– <em>n</em>. very bad events or situations that cannot be avoided</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US, Australia to Provide Underwater Internet Cables for Pacific Islands  (2023/10/26) | 美澳为太平洋岛国提供互联网服务</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/us-australia-to-provide-underwater-internet-cables-for-pacific-islands.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The technology company Google will work together with the United States and Australia to offer internet service to Pacific Island nations such as Tuvalu.<br/>
科技公司谷歌将与美国和澳大利亚合作，为图瓦卢等太平洋岛国提供互联网服务。</p>
<p>The agreement continues a project Google is working on in the area.<br/>
该协议延续了谷歌在该地区正在进行的一个项目。</p>
<p>The announcement came on the same day that Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visited with U.S. President Joe Biden at the White House.<br/>
就在宣布这一消息的同一天，澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞在白宫拜访了美国总统乔·拜登。</p>
<p>The state visit has been planned for a long time.<br/>
这次国事访问计划已久。</p>
<p>The underwater cable project will bring internet service to Tuvalu, Micronesia, Kiribati, the Marshall Islands, Papua New Guinea, the Solomon Islands, Timor-Leste and Vanuatu.<br/>
该海底电缆项目将为图瓦卢、密克罗尼西亚、基里巴斯、马绍尔群岛、巴布亚新几内亚、所罗门群岛、东帝汶和瓦努阿图提供互联网服务。</p>
<p>A Biden administration official said Australia will provide $50 million for the project and the U.S. will give $15 million.<br/>
拜登政府的一名官员表示，澳大利亚将为该项目提供5000万美元，美国将提供1500万美元。</p>
<p>The Pacific islands are an area of interest for both the U.S. and China. Each nation has been working to expand their relationships with the island nations. They have been promising military partnerships and building projects.<br/>
太平洋岛屿是美国和中国都感兴趣的地区。两国都在努力扩大他们与这些岛国的关系。他们一直承诺建立军事伙伴关系和建设项目。</p>
<p>Biden has said work by U.S. telecommunications and internet companies such as Google is a national security issue. The companies that own or oversee cables that connect small countries to the internet can control the flow of information around the world.<br/>
拜登表示，谷歌等美国电信和互联网公司所做的工作是一个国家安全问题。拥有或监督将小国连接到互联网的电缆的公司可以控制世界各地的信息流。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·费里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pakistan Prepares to Deport Illegal Afghans  (2023/10/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/pakistan-prepares-to-deport-illegal-afghans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Pakistani government has approved the creation of several <strong>deportation</strong> centers for hundreds of thousands of Afghans living illegally in the country. Pakistan plans to arrest and send the Afghan nationals back to Afghanistan starting next month.</p>
<p>The government recently approved the Illegal Foreigners Repatriation Plan. It sets a November 1 <strong>deadline</strong>. The deadline is for all "illegal/unregistered foreigners" and those overstaying their visas. These groups are required to return to their countries. If they do not, they face deportation for breaking Pakistan's immigration laws.</p>
<p>Pakistani Interior Minister Sarfaraz spoke when the deadline was announced in early October. He said an estimated 1.7 million Afghans are among those facing deportation.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Afghan refugees board a bus from Karachi, Pakistan, to Afghanistan on Sept. 21, 2023. Pakistan, on Oct. 3, 2023, ordered undocumented immigrants to leave the country by Nov. 1. (Photo by Rizwan TABASSUM / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ddb72e6e-86fe-4073-93a7-b010d5f81de8_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">
Afghan refugees board a bus from Karachi, Pakistan, to Afghanistan on Sept. 21, 2023. Pakistan, on Oct. 3, 2023, ordered undocumented immigrants to leave the country by Nov. 1. (Photo by Rizwan TABASSUM / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Official <strong>sources</strong> told VOA that special deportation centers would be established in four areas: Punjab, Sindh, Baluchistan, and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa.</p>
<p>Afghans detained in Punjab and Sindh will be moved to centers in the Rawalpindi and Karachi areas.</p>
<p>Khyber Pakhtunkhwa will have two deportation centers in Nowshehra and Chamkani. While Baluchistan will have three centers: one in the capital of Quetta, and others in the areas of Pishin and Qilla Abdullah districts. These two areas are on Pakistan's 2,600-kilometer border with Afghanistan. Most refugee families are in those areas.</p>
<p>The new plan <strong>empowers</strong> local administrations, police, and other officials to detain and deport Afghan nationals illegally living in the country. The plan also says that individuals charged with or on trial for minor crimes will be sent out of the country. It also says that those charged with or facing trial for "serious crimes" will not be sent back to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Pakistan has promised to carry out the deportations in "a <strong>phased </strong>and orderly" way. It also said that it would not target the 1.4 million Afghan refugees living legally in the country. The government added it would not target 900,000 Afghan citizens who are registered in Pakistan as economic migrants.</p>
<p>The government has told law enforcement agencies not to <strong>harass</strong> legal refugees and those with Afghan nationality documents. However, Afghanistan's Taliban rulers and refugee families have claimed that some Afghans experienced abuse and mistreatment from the police.</p>
<p>The Taliban have called on Pakistan to reconsider the deportation plan, calling it "<strong>inhumane</strong>" and "unacceptable." However, they have recently set up special camps on the Afghan side of the border. The camps will provide immediate shelter, health care, food, and financial assistance to families returning from the neighboring country.</p>
<p>Officials in both countries have confirmed that tens of thousands of Afghans have voluntarily returned to their home country since Pakistan announced the deadline nearly a month ago.</p>
<p>Taliban spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid on Afghan television urged Pakistan to treat Afghan refugees "humanely" and extend the period of deportation. He asked all the refugees to return to their country. He said the Taliban has made Afghanistan into a "safer and better" place.</p>
<p><strong>Taliban rule in Afghanistan </strong></p>
<p>The Taliban seized power from a U.S.-backed government in August 2021. At that time, U.S. and NATO troops left the country after nearly 20 years of involvement in the Afghan war.</p>
<p>After the Taliban took over, hundreds of thousands of people fled to Pakistan. They feared punishment for their connections to Western forces. They included human rights defenders, former government officials, professionals, female activists and reporters.</p>
<p>Many have since moved to the U.S. and other Western countries. But thousands are waiting in hopes of immigrating to the United States or Europe.</p>
<p>The Taliban has enforced Islamic law in the country. The group has barred <strong>teenage </strong>girls from schools and many women from work. The restrictions mean many refugee families do not want to return to Afghanistan. They say their daughters cannot seek education or work in the country.</p>
<p>The United Nations has urged Pakistan to suspend its deportation plan. It warns the plan could mean Afghans will be subject to abuse by the country's ruling Taliban officials.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Ayaz Gul reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>deport </strong>– <em>v</em>. to force (a person who is not a citizen) to leave a country</p>
<p><strong>deadline </strong>– <em>n</em>. a date or time when something must be finished</p>
<p><strong>source </strong>–n. a person who tells a reporter information</p>
<p><strong>empower </strong>– <em>v</em>. to give official authority or legal power to (someone)</p>
<p><strong>phased </strong><em>– adj.</em> done gradually in steps and according to a plan</p>
<p><strong>harass </strong>– <em>v</em>. to annoy or bother (someone) in a constant or repeated way</p>
<p><strong>humane </strong><em>– adj.</em> kind or gentle to people or animals</p>
<p><strong>teenage </strong>– <em>adj</em>. between 13 and 19 years old</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Publishers Worry Over Google’s New AI Search Tool   (2023/10/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/publishers-worry-over-google-s-new-ai-search-tool.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Publishing companies are growing increasingly concerned about <strong>generative AI</strong>, especially a <strong>model</strong> developed by Google.</p>
<p>Since May, Google has begun releasing a new form of search in the United States, India, and Japan powered by generative AI. The product is called Search Generative Experience, or SGE. SGE uses AI to create <strong>summaries </strong>for some search questions. Google says those summaries appear on the top of the Google search homepage, with links to "dig deeper."</p>
<p>If publishers want to prevent their content from being used by Google's AI to create those summaries, they must use the same tool that would prevent them from appearing in Google search results. That would make it difficult for people using search to find the publishers that choose not to be involved in SGE.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman passes the logo from the web search engine provider Google during the digital society festival 're:publica', at the Arena Berlin in Berlin, Germany June 9, 2022. (REUTERS/Annegret Hilse)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/94f7b5b3-e02a-4eeb-9cca-5185e660ce40_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">
A woman passes the logo from the web search engine provider Google during the digital society festival 're:publica', at the Arena Berlin in Berlin, Germany June 9, 2022. (REUTERS/Annegret Hilse)</span></div>
<p>Google says that the AI-generated summaries are put together from many web pages and that the links are designed to be a starting point to learn more. The company describes SGE as an <strong>opt-in</strong> experiment for users, who will help develop and improve the product.</p>
<p>To publishers, however, the new search tool is the latest concern in an unusual relationship. Publishers both compete against Google for online advertising and depend on the company for search traffic.</p>
<p>Four major publishers spoke to Reuters news agency recently. The businesses said they are trying to understand their place in a world where AI could control how users find and pay for information. The publishers asked not to be identified because of ongoing negotiations with Google.</p>
<p>Publisher concerns relate to a number of issues. They include the issue of web traffic; whether publishers will be credited as the providers of information that appears in the SGE summaries; and whether those summaries are correct. Most importantly, publishers want to be paid for the <strong>content</strong> on which Google and other AI companies train their AI tools.</p>
<p>A Google spokesperson said in a statement: "As we bring generative AI into Search, we're continuing to <strong>prioritize </strong>approaches that send valuable traffic to a wide range of creators, including news publishers, to support a healthy, open web."</p>
<p>On the issue of payments, Google said it is developing a better understanding of the business of generative AI<strong> applications</strong> and getting opinions from publishers and others.</p>
<p>In late September, Google announced a new tool called Google-Extended. It gives publishers the choice to block their content from being used by Google to train its AI models.</p>
<p>Giving publishers the choice to not be used for AI is a "good faith<strong> gesture</strong>," said Danielle Coffey, president and chief executive of the News Media Alliance, an industry trade group. "Whether payments will follow is a question mark, and to what extent there is openness to having a healthier value exchange," Coffey added.</p>
<p>The new tool does not permit publishers to block their content from being used for SGE without disappearing from traditional Google search.</p>
<p>Publishers want evidence that people are using their websites to secure advertisers. Showing up in Google search is important to their business. The design for SGE has pushed the links that appear in traditional search further down the webpage. That might reduce traffic to those links by as much as 40 percent, said an official at one of the publishers.</p>
<p>More worrying is the possibility that people searching the web will avoid <strong>clicking </strong>any of the links if the SGE passage meets the users' need for information.</p>
<p>Nikhil Lai is an expert with Forrester Research, a company based in Cambridge, Massachusetts. He said SGE is "definitely going to decrease publishers'...traffic and they're going to have to think about a different way to measure the value of that content, if not click through rate."</p>
<p>Even so, he believes publishers will remain trusted because their links will appear in SGE.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Helen Coster reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>generative AI</strong> <em>– n.</em> a type of artificial intelligence technology that can produce different kinds of content</p>
<p><strong>model</strong> <em>– n.</em> a particular type or version of a product</p>
<p><strong>summary</strong> <em>–n. </em>a restatement of written material that is shorter and contains only the main points</p>
<p><strong>opt-in</strong><em> —n.</em> to choose to do or be involved in something</p>
<p><strong>content</strong> <em>– n. </em>the things that are in something; the ideas, facts, or images that are in a book, article, speech, movie, etc.</p>
<p><strong>prioritize </strong>–<em> v.</em> to organize (things) so that the most important thing is done or dealt with first</p>
<p><strong>application</strong> <em>– n. </em>a computer program that performs a particular task</p>
<p><strong>gesture</strong> <em>– n.</em> something said or done to show a particular feeling or attitude</p>
<p><strong>click</strong> <em>–n. </em>electronic evidence that a person has looked at a website</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More US States Teach Financial Education in High School  (2023/10/25) | 越来越多美国州要求高中进行理财教育</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/more-us-states-teach-financial-education-in-high-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>An increasing number of American states are requiring that students receive personal finance education in order to complete high school. At the same time, states are hoping to improve math skills among students in the United States.<br/>
美国越来越多州要求学生接受个人理财教育才能完成高中学业。与此同时，各州希望提高美国学生的数学技能。</p>
<p>Capital City Public Charter School in Washington, D.C. has a course called Advanced Algebra with Financial Applications. The school has offered the math class for more than 10 years. The class provides students with basic knowledge about money management and helps them sharpen their math skills. Classes discuss credit, investments, and loans, for example, and connect these ideas with methods of math for calculating interest, budgeting and more.<br/>
华盛顿特区首都公立特许学校开设了一门名为“高级代数与金融应用”的课程。这所学校开设这门数学课程已有10多年了。该课程为学生提供有关资金管理的基本知识，并帮助他们提高数学技能。例如，课程讨论信贷、投资和贷款，并将这些想法与计算利息、预算等的数学方法联系起来。</p>
<p>The high school may be a leader in providing financial education, but in recent years, many others have offered similar courses.<br/>
这所高中可能是提供金融教育的领导者，但近年来，许多其他学校也开设了类似的课程。</p>
<p>Since 2020, nine U.S. states have passed laws or policies requiring schools to provide personal finance education before students can graduate from high school. The U.S. non-profit organization, Council for Economic Education, says 30 states now have such policies in place.<br/>
自2020年以来，美国九个州通过了法律或政策，要求学校在学生高中毕业前提供个人理财教育。美国非营利组织经济教育委员会表示，目前已有30个州制定了此类政策。</p>
<p>The increase comes as educators are trying to improve students' math skills, which dropped during the pandemic and have not fully recovered. At the same time, a general dislike or disinterest for math remains a barrier among young people.<br/>
这一增长正值教育工作者试图提高学生的数学技能之际，数学技能在疫情期间有所下降并且尚未完全恢复。与此同时，对数学的普遍厌恶或不感兴趣仍然是年轻人的一个障碍。</p>
<p>Tonica Tatum-Gormes teaches the course at the Washington school. She said students get more interested in math when they see how it connects with their future financial well-being.<br/>
托尼卡·泰特姆-戈麦斯这所华盛顿学校教授这门课程。她说，当学生们看到数学与他们未来的经济状况之间的联系时，他们会对数学更感兴趣。</p>
<p>Students begin to understand that "‘yes, I need to learn decimals, and I need to learn fractions, and I need to learn percentages because I have to manage my money and I have to take out a loan,'" Tatum-Gormes said.<br/>
泰特姆-戈麦斯说：“学生们开始明白，‘是的，我需要学习小数，我需要学会分数，我需要学百分比，因为我必须管理我的资金，我必须取得贷款。’”</p>
<p>Supporters say personal finance courses help students learn how to make smart money decisions and develop an interest in math as a result.<br/>
支持者表示，个人理财课程有助于学生学习如何做出明智的理财决策，并因此培养对数学的兴趣。</p>
<p>The Council for Economic Education says financial education should include exploring subjects like earning, budgeting, saving, investing, and managing credit and financial risk. Experts say the class does not have to be taught by a traditional math teacher.<br/>
经济教育委员会表示，金融教育应包括探索诸如收入、预算、储蓄、投资以及信贷和金融风险管理等科目。专家表示，这门课不必由传统数学老师来教。</p>
<p>Idaho is one of the states where a new financial literacy requirement is in place.<br/>
爱达荷州是实施新的金融知识要求的州之一。</p>
<p>The new program will give students the chance to use skills from their algebra, calculus, and economics classes in real life. In the class, they will calculate their future student loans, rent payments, and income requirements.<br/>
新课程将让学生有机会在现实生活中运用代数、微积分和经济学课程中的技能。在课堂上，他们将计算未来的学生贷款、租金和收入要求。</p>
<p>Experts say the 2007-2008 financial crisis, pandemic-linked economic insecurity and current high inflation may have increased Americans' desire for stronger financial knowledge. Less than one-fourth of millennials show basic financial literacy, the Council for Economic Education says.<br/>
专家表示，2007-2008年的金融危机、与疫情相关的经济不安全以及当前的高通胀可能增加了美国人对更强大金融知识的渴望。经济教育委员会表示，只有不到四分之一的千禧一代具备基本的金融知识。</p>
<p>In 2020, the American civil rights group, NAACP, released a resolution calling for more financial literacy programs in K-12 schools.<br/>
2020年，美国民权组织全国有色人种协进会发布了一项决议，呼吁在K-12学校开展更多的金融扫盲课程。</p>
<p>A study by the non-profit Next Gen Personal Finance Schools looked at states without high school financial literacy requirements. It found that in schools with mainly Black and Hispanic student populations, only seven percent of students have access to a half-school year personal finance course. That figure rises to 14.2 percent for schools with less than a quarter of students identifying as Black or Hispanic.<br/>
非营利组织“下一代个人金融学校”的一项研究考察了没有高中金融素养要求的州。研究发现，在以黑人和西班牙裔学生为主的学校，只有7%的学生能够上半学年的个人理财课程。对于黑人或西班牙裔学生不到四分之一的学校，这一数字上升到14.2%。</p>
<p>That lack of fairness is a driving force behind the financial literacy course at Capital City Public Charter School. It serves a student population that is 64 percent Latino and 25 percent Black.<br/>
这种缺乏公平是首都公立特许学校金融素养课程背后的驱动力。它为拉丁裔占64%和黑人占25%的学生群体提供服务。</p>
<p>"It's an empowering course," says Laina Cox, head of the school. "I think it gives our young people the language that they need and the voice when they're in certain rooms and at certain tables."<br/>
该校校长莱娜·考克斯表示：“这是一门充满力量的课程。我认为，当我们的年轻人在某些场合时，它给了他们所需要的语言和声音。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why the Interest Rate of US Treasury Notes Matters  (2023/10/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/why-the-interest-rate-of-us-treasury-notes-matter.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. government needs money to operate.</p>
<p>A lot of that money comes from taxes. However, much of the money the U.S. government uses to pay its costs comes from borrowing in the form of U.S. Treasury securities.</p>
<p>Investors, who believe the U.S. government will be able to pay them back, agree to loan the government money for a period of time. They receive interest payments regularly or in a way set by the Treasury.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Federal Reserve Chairman Jerome Powell speaks at a meeting of the Economic Club of New York, Oct. 19, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig, file)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ab6003e3-0af3-4943-aefe-b4e1290c264c_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/>
<br/>
<span class="imagecaption">
Federal Reserve Chairman Jerome Powell speaks at a meeting of the Economic Club of New York, Oct. 19, 2023, in New York. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig, file)</span></div>
<p>The difference between the loan amount and the investment return is called the yield.</p>
<p>In past years, the interest rate on the U.S. government 10-year note was low. For example, when the COVID-19 pandemic started, the interest rate for a 10-year government debt security was less than one percent. If you loaned the U.S. government $100, you would receive about one dollar a year in interest until the note "matures," or is paid back.</p>
<p>Now, however, the yield has jumped to about five percent for a 10-year note. A note is a debt security with a term of between two and 10 years. That means investors who agree to lend money to the U.S. government for a period of 10 years will earn about a five percent return each year.</p>
<p>That sounds good for investors. But everyone is not happy about it.</p>
<p>The reason is that many other interest rates are tied to the U.S. rate for the 10-year note.</p>
<p>In a recent report, the Associated Press called the 10-year note "the <strong>centerpiece</strong> of the global financial system."</p>
<p>Many mortgage rates, the interest rates people pay for their home loans, are connected to the 10-year note. As a result, borrowing money becomes more costly. Over the life of a 30-year home mortgage agreement, a homeowner could pay hundreds of thousands of dollars more in interest than just two or three years ago.</p>
<p>In addition, the high rates on the 10-year note make it harder for some new businesses to grow. A young business often does not make money. But if it wants to hire new people or create a new product, it will often take out a loan from a bank or agree to pay investors interest. Since the financial crisis of 2008, the cost of these loans has mainly been very low – only a little higher than zero percent interest.</p>
<p>The low rates permitted many companies to borrow money at a low cost. Many of the world's economies that were struggling recovered because of the low rates. Individual investors bought stocks because they did not see a large cost to borrow money. They did not see U.S. Treasury securities as a good investment because their interest rates were so low.</p>
<p>But now, interest rates are rising. As a result, some businesses are choosing not to expand. Some are even reducing their workforce in order to reduce operating costs.</p>
<p><strong>Why did the interest rates rise so fast?</strong></p>
<p>The cost of living increased quickly once many countries re-opened after the pandemic. Cars, food and energy prices all went higher. The war in Ukraine reduced the food and energy supply in Europe and Africa, so those costs increased for Europeans and Africans.</p>
<p>Many people found that the usual amount of money did not buy the usual amount of goods. That is called inflation. In some countries, the price of food and energy doubled in a short time. Home prices increased because many people decided they needed more space if they were going to do their jobs from home.</p>
<p>The fast inflation concerned government banks around the world. In countries such as the U.S. and areas like Europe, central banks decided to raise the interest rates they control as a way to reduce, or slow, inflation.</p>
<p>Central bankers believe that increasing interest rates can keep people and businesses from spending too much money. To a point, the plan has worked. In the U.S., some data shows inflation is slowing.</p>
<p>Economists who study the U.S. have been surprised that the economy stayed strong even as interest rates for Treasury securities have increased. People are still spending money and the employment rate is high.</p>
<p>But some investors are thinking that a yield of about 5 percent is better than putting money into stocks that might lose value. As a result, stocks prices have dropped since the summer.</p>
<p>Because U.S. Treasury securities are not a high-risk investment, the U.S. dollar has gotten stronger compared to the Euro, the British pound and the Australian dollar.</p>
<p>High interest rates also hurt some investors who decided to put their money in safe U.S. Treasury securities five or 10 years ago. If those investors purchased bonds paying a lower interest rate than today, they would lose money if they tried to sell those securities on the open market now.</p>
<p>One large investment <strong>fund</strong> that purchases U.S. debt securities with different terms has lost three percent of its value this year. If this situation continues, the fund is <strong>on track</strong> to lose value for the third year <strong>in a row</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver. </p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fund (mutual fund) </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind of investment that uses the money from many different people to buy investments and which shares the risk and returns with its investors</p>
<p><strong>on track </strong><em>–adj. </em>happening as expected</p>
<p><strong>in a row </strong><em>–adj.</em> one after another</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Women in Iceland, Including PM, Strike for Equal Pay  (2023/10/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/women-in-iceland-including-pm-strike-for-equal-pay.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Iceland's prime minister and women across the island nation went on strike Tuesday. They are pushing for an end to unequal pay and <strong>gender</strong>-based violence.</p>
<p>Icelanders awoke to all-male news teams announcing shutdowns across the nation. Schools closed down, public transportation was delayed, hospitals had fewer workers, and hotel rooms went uncleaned.</p>
<p>Katrin Jakobsdóttir is Iceland's prime minister. She said that she would stay home as part of the women's strike and expected other women on her cabinet to do the same.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="People across Iceland gather during the women's strike in Reykjavik, Iceland, Tuesday, Oct. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Arni Torfason)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7ee5-08dbd4b469a2_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">
People across Iceland gather during the women's strike in Reykjavik, Iceland, Tuesday, Oct. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Arni Torfason)</span></div>
<p>Iceland's trade <strong>unions</strong> are the main organizers of the strike. They called on women and <strong>nonbinary</strong>, a term to describe those who do not identify as male or female, to strike. They refused to do both paid and unpaid work, including household work, for the day. About 90 percent of Icelandic workers belong to a union.</p>
<p>Schools and the health system, which have large female workforces, said they would be heavily affected by the walkout. National broadcaster RUV said it was reducing television and radio broadcasts for the day.</p>
<p>Tuesday's walkout lasts from midnight to midnight. It is called the biggest strike since Iceland's first such event on October 24, 1975. That was when 90 percent of women refused to work, clean or look after children, to express anger at discrimination in the workplace.</p>
<p>In 1976, Iceland passed a law guaranteeing equal rights of men and women. Since then, there have been several partial-day strikes. The most recent one came in 2018, with women walking off the job in the early afternoon. That represented the time of day when women, on average, stop earning compared to men.</p>
<p>Iceland is a country of about 380,000 people. It sits just below the Arctic Circle in the North Atlantic Ocean. It has been ranked as the world's most gender-equal country 14 years straight by the World Economic Forum, which measures pay, education, health care among others. No country has reached full equality, and there remains a gender pay <strong>gap</strong> in Iceland.</p>
<p>"We have not yet reached our goals of full gender equality and we are still <strong>tackling</strong> the gender-based wage gap, which is unacceptable in 2023," the prime minster said.</p>
<p>The cabinet is evenly split between male and female ministers. Nearly half of lawmakers in Iceland's parliament are women.</p>
<p>Many women in Iceland are in high paying and powerful positions. But the lowest paying jobs, such as cleaning and child care, are still mostly done by women.</p>
<p>The work is very important for Iceland's <strong>tourism</strong> economy. It also depends heavily on immigrants, who largely work longer hours and take home the lowest pay. Around 22 percent of the female workforce is foreign born, found Statistics Iceland.</p>
<p>Large parts of the center of the capital, Reykjavík, will be closed to traffic ahead of a protest on Tuesday afternoon. Protest signs, posted on social media before the event, hit back at the idea that Iceland is already perfect for women with the <strong>slogan</strong>, "You call this gender equality?"</p>
<p>Iceland's 1975 strike led to similar protests in other countries including Poland. There, women boycotted jobs and classes in 2016 to protest a proposed abortion ban.</p>
<p>In Spain, women struck for 24 hours in 2018. The country's major unions estimated that 5.3 million people joined the strike.</p>
<p>Spain's Equality Minister Irene Montero said Tuesday that the 2018 strike was <strong>inspired</strong> by Iceland's 1975 walkout. She expressed full support for the latest protest.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gender </strong><em>— n. </em>a person's own sense of being male, female, some combination of male and female, or neither male nor female</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>union </strong><em>— n. </em>an organization of workers formed to protect the rights and interests of its members</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nonbinary </strong><em>— n. </em>not identifying as male or female</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gap </strong><em>— n. </em>a space between two people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tackle </strong><em>— v. </em>to deal with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tourism </strong><em>— n. </em>the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>slogan </strong><em>— n. </em> a word or phrase that is easy to remember and is used by a group or business to attract attention</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inspire </strong><em>— v. </em>to give an idea about what to do or create</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Propose ‘Law of Nature’ Expanding on Evolution  (2023/10/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-propose-law-of-nature-expanding-on-evolution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>British naturalist Charles Darwin presented his theory of <strong>evolution</strong> in the 1859 book <em>On the Origin of Species</em>. He proposed that biological species change over time by gaining <strong>traits</strong> that help them survive and reproduce.</p>
<p>Now 164 years later, nine scientists and philosophers propose a new "law of nature" that includes the biological evolution described by Darwin. They say Darwin's theory is a striking example of a much larger happening that appears at the level of atoms, minerals, planetary atmospheres, planets, stars and more.</p>
<p>"We see evolution as a universal process that <strong>applies</strong> to numerous systems, both living and nonliving, that increase in <strong>diversity</strong> and <strong>patterning</strong> through time," said Robert Hazen. He is a mineralogist and astrobiologist at the Carnegie Institution for Science based in Washington, D.C. Hazen is a co-writer of the scientific paper describing the new law in the publication <a class="wsw__a" href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2310223120" target="_blank">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</a>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Pigeon bones are displayed in Charles Darwin's former home Down House, Kent, southern England February 12, 2009. (REUTERS/Tal Cohen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0292-08dbd00f9100_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Pigeon bones are displayed in Charles Darwin's former home Down House, Kent, southern England February 12, 2009. (REUTERS/Tal Cohen)</span></div>
<p>The scientists propose a rule called "the law of increasing functional information." It holds that evolving systems, biological or non-biological, always form from several interacting building blocks like atoms or cells. The process, they say, creates many different combinations. Evolution happens when these combinations are subject to selection for useful functions, or purposes.</p>
<p>"We have well-documented laws that describe such everyday <strong>phenomena</strong> as forces, motions, gravity, electricity and magnetism and energy," Hazen said. "But these laws do not, individually or collectively, describe or explain why the universe keeps getting more diverse and complex at scales of atoms, molecules, minerals and more."</p>
<p>For example, scientists say just two elements, hydrogen and helium, made up the first generation of stars following the Big Bang at the beginning of our universe about 13.8 billion years ago.</p>
<p>That first generation of stars created about 20 heavier elements such as carbon, nitrogen, and oxygen in their centers, or cores. These elements exploded into space at the end of the stars' life cycles. The following generation of stars that formed from parts of the first generation then similarly created almost 100 more elements.</p>
<p>But Hazen said only a small number of all possible combinations would "work." They have some useful level of function. So, nature just prefers them, he said.</p>
<p>Hazen added that "function" might mean that a collection of atoms makes a stable mineral <strong>crystal</strong> that can survive, or that a star keeps its active structure, or that "a life form learns a new 'trick' that <strong>allows</strong> it to compete better than its neighbors," Hazen added.</p>
<p>The writers proposed three universal ideas about selection: the basic ability to last; the lasting nature of active processes that may enable evolution; and the development of new qualities as an <strong>adaptation</strong> to an environment.</p>
<p>The scientists said some biological examples include organisms developing the ability to swim, walk, fly and think. Humans developed after their ancestors evolved from chimpanzees and gained traits including upright walking and increased brain size.</p>
<p>Michael Wong is the paper's lead writer and an astrobiologist and planetary scientist at the Carnegie Institution. He said, "I think this paper is important because it describes a view of the <strong>cosmos</strong> rooted in function."</p>
<p>Jonathan Lunine is chair of Cornell University's astronomy department. He is another of the paper's writers. He said the new law explains "why the diverse systems that make up the cosmos evolve the way they do."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Reuters and other sources. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>evolution</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>the process by which living creatures change in ways that make them better able to survive over long periods of time</p>
<p><strong>trait</strong> <em>–n.</em> a particular quality that a person of thing has that makes it different from another thing</p>
<p><strong>apply </strong>–v. to have an effect on something</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong>–n. the quality of including many different kinds of things</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong>–v. to order something in a particular or repeating way</p>
<p><strong>phenomenon </strong>–n. (pl. phenomena) something that happens that can be observed</p>
<p><strong>crystal </strong>–n. a form of an element or mineral that is regularly and geometrically structured</p>
<p><strong>allow </strong>–v. to let happen</p>
<p><strong>adaptation </strong>–n. the quality of changing to meet a need or to survive</p>
<p><strong>cosmos </strong>–n. the universe as an ordered system</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Controller Aims to Make Gaming Easier for People with Disabilities  (2023/10/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/new-controller-aims-to-make-gaming-easier-for-people-with-disabilities.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Paul Lane uses his mouth and face to push buttons and guide his virtual car on <em>Gran Turismo</em>,<em> </em>a game on the PlayStation 5. It is how he has been playing for the past 23 years, after a car accident left him unable to use his fingers.</p>
<p>Playing video games has long been difficult for people with disabilities. The controllers for the PlayStation, Xbox or Nintendo can be very hard, or even impossible, to use for people with limited mobility.</p>
<p>As part of the gaming industry's efforts to fix the problem, Sony has worked with Lane and others to develop the new Access controller for PlayStation. Other companies, including Microsoft, and even people with <strong>3-D</strong> printers have also created their own <strong>accessible</strong> controllers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Paul Amadeus Lane uses a Sony Access controller to play a PlayStation 5 video game at Sony Interactive Entertainment headquarters Thursday, Sept. 28, 2023, in San Mateo, Calif. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;squez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7973-08dbd0afeb44_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Paul Amadeus Lane uses a Sony Access controller to play a PlayStation 5 video game at Sony Interactive Entertainment headquarters Thursday, Sept. 28, 2023, in San Mateo, Calif. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V<i>&amp;#</i>225;squez)</span></div>
<p>"I was big into sports before my injury," said Cesar Flores. The 30-year-old has used a wheelchair since a car accident eight years ago. He also worked with Sony on the controller. "And when I play video games, it reminds me that I'm still human. It reminds me that I'm still one of the guys."</p>
<p>Putting the traditional controller aside, Lane, 52, switches to the Access. It is round and <strong>customizable</strong> and can rest on a table or wheelchair <strong>tray.</strong> It can be customized in many ways, depending on what the user needs. That includes switching buttons and thumbsticks, programming special controls and combining two controllers to be used as one. As Lane plays <em>Gran Turismo</em>, he uses the back of his hand on the controller.</p>
<p>Lane and other gamers have been working with Sony since 2018 to help design the Access controller. The idea was to create something that could work for many people with different needs, rather than centering on any particular disability.</p>
<p>Mark Barlet is the founder and executive director of the nonprofit AbleGamers. He said his organization has been supporting gamers with disabilities for nearly 20 years. AbleGamers also helped both Sony and Microsoft with their controllers.</p>
<p>"The last five years I have seen the game accessibility movement go from (independent) <strong>studios</strong> working on some features to triple-A games being able to be played by people who identify as blind," he said. "In five years, it's been <strong>breathtaking</strong>."</p>
<p>PlayStation's Access controller will go on sale worldwide on December 6 and cost $90 in the U.S.</p>
<p>Alvin Daniel of PlayStation said the device was designed with three ideas in mind to make it usable for as many players as possible.</p>
<p>First, the player does not have to hold the controller to use it. It can lay flat on a table or wheelchair tray, for example. It was important for it to fit on a wheelchair tray, since once something falls off the tray, it might be impossible for the player to pick it up without help. It also had to be <strong>durable</strong> for this same reason.</p>
<p>Second, it is much easier to press the buttons than on the common controller. It comes with buttons in different sizes and shapes so people can experiment with shaping it the way it works best for them. The third is the thumbsticks, which can also be changed depending on what works for the person using it.</p>
<p>After his accident, Lane stopped gaming for seven years. For someone who began playing video games as a young child, "it was a <strong>void</strong>" in his life, he said.</p>
<p>"Having gaming and having an <strong>opportunity</strong> to game at a very high level, to be able to do it again, it is like a reunion, (like losing) a close <strong>companion</strong> and being able to reunite with that person again."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>3-D </strong><em>— n. </em>made in a way that causes an image to appear to be three-dimensional</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>accessible </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be used or obtained</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>customize </strong><em>— v. </em>to change in order to fit the needs or requirements of a person, business, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tray </strong><em>— n. </em> a thin, flat, and often rectangular piece of plastic, metal, wood, etc., that has a low rim and that is used for carrying things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>studio </strong><em>— n. </em>the building or room where an artist works</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breathtaking </strong><em>— adj. </em>very great or surprising</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>durable </strong><em>— adj. </em>staying strong and in good condition over a long period of time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>void </strong><em>— n. </em>a large empty space</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>opportunity </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>companion </strong><em>— n. </em>a person or animal you spend time with or enjoy being with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Uganda’s President Aims to Ban Used Clothing from the West  (2023/10/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/uganda-s-president-aims-to-ban-used-clothing-from-the-west.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>People, rich and poor, crowd into Owino Market. Owino is a huge open market in Kampala, the capital city of Uganda. People here are mostly looking for secondhand clothing, clothes that have been worn by someone else. The clothes are usually low-cost but still are well made.</p>
<p>Such clothes usually come from Europeans and Americans who no longer want or need them. Businesses purchase the used clothing, and other businesses export them to sell in Africa. The business is valued at millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Some people say the demand for such clothes demonstrates that Africans believe Western <strong>fashion</strong> is better than clothes made in Africa.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ugandans buy used clothes at Owino Market, in Kampala, Uganda, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d66d-08dbcf655942_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ugandans buy used clothes at Owino Market, in Kampala, Uganda, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)</span></div>
<p>In 2017, the U.S. Agency for International Development aimed to find out about the clothes East Africans buy. Its study found that about two-thirds of people in seven East African countries have "purchased at least a <strong>portion</strong> of their clothes from the secondhand clothing market."</p>
<p>Although they are popular, secondhand clothes are facing increasing resistance. Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni has held power in Uganda since 1986. He declared in August that he was banning imports of used clothing. He said the clothes are "from dead people."</p>
<p>"When a white person dies, they gather their clothes and send them to Africa," Museveni said.</p>
<p>Trade officials have not yet enforced the president's declaration, which requires a legal measure, such as an executive order.</p>
<p>Other African governments are trying to stop used clothing imports, saying the business is like sending waste to Africa and harms local cloth industries.</p>
<p>The East African Community trade bloc includes Burundi, Congo, Kenya, Rwanda, South Sudan, Tanzania and Uganda. It has advised banning imports of secondhand clothing since 2016. However, member states have not put bans into effect.</p>
<p>In Uganda, the president's statement has spread concern among traders. A ban would put them out of business. Traders sell used clothes across the country of 45 million people. They do business in large open-air markets, roadside stands and even in stores in <strong>malls</strong>.</p>
<p>A group of traders in Kampala, known as KACITA, opposes a ban on secondhand clothing. The group suggests slowly reducing the imports so that local clothing producers can develop the ability to meet demand.</p>
<p>Some Ugandan clothing makers, like Winfred Arinaitwe, admit that the quality of locally made cloth is often poor. Many people choose to buy used clothing, she said.</p>
<p>"Because it lasts longer," she said, "it can easily be seen."</p>
<p>In Owino Market, a ban on used clothes is unbelievable to many. Some say they do not believe the president's threat.</p>
<p>Abdulrashid Ssuuna's job is to get people in the market to visit his brother's used clothing business. He said a ban would deny him a way to make a living.</p>
<p>"It's like they want to chase us out of the country," he said of the president's order. He said he cannot <strong>afford</strong> to sell new clothes.</p>
<p>The market is competitive, with sellers sitting behind <strong>heaps</strong> of clothes and shouting words of welcome to possible buyers.</p>
<p>If he helps his brother sell clothing, "I get something," said Ssuuna, who started this work after dropping out of high school in 2020.</p>
<p>The market is always full of buyers, but business is unpredictable. Traders must try to imagine what people want before other sellers do.</p>
<p>Tadeo Walusimbi has been a used clothing trader for six years. He said some days are better than others, but he warned a government ban would not be supported.</p>
<p>It "will not work for me and for so many people," Walusimbi said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Rodney Muhumuza reported this story for Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fashion</strong>–<em>n</em>. a kind of clothing that is popular at a given time</p>
<p><strong>portion</strong>–<em>n</em>. a part of a whole amount</p>
<p><strong>mall</strong>–<em>n</em>. a large building that has many stores inside it</p>
<p><strong>afford</strong>–<em>v</em>. to have enough money to pay for something</p>
<p><strong>heap</strong> –<em>n</em>. a large, disordered group of things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Build First AI Tool to Discover Supernovas  (2023/10/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/researchers-build-first-tool-to-discover-supernovas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists say they have built an artificial intelligence (AI) tool that can successfully identify and confirm supernovas.</p>
<p>A supernova is an "extremely bright, super-powerful explosion of a star," the American space agency NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://spaceplace.nasa.gov/supernova/en/">reports</a>. The explosion takes place at the end of a star's life.</p>
<p>The current process for discovering supernovas usually involves both machines and people. Telescopes repeatedly collect images of the night sky and compare these images to identify differences in observed objects. These differences can suggest the presence of supernovas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A deep-space image shows the galaxy where the supernova happened. (Image Credit: Legacy Surveys/D. Lang (Perimeter Institute/NASA/JPL-Caltech) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-31f9-08dbd0f759df_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A deep-space image shows the galaxy where the supernova happened. (Image Credit: Legacy Surveys/D. Lang (Perimeter Institute/NASA/JPL-Caltech) </span></div>
<p>Robotic telescopes can present a list of possible supernovas to human scientists. This data is then examined by human scientists whose job it is to identify and confirm supernova candidates. Now, for the first time, researchers say they have successfully used an AI tool to complete all steps in this process.</p>
<p>An international team of scientists developed the AI-based system. Researchers from Northwestern University in Chicago, Illinois led the team. The team's chief was Adam Miller, an assistant professor of Physics and Astronomy at Northwestern.</p>
<p>Miller <a class="wsw__a" href="https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2023/10/first-supernova-detected-confirmed-classified-and-shared-by-ai/">said</a> his team recently informed the international astronomical community of its success with the new AI system. The tool is called the Bright Transient Survey Bot, or BTSbot.</p>
<p>The robot was used to find, identify and <strong>classify</strong> a supernova for the first time, Miller said. He noted that researchers had spent more than 2,000 hours over the past six years looking at telescope data in order to find and classify supernova candidates.</p>
<p>"For the first time ever, a series of robots and AI algorithms has observed, then identified, then communicated with another telescope to finally confirm the discovery of a supernova," Miller said.</p>
<p>The researchers say the new system can take over much of the work humans now do looking for and classifying supernovas. This can free up scientists to do more in-depth examinations of the supernovas themselves and the reasons they were created.</p>
<p>In order to confirm a supernova, scientists have to examine its spectrum. The spectrum represents the object's <strong>dispersed</strong> light, which shows elements that were present during the explosion of a supernova.</p>
<p>The study of supernovas has high scientific value because it can help astronomers learn more about the universe and how it began. For example, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://spaceplace.nasa.gov/supernova/en/">says</a> scientists have learned a lot about the behaviors and chemical processes of stars from supernovas.</p>
<p>Miller said the new tool can help researchers "<strong>analyze</strong> their observations and develop new <strong>hypotheses</strong>" to explain why the supernova explosions happened.</p>
<p>Nabeel Rehemtulla co-led the research and development of the BTSbot. He said the tool greatly "streamlines large studies of supernovas." This helps scientists better understand the life cycles of stars and helps to identify elements supernovas create, such as carbon, iron and gold, Rehemtulla noted.</p>
<p>The research team said testing of the BTSbot involved looking at a newly discovered supernova candidate called SN2023tyk. The AI tool identified the supernova on October 5.</p>
<p>After the identification, the BTSbot requested additional data on its own from the California-based Palomar Observatory. Then, another telescope, known as the SED Machine, performed its own "in-depth observations" to get information on the object's spectrum.</p>
<p>The SED Machine then sent the spectrum data to the California Institute of Technology (Caltech). Caltech uses an AI <strong>algorithm</strong> to classify the kind of supernova. This can either be a thermonuclear explosion of a white dwarf or the collapse of a star's center, or core.</p>
<p>The algorithm classified the supernova a Type 1a, a kind of star explosion in which a white dwarf in a star system fully explodes.</p>
<p>Rehemtulla said the success of the BTSbot will ease supernova identifications, while freeing up human scientists to do more detailed study of the newly discovered objects.</p>
<p>"The beauty of it is that, once everything is turned on and working properly, we don't actually do anything," Rehemtulla noted. "We go to sleep at night, and, in the morning, we see that BTSbot, and these other AIs, <strong>unwaveringly</strong> do their jobs."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Northwestern University and NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>classify </strong><em>– v. </em>to put people or things together in groups based on their kind, size, etc.</p>
<p><strong>disperse </strong><em>– v. </em>to separate and go into different directions</p>
<p><strong>analyze </strong><em>– v. </em>examine the details of something</p>
<p><strong>hypothesis </strong><em>– n. </em>a theory for something that has not yet been proven</p>
<p><strong>algorithm </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of steps that are followed in order to solve a mathematical problem or to complete a computer process</p>
<p><strong>unwavering </strong><em>– adj. </em>not moving of changing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Tiny Antarctic Ocean Animal Raises Big Questions  (2023/10/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/tiny-antarctic-ocean-animal-raises-big-questions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Antarctic krill, a relative of shrimp and crabs, are only a few centimeters in size. But scientists say they are important to the area's <strong>food web</strong>, including food for some of the Earth's largest animals, whales.</p>
<p>Fishing ships in the Antarctic gather krill for use as food in an increasing number of products. That has activists concerned.</p>
<p>Alistair Allan is an activist with the Bob Brown Foundation, an Australian environmental group with ties to the country's Green Party. Allan said he was worried the ship activity could harm the whales: "You have the ships almost running into whales feeding on the same things they're fishing."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey shows an Antarctic krill (Euphausia suberba). (Chris Gilbert/British Antarctic Survey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9a99-08dbcf5f10d0_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey shows an Antarctic krill (Euphausia suberba). (Chris Gilbert/British Antarctic Survey)</span></div>
<p>Krill fishing is banned in U.S. waters because of concerns it could affect whales, seals and other sea animals. But krill fishing has gone on for about 60 years. It is believed to have started when the former Soviet Union sent an industrial fleet to the Antarctic in search of a supply of high-protein food.</p>
<p>Demand has increased over the years. Krill is used a lot in the fish farming industry. They are also used in nutritional supplements, pet food and other high-protein foods.</p>
<p>The Associated Press reports that 10 to 12 ships, mainly from Norway and China, head to the South Orkney Islands, to fish for krill each December. Fishing countries agreed to a catch limit under a <strong>conservation</strong> agreement. In 2022, that level was about 416,000 metric tons.</p>
<p>A coalition of countries led by the U.S. has called for additional restrictions. The coalition says krill is important to other animals. It also says that krill removes greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. However, China and Russia have opposed efforts to put in place new restrictions.</p>
<p>There are reports that the krill boats are a danger to whales. In addition to that, a study from the University of California, Santa Cruz found that pregnancy rates among humpback whales in Antarctica have fallen sharply. The reason, it said, might be a lack of krill.</p>
<p>Also, research published by the World Wildlife Fund, a Swiss conservation group, says that krill remove 23 million tons of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere. The research suggests that krill do this by eating phytoplankton, microscopic forms of life that make food from sunlight and carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Emma Cavan is a biologist at Imperial College London. She helped write the report. She said: "Antarctic krill are worth more to nature and people left in the ocean..."</p>
<p><strong>More rules for krill harvesting</strong></p>
<p>The Commission for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources, or CCAMLR, is an international body with 27 member states established in 1982. The group, based in Tasmania, Australia, makes rules for conservation issues like krill fishing.</p>
<p>But some supporters of the group say it has to consider climate change in its rules.</p>
<p>Clair Christian is head of the Antarctic and South Ocean Coalition, a nonprofit group based in Washington, D.C. Her group represents environmental groups at CCAMLR meetings. Christian told the AP that CCAMLR is supposed to support conservation, "It's not to enable fishing," she said.</p>
<p>The Australia-based Association of Responsible Krill harvesting companies (ARK) represents members who harvest 90 percent of the Antarctic krill. Members accepted <strong>self-imposed</strong> restrictions in 2018.</p>
<p>The group has agreed to place stronger rules on moving krill between ships and to study the effects of climate change on krill.</p>
<p>But the group says its catch limits should be higher. It noted that its members catch less than one percent of the estimated 60 million metric tons of krill found in the main Antarctic fishing grounds. That leaves 99 percent for whales and other animals.</p>
<p>Activists, however, are calling for reform. Helena Herr studies whales at the University of Hamburg, in Germany. Herr briefly served in an advisory position with the ARK group. She believes krill fishing should be banned. She said she did not trust the estimates of the amount of krill in the Antarctic.</p>
<p>"The data is based on such <strong>vague assumptions</strong> that we don't really know what we're doing," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Joshua Goodman and David Keyton reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>food web</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>the interconnected system of animals and plants that provide food and nutrients</p>
<p><strong>conservation</strong> <em>–v.</em> the preservation and management of animals, plants, and natural resources for the present and the future</p>
<p><strong>self-imposed </strong><em>–adj.</em> a requirement placed on yourself; a requirement that a group places on itself instead of having an outside group place requirements on it</p>
<p><strong>vague </strong><em>–adj.</em> lacking details or clarity; something that could mean anything</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>EU to Investigate Chinese EV Makers over Competition Concerns  (2023/10/23) | 欧洲调查中国电动汽车制造商</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/eu-to-investigate-chinese-ev-makers-over-competition-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Chinese automakers are making gains in Europe's electric vehicle (EV) market.<br/>
中国汽车制造商在欧洲电动汽车市场上取得一些进展。</p>
<p>The competitive threat has led the European Union to launch an investigation into China's government support for its EV industry.<br/>
这种竞争威胁导致欧盟对中国政府支持其电动汽车行业展开调查。</p>
<p>The investigation adds to technology-related tensions between the West and China. At the same time, China is one of Europe's biggest trading partners and the world's biggest auto market.<br/>
这项调查加剧了西方和中国之间与技术相关的紧张关系。与此同时，中国是欧洲最大的贸易伙伴之一，也是世界上最大的汽车市场。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Chinese EV makers and Europe<br/>
中国电动汽车制造商与欧洲</span></p>
<p>Chinese EV makers like Europe because auto import taxes are just 10 percent compared to 27.5 percent in the United States, automotive expert Matthias Schmidt said. Europe also has the world's second-biggest EV battery market after China.<br/>
汽车专家马蒂亚斯·施密特表示，中国电动汽车制造商喜欢欧洲，因为其汽车进口税仅为10%，而美国为27.5%。欧洲也是仅次于中国的全球第二大电动汽车电池市场。</p>
<p>Car buyers in Europe like how Chinese EVs are not costly yet filled with features and stylish designs. Concerns about the threat to local carmakers and jobs are just not as important for some European buyers who face increased living costs.<br/>
欧洲的购车者喜欢中国电动汽车价格不高，但充满了各种功能和时尚设计。对于一些面临生活成本增加的欧洲买家来说，对当地汽车制造商和就业威胁的担忧没那么重要。</p>
<p>British retiree John Kirkwood replaced his Volkswagen Passat three years ago with an MG5 station wagon. The MG5's price was much lower than the price of the nearest competitor — a Kia that cost thousands more.<br/>
英国退休人员约翰·柯克伍德三年前用一辆名爵5旅行车取代了他的大众帕萨特。名爵5的价格远低于最接近的竞争对手起亚的价格，后者的价格高出数千美元。</p>
<p>"It's nice. It's quiet, it's refined" and very quick, Kirkwood said, adding that he had few concerns about the Chinese ownership of the British brand.<br/>
柯克伍德说：“它很好。它很安静，很精致”，而且提速很快。他补充说，他对中国拥有这家英国品牌的所有权并不担心。</p>
<p>MG is owned by SAIC Motor, China's biggest automaker. SAIC is the largest Chinese EV company in Europe too. Another Chinese automaker, BYD, is growing fast. Other companies with complete or partial Chinese ownership include Geely, which owns Sweden's Volvo and a number of EV brands including Polestar, Lynk &amp; Co. and British sports car maker Lotus.<br/>
名爵隶属于中国最大的汽车制造商上汽集团。上汽集团也是欧洲最大的中国电动汽车公司。另一家中国汽车制造商比亚迪正在快速发展。其他完全或部分拥有中国所有权的公司包括吉利，吉利拥有瑞典沃尔沃，以及包括极星、领克和英国跑车制造商莲花在内的多个电动汽车品牌。</p>
<p>Chinese EV makers combined sales are a small part of the 9.2 million vehicles sold in Europe every year. But Chinese EV builders have been taking up a piece of the smaller EV market at a fast rate.<br/>
中国电动汽车制造商的总销量只占欧洲每年920万辆汽车销量中的一小部分。但中国电动汽车制造商一直在快速占领小型电动汽车市场。</p>
<p>Schmidt's information suggests that Chinese automakers make up only about three percent of Western Europe's total car market, but Chinese manufacturers have 8.4 percent of the EV market. That number is up from 6.2 percent last year. In 2019, it was almost zero.<br/>
施密特的信息表明，中国汽车制造商仅占西欧汽车总市场的3%左右，但中国制造商占电动汽车市场的8.4%。这个数字比去年的6.2%有所上升。2019年，这一数字几乎为零。</p>
<p>The sales increase is leading some to worry about Europe's automotive industry. That powerful industry is mainly centered in France and Germany and employs many workers.<br/>
销量的增长导致一些人对欧洲汽车业感到担忧。这个强大的产业主要集中在法国和德国，雇佣了许多工人。</p>
<p>Last month, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen said, "Global markets are now flooded with cheaper Chinese electric cars," with prices "kept artificially low by huge state subsidies."<br/>
上个月，欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩表示，“全球市场现在充斥着更便宜的中国电动汽车”，价格“被巨额国家补贴人为压低”。</p>
<p>A subsidy is government support that permits a company to sell products at unfairly low prices.<br/>
补贴是指政府支持使得公司可以以不公平的低价销售产品。</p>
<p>The commission, the EU's executive arm, officially opened its investigation this month, saying it would take up to 13 months and could result in import duties, another word for taxes.<br/>
欧盟执行机构欧盟委员会本月正式开始调查，称这将需要长达13个月的时间，并可能导致进口税。</p>
<p>China voiced "strong dissatisfaction" and promised to "firmly safeguard" Chinese companies' rights. The Chinese Commerce Ministry said the EU investigation is based on "subjective assumptions," lacks enough evidence and goes against World Trade Organization rules.<br/>
中国表示“强烈不满”，并承诺“坚决维护”中国公司的权利。中国商务部表示，欧盟的调查是基于“主观假设”，缺乏足够的证据，违反了世界贸易组织的规定。</p>
<p>Executives at Shanghai-based Aiways, a company headed by Volvo's former China sales chief, rejected accusations that the Chinese government unfairly supports its businesses.<br/>
沃尔沃前中国销售总监领导的总部位于上海的爱威汽车公司的高管驳斥了有关中国政府不公平地支持其业务的指控。</p>
<p>"We're not selling inside China, we're not being subsidized in China," said Alexander Klose, vice president of overseas operations. Klose said his company does get "some subsidies for putting a plant somewhere," but added that he believes that is "what everybody has in Europe."<br/>
负责海外业务的副总裁亚历山大·克洛泽说：“我们不在中国境内销售，也不在中国获得补贴。”克洛泽说，他的公司确实“因为在某个地方建厂获得了一些补贴”，但他补充说，他相信这是“欧洲每家都有的”。</p>
<p>The EU should be working on getting to a "green future "rather than keeping competition out," he said.<br/>
他说，欧盟应该致力于实现“绿色未来”，而不是阻止竞争。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>American Scores on College Admissions Test Drop to 30-year Low  (2023/10/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/american-scores-on-college-admissions-test-drop-to-30-year-low.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>American high school students' scores on the ACT college admissions test have dropped to their lowest in more than 30 years.</p>
<p>The average score of students who completed high school in 2023 was 19.5 out of a possible 36. Last year, students averaged 19.8.</p>
<p>The average score dropped for the sixth straight year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An ACT Assessment preparation book is seen, April 1, 2014, in Springfield, Ill. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/afddc5fe-a4a3-47d4-b891-f36ea79e675c_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An ACT Assessment preparation book is seen, April 1, 2014, in Springfield, Ill. </span></div>
<p>Scores were already falling before the COVID-19 pandemic. But the scores fell faster during and after the pandemic period.</p>
<p>The students who took the test in 2023 were in their first year of high school when COVID-19 reached the United States.</p>
<p>Janet Godwin leads ACT, the nonprofit organization that administers the test. She said that high schools are "not doing enough to ensure that graduates are truly ready for <strong>postsecondary</strong> success in college and career."</p>
<p>The average scores in reading, math and science were all below the level that ACT says demonstrates a good chance of succeeding in first-year college courses. The average score in English was just above the "<strong>benchmark</strong>" level, but it was still lower than in 2022.</p>
<p>The falling scores come at the same time many colleges and universities established admissions policies that do not require the test. However, students are welcome to provide the scores if they wish.</p>
<p>Some universities do not look at test scores even if students send them in. College admission tests have been criticized for favoring students who come from wealthier families and schools.</p>
<p>Godwin, however, said the test scores from her organization still help universities place students in the proper classes.</p>
<p>"Even in a test-optional environment, these kinds of objective test scores about <strong>academic</strong> readiness are <strong>incredibly</strong> important," she said.</p>
<p>Some current high school students wonder why the tests are necessary. Denise Cabrera is a 17-year-old in Hawaii. She said all of her classmates had to take the test in 11th <strong>grade</strong>.</p>
<p>Cabrera said she believed taking it and getting a good score would help her get into a good college. But she thinks colleges and universities can learn more about a student by looking at "different qualities ... outside of just a one-time test score."</p>
<p>Godwin said about 1.4 million high school students took the test this year. That was an increase over 2022 but still below the numbers recorded before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Only 21 percent of students reached the levels the ACT organization believes are necessary to predict good success in college.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>postsecondary </strong><em>–adj.</em> school or work that comes after high school</p>
<p><strong>bechmark </strong><em>–n.</em> a score or result that is of a certain (often high) standard</p>
<p><strong>academic </strong><em>–adj.</em> having to do with school or education</p>
<p><strong>incredibly </strong><em>–adv.</em> used to amplify the importance of the word coming next, hard to believe</p>
<p><strong>grade </strong><em>–n.</em> the year a person is in school</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do You Define Success?  (2023/10/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-do-you-define-success.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>We all want to be a success in life. But success can look different from person to person. Perhaps the <u>key to success</u> is really knowing yourself. What do you want? What are your skills and <strong>strong suits</strong>? What are you really good at and what are you not?</p>
<p><u>Climbing the ladder of success</u> also requires different <strong>strategies</strong> in different industries. If want to be a success in a traditional corporate environment, you may have to wear business clothing like a suit. As they say, you may have to <u>dress for success</u>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Australian actress Margot Robbie arrives for the European premiere of Barbie in central London on July 12, 2023. The movie has been a huge success. (Photo by JUSTIN TALLIS / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0c46d1b8-0cc9-4e5a-8d15-f575bb0ec75f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Australian actress Margot Robbie arrives for the European premiere of "Barbie" in central London on July 12, 2023. The movie has been a huge success. (Photo by JUSTIN TALLIS / AFP)</span></div>
<p>If want a creative job, you may need to wear the latest <strong>fashions</strong>. Again, English has a common expression about clothes and future job goals: "<u>Dress for the job you want, not the one you have."</u></p>
<p>However, success takes more than just the right clothes. It also takes hard work. Oftentimes others do not see all the hard work that goes into a project. They think success comes suddenly, for example overnight. Let's say an unknown writer <u>makes it big</u> with her first book. People may call her an <u>overnight success</u>. But they do not know about the many years she spent studying and writing.</p>
<p>Another<strong> ingredient</strong> in the <u>recipe for success</u> is a plan. To reach your goal, you need to get organized and break the goal down into doable steps. You know what they say – <u>if you fail to plan, you plan to fail.</u></p>
<p>Many English phrases make the <u>road to success</u> sound like a real physical path -- something we could find on a map.</p>
<p>Real roads are <strong>paved</strong> with materials such as <strong>asphalt</strong>. But when we talk about success, the roads to it are paved with different materials. Sometimes we say the roads are <u>paved with gold</u>. This suggests a place where success, especially financial wealth, is easy to come by.</p>
<p>For some people the road to success is paved with hard work or luck. Others may find their road to success is paved with failures. Learning from their failures taught them how to succeed.</p>
<p>Often if you follow the right road, you can achieve your goal. Then, life is filled with the <u>sweet smell of success</u>. You <u>have the world at your feet</u>. You are <u>riding high</u>. You've <u>got it made</u> and are <u>killing it.</u> You are <u>golden</u>. As you can see, we have many expressions describing success.</p>
<p>But make sure that you do not lose sight of what really makes you happy and successful. Some people <u>become a victim of their own success</u>. This means you start having problems because of your success. And that explains our final popular English saying, a gentle warning: <u>Be careful what you wish for: you just might get it.</u></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>How would you define success for your English studies? And do you have a plan to reach it? Go to our website and comment on the story. Or you can send us an email to this address: <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:LearningEnglish@voanews.com">LearningEnglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>In the subject line, write Words and Their Stories and "success."</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>strong suit</strong> <em>– n.</em> something in which one excels</p>
<p><strong>strategy </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>a careful plan or method</p>
<p><strong>fashion </strong><em>– n. </em><strong> </strong>a common style especially of dress during a particular time or among a certain group</p>
<p><strong>ingredient </strong><em>– n. </em>something that enters into a compound or is a component part of any combination or mixture</p>
<p><strong>recipe </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of instructions for making something (as a food dish) from various things</p>
<p><strong>paved </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>to lay or cover with material (such as asphalt or concrete) that forms a firm level surface for travel</p>
<p><strong>asphalt </strong><em>– n.</em> any of various compositions of asphalt having different uses (as for pavement or for waterproof cement or paint)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dwight Eisenhower: Cold Warrior  (2023/10/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/americas-presidents-dwight-eisenhower.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Dwight Eisenhower. He took office in 1953 and was re-elected in 1956.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Dwight Eisenhower" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9d19cda0-2944-45f4-af72-7052bd01277a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Dwight Eisenhower</span></div>
<p>Eisenhower was famous before he became president of the United States. He was a general in World War II, and led the Allied invasion of Europe. The attack began with the air and sea operation called D-Day.</p>
<p>As president, Eisenhower became known for his efforts to keep peace. He tried to have good relations with the Soviet Union especially. He believed one of the best ways to do that was to build America's military strength.</p>
<p>When Americans think of Eisenhower, they often note the growth of the U.S. defense industry, and tensions with the Soviet Union. Those tensions became known as the Cold War, and lasted long after Eisenhower left office.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Dwight David Eisenhower was born in Texas, but raised in the state of Kansas. His parents had seven sons. The future president was the third.</p>
<p>Eisenhower's parents did not have much money. His father worked as a mechanic. His mother was a member of the Mennonite Church, which opposed war and violence for any reason.</p>
<p>But young Dwight – who used the nickname "Ike" – enjoyed reading about military history and doing physical activities. He played football, and liked hunting and fishing.</p>
<p>When he finished high school, Eisenhower earned a position at the U.S. Military Academy, better known as West Point.</p>
<p>At first, he did not excel as a soldier. Eisenhower tested some of the Army's traditional ideas. But in time, military leaders came to value Eisenhower's ability to think independently and <strong>strategically</strong>.</p>
<p>He accepted increasingly important positions. In only a few years, Eisenhower took command of Allied troops during World War II. He directed invasions in North Africa, Italy, and finally in Western Europe.</p>
<p>His words "Okay, let's go" launched the invasion of Normandy, France on June 6, 1944.</p>
<p>Eisenhower's personal life changed during his military years. He married a young woman named <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/mamieeisenhower" target="_blank">Mamie Doud</a> in 1916. The following year they had a son named Doud Dwight; however, the boy became sick and died at the age of three.</p>
<p>In 1922, the Eisenhowers had a second son, named <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/23/us/john-eisenhower-historian-and-son-of-the-president-dies-at-91.html" target="_blank">John</a>.</p>
<p>Mamie and the boy spent many months separated from Dwight. And, even when the family was together, they were often moving from place to place. They moved nearly 30 times during Eisenhower's military career.</p>
<p>After he retired from <strong>active duty</strong> in the Army, Eisenhower accepted a position as president of Columbia University in New York. Then he returned to the military to lead NATO forces in Europe.</p>
<p>In the early 1950s, Republican Party officials urged Eisenhower to be their candidate for president. Many Americans approved of Eisenhower's war record, his efforts to contain communism, and his wide smile. They seemed to agree with his campaign <strong>slogan</strong>, "I like Ike," and decisively elected him into office.</p>
<p>His 1952 election brought an end to the Democratic Party's 20-year control of the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>Although he declared himself a Republican, Eisenhower was a political moderate in many of his ideas. He continued some of the <strong>domestic</strong> policies of former presidents<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html" target="_blank"> Franklin Roosevelt</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-harry-truman/4067702.html" target="_blank">Harry Truman</a>.</p>
<p>Eisenhower also wanted the government to invest in public works projects. Notably, he approved a bill to build more than 65,000 kilometers of roads. Today the U.S. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/interstate/history.cfm">highway system</a> connects all parts of the country and supports the nation's economy.</p>
<p>Eisenhower also worked hard to have peaceful relations with other countries. In his first months as president, he signed the agreement that ended fighting in the Korean War.</p>
<p>He also tried to ease tensions between the United States and Soviet Union. In 1952, the U.S. government tested the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/united-states-tests-first-hydrogen-bomb">first hydrogen bomb</a>. It was even more powerful than the atomic bomb.</p>
<p>Soon, the Soviet Union carried out a hydrogen bomb test of its own.</p>
<p>The two countries became actively involved in an arms race that made many people around the world very, very nervous.</p>
<p>Eisenhower did not fully trust the Soviet leadership, but made some efforts to <strong>achieve</strong> an agreement on arms control. At the same time, he approved a plan for U.S. airplanes to fly secretly over the Soviet Union to gather information.</p>
<p>In 1959, Eisenhower and the Soviet leader, Nikita Khrushchev, met in the American state of Maryland. Modern presidents use a mountain <strong>retreat</strong> there, which Eisenhower called <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/news/ask-history/how-did-camp-david-gets-its-name">Camp David</a>, after his grandson.</p>
<p>The U.S. and Soviet officials did not develop a treaty, but they did agree to meet again the following year.</p>
<p>However, the agreement collapsed. In 1960, Soviet missiles brought down one of the American spy planes, called a <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/cold-war/u2-spy-incident">U-2</a>. The pilot was captured.</p>
<p>At first, Eisenhower's government denied that the plane was secretly gathering information. Officials said it was only a weather aircraft.</p>
<p>But then the Soviets produced evidence that the U-2 was, in fact, a spy plane. Khrushchev said he could not trust Eisenhower and his government, and he ended talks on limiting or disarming nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>During his two terms in office, Eisenhower tried many ways to avoid all-out war. He approved other secret actions, especially by the Central Intelligence Agency, or CIA . Eisenhower sent U.S. Marines into Lebanon to try to end unrest there. And he decided against ordering air strikes on Vietminh forces when they surrounded French troops at <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/french-defeated-at-dien-bien-phu">Dien Bien Phu</a>, Vietnam.</p>
<p>In all these efforts, Eisenhower used the threat of U.S. military power to help achieve his foreign policy goals. But he warned Americans against letting businesses aiding the defense industry become too powerful.</p>
<p>In his final speech as president, Eisenhower spoke of the dangers of what he called the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.npr.org/2011/01/17/132942244/ikes-warning-of-military-expansion-50-years-later">military-industrial complex</a>. He did not want the country to depend only on war to resolve conflicts. And, he did not want the U.S. government to spend so much on weapons that it could not provide other services to Americans.</p>
<p>Shortly after that speech, Eisenhower retired to a home he and his wife had bought in Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. Many Americans were sad to see him go.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Eisenhower's presidency lasted most of the 1950s. During that time, the American economy was, for the most part, strong. Many Americans had enough money to buy homes and televisions.</p>
<p>At the same time, Eisenhower's presidency was a time of unease. Racial discrimination was intense. In 1954, the U.S. Supreme Court <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pbs.org/wnet/supremecourt/rights/landmark_brown.html">declared</a> that states could no longer have separate public schools for white and black students. Some whites strongly objected to the decision. They tried to block black students from entering schools, sometimes using violence.</p>
<p>Eisenhower sent troops to enforce the federal law to <strong>desegregate</strong> public schools.</p>
<p>Later, Eisenhower used the power of his office to enforce other desegregation and voting rights laws. But he did not speak up strongly in support of civil rights. He thought both those who blocked civil rights legislation and those who demanded it were extreme.</p>
<p>Eisenhower also did not publicly criticize Senator Joseph McCarthy, who accused the U.S. government of protecting Soviet spies. Eisenhower strongly disliked McCarthy, but he permitted the "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/cold-war/red-scare" target="_blank">Red Scare</a>" to continue until the lawmaker could discredit himself.</p>
<p>Finally, despite Eisenhower's efforts, the Cold War did not end; in fact, tensions between the U.S. and Soviet Union increased. Although Eisenhower succeeded in keeping the country out of war, many events during his presidency created the conditions for later conflicts.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Eisenhower was a popular president, both before, during, and after his time in office.</p>
<p>During his final years, he wrote several books about his life, traveled, and advised later presidents. He had suffered a heart attack during his first term in office, and eventually suffered another one.</p>
<p>He died at the age of 78 with his family by his side.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>strategically</strong> - <em>adv.</em> creating and using plans to reach a goal</p>
<p><strong>active duty</strong> - <em>n.</em> employment as a full-time member of the military</p>
<p><strong>slogan</strong> - <em>n.</em> a word or phrase that is easy to remember and is used to attract attention</p>
<p><strong>domestic</strong> - <em>n. </em>of, relating to, or made in your own country</p>
<p><strong>achieve</strong> - <em>v.</em> to get or reach (something)</p>
<p><strong>retreat</strong> - <em>n.</em> a place that is quiet and private</p>
<p><strong>desegregate</strong> -<em> v.</em> to end a policy that keeps people of different races apart</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australians Claim to Create Most Complete Map of Universe’s History  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/australians-claim-to-create-most-complete-map-of-universe-s-history.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Australian researchers say they have produced the most complete history of the universe to date. An Australian National University team says the study offers new ideas about how the universe might have started.</p>
<p>The research team says the study's aim was to understand the beginnings of all the objects in the universe.</p>
<p>The American space agency, NASA, says the universe "includes all of space, and all the matter and energy that space contains. It even includes time itself and, of course, it includes you."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A picture taken in Fontainebleau, southern Paris on August 13, 2023 shows shooting stars streaking across the Milky Way during the Nuits des &lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;233;toiles (Starry Night), a major annual celebration for astronomy enthusiasts. (Photo by Miguel MEDINA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5d8f-08db9ceb5d34_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A picture taken in Fontainebleau, southern Paris on August 13, 2023 shows shooting stars streaking across the Milky Way during the "Nuits des <i>&amp;#</i>233;toiles" (Starry Night), a major annual celebration for astronomy enthusiasts. (Photo by Miguel MEDINA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>NASA adds that "the Milky Way is but one of billions of <strong>galaxies</strong> in the observable universe -- all of them, including our own, are thought to have supermassive black holes at their centers."</p>
<p>A black hole is an area in space with gravity so strong that even light cannot escape it.</p>
<p>The Australian team says it has created the most complete <strong>maps</strong> showing the history of the universe.</p>
<p>The lead writer is honorary professor Charley Lineweaver. He said that when the universe began 13.8 billion years ago in a hot big bang, there were no objects, such as atoms, people, planets, stars, or galaxies.</p>
<p>The writers say the mapping provides new ideas about how the universe came into being.</p>
<p>The Australian National University (ANU) study is published in the most recent publication of <em>The American Journal of Physics. </em></p>
<p>The first map shows temperature and density of the universe as it expanded and cooled. The second map shows the mass and size of all objects in the universe.</p>
<p>The ANU researchers say the study suggests the universe may have started as what is known as an instanton not a singularity. An instanton has a defined size and mass. A singularity is defined as a point of <strong>infinite</strong> density and temperature.</p>
<p>Put simply, this would mean that the beginning of the universe was not infinite in size. That is important because researchers say that what lies beyond the limits of the universe is "also a major mystery."</p>
<p>Lineweaver told VOA that mapping the universe will increase our understanding of it.</p>
<p>"When you <strong>extrapolate</strong> in so many different ways it gives you just a lay of the land that I just think is a beautiful way of understanding the universe," he said. "If there is one way to understand the Big Bang, it started out hot and dense and it got cooler and less dense, and as it did that, particles and objects of all kinds <strong>condensed</strong> out of this hot, dense background."</p>
<p>He said that understanding that is something that we should all make an attempt to do because that is probably the most important understanding underlying the history of the universe.</p>
<p>Lineweaver says he believes that research into the beginning of the universe could help to answer some basic scientific questions about life beyond Earth.</p>
<p>"The basic idea is, well, if we can figure out how we got here, maybe we can make better guesses about whether other life forms have <strong>evolved</strong> elsewhere."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Phil Mercer reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>galaxy </strong>– <em>n</em>. any one of the very large groups of stars that make up the universe</p>
<p><strong>bang </strong><em>– n.</em> an implosion or explosion</p>
<p><strong>infinite </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having no limits</p>
<p><strong>extrapolate </strong><em>– v.</em> to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts</p>
<p><strong>condense </strong><em>– v.</em> to change from a gas into a liquid</p>
<p><strong>evolve</strong> <em>– v. </em>to develop from something else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New York Mayor Makes Robocalls in Different Languages Using AI  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/new-york-mayor-makes-robocalls-in-different-languages-using-ai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>New York Mayor Eric Adams has been using artificial intelligence (AI) to make robot phone calls in several languages.</p>
<p>The technology changes Adam's voice into languages that he does not speak. And it raises new ethical questions about the government's use of AI.</p>
<p>Adams told reporters about the phone calls, called robocalls, recently. He said they have gone out in languages like Mandarin and Yiddish for city events. They have not included any information that he only speaks English or that the calls were created using AI.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - New York City Mayor Eric Adams speaks in New York's Times Square during a news conference, Dec. 30, 2022. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fdee-08dbd0afeb39_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - New York City Mayor Eric Adams speaks in New York's Times Square during a news conference, Dec. 30, 2022. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey, File)</span></div>
<p>"People stop me on the street all the time and say, ‘I didn't know you speak Mandarin,'" Adams said. "The robocalls that we're using, we're using different languages to speak directly to the <strong>diversity</strong> of New Yorkers."</p>
<p>The calls come as questions arise over how best to use AI ethically and legally. <strong>Deepfake</strong> videos or audio can make it appear that anyone anywhere is doing anything a person on the other side of a computer screen wants them to do.</p>
<p>The Surveillance Technology Oversight Project called Adams' robocalls an unethical use of AI that is misleading to the people of New York.</p>
<p>Albert Fox Cahn is executive director of the organization. He said the calls are very unethical, especially because they are paid for with public money. "Yes, we need announcements in all of New Yorkers' native languages, but the deepfakes are just a <strong>creepy</strong> <strong>vanity</strong> project."</p>
<p>There is a growing use of artificial intelligence and deepfakes, especially in politics and election misinformation. It has led to calls for more rules and policing from the government and major media companies.</p>
<p>Google was the first big technology company to say it would identify political advertisements that use AI to fake a candidate's voice or actions. Meta does not have a rule specific to the use of AI in political ads. But the company has a policy restricting fake or <strong>manipulated</strong> audio and imagery used for misinformation.</p>
<p>A bipartisan bill in the U.S. Senate would ban "materially <strong>deceptive</strong>" deepfakes relating to federal candidates, with exceptions for <strong>parody</strong>. This month, two Democratic members of Congress sent a letter to the heads of Meta and X, formerly known as Twitter. The letter shared concerns about AI-created political ads on social media platforms.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, a number of technology companies have shown off AI tools that can take a person's speech and make it sound as if that person is speaking a different language.</p>
<p>In September, the music streaming service Spotify introduced an AI feature to translate a recording, or podcast, into several languages in the speaker's voice. More recently, the startup ElevenLabs in October introduced a voice translation tool. The tool can change spoken words to another language while keeping the voice of the speaker.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Adams' office said they used the ElevenLabs tool for their robocalls. Native speakers listened to the recordings before they went out to make sure the translations were accurate. Calls have been made in Spanish, Yiddish, Mandarin, Cantonese and Haitian Creole.</p>
<p>Adams defended himself against ethical questions about his use of artificial intelligence, saying his office is trying to reach New Yorkers through the languages they speak.</p>
<p>"I got one thing: I've got to run the city, and I have to be able to speak to people in the languages that they understand, and I'm happy to do so," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mayor </strong><em>— n. </em>an official who is elected to be the head of the government of a city or town</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diversity </strong><em>— n. </em> the quality or state of having many different forms, types, ideas, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>deepfake </strong><em>— n. </em>a real-looking, but untrue, video.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>creepy </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing people to feel nervous and afraid</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vanity </strong><em>— n. </em>the quality of people who have too much pride in their own appearance, abilities, achievements, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>manipulate </strong><em>— v. </em>to move or control with your hands or by using a machine</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>deceptive </strong><em>— adj. </em>intended to make someone believe something that is not true</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>parody </strong><em>— n. </em>a piece of writing, music, etc., that imitates the style of someone or something else in an amusing way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'When' with Past Tense  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/when-with-past-tense.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about using "when" with past simple or past continuous tenses.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3e4a-08dbd0147fdb_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Hi,</p>
<p>I'm a learner from China. Could you please help me with the following question?</p>
<p>Is the sentence <em>The good news came when we weren't expecting it </em>grammatically correct?</p>
<p>If it is correct, how can we understand the following rule:</p>
<p>"As a general rule, you should use "while" in a clause with a continuous action, using a verb in a continuous tense. Use "when" in a clause with a single action, using a simple past or present tense."</p>
<p>Many thanks,</p>
<p>Jinye</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Jinye. Keep up the good work learning English with us!</p>
<p>The sentence "The good news came when we weren't expecting it" is grammatically acceptable.</p>
<p><strong>When and while </strong></p>
<p>As for "when" and "while" we answered a question about <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/how-to-use-when-and-while-/5888101.html" target="_blank">How to Use ‘When' and ‘While'</a> in an earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em> program.</p>
<p>We explained that some experts call both words "subordinating conjunctions" in some cases. This means they signal how pieces of information are related to one another. And we shared that general rule to give an idea of how they are used in English.</p>
<p>Let's look at these two examples:</p>
<p><em>When the phone rang, I was making dinner.</em></p>
<p><em>While I was making dinner, the phone rang.</em></p>
<p>"While" and "when" both relate to time although "while" usually signals that two events are happening at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>Using English in real life</strong></p>
<p>Another issue to consider is how people use language in real life. Sometimes, the real-life use of language does not seem to equal textbook rules.</p>
<p>For example, many native users of English use "when" with continuous action. In fact, "when" is used with past progressive more often than "while" in the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/use-a-language-corpus-to-improve-your-vocabulary/7189316.html" target="_blank">Corpus of Contemporary American English</a>. Here are some example sentences from the corpus.</p>
<p><em>When I was growing up, I wanted to be a cowboy.</em></p>
<p><em>I was thinking about her when we were talking.</em></p>
<p><em>When he was running for President, Obama gave electrifying speeches.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Jinye.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Try Listening to Learn about Wildlife  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-try-listening-to-learn-about-wildlife.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A team of scientists is studying the sound of the forest in Ecuador to learn how artificial intelligence (AI) could follow animal life in recovering environments.</p>
<p>When scientists want to measure new forest growth, they can study large areas of land with tools like satellites and <strong>lidar</strong>.</p>
<p>But understanding how fast and in what amount wildlife is returning to an area is more difficult. Sometimes it requires an expert to listen through sound recordings and pick out animal calls.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - View of the forest in Combu Island on the banks of the Guama River, near the city of Belem, Para state, Brazil, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5ef1-08dba4b4c311_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - View of the forest in Combu Island on the banks of the Guama River, near the city of Belem, Para state, Brazil, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)</span></div>
<p>Jorg Muller is a field expert on birds at the University of Wurzburg Biocenter in Germany. He wondered if there was a different way.</p>
<p>Muller told the French news agency AFP: "I saw the <strong>gap</strong> that we need, particularly in the tropics, better methods to <strong>quantify</strong> the huge <strong>diversity</strong>... to improve <strong>conservation</strong> actions."</p>
<p>So, he turned to bioacoustics, which uses sound to learn more about animal life and the environments in which they live.</p>
<p>The tool has been used by scientists for some time. But more recently, researchers are using it with computer learning to study large amounts of data more quickly.</p>
<p>Muller and his team recorded wildlife sounds at sites in Ecuador's Choco area. The environments they recorded included areas that were once used for agriculture and raising livestock to old-growth forests.</p>
<p>They first had experts listen to the recordings and index the sounds of different animals. Then, they examine the sound quality to measure the environment.</p>
<p>Finally, they ran two weeks of recordings through an AI computer program trained to understand 75 different bird calls.</p>
<p><strong>More recordings needed</strong></p>
<p>The program was able to pick out the calls on which it was trained. However, scientists wondered if the program could correctly identify the number of different kinds of plants and animals in each environment.</p>
<p>To see if the program could do that, the team used two different controls. One was from the experts who listened to the audio recordings, and the second was based on examples from each environment, which can be used to understand<strong> </strong>biodiversity.</p>
<p>Since the amount of available sounds used to train is limited, the AI program could only identify one-fourth of the bird calls that experts could. But it was still able to correctly measure biodiversity levels in each environment, the study said.</p>
<p>The research was published recently in <em>Nature Communications</em>. The study said the scientists' results show that the AI program is a powerful tool to measure the recovery of animal communities in <strong>tropical</strong> forests.</p>
<p>The research noted that biodiversity found from recordings can be quantified in a cost-effective and complete way. And it said that it can measure environments, "... from active agriculture to recovering and old-growth forests."</p>
<p>There are still areas for improvement, including the lack of animal sounds on which to train AI models. And the method can only capture animals that use sound to communicate.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Agence France-Presse reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lidar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a remote sensing method that uses light in the form of a pulsed laser to measure ranges (variable distances) to the Earth</p>
<p><strong>gap </strong>– <em>n</em>. a missing part</p>
<p><strong>quantify </strong>– <em>v</em>. to find or calculate the quantity or amount of (something)</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the quality or state of having many different forms, types, or ideas</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong>– <em>n</em>. the protection of animals, plants, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>tropics </strong>– <em>n</em>. the part of the world that is near the equator where the weather is very warm</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Water Levels Low in North Brazil, Near Amazon River  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/water-levels-low-in-north-brazil-near-amazon-river.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>People, animals and fish who depend on the waterways connected to the Amazon River close to the Brazilian city of Manaus are facing a long period of dry weather.</p>
<p>The city's port is an important economic area for northern Brazil. But recently, the water level of the area where the Amazon and Rio Negro rivers meet reached a very low level.</p>
<p>The civil defense agency in Amazonas state said the drought is hurting over 400,000 people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="View of a stranded ferry boat at the Marina do Davi, a docking area of the Negro river, city of Manaus, Amazonas State, northern Brazil, on October 16, 2023. (Photo by MICHAEL DANTAS / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6dd3975d-c5bd-4886-9a92-a533a1227a23_cx5_cy10_cw91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">View of a stranded ferry boat at the Marina do Davi, a docking area of the Negro river, city of Manaus, Amazonas State, northern Brazil, on October 16, 2023. (Photo by MICHAEL DANTAS / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Those who have floating homes or use boats to move around on the river for work cannot travel. They cannot get fuel, food or fresh water.</p>
<p>Animals and fish along the river are dying. Thousands of dead fish float on the water's surface. A number of river dolphins died when they washed up on land. Dolphins are rare water mammals that live in Brazil's biggest rivers.</p>
<p>The organization that runs the port said the water level is only about 14 meters, the lowest since measurements started in 1902.</p>
<p>The <strong>previous</strong> all-time low came in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Without water, ‘there is no life'</strong></p>
<p>Brazil's <strong>monitoring</strong> and disaster alert center, Cemaden, said the rainfall in the Amazon area is the lowest it has been since July to September 1980.</p>
<p>The nation's science ministry said the weather pattern known as El Ni<i></i>241;o is to blame for the <strong>drought</strong> and low rainfall.</p>
<p>Reporters in the area are describing the situation as "<strong>grim</strong>."</p>
<p>Raimundo Silva do Carmo is a fisherman. But he cannot fish at this time. It takes him much of the day just to get water. One recent morning he was making his fourth visit of the day to a well east of Manaus.</p>
<p>He called carrying a water container back and forth "dreadful work" made harder because of the hot sun. "Without water," he said, "there is no life."</p>
<p>Another man, Joaquim Mendes da Silva is 73. For 43 years, he repaired ships on a large lake. The water is the lowest he has ever seen.</p>
<p>Children in the area stopped going to school one month ago because they could no longer travel by boat to the schoolhouse.</p>
<p>Along with Amazonas state, Cemaden said seven other states recorded their lowest rainfall in 40 years for the period from July to September.</p>
<p>The drought is hurting all of the waterways that connect to the Amazon River, an area that contains 20 percent of the world's fresh water. By last week, 42 of the 62 cities and towns in the area declared a state of emergency.</p>
<p>In one area, about 600 kilometers east of the lake, about 300 families are having trouble getting food and supplies in the Auati-Paraná reserve. They can only use small boats to get to the closest city. As a result, their travel time is 14 hours instead of the usual nine.</p>
<p>Along the river, people fish for a large fish called a pirarucu. The fish weigh as much as 200 kilograms. People catch the fish and then take them to local markets. They usually bring their catch to market by boat. But they can no longer sell the fish because they cannot reach the market.</p>
<p>Edvaldo de Lira is a local business leader. He said the fishermen "run the risk of catching fish in the lake, and it arrives <strong>spoiled</strong>. So, there is no way for us to fish," de Lira said.</p>
<p>Rain does not fall all year in the Amazon area. Rainfall is light from May to October, but the El Ni<i></i>241;o weather event is reducing the rain more than usual, said Ana Paula Cunha of Cemaden.</p>
<p>Climate scientists say the effects of El Ni<i></i>241;o this year are stronger because of global warming. Warming temperatures, they say, are because of carbon gases from years of burning coal, oil and gas.</p>
<p>One of the important rivers in the Amazon area is the Madeira. It travels over 3,500 kilometers from Bolivia to Brazil. Four of its five lowest water levels were recorded in the last four years, the Brazilian Geological Survey said.</p>
<p>In the port city of Porto Velho, the river's level is the lowest since measurements started in 1967. Brazil's fourth-largest hydroelectric dam, which produces power from water, is in nearby Santo Antonio. It stopped producing power last week for the first time since it opened in 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Unprecedented difficulties</strong></p>
<p>For now, the Brazilian government of President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva is sending food and water to the far away communities in the northern part of the country. Engineers will start digging paths along dry rivers for boat travel. Payments will soon go to families who cannot work.</p>
<p>But the problems will continue, experts say.</p>
<p>Photographs of dead dolphins appeared in newspapers and on television programs. Ayan Fleischmann is a hydrologist, or a scientist who studies water, at the Mamiraua Sustainable Development Institute. It describes itself as a social organization supervised by the Ministry of Science, Technology and Innovation. He said the photos were a "shock for everyone." He said the extreme heat may have hurt the organs of the dolphins or contributed to the growth of harmful bacteria.</p>
<p>"It was an unprecedented tragedy," he said. Unprecedented means never seen before.</p>
<p>Experts in Brazil from the National Institute for Space Research say the drought will likely continue until the end of 2023.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this report for VOA Learning English based on reporting from the Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>previous</strong> –adj. taking place at an earlier time</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong>–v. to watch or observe over time for a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a period with very little rain or with an abnormally low amount of rainfall</p>
<p><strong>grim </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing feelings of sadness or worry</p>
<p><strong>spoiled </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>ruined; no longer usable or edible</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists to Study Fish after Fukushima Water Release  (2023/10/20) | 科学家研究日本核污水排海后的鱼类情况</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-to-study-fish-after-fukushima-water-release.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A team of international scientists collected fish samples from an area near Japan's Fukushima nuclear plant Thursday. They are examining the effects of the recent release of treated radioactive water from the plant into the sea.<br/>
一个国际科学家小组星期四从日本福岛核电站附近地区采集了鱼类样本。他们正在研究最近处理过的放射性水从核电站排入大海的影响。</p>
<p>The study by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is the first since the water release began in August. Local fishermen criticized the release. It also led China to ban all seafood products from Japan over food safety fears.<br/>
国际原子能机构的这项研究是自8月份开始排海以来的首次。当地渔民批评这次排海。这也导致中国出于对食品安全的担忧，禁止所有来自日本的海鲜产品。</p>
<p>Scientists from China, South Korea and Canada observed the collection of fish samples at Hisanohama Port, about 50 kilometers south of Fukushima.<br/>
来自中国、韩国和加拿大的科学家在福岛以南约50公里的久滨港观察了鱼类样本的采集情况。</p>
<p>The samples will be sent to laboratories in each country for independent testing, the U.N. nuclear agency said.<br/>
这家联合国下属的核机构表示，这些样本将被送往每个国家的实验室进行独立检验。</p>
<p>Paul McGinnity is a research scientist with the IAEA overseeing the study. He said, "The Japanese government has requested that we do this and one of the reasons they want us to do this is to try and strengthen confidence in the data that Japan is producing."<br/>
保罗·麦金尼提是国际原子能机构的一名研究科学家，他负责监督这项研究。他说：“日本政府请求我们这样做，他们希望我们这样做的原因之一是试图加强对日本正在产生的数据的信心。”</p>
<p>More than a million metric tons of water was contaminated by contact with fuel at the nuclear reactor following the 2011 earthquake and tsunami disaster.<br/>
2011年地震和海啸灾难后，超过100万公吨的水因接触核反应堆的燃料而受到污染。</p>
<p>Before being released, the water is filtered to remove isotopes, leaving only tritium, which is difficult to separate. Plant operator Tepco said the levels of tritium in the water are weakened to below official limits.<br/>
在排海之前，这些水被过滤以去除同位素，只留下难以分离的氚。核电站运营商东电表示，水中的氚含量已降至官方限值以下。</p>
<p>The IAEA says that tritium is "a naturally occurring radioactive form of hydrogen that is produced in the atmosphere when cosmic rays collide with air molecules."<br/>
国际原子能机构表示，氚是“宇宙射线与空气分子碰撞时在大气中产生的一种天然放射性氢。”</p>
<p>The agency says tritium cannot enter the body through human skin. It is only harmful if ingested in a very large amount.<br/>
该机构表示，氚不能通过人体皮肤进入人体。只有大量摄入才有害。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Disagreements  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/grammar-and-disagreements.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Consider almost any social or political issue. It could be local or international.</p>
<p>Some people have one idea about the issue, and other people have other ideas about the issue. In other words, people disagree with each other.</p>
<p>In this week's<em> Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore disagreements. We will learn about the verb, disagree, and the noun form, disagreement. We will learn some important ideas about how to use the terms.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1795-08dbcffb2b0f_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start with some history.</p>
<p><strong>History </strong></p>
<p>When we explore individual words, we often look at their histories. Words – like people – grow and change over time. By learning a little about these changes, we can make words more memorable and meaningful to us.</p>
<p>So, let's take a look at the verb "disagree."</p>
<p>Disagree first appeared in English over 500 years ago. The <em>Online Etymology Dictionary</em> tell us that disagree first meant "refuse <strong>assent</strong> to." It came from an Old French word desagreer, a word that we can break into two parts. Des- meant "not, opposite of" and agreer meant "to please; satisfy." In English, you might think of these two parts as dis- and agree.</p>
<p>With time, disagree took on new meanings. About 450 years ago, it took on the meaning of differing in opinion, or expressing differing views, the <em>Online Etymology Dictionary</em> tells us.</p>
<p>Some time later, we have the birth of the noun form disagreement.</p>
<p><strong>Usage </strong></p>
<p>We have followed disagree from its beginning. But how do we explain its modern usage?</p>
<p>One important idea is that we generally use disagree without an object. So, for example, you might say a simple, complete sentence such as this:</p>
<p><em>I disagree.</em></p>
<p>Or you might say this:</p>
<p><em>The two sides disagree.</em></p>
<p>But what about more complex sentences, you might ask? Internet data sources can give us some important information about how to do that.</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer contains data from many written materials. We can do a careful study of exact words.</p>
<p>What <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=disagree+*&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-fiction-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">Google's Ngram Viewer</a> tells us is that by far the most commonly used word after the verb disagree is the word "with." After the word "with," we generally have a pronoun, noun, or noun phrase.</p>
<p>So, for example, you might hear or read a sentence that involves a pronoun after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>I disagree with you.</em></p>
<p>You might hear or read a sentence that has a noun after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>He disagrees with Tom.</em></p>
<p>Or you might hear or read a sentence that has a noun phrase after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>They disagree with these ideas.</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>We disagree with the prime minister's policies.</em></p>
<p>What about the noun disagreement, you might ask?</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=disagreement+*+&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">tells us </a>that once again, the word "with" is commonly used after the noun disagreement. So, you might hear or read the following:</p>
<p><em>He had a disagreement with his friend.</em></p>
<p>And what words might we use before the noun disagreement? <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=*+disagreement&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-fiction-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">Google's Ngram Viewer tells us</a> we are more likely to hear or read the short word "a," as in "a disagreement," So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>They had a disagreement.</em></p>
<p><strong>Quiz </strong></p>
<p>You may have noticed a difference between how we explored disagree and disagreement. We explored words that commonly come before and after disagreement, but we only explored a word that comes after the verb disagree. We did not explore the most common word that comes before disagree. Aside from pronouns, can you guess what the most common word is before the verb disagree?</p>
<p>Here is a hint: think about one short word that we often use before a verb in English.</p>
<p>Write us your answer in the comments section on our website or in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>assent </strong><em>– n. </em>to agree to or approve of something (such as an idea or suggestion)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Google's Antitrust Trial Could Change the Internet Search Market  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-google-s-antitrust-trial-could-change-the-internet-search-market.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A court in the United States is hearing evidence in a case against search engine provider Google. The government accuses the company of using illegal methods to crush business competitors.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Justice is leading the case against Google in a court in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>The trial could change the way Google is permitted to do business in the future. The case is one of the biggest antitrust trials in American history. Antitrust is a term relating to laws designed to prevent illegal competition.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Google sign is shown over an entrance to the company's new building in New York on Wednesday, Sept. 6, 2023." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4c21-08dbb2f1897a_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Google sign is shown over an entrance to the company's new building in New York on Wednesday, Sept. 6, 2023.</span></div>
<p>If the trial judge rules in favor of the government, the resulting punishment could lead to new online search possibilities for individual users and businesses.</p>
<p>Google's search engine earned a huge market share by helping people quickly connect to the wealth of information available on the internet. Google co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin developed the search technology in the late 1990s.</p>
<p>The Justice Department argues that Google has an unfair advantage in the market because its search engine is the <strong>default</strong> choice on the world's most popular smartphones and web browsers.</p>
<p>Witnesses from device makers, service providers and Google recently <strong>testified</strong> about one way the company's search engine is able to remain the default choice. They said the company pays an estimated $10 billion yearly to phone makers and other businesses in exchange for the default position.</p>
<p>In opening arguments, Justice Department lawyer Kenneth Dintzer said, "This case is about the future of the internet and whether Google will ever face meaningful competition in search."</p>
<p>Google has denied accusations that it uses unlawful methods to keep its huge market share. It says its search engine is wildly popular across the world because it offers users a high level of quality. Google lawyers have also argued that any users not happy with its search services can easily change to competitors.</p>
<p>But industry experts point out that many users choose to keep Google as the default so they do not have to take additional steps to change it. Research has shown that because of this ease, very few people change the default setting of Google.</p>
<p>The chief executives from two privacy-centered search engines, DuckDuckGo and Neeva, have argued that the default system favors Google and hurts their businesses. Neeva closed its operations earlier this year.</p>
<p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella also testified that Google has established a strong hold over users over the years. "You get up in the morning, you brush your teeth and you search on Google," Nadella said. He added that the only way to break this dependence is to remove Google as the default choice.</p>
<p>To solve this problem, industry experts say the judge may order a requirement for smartphones and web browsers to present a series of search engines to users during the setup process. This is already being done in Europe. But research shows that so far, most European users are still choosing to go with Google.</p>
<p>Florian Schaub is a professor of information at the University of Michigan who has studied people's online behavior. He says the fairest result in the trial would be a total ban on default agreements between technology companies.</p>
<p>Schaub spoke to the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>He said the current search environment is being shaped "by the big companies that control the space." He added, "What the government can do is inject some neutralism into this and give <strong>consumers</strong> some actual choices."</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a Justice Department lawyer accused Google in court of using unfair methods to push up internet advertising prices. The government <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-google-monopolizing-digital-advertising-technologies">argues</a> that "Google now controls the digital tool that nearly every major website publisher uses to sell ads on their websites."</p>
<p>The Justice Department accuses Google of using unfair methods to control online <strong>auctions</strong> that connect buyers and sellers of online advertising. By making small changes to the auction system, Google can drive ad prices up to make more money, government lawyers say.</p>
<p>Advertisers and website publishers have long criticized Google's ad business as being too complex and secretive.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>default </strong><em>– n. </em>what exists or happens if no changes are made</p>
<p><strong>testify </strong><em>– v. </em>to make a declaration under oath for the purpose of establishing a fact (as in a court)</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>– n.</em> someone who buys goods or services</p>
<p><strong>auction </strong><em>– n. </em>a sale in which things are sold to the person offering the most money</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Chemical Used in Air Coolers Needs Replacing  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-chemical-used-in-air-coolers-needs-replacing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Jennifer Byrne owns a heating and air conditioning repair company in the American city of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>Air conditioning, or AC equipment, cools the air in a home. To do this, the equipment uses a gas called a refrigerant.</p>
<p>While working on AC equipment in a house, Byrne puts gas from the equipment into a special container.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Operators move a used refrigerant cylinder at the A-Gas Rapid Recovery DFW facility on Monday, Oct. 9, 2023, in Arlington, Texas. (AP Photo/Sam Hodde)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a17b-08dbcf3bd83d_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Operators move a used refrigerant cylinder at the A-Gas Rapid Recovery DFW facility on Monday, Oct. 9, 2023, in Arlington, Texas. (AP Photo/Sam Hodde)</span></div>
<p>The gas is known by an industrial name: R-410A. Scientists say it traps 2,088 times more heat in the atmosphere than carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Because chemical refrigerants capture heat, some people say they need to be replaced with something else. Some scientists are worried that the release of methane, carbon dioxide, and other gases is making the atmosphere warmer.</p>
<p>The Clean Air Act bars businesses from releasing refrigerants into the air on purpose. Some companies are trying to find replacement gases that trap less heat, which might work almost as well.</p>
<p>Leaking AC equipment in homes is one way the gases get into the atmosphere. Cars are another <strong>source</strong> of these pollutants, said Eckhard Groll. He is an expert in refrigeration and head of mechanical engineering at Purdue University in the state of Indiana.</p>
<p>He said AC units in cars can leak. He said that, on average, about 25 percent of refrigerant from all cars leak out every year. There are more than 200 million gasoline cars in the U.S. alone, Groll said. Using those numbers, Groll said he estimates about 45 million kilograms of refrigerant is leaking into the atmosphere each year.</p>
<p>Supermarkets are the second-largest source of leaks. Long pipes carry refrigerant to coolers that store food. Danielle Wright is head of the North American Sustainable Refrigeration Council, a nonprofit group based in Mill Valley, California. It supports cleaner methods of cooling.</p>
<p>Wright said the average supermarket leaks about 25 percent of its refrigerant each year. That number is based on a U.S. Environmental Protection Agency report from 2005.</p>
<p>She criticized supermarkets, saying "...it's <strong>cheaper</strong> to leak the refrigerant than to build a leak-proof system."</p>
<p>Limiting leaks is important because the refrigerant can be reused. Many businesses <strong>recycle</strong> refrigerant gas. One such company, A-Gas, was founded in Britain in 1993. The company has several centers in the U.S.</p>
<p>Refrigerants can be used many times over and can last for 30 years, said Mike Armstrong, President of A-Gas in the Americas. The company takes in refrigerants and containers from around the U.S. and other countries. It processes the gas to be sold and used again. He said his business is doing well.</p>
<p>"This industry is probably going to increase four to five times in the next couple years," Armstrong said.</p>
<p>The chemical industry is also looking for a chemical to replace R-410A. Some researchers have suggested carbon dioxide itself as a possibility. But Groll of Purdue University said that carbon dioxide has to be under high pressure to work as a refrigerant. Completely different equipment would be necessary.</p>
<p>Christopher Cappa teaches environmental engineering at the University of California, Davis. He said carbon dioxide would be useful "if we're pulling it out of the atmosphere." But he added, "if we're producing it just as a refrigerant, that wouldn't be necessarily nearly as good."</p>
<p><strong>Refrigeration easier to clean than air conditioning</strong></p>
<p>Wright of the Sustainable Refrigeration Council supports the use of carbon dioxide. "This is kind of a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/low-hanging-fruit/7025641.html">low-hanging fruit</a>, it's a known technology and it's market ready," she said.</p>
<p>However, she said that reducing leaks from air conditioners is more difficult. She said chemical and equipment manufacturers and existing building rules have slowed the growth of new refrigerants in the U.S.</p>
<p>But one manufacturer, Trane Technologies, said it has been working hard on different choices. Trane says it has a refrigerant that is 78 percent less damaging to the environment than the current one. The company says it will start using it in its equipment beginning in 2024.</p>
<p>And at Harvard University, researchers are working to develop a solid refrigerant instead of a gas. Jarad Mason, an assistant professor of chemistry and chemical biology at Harvard University, is working on the project.</p>
<p>He said he is hopeful about using solid materials because they could be used in both large buildings and normal homes.</p>
<p>"Demands for heating and cooling are only going to increase," he said. He added that researchers must find ways of cooling that do not harm the environment and are not costly.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Isabella O'Malley wrote this story for the Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>source </strong>–n. where something comes from</p>
<p><strong>cheaper </strong>–comp. adj. less costly than something else</p>
<p><strong>recycle </strong>–v. to take something that has been used before, reprocess it, then use it again as if it were new</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Old Ways of Making Wine Gain New Fans  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/old-ways-of-making-wine-gain-new-fans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Wine made by ancient methods is gaining new fans.</p>
<p>Wine is an alcoholic drink made from fruit like grapes.</p>
<p>Natural wine uses methods that reduce processing and harmful effects on the Earth. Research company IWSR Drinks Market Analysis found that people in the U.S. are seeking natural wine in increasing numbers. At the same time, the number of wine buyers has been dropping since 2015.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Interns at Pax Wines in Sebastopol, Calif., stomp organic grapes with their bare feet in large vats, pulling out the juice to start the fermentation process on Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Haven Daley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/eff3d4fe-ea45-49c3-a3c7-75322d559b2e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Interns at Pax Wines in Sebastopol, Calif., stomp organic grapes with their bare feet in large vats, pulling out the juice to start the fermentation process on Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Haven Daley)</span></div>
<p>Natural and other Earth-friendly wines made up less than one percent of sales in 2021. But demand for those wines was rising faster than other kinds on the whole, reported Drizly, an online site for ordering and shipping wine and other alcohol.</p>
<p>Most natural wines are made with organic grapes collected by hand. Organic growers do not use poisonous chemicals to stop or control insects or<strong> </strong>unwanted plant growth.</p>
<p>To make wine, the grapes need to be crushed. Some wine producers crush grapes by foot like people of ancient times. Afterwards, the crushed grapes <strong>ferment</strong> naturally. Manufacturers do not add water, yeast or other substances.</p>
<p>There are exceptions. Some natural winemakers add sulfites, a chemical produced naturally in grapes. Extra sulfites can help preserve, or keep, the wine. And some winemakers clear the final liquid of any small pieces that could make it look cloudy.</p>
<p>The result is wines that are earthy and less predictable than many of the wines created by bigger producers.</p>
<p>"The first time you taste it, you can tell it's alive," said John Keller. He is the owner and winemaker at Neu Cellars in Northern Michigan.</p>
<p>But selling natural wine processes can be difficult. Natural wine has no set definition in the U.S. It is not easy to find, since most natural wines do not identify as such on their <strong>labels</strong>.</p>
<p>"Natural just sounds good, but <strong>conventional</strong> wine is pretty natural too," said Anita Oberholster. She is a professor in the Department of Viticulture and Enology at the University of California, Davis. "If the idea of natural wine is going to grow, we should do research on it and define it."</p>
<p>Keller of Neu Cellars has a degree in biochemistry. He started out working for a big winemaker in California. But he left because he was not happy about all the chemical mixes it used. These include gelatin, oak dust, and eggs.</p>
<p>However, some say the line between natural and conventional wines is very narrow.</p>
<p>Many products added to wine, like yeast, are natural products, Oberholster said. And many conventional wines are made without adding anything.</p>
<p>Some in the industry would like to establish rules<strong> </strong>for producing natural wine. France's wine industry took such action in 2020, enacting requirements that winemakers must meet to identify their wines as natural.</p>
<p>Some manufacturers argue that rules can make wine making more costly. Keller uses organic grapes but he says he cannot support the cost of repeated inspections for approval as an organic wine.</p>
<p>Anthony Zhang is the co-founder and CEO of Vinovest, a wine investment company. He sees another problem.</p>
<p>Vinovest says some wine companies are profiting from the lack of rules. They use labeling content like imagery that suggests their wine making is natural when they are not, he argues.</p>
<p>That can mislead buyers who often will pay higher prices for wines made by smaller producers that use natural methods.</p>
<p>However, buyers may have more information on wine bottles soon. Starting in December, wines sold in the European Union will have to identify on their labeling all the substances each product contains.</p>
<p>Oberholster expects the U.S. to pass similar measures as well in the next few years.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dee-Ann Durbin and Haven Daley reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ferment </strong>– <em>v</em>. to go through a chemical change that results in the production of alcohol</p>
<p><strong>conventional </strong>– <em>adj</em>. common and ordinary</p>
<p><strong>label </strong>– <em>adj</em>. a piece of paper or cloth that is attached to something to identify or describe that thing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gaza Hospital Explosion Limits Biden Visit to Israel, Middle East  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gaza-hospital-explosion-limits-biden-visit-to-israel-middle-east.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden visited Israel on Wednesday after the October 7 attack by the militant group Hamas that killed more than 1,400 people.</p>
<p>In addition to talks with Israeli leaders, Biden had planned to visit Jordan. But, that part of his plan was canceled after an explosion killed hundreds of people at a hospital in Gaza.</p>
<p>Since the attack by Hamas on civilians earlier this month, Israel has answered with air strikes and other attacks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (L) greets US President Joe Biden upon his arrival at Tel Aviv's Ben Gurion airport on October 18, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Brendan SMIALOWSKI / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fb1386b2-cdd4-4f7e-91cf-96d29f8d2ffd_cx7_cy0_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (L) greets US President Joe Biden upon his arrival at Tel Aviv's Ben Gurion airport on October 18, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Brendan SMIALOWSKI / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Hamas fighters said Israel was to blame for the blast that they said killed about 500 people. Israel's defense force responded, saying the explosion came from an off-target rocket fired by the Islamic Jihad militant group.</p>
<p>Before the explosion, Biden was supposed to speak with King Abdullah II of Jordan, President Abdel Fattah el-Sisi of Egypt and Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas to discuss humanitarian aid for Gazans.</p>
<p>Israel has promised a full ground invasion of Gaza and asked that Palestinians living in the northern part of the territory <strong>evacuate</strong> to the south. About 600,000 people so far have followed the order.</p>
<p>About 3,000 Palestinians have died during Israel's operations, the Gaza Health Ministry said.</p>
<p>Biden said he was given information from U.S. military experts that made him believe the hospital explosion was not from an Israeli weapon. While in Israel, he said he was sad to see what happened to the hospital, but "it appears it was done by the other team, not you."</p>
<p>Islamic Jihad says it was not responsible for the explosion.</p>
<p>Biden said he understands that many people watching the conflict from afar might not believe him.</p>
<p>He told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu that "Americans are <strong>grieving</strong>," and "worried" about how difficult it will be for Israel to respond to the attack.</p>
<p>The Biden administration said Wednesday that Biden spoke with King Abdullah II and chose to postpone his travel to Jordan.</p>
<p>As Biden was in Israel, the United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres called for a humanitarian cease-fire that would permit Hamas to release Israeli hostages. In addition, the U.N. would like Israel to re-open its borders with Gaza to permit food and water to enter.</p>
<p>The U.S. president said he was concerned that food and other aid would not reach the Palestinian people who need it the most.</p>
<p>"If Hamas <strong>diverts</strong> or steals the assistance, they will have demonstrated once again that they have no concern for the welfare of the Palestinian people," Biden said.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. approved $100 million in aid if it could be delivered to the neediest people.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said Biden's visit was "deeply moving." Biden said the U.S. would continue to support Israel but also work "to prevent more tragedy to innocent civilians."</p>
<p><strong>UN Concerns</strong></p>
<p>The Palestinian ambassador to the United Nations is Riyad Mansour. He said the meeting with Jordan, Egypt and the Palestinian leaders would only happen if Biden were to negotiate a cease-fire.</p>
<p>Israel is being criticized for cutting off electricity and restricting entry to Gaza. European Council President Charles Michel called Israel's tactic "not in line with international law."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by VOA's Patsy Widakuswara and wire services.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>evacuate </strong>–v. to leave or be moved from an area because of a threat or because it is unsafe</p>
<p><strong>grieve </strong>–v. the show great sadness because of an event especially in public</p>
<p><strong>divert </strong>–v. to take in a different direction that planned</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Climate, Land Use Changes Sharply Reduce Pollinating Insects  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-climate-land-use-changes-sharply-reduce-pollinating-insects.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests changes in world climate and land use are sharply reducing the number of insects needed for <strong>pollinating</strong> crops.</p>
<p>The study looked at thousands of species and areas around the world. It found that the number of pollinating insects dropped by 61 percent during periods of abnormally high temperatures and reduced supply of flowering plants.</p>
<p>Leaders of the study noted that bees, flies, moths and other pollinators are more affected than the general insect population. Results of the research recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adh0756">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Science Advances</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Bees and other insects gather on a sunflower at the Agro Brasilia, an agricultural exhibition on the outskirts of Brasilia, Brazil, May 18, 2012. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-55cc-08dbcf1b8f89_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Bees and other insects gather on a sunflower at the Agro Brasilia, an agricultural exhibition on the outskirts of Brasilia, Brazil, May 18, 2012. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)</span></div>
<p>"We're seeing the climate change is already having this really strong <strong>impact</strong> on pollinators," study co-writer Tim Newbold told The Associated Press. He is an ecologist at the University College of London.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture estimates about 35 percent of world food crops and 75 percent of flowering plants depend on insects and other animal pollinators to reproduce.</p>
<p>The study found the biggest problems with pollinator loss are in the tropics – areas that sit close to Earth's equator. The countries most at risk of crop loss from reduced pollinators include China, India, Indonesia and Brazil. Sub-Saharan Africa is also in danger, especially its cocoa and mango crops, the study found.</p>
<p>Given the current situation, the researchers said some important tropical crops – especially coffee and cocoa – could be badly hurt. Those plants depend heavily on bees and flies to help them reproduce.</p>
<p>Past studies have shown insect populations are decreasing for several reasons, including climate change and loss of <strong>habitat</strong>.<strong> </strong>Other studies have shown shrinking numbers of pollinators, with coffee and cocoa plants especially harmed by the absence.</p>
<p>Newbold, from the University College of London, said he sees a "double hit of climate change" affecting the coffee plants themselves, as well as the pollinators they depend on.</p>
<p>This does not mean, however, that there will be no coffee or chocolate available, said the study's lead writer, Joe Millard. It will just mean buyers will have to pay more for them. Millard is a computational ecologist at the Natural History Museum in London.</p>
<p>University of Delaware insect expert Douglas Tallamy – who was not part of the research – said this study is unusual because it centered on the tropics, which other research has not. "We're not paying enough attention to the tropics," Tallamy said. "They are important."</p>
<p>Newbold noted that pollinating insects in the tropics are likely hit harder than other places because they are already near their temperature limits that place them at risk. "Massive warming in the tropics is pushing those species over the edge," Newbold said.</p>
<p>Habitat loss is the main driver for the shrinking number of pollinators because it leaves less food for them, Millard said. Climate change, <strong>parasites</strong>, disease, and chemicals in the environment add to that difficulty.</p>
<p>Newbold said scientists are still trying to find out why pollinators seem to be suffering worse effects from warming temperatures than other insects. It could be because they have hairier legs and bodies that help them carry <strong>pollen</strong>, the researchers said.</p>
<p>It is like "being forced to have a big furry coat and it's getting hot," Newbold said.</p>
<p>But the University of Delaware's Tallamy is not so sure. He said that the study's data is solid, but its explanation as to cause of impact is more of a <strong>guess</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pollinate </strong><em>– v. </em>to carry pollen from a male part of a flower to the female part of another flower of the same type</p>
<p><strong>habitat </strong><em>– n. </em>the natural environment of a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>– n.</em> the affect a person, event or situation has on someone or something</p>
<p><strong>parasite </strong><em>– n.</em> a plant or animal that lives on or inside another plant or animal in order to get food</p>
<p><strong>pollen </strong><em>– n.</em> a powdery substance produced by flowers that is carried by insects or wind and makes other flowers produce seeds</p>
<p><strong>guess </strong><em>– adj. </em>to form an opinion of from little or no evidence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some Mexican Students Will Pay Less to Attend California Community Colleges  (2023/10/18) | 部分墨西哥学生就读加州社区大学将能享受低学费</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/some-mexican-students-will-pay-less-to-attend-california-community-colleges.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>
California Governor Gavin Newsom signed a law last week permitting low-income Mexican students to pay the same cost as Californians to attend some community colleges.<br/>
加州州长加文·纽瑟姆上周签署了一项法律，允许低收入的墨西哥学生支付与加州人相同的费用进入一些社区大学。</p>
<p>The law starts next year and will run as a pilot, or test program, for five years. The program is open to Mexican students who live within 72 kilometers of the U.S. border in California.<br/>
该法律将于明年开始实施，并将作为试点或测试项目运行五年。该项目对居住在美国加州州界72公里以内的墨西哥学生开放。</p>
<p>In California, the Education Data Initiative says the average yearly cost of tuition at community colleges for Californians is $1,500. For out-of-state students, the yearly cost is nearly $10,000. It means a possible saving of more than $8,000 for some Mexican students under the program.<br/>
在加州，教育数据倡议组织表示，加州人在社区大学的平均年学费为1500美元。对于州外的学生来说，每年的费用将近1万美元。这意味着该项目可能为一些墨西哥学生节省8000多美元。</p>
<p>David Alvarez is a California state lawmaker who worked on the law. He said many Mexicans travel between the two countries to work or visit family. And the law will help make education readily available to prepare them for jobs.<br/>
大卫·阿尔瓦雷斯是加州的一名州议员，他曾参与这项法律的制定。他说，许多墨西哥人往返于两国之间工作或探亲。这项法律将有助于他们随时接受教育，为就业做好准备。</p>
<p>Alvarez said in a statement that the program would help "prepare a more diverse population among our workforce."<br/>
阿尔瓦雷斯在一份声明中表示，该计划将有助于“在我们的劳动力中培养更多样化的人群”。</p>
<p>Southwestern College in Chula Vista, California, is just 11 kilometers from the U.S. border with Mexico. The college's president Mark Sanchez said many students at the school split their time between the two countries.<br/>
位于加州丘拉维斯塔的西南学院距离美国与墨西哥的边境只有11公里。该学院院长马克·桑切斯表示，该校许多学生穿梭于两国之间。</p>
<p>"Without this pilot, we risk everything in terms of loss of talent," he told lawmakers at a hearing last June.<br/>
他在去年6月的一次听证会上对议员表示：“如果没有这个试点，我们将面临人才流失的风险。”</p>
<p>Students from Mexico who decide to go to Southwestern College will save about $7,000 based on the lower cost for Californians.<br/>
来自墨西哥的学生如果决定去西南学院，将在享受加州人低廉学费的基础上节省约7000美元。</p>
<p>The law requires community colleges to report by 2028 on the attendance and the number of students receiving in-state tuition under the program.<br/>
该法律要求社区大学在2028年前报告入学率和根据该计划享受州内学费的学生人数。</p>
<p>In 2015, California passed a similar law that permitted students who lived close to its border with Nevada to attend Lake Tahoe Community College at in-state tuition.<br/>
2015年，加州通过了一项类似的法律，允许居住在加州与内华达州边境附近的学生以州内学费进入太浩湖社区学院。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·菲利德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN Report: Education Technology Should Be Used Carefully  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/un-report-education-technology-should-be-used-carefully.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic showed how useful digital technology could be for schools. But it also showed the limitations of technology in the educational setting. Millions of students were able to attend classes online to avoid spreading the virus. But many students failed to learn by such methods. Their educational progress slowed and in some cases went backwards.</p>
<p>Digital tools and the internet have made it easier for students to <strong>access</strong> educational resources. However, a large number of schools around the world remain unconnected to the internet. Additionally, digital tools have entered markets that have no official supervision. Such educational products do not require any testing or proof as to their value to schools and learners.</p>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) argues against unsupervised wide use of digital tools and AI in education. A recent UNESCO report says there is little evidence that wide technology use improves learning. The organization says digital educational tools can never replace the human connection of teacher and student.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Michael Burton-Straub, left, and Declan Lewis attempt to Find the Bot in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0840-08db135b1232_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Michael Burton-Straub, left, and Declan Lewis attempt to "Find the Bot" in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.<i>&amp;#</i>160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)</span></div>
<p>Audrey Azoulay is UNESCO's Director General. She says there is a very large divide, or gap, between rich and poor countries when it comes to digital resources. Just 40 percent of primary schools worldwide have access to the internet, she said. Many schools also lack electricity, especially in Africa and Central and Southern Asia. In sub-Saharan Africa, just 32 percent of schools have electricity.</p>
<p>And, internationally, about one-third of students were unable to attend online classes during the pandemic.</p>
<p>"Even if connectivity was universal, it would still be necessary to demonstrate ...that digital technology offers real added value in terms of effective learning," the report says.</p>
<p>Often, technology changes faster than it is possible to study it, the report says. Educational technology products change every three years on average. In Britain, for example, just seven percent of educational technology companies had done studies to judge the effectiveness of their products.</p>
<p>UNESCO also reported that many companies pay for studies on the effectiveness of their own product. These studies are not independent examinations.</p>
<p>Pearson, an education technology company, has a tool called Successmaker for teaching math and reading. Independent studies show the tool has little or <strong>negative</strong> effectiveness in learning. But the company stands by the results of the private study it paid for. That study found the product very helpful to learning.</p>
<p>UNESCO says such companies need to be better regulated. Azoulay said just 14 percent of countries require data protection in education.</p>
<p>"Student data should not be used either by education technology or advertising technology companies for marketing purposes," the report says. Yet a study of 163 products found that 89 percent of them gathered student data and sent them to third-party companies, often for advertising purposes. This usually happened without the student or parent knowing, the study said.</p>
<p>UNESCO argues that technology holds great possibilities for education. But studies have shown that educational technologies are most effective when a teacher is involved in the <strong>instructional</strong> process.</p>
<p>"We must never forget the social and emotional <strong>dimensions</strong> of teaching and learning," Azoulay said, adding, "no screen will ever replace a teacher."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>negative </strong><em>— adj. </em>harmful or bad</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>regulation </strong><em>— n. </em>an official rule or law that says how something should be done</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>instruction </strong><em>— n. </em>the action or process of teaching</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dimension </strong><em>— n. </em>the amount or number of things that something affects or influences</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pepper X Sets Guinness Record for Hottest Pepper  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/pepper-x-sets-guinness-record-for-hottest-pepper.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ed Currie is the pepper expert who grew the Carolina Reaper, which has been considered the hottest pepper in the world since 2013. Ten years later, Currie broke his record with one that is three times hotter: Pepper X.</p>
<p>The Guinness Book of World Records named Currie’s latest creation the world’s <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2023/10/pepper-x-dethrones-carolina-reaper-as-worlds-hottest-chilli-pepper-759706">“hottest chili pepper”</a> this month.</p>
<p>Guinness uses what are called Scoville Heat Units (SHU) to measure heat in a chili pepper. A normal jalapeno pepper registers about 5,000 units. A habanero, the record-holder about 25 years ago, reaches 100,000 SHU.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Pepper X pepper is shown on Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023, in Fort Mill, S.C. The pepper variety is now the hottest pepper in the world according to the Guinness Book of World Records (AP Photo/Jeffrey Collins)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/sp/01000000-0aff-0242-0f71-08dbcf20c95f_cx0_cy11_cw84_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">A Pepper X pepper is shown on Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023, in Fort Mill, S.C. The pepper variety is now the hottest pepper in the world according to the Guinness Book of World Records (AP Photo/Jeffrey Collins)</span></div>
<p>The Carolina Reaper held the record since 2013 with 1.64 million SHU. And Pepper X is the new record holder with an average of 2.69 million units. By comparison, pepper spray commonly carried by police is around 1.6 million units. And bear spray, a product to keep bears away, is advertised to have 2.2 million units.</p>
<p>Currie said when he first tried Pepper X, “I was feeling the heat for three-and-a-half hours.” Currie, one of only five people so far to eat an entire Pepper X added, “Then the <strong>cramps</strong> came.” The cramps, he said, left him lying in pain for another hour.</p>
<p>Currie started working on Pepper X after he set the record in 2013 with the Carolina Reaper. He <strong>crossbred</strong> 100 different kinds of peppers every year for 10 years. Currie hoped that just one or two would make it through the development process. His goal was to offer an extremely hot pepper flavored with a little sweetness.</p>
<p>Pepper X is greenish yellow. It is a crossbreed of a Carolina Reaper and, what Currie mysteriously called, a “pepper that a friend of mine sent me from Michigan that was brutally hot.”</p>
<p>The chemical in peppers that causes the burn is called capsaicin. The chemical causes a burning sensation when it touches human tissue. The burning sensation is also said to release chemicals into the body called endorphins and dopamine.</p>
<p>Currie started growing peppers after ending drug and alcohol <strong>addictions</strong>. He considers that sensation a natural “high.” He shares his peppers with medical researchers, hoping they can use them to treat disease and help people who suffer <strong>chronic</strong> pain or discomfort.</p>
<p>Currie is trying to build a business with his new creation. In the past, Currie permitted people to grow his peppers without protecting his ideas. His lawyers say they have counted more than 10,000 products that use the Carolina Reaper name, or other <strong>intellectual property</strong>, without permission.</p>
<p>For Pepper X, he said no seeds will be released without his permission. “Everybody else made their money off the Reaper. It’s time for us to reap the <strong>benefits</strong> of the hard work I do,” Currie said.</p>
<p>Currie wants people to eat peppers and thinks they can gain from the experience that comes after the burn. He warns people from reaching too quickly for a Carolina Reaper or Pepper X.</p>
<p>When asked if Pepper X is the “pinnacle” or the hottest a pepper can be, Currie said with a smile, “No, it’s not the pinnacle.”</p>
<p>I’m Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from the Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cramps</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. (usually pl) </em>a feeling of pain and tightening often near the stomach or abdomen or in the muscles</p>
<p><strong>crossbred</strong> <em>–v.</em> to purposely breed different versions of similar plants so that the offspring will have certain qualities</p>
<p><strong>addiction </strong><em>–n.</em> a strong and harmful need to regularly have something, often a drug, or to do something like gambling</p>
<p><strong>chronic </strong><em>–adj. (medical)</em> continuing for a long time or repeatedly</p>
<p><strong>intellectual property </strong>–n. the inventions of a person that are recognized as that person’s property and which cannot legally be copied</p>
<p><strong>benefits </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> the good results of work</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Groups Demand Urgent Rules to Protect Whales from Ships  (2023/10/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/groups-demand-urgent-rules-to-protect-whales-from-ships.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An alliance of environmental groups is calling for new federal rules to protect an endangered whale from crashes with ships.</p>
<p>The groups presented their demands in a document, called a petition, provided to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) on September 28.</p>
<p>The action aims to protect the North Atlantic right whale, which has long been considered endangered. The population of these extremely large sea animals has decreased sharply in recent years. Just 340 are believed to be alive today.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A North Atlantic right whale is seen feeding on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-97ad-08dbcb2ccb79_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A North Atlantic right whale is seen feeding on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)</span></div>
<p>Officials at NOAA have said ship collisions are among the most serious threats to the survival of the whale. One rule the environmental groups are calling for would seek to prevent ship strikes by making more ships slow down for whales. NOAA has yet to release a final updated speed rule although it proposed new rules more than a year ago, the groups said.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have appealed for urgency in enacting the measure. They say it is important to approve new rules before the upcoming birthing season. At that time of year, the whales migrate hundreds of miles from waters off New England and Canada to areas off the coasts of Florida and Georgia.</p>
<p>"Even one ship strike would bring these whales closer to <strong>extinction</strong>, but speed limits can help prevent that," said Kristen Monsell. She is a legal director at the Center for Biological Diversity, one of the groups that prepared the petition to NOAA. "Federal officials can't sit back and do nothing while right whales are in danger," Monsell told The Associated Press.</p>
<p>Katie Wagner is a spokesperson for NOAA. She said she expects the agency to announce its final action on the proposed rule sometime this year. That means the rule could be publicized during the middle of <strong>calving</strong> season and may not be put into effect until even later.</p>
<p>Wagner said NOAA knows about the petition but has a policy not to comment on legal matters. The agency is considering expanding "slow zones" off the U.S. East Coast, and also requiring more ships to obey those rules.</p>
<p>NOAA denied a request from environmentalists last year to immediately put new rules in place. At the time, the agency said in public documents that it was considering "long-term, <strong>substantive</strong>" measures to reduce whale strikes by ships. Wagner said NOAA received more than 90,000 comments on the proposed rule and would use those to decide on its final action.</p>
<p>Right whales were once common off the U.S. East Coast. But the animals fell in numbers after years of heavy hunting activities. The whales have long been protected under the Endangered Species Act.</p>
<p>Right whales are also at risk of becoming accidentally <strong>entangled</strong> in fishing equipment. Proposed restrictions to prevent such entanglements have been the subject of a legal case between the federal government and fishermen.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>no longer existing; when a living thing disappears from the Earth forever</p>
<p><strong>calving </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for when certain animals give birth</p>
<p><strong>substantive </strong><em>– adj.</em> important or serious</p>
<p><strong>entangle </strong><em>– v.</em> to cause something to become caught in something such as a net or ropes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gates Foundation Helps mRNA Vaccine Development in Africa  (2023/10/17) | 盖茨基金会帮助非洲开发mRNA疫苗</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gates-foundation-helps-mrna-vaccine-development-in-africa.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation announced last week that it will invest $40 million in African drug makers. The money will help produce new messenger RNA vaccines in Africa. The continent's people were the last to receive vaccinations against COVID-19 during the pandemic.<br/>
比尔和梅琳达·盖茨基金会上周宣布，将向非洲制药商投资4000万美元。这笔钱将帮助在非洲生产新的信使核糖核酸疫苗。在大流行期间，非洲大陆的人民是最后一批接种新冠肺炎疫苗的人。</p>
<p>The foundation said that its investment marks an important step forward in improving vaccine equity. It said making vaccines and getting them approved for use could take at least three more years.<br/>
该基金会表示，其投资标志着在提高疫苗公平性方面迈出了重要一步。它表示，生产疫苗并获批使用可能至少还需要三年时间。</p>
<p>"Whether it's for local diseases in Africa like Rift Valley (fever) or for global diseases like TB (tuberculosis), mRNA looks like a very promising approach," Bill Gates told the Associated Press.<br/>
比尔·盖茨告诉美联社：“无论是针对非洲的局部疾病，如裂谷热，还是针对结核病，信使核糖核酸看起来都是一种非常有前景的方法。”</p>
<p>The Microsoft founder added, during a visit to the Institut Pasteur in Dakar, Senegal, "And so it allows us to bring in lots of African capabilities to work on these vaccines, and then this can be scaled up."<br/>
这位微软创始人在访问位于塞内加尔达喀尔市的巴斯德研究所时补充道，“因此，这使我们能够引入大量非洲能力来研究这些疫苗，然后可以扩大规模。”</p>
<p>The announcement came as the foundation opened its yearly three-day Grand Challenges event. The gathering brought together scientists and public health researchers from around the world.<br/>
值此消息宣布之际，该基金会一年一度的为期三天的“大挑战”活动拉开了帷幕。这次活动汇集了来自世界各地的科学家和公共卫生研究人员。</p>
<p>Institut Pasteur, along with South Africa-based company Biovac, will be using an mRNA research and manufacturing process developed by Quantoom Biosciences in Belgium.<br/>
巴斯德研究所和南非Biovac公司将使用比利时Quantoom生物科学公司开发的信使核糖核酸研发和制造工艺。</p>
<p>The foundation is giving five million dollars to each vaccine manufacturer. It will award another $10 million to other companies not yet identified. The remaining $20 million is going to Quantoom "to further advance the technology and lower costs."<br/>
该基金会向每家疫苗制造商捐赠500万美元。它将向其他尚未确定的其它公司再奖励1000万美元。剩下的2000万美元将用于Quantoom公司“进一步推进技术和降低成本”。</p>
<p>Pfizer and its partner BioNTech along with Moderna used the mRNA technology to develop COVID-19 vaccines in record time. The medicine supplies genetic direction to human cells leading to antibody production to fight COVID-19.<br/>
辉瑞公司及其合作伙伴BioNTech，连同莫德纳公司在打破记录的时间内使用mRNA技术开发了新冠肺炎疫苗。该药物为人类细胞提供基因方向，从而产生抗体来对抗新冠肺炎。</p>
<p>Those COVID-19 mRNA vaccines were quickly pushed through approval processes and received emergency use permission during the pandemic. The new vaccines under development in Africa will take longer anywhere from three to seven years.<br/>
这些新冠肺炎mRNA疫苗很快通过了审批程序，并在大流行期间获得了紧急使用许可。非洲正在研发的新疫苗需要三到七年的时间。</p>
<p>Dr. Amadou Sall is chief executive officer at Institut Pasteur. He said the deal will help build vaccine self-reliance in Africa. The organization has been producing yellow fever shots since the 1930s. It now hopes mRNA technology can be used to produce vaccines for other diseases in Africa including Lassa fever, Rift Valley fever, and Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever.<br/>
阿马杜·萨尔博士是巴斯德研究所的首席执行官。他说，该协议将有助于非洲建立疫苗自力更生的能力。自20世纪30年代以来，该组织一直在生产黄热病疫苗。它现在希望信使核糖核酸技术可以用于生产非洲其他疾病的疫苗，包括拉萨热、裂谷热和克里米亚-刚果出血热。</p>
<p>"What we want is next time there is a pandemic — we hope it won't happen soon — Africa would be able to make its own vaccine, to contribute to the development, and make sure that we protect the population," Sall said. "What happened with COVID should never happen again in the sense that Africans should get vaccinated as a matter of equity."<br/>
萨尔说：“我们希望下次疫情爆发时非洲将能够制造自己的疫苗，为发展做出贡献，并确保我们保护人民。当然我们希望下次疫情不会来得那么快。从非洲人应该公平接种疫苗的意义上讲，新冠肺炎的情况不应该再次发生。”</p>
<p>Jose Castillo is the leader of Quantoom Biosciences. He said the mRNA technologies permit low- and middle-income countries "to become autonomous in terms of research and development."<br/>
何塞·卡斯蒂略是Quantoom生物科学公司的负责人。他说，信使核糖核酸技术能够让中低收入国家“在研发方面实现自主”。</p>
<p>With $8.3 billion to give away in 2023, the Gates Foundation is the world's largest private philanthropic donor. The organization has spent billions of dollars to vaccinate against polio, treat and prevent malaria and HIV and, more recently, to develop vaccines for diseases like cholera.<br/>
盖茨基金会是世界上最大的私人慈善捐赠机构，它将在2023年捐出83亿美元。该组织已花费数十亿美元接种脊髓灰质炎疫苗，治疗和预防疟疾和艾滋病毒，最近还开发了霍乱等疾病的疫苗。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gaza Aid Halted in Egypt as Israeli Air Strikes Continue  (2023/10/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gaza-aid-halted-in-egypt-as-israeli-air-strikes-continue.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Emergency aid for Gaza was being held up at a border crossing in Egypt Monday as Israel continued to launch air strikes into the Palestinian-ruled territory.</p>
<p>Egyptian officials said Israel has not cooperated in recent days with efforts to get large aid shipments into Gaza from a crossing in Rafah, Egypt.</p>
<p>On Friday, Israel began ordering Palestinians to leave Gaza City and surrounding areas in the north, telling them to head to the south. Israeli officials say the order was issued ahead of a planned military ground campaign against forces of Palestinian ruler Hamas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Palestinians carry a person wounded in Israeli airstrikes in Khan Younis, Gaza Strip, Monday, October 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Fatima Shbair)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7908-08dbce7360b4_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Palestinians carry a person wounded in Israeli airstrikes in Khan Younis, Gaza Strip, Monday, October 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Fatima Shbair)</span></div>
<p>Hamas militants have built major military bases in the north. Israel's expected ground offensive there is expected to center on killing Hamas leaders, recovering captives, and destroying the group's military equipment, The Associated Press (AP) reported.</p>
<p>More than a million people had already fled their homes in northern Gaza in preparation for a ground invasion.</p>
<p>Israel has continued to attack positions in Gaza after Hamas launched a major military operation into southern Israel on October 7. Israeli airstrikes have destroyed whole neighborhoods as Palestinian militants continued firing rockets into Israel.</p>
<p>Israeli officials say more than 1,400 Israelis – including many civilians – have died in the conflict. Health ministry officials in Gaza say at least 2,750 Palestinians have been killed and 9,700 injured since the Hamas attacks began.</p>
<p>Israel controls the other two crossing points into Gaza. But it has declared a "complete <strong>siege</strong>" of the coastal Palestinian territory. This means Israel has cut off food, water, fuel and electricity supplies to the area.</p>
<p>Gaza has been under a joint Israeli-Egyptian blockade ever since Hamas seized control of the territory in 2007. The blockade closely controls movements of goods and people into Gaza.</p>
<p><strong>Mediators</strong> have pressed in recent days for a cease-fire that would permit the waiting aid to enter, as well as give foreigners a chance to leave Gaza.</p>
<p>The AP reported Egypt's foreign minister as saying Israel "has not taken a position to open the crossing from the Gaza side." The Israeli government did not immediately answer a request from AP for comment.</p>
<p>In Gaza, Palestinians crowded hospitals and schools Monday seeking shelter as food, water and medicine remained in short supply.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Palestinians sheltering in U.N. centers are getting less than 1 liter of water per day, the AP reported. Hospitals warned of operations nearing collapse because of power and fuel shortages.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) said it was concerned about disease spread linked to mass displacements and poor water quality. Four hospitals in northern Gaza are no longer operating and 21 had received Israeli orders to close. Many doctors have so far refused, saying it would mean death for critically ill patients and people receiving breathing assistance.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>siege </strong><em>– n. </em>a military operation in which enemy forces surround an area and cut off necessary supplies</p>
<p><strong>mediator </strong>–n. a person who works with opposing sides to reach an agreement or ease a dispute</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google Says AI-powered System Is Improving City Traffic Flows  (2023/10/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/google-says-ai-powered-system-is-improving-city-traffic-flows.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google says an artificial intelligence (AI)-powered system it created is helping improve traffic flow in major world cities.</p>
<p>The system, called Project Green Light, is currently in use in 12 cities. The project aims to save fuel and lessen air pollution, or emissions, from automobiles.</p>
<p>Google first announced the program in 2021, when it was testing the system in four areas of Israel. Since then, the company has kept expanding Project Green Light. Among cities now taking part in the program are Bangalore, Budapest, Jakarta, Manchester, Haifa, Hamburg, Rio de Janeiro, and Seattle.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Vehicles are caught in congestion as the flow of traffic increases at toll road in Cikarang, West Java, Indonesia, Friday, April 29, 2022. Google says its AI-powered system helps improve traffic flow. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b34f-08db2c933873_cx16_cy17_cw79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Vehicles are caught in congestion as the flow of traffic increases at toll road in Cikarang, West Java, Indonesia, Friday, April 29, 2022. Google says its AI-powered system helps improve traffic flow. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)</span></div>
<p>In an <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/google-ai-reduce-greenhouse-emissions-project-greenlight/">online announcement</a>, Google's Yossi Matias explained the latest progress. He noted that the system is being tested in areas with severe traffic issues. Generally, this is at major crossings with heavy traffic and complex traffic lights. These areas where vehicles start and stop are known as intersections.</p>
<p>The company said research has shown that at such intersections, automobile emissions can be 29 times higher than on open roads. In addition, Google's own research found that vehicles that must stop and start account for about half of those emissions.</p>
<p>Project Green Light uses individual driver data from Google Maps. This data is combined with AI methods to produce models of each intersection where the system is in place, the company says. The data from Maps is also used to create another model on how different traffic lights interact.</p>
<p>The modeling process for intersections considers several elements. These include the structure of streets, traffic flows, signal scheduling and how the vehicles interact with lights.</p>
<p>The models are used to reduce stop and start times and create smoother traffic flows, a process called optimization. Google says one goal is to optimize multiple intersections at the same time to create "waves of green lights" for vehicles on the road.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Google and Reuters. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>efficient </strong><em>– adj.</em> working well and not wasting time and energy</p>
<p><strong>gridlock </strong><em>– n.</em> heavy traffic conditions prevented vehicles from moving in any direction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>App Shows How Ancient Greek Buildings Looked Thousand Years Ago  (2023/10/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/app-shows-how-ancient-greek-buildings-looked-thousand-years-ago.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>If you visit the Acropolis in Athens, Greece, you will see the rocky grounds high above the city that include the famous ruins of the Parthenon.</p>
<p>However, if you use a new <strong>app</strong> from Greece's culture ministry, you can see what the building and grounds looked like more than 2,000 years ago.</p>
<p>The app lets visitors see the famous place in its true <strong>glory</strong>, with the bright colors and details it had in the past. <strong>Archaeologists</strong> and other historians worked to create digital images showing how the Acropolis looked when it was new.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man holds up a tablet showing a digitally overlayed virtual reconstruction of the ancient Parthenon temple, at the Acropolis Hill in Athens, Greece on Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6a707333-5c66-4d5e-b91a-d288779f7611_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man holds up a tablet showing a digitally overlayed virtual reconstruction of the ancient Parthenon temple, at the Acropolis Hill in Athens, Greece on Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)</span></div>
<p>In the app, the Parthenon, for example, has its famous <strong>marble</strong> sculptures that are now at the British Museum in London. The app lets visitors see the sculptures where they used to be near the Parthenon. Greece wants Britain to return the sculptures.</p>
<p>Experts say the app, called Chronos, is an example of how Artificial intelligence, or AI, technology is being used to tell the stories of the past.</p>
<p>The technology that expands what people can see is called <strong>augmented reality</strong> or AR. Companies such as Meta and Apple are making big investments in apps and <strong>hardware</strong> that can bring the technology to more people.</p>
<p>Maria Engberg recently wrote a book about the subject. She said most people will first experience augmented reality through their phones at places like the Acropolis.</p>
<p>She said travelers will see the technology when they take tours. They will be able to see photos and videos as they walk around historic places. Engberg is a professor at Malmo University in Sweden.</p>
<p>"I think we will see really interesting customer experiences in the next few years as more <strong>content</strong> from museums and archives becomes <strong>digitized</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>The government and other groups are making investments in AR as more visitors come to Greece following the end of the COVID-19 pandemic. Visitors to Greece in the first half of 2023 increased by over 20 percent compared to 2022, bringing over $10 billion to the Greek economy.</p>
<p>Microsoft worked with the Greek culture ministry to create a digital tour of Olympia, the home of the first Olympic Games. Lina Mendoni leads the agency. Earlier this year, she said the new technology lets "real visitors and <strong>virtual</strong> visitors anywhere around the world share historical knowledge."</p>
<p>Cosmote is the Greek telecommunications company that worked on the Chronos app. Panayiotis Gabrielides of Cosmote said advanced smart phones and faster communications networks will permit visitors to "download even higher-quality content." He said more guides and features will be available soon.</p>
<p>But for now, visitors can use Chronos to see how the Parthenon and other parts of the Acropolis once looked.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app</strong> <em>–n.</em> (application) a computer program that does a specific task often especially designed for a smart phone</p>
<p><strong>glory </strong><em>–n.</em> a praiseworthy condition or state</p>
<p><strong>archaeologist </strong><em>–n.</em> a scientist who studies the lives of ancient people</p>
<p><strong>marble </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind of stone often used to decorate public buildings</p>
<p><strong>augmented reality </strong><em>–n.</em> technology that adds to people's senses of what reality is</p>
<p><strong>hardware </strong><em>–n. (industry specific)</em> the physical electronic devices that use software</p>
<p><strong>content </strong><em>–n.</em> media such as writing, sound and pictures</p>
<p><strong>digitized </strong><em>–adj.</em> something in electronic form that can be used by computers</p>
<p><strong>virtual </strong><em>–adj.</em> existing on computers but not in the physical world</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
