<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>India Works to Build World’s Largest Renewable Energy Project  (2023/12/9) | 印度致力于打造全球最大可再生能源项目</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/india-works-to-build-world-s-largest-renewable-energy-project.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>India is planning to launch the world's largest renewable energy project near the country's border with Pakistan.<br/>
印度正计划在该国与巴基斯坦边境附近启动世界上最大的可再生能源项目。</p>
<p>The term renewable describes energy produced from natural sources, such as sunlight or wind. These sources are considered renewable because they are continually produced in nature.<br/>
“可再生能源”一词是指由自然资源（如阳光或风能）产生的能源。这些资源被认为是可再生的，因为它们是在自然界中不断产生的。</p>
<p>The Indian effort would be so huge it could be seen from space. Officials say it will use solar and wind equipment to produce electricity.<br/>
该印度项目将是如此巨大，以至于可以从太空中看到。官方称其将使用太阳能和风能设备发电。</p>
<p>The project is named the Khavda Renewable Energy Park, after the closest village in the area.<br/>
该项目以该地区最近的村庄命名为“卡夫达可再生能源园区”。</p>
<p>Reporters from The Associated Press recently visited the project area. They reported that thousands of workers are taking part in building activities. Some workers placed pillars in the ground to hold panels to capture sunlight. The large pillars can be seen rising into the distance for as far as the eye can see.<br/>
美联社记者最近参观了该项目区域。他们报道说，成千上万的工人正在从事建筑活动。一些工人把柱子安装在地上，用来固定太阳能电池板以获取阳光。这些大柱子延伸至目光所能及的远方。</p>
<p>Other workers prepared parts of the ground to support large wind collectors, called turbines. Others were seen transporting building materials or running wiring over many kilometers.<br/>
其他工人在准备用于支撑大型涡轮机的基础部分。还能看到其他人在数公里外运输建筑材料或布线。</p>
<p>When completed, the project will be about the size of Singapore, spreading over 726 square kilometers. The Indian government estimates it will cost at least $2.26 billion.<br/>
该项目建成后占地726平方公里，相当于新加坡的面积。印度政府估计，这将花费至少22.6亿美元。</p>
<p>Leaders meeting at the COP28 climate conference in Dubai have said an expansion of renewable energy will be important as the world seeks to meet future environmental targets. Some leaders have said any final climate agreement must call for a tripling of renewable energy worldwide.<br/>
在迪拜举行的第二十八届联合国气候变化大会上，各国领导人表示，随着世界寻求实现未来的环境目标，扩大可再生能源将非常重要。一些领导人表示，任何最终的气候协议都必须要求全球可再生能源增加三倍。</p>
<p>In addition, environmental activists say major cuts must be made in the use of non-sustainable planet-warming energies, such as coal, oil and natural gas.<br/>
此外，环保活动人士表示，必须大幅削减煤炭、石油和天然气等不可持续、能导致全球变暖的能源的使用。</p>
<p>The Khavda project is being built in the middle of the Rann of Kutch, in India's western Gujarat state. The Rann is an extreme environment containing a salt desert and wetlands.<br/>
卡夫达项目正在印度西部的古吉拉特省库奇兰恩中部建造。库奇兰恩是一处包括盐沙漠和湿地的极端环境。</p>
<p>When AP reporters visited, two days of unseasonal heavy rains had left the ground muddy and wet. The only escape for water in the area is through evaporation. The rainy conditions made the jobs harder for the workers, the AP reported.<br/>
当美联社记者访问时，两天的非季节性暴雨使地面泥泞潮湿。该地区水的唯一出路是蒸发。据美联社报道，下雨的天气使工人们的工作更加困难。</p>
<p>An estimated 4,000 workers and 500 engineers have been living in camps over the past year to try to get the project up and running.<br/>
在过去的一年里，估计有4000名工人和500名工程师住在营地里，试图让项目启动并运行。</p>
<p>Once completed, it will supply 30 gigawatts of renewable energy each year. This would be enough to power nearly 18 million Indian homes.<br/>
一旦建成，它将每年提供30千兆瓦的可再生能源。这将足以为近1800万户印度家庭供电。</p>
<p>India is mostly powered by carbon fuels, especially coal. Coal produces about 70 percent of the nation's electricity. Renewable energy currently makes up just 10 percent of India's electricity needs.<br/>
印度主要依靠碳燃料，尤其是煤炭提供电力。煤炭生产的电力约占全国电力的70%。可再生能源目前仅占印度电力需求的10%。</p>
<p>The country is currently the third-largest polluter of planet-warming gases, behind China and the United States.<br/>
印度目前是全球变暖气体的第三大污染国，仅次于中国和美国。</p>
<p>KSRK Verma is the project leader for Adani Green Energy Limited. The Indian government has contracted with the company to build 20 gigawatts of the project. Verma has 35 years of experience in the industry. He called the Khavda project one of the most difficult he has ever led.<br/>
维尔马是阿达尼绿色能源有限公司的项目负责人。印度政府已与该公司签订合同建造其中20千兆瓦的项目。维尔马拥有35年的行业经验。他称卡夫达项目是他负责过的最困难的项目之一。</p>
<p>"It's not at all (an) easy site to work at," he said. He noted the area's severe conditions, including high winds, heavy rains and earthquake activity.<br/>
他说：“这不是一个容易工作的地方。”他提到了该地区的恶劣条件，包括大风、暴雨和地震活动。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rock Group Ends Live Concerts, Becomes Computerized Avatars  (2023/12/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/rock-group-ends-live-concerts-becomes-computerized-avatars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Recently, members of the American rock band Kiss closed out their final performance. The group's "The End of the Road" <strong>concert</strong> series ended in New York City's famous Madison Square Garden.</p>
<p>But as it turns out, fans will still be able to enjoy Kiss performances for years to come.</p>
<p>The band formed in 1973. It is currently made up of founders Paul Stanley and Gene Simmons, as well as Tommy Thayer and Eric Singer. Towards the end of Saturday's show, the band members left the stage and <strong>revealed</strong> computerized likenesses of themselves. The computerized <strong>avatars</strong> launched into a performance of the song "God Gave Rock and Roll to You."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gene Simmons, left, Tommy Thayer and Paul Stanley of KISS perform during the final night of the Kiss Farewell Tour on Saturday, Dec. 2, 2023, at Madison Square Garden in New York. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7ab7da4f-f61f-4895-8da8-93c4dcd6ee61_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Gene Simmons, left, Tommy Thayer and Paul Stanley of KISS perform during the final night of the "Kiss Farewell Tour" on Saturday, Dec. 2, 2023, at Madison Square Garden in New York. (Photo by Evan Agostini/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>After 50 years of Kiss, the band now hopes to be remembered forever.</p>
<p>The avatars were created by George Lucas' special-effects company Industrial Light &amp; Magic. The company also worked with Pophouse Entertainment Group. Bjorn Ulvaeus, a member of the Swedish musical group ABBA, is its founder.</p>
<p>The two companies recently came together for the "ABBA Voyage" show in London. Fans there could enjoy a full concert by the Swedish band as performed by the computerized avatars.</p>
<p>Per Sundin is chief executive officer of Pophouse Entertainment. He said the new technology lets Kiss continue its history for "<strong>eternity</strong>."</p>
<p>He said the band was not on stage during the computerized performance. He added, "Kiss could have a concert in three cities in the same night across three different continents. That's what you could do with this."</p>
<p>In order to create their computerized avatars, Kiss performed in equipment that followed their movement. This equipment is called motion capture suits.</p>
<p>Experimentation with this kind of technology has become increasingly common in the music industry. In October, K-pop star Mark Tuan partnered with Soul Machines to create a computerized version of himself called "Digital Mark." The technology lets fans have one-on-one talks with Digital Mark. Tuan is the first famous person to attach their likeness to OpenAI's GPT artificial intelligence technology.</p>
<p>Aespa is a K-pop girl group. The group often performs alongside their computerized avatars. In fact, the four-member band is meant to be seen as a group of eight.</p>
<p>Another girl group, Eternity, is made up entirely of computerized performers. No humans are necessary.</p>
<p>Kiss performer Paul Stanley told reporters that what they have done "... has been <strong>amazing</strong>, but it's not enough. The band<strong> deserves</strong> to live on because the band is bigger than we are."</p>
<p>"We can be forever young and forever <strong>iconic</strong> by taking us to places we've never dreamed of before," Kiss performer Gene Simmons added. "The technology is going to make Paul jump higher than he's ever done before."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Sherman reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>concert </strong>– <em>n</em>. a public performance of music</p>
<p><strong>revealed </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make (something) known</p>
<p><strong>avatar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a small picture that represents a computer user in a game or on the Internet</p>
<p><strong>eternity </strong>– <em>n</em>. time without an end</p>
<p><strong>amazing </strong>– <em>adj</em>. causing great surprise or wonder</p>
<p><strong>deserve </strong>– <em>v</em>. used to say that someone or something should or should not have or be given something</p>
<p><strong>iconic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. being a famous person or thing that people admire and see as a symbol of a particular idea or way of life</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ability or Capability?  (2023/12/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/ability-or-capability.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the difference between the words "ability" and "capability."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA <em>Ask a Teacher</em>,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9123-08dbf73fdce2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am Lyla from China. I am <strong>confused</strong> about "ability" and "capability." I looked them up in the dictionary, but I still can't tell them apart.</p>
<p>Can you explain the difference?</p>
<p>Thanks, and best regards,</p>
<p>Lyla</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for your question, Lyla. The words are so similar that their use can even trouble native English speakers! Generally, ability describes special skills and qualities now in use. "Capability" speaks more to the possible power or use of those skills and qualities.</p>
<p>Let's take a closer look at each.</p>
<p><strong>Ability</strong></p>
<p>"Ability" is a noun that comes from the adjective "able." If you are "able," you can do something. You can carry out an action. "Ability" means a quality, skill, or <strong>aptitude</strong> that you have that makes it possible for you to do something. Compare these sentences:</p>
<p><em> I have the ability to speak Russian and English. </em></p>
<p><em>Courtney's disabilities are the result of a car accident. </em></p>
<p><em>Henry's cooking abilities increased over years of practice in his own home.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "capability."</p>
<p><strong>Capability</strong></p>
<p>"Capability" is the quality or state of being capable. "To be capable" means having qualities or skills to successfully perform some future action. Your "capability" depends more on the situation, environment, or your desire to do something rather than just your ability to do it.</p>
<p><em>He has the capability of lifting very heavy weights, but he injured himself last year, so he chooses to lift light weights while he recovers. </em></p>
<p>"Capability" also can mean a skill set that can be further developed.</p>
<p><em>The new employees have strong capabilities in marketing. They just need more experience in the business world. </em></p>
<p>Finally, "capability" is the possibility to be affected by use or treatment.</p>
<p><em>The movie Oppenheimer is about the development of the United States' nuclear capabilities and eventual use of those weapons.</em></p>
<p><em>Critics question the administration's capability to compromise on a solution.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Lyla.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>confused</strong> –adj. lost or unsure of something</p>
<p><strong>aptitude</strong> <em>— n</em>. the ability to learn something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Technology Industry Divided over How to Govern AI Development  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/technology-industry-divided-over-how-to-govern-ai-development.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Technology leaders have shown major support for laws to govern artificial intelligence use. At the same time, they are seeking to guarantee that any future AI rules work in their favor.</p>
<p>The technology industry is increasingly divided about how to govern AI. One side supports an "open science" method to AI development; the other supports a closed method.</p>
<p>Facebook parent Meta and IBM recently launched a new group called the AI Alliance. The group supports the "open science" method of AI development. On the other side are companies such as Google, Microsoft and ChatGPT-maker OpenAI.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai speaks about Google DeepMind at a Google I/O event in Mountain View, Calif., May 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9928c3fd-329b-4073-8655-13e3ea0dc824_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai speaks about Google DeepMind at a Google I/O event in Mountain View, Calif., May 10, 2023. (AP Photo/Jeff Chiu, File)</span></div>
<p>Safety is at the heart of the debate. But, tech leaders are also arguing about who should profit from AI developments.</p>
<p><strong>What is open-source AI?</strong></p>
<p>The term "open-source" comes from a common method of building software in which the code is widely available at no cost. Anyone can examine and make changes to it.</p>
<p>Open-source AI involves more than just code. Computer scientists differ on how to define "open source." They say the identifications are dependent on which parts of the technology are publicly available and if there are restrictions on use.</p>
<p>Some computer scientists use the term "open science" to describe the wider philosophy.</p>
<p>IBM and Meta lead the AI Alliance. Members include Dell, Sony, chipmakers AMD and Intel, and several universities and smaller AI companies. The alliance is coming together to say "that the future of AI is going to be built ... on top of the open scientific exchange of ideas and on open <strong>innovation</strong>, including open source and open technologies," said Darío Gil of IBM. Gil made the comment in a discussion with The Associated Press.</p>
<p><strong>Concerns about open-source AI</strong></p>
<p>Part of the confusion about open-source AI is that the company that built ChatGPT and the image-generator DALL-E is called OpenAI. But its AI systems are closed.</p>
<p>"There are near-term and commercial <strong>incentives </strong>against open source," said Ilya Sutskever, OpenAI's chief scientist and co-founder, in a video with Stanford University in April.</p>
<p>But there is also a longer-term worry about the open development method. Sutskever noted one worry is that an AI system with powerful abilities could be too dangerous to make available to the public.</p>
<p>For example, he described a possible AI system that could learn how to start its own biological laboratory.</p>
<p>Even current AI models present risks. They could create disinformation campaigns, for example, said David Evan Harris of the University of California, Berkeley. Such campaigns could<strong> disrupt</strong> democratic elections, he said.</p>
<p>"Open source is really great in so many <strong>dimensions</strong> of technology," but AI is different, Harris said.</p>
<p>The Center for Humane Technology, a longtime critic of Meta's social media activities, is among the groups drawing attention to the risks of open-source or leaked AI models.</p>
<p>"As long as there are no <strong>guardrails</strong> in place right now, it's just completely irresponsible to be deploying these models to the public," said the group's Camille Carlton.</p>
<p><strong>Benefits and dangers</strong></p>
<p>An increasingly public debate has appeared over the good and bad of using an open-source method to AI development.</p>
<p>Meta's chief AI scientist, Yann LeCun, this fall criticized OpenAI, Google, and Anthropic on social media for what he described as "massive corporate lobbying." Le Cun argues that the companies are trying to write rules in a way that help their high-performing AI models and could help them hold their power over the technology's development. The three companies, along with OpenAI's key partner Microsoft, have formed their own industry group called the Frontier Model Forum.</p>
<p>LeCun said on X, formerly Twitter, "Openness is the only way to make AI platforms reflect the entirety of human knowledge and culture."</p>
<p>For IBM, the dispute feeds into a much longer competition that began before the AI boom. IBM was an early supporter of the open-source Linux operating system in the 1990s.</p>
<p>Chris Padilla leads IBM's international government affairs team. The companies are trying to raise fear about open-source innovation as they have in the past, he suggested.</p>
<p>He added, "I mean, this has been the Microsoft model for decades, right? They always opposed open-source programs that could compete with Windows or Office. They're taking a similar approach here."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Matt O'Brien reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>innovation</strong> <em>– n.</em> the act of introducing new ideas, devices, or methods</p>
<p><strong>incentive</strong> <em>– n.</em> something that encourages a person to do something</p>
<p><strong>disrupt</strong> <em>– v.</em> to interrupt the normal progress or activity of something</p>
<p><strong>dimension</strong> <em>– n.</em> a part of something</p>
<p><strong>guardrail</strong> <em>– n.</em> a protective device along the side of a road that prevents vehicles from driving off the road (can be used metaphorically)</p>
<p><strong>lobby</strong><em> – v.</em> to try to influence government officials to make decisions for or against something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Hanukkah Is Celebrated around the World  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/how-hanukkah-is-celebrated-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hanukkah (also written as Chanukah) is Judaism's "<strong>festival</strong> of lights." On eight straight nights, Jews come together with family and friends at the end of daylight to light one additional <strong>candle</strong> in the menorah.</p>
<p>A menorah is a lamp or candle holder used in Jewish religious ceremonies. It usually has eight branches, with a ninth place for the candle called shamash from which all the others are lit.</p>
<p>In Hebrew, Hanukkah means "<strong>dedication</strong>."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An Ultra-Orthodox Jewish man stands in front of a menorah on the third eve of Hanukkah, at the Western Wall, Judaism's holiest site in Jerusalem's old city on December 13, 2009. (AP Photo/Sebastian Scheiner, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/91867a88-114c-467a-a11f-6be7ffeb1480_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An Ultra-Orthodox Jewish man stands in front of a menorah on the third eve of Hanukkah, at the Western Wall, Judaism's holiest site in Jerusalem's old city on December 13, 2009. (AP Photo/Sebastian Scheiner, File)</span></div>
<p>The holiday marks the rededication of the Temple in Jerusalem about 2500 years ago. That was the time a small group of Jewish fighters took it back from occupying foreign forces. The fighters found a very small supply of oil in the religious building, or temple, and used it to keep a menorah lit for eight days. Their practice of lighting a nightly candle and cooking foods like potato pancakes called latkes, serve to remember the event.</p>
<p><strong>When is Hanukkah 2023?</strong></p>
<p>The dates of the holiday are based on the Hebrew month of Kislev, which usually falls sometime in November or December in the Gregorian calendar.</p>
<p>This year, Hanukkah is being celebrated from December 7 through December 15.</p>
<p><strong>Do Hanukkah celebrations differ?</strong></p>
<p>There are different branches of Judaism, like Reform, Conservative and Orthodox. But they all celebrate the holiday by bringing light into the darkness and remembering that even a small and unlikely-to-succeed effort can make great change.</p>
<p>The Talmud is Judaism's central religious book. Within it, there is a dispute over the order of lighting. But even with that dispute, most start with one candle and increase the lighting by one more candle each night while saying religious <strong>blessings</strong>.</p>
<p>The candles are added from right to left, but lit from left to right on the menorah, thus always starting with the newest light.</p>
<p>The tradition calls for candles with a real<strong> flame</strong>. But some also use electric ones in public areas, such as in hospitals, for safety reasons.</p>
<p><strong>How is Hanukkah celebrated?</strong></p>
<p>A menorah is lit in each household and traditionally is placed where it can be seen from the outside, such as a doorway or near a window. It represents the spreading of God's light to all nations.</p>
<p>The lighting of menorahs in city streets and public areas, like parks or areas of interest, has become more common in recent years in countries around the world.</p>
<p>In addition to menorah lightings, giving money to those in need and social works are also part of the celebration for many. This comes out of the belief that the Jewish people are called by God to help make the world better for all.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Giovanna Dell'Orto</em><em> reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>festival </strong>– <em>n</em>. a special time or event when people gather to celebrate something</p>
<p><strong>candle </strong>– <em>n</em>. wax that has been formed into a stick or another shape and has a string in the middle that can be burned</p>
<p><strong>dedication </strong>– <em>v</em>. to officially make (something) a place for honoring or remembering a person or event</p>
<p><strong>blessing </strong>– <em>n</em>.<strong> </strong>a short prayer</p>
<p><strong>flame </strong>– <em>n</em>. the hot, glowing gas that can be seen when a fire is burning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Studies Possible Change to Safer Nuclear Fuel  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-studies-possible-change-to-safer-nuclear-fuel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Documents show that a U.S. research program is making progress on its goal to use a safer kind of fuel for nuclear-powered Navy submarines and military ships. But the program's governmental financial support is at risk.</p>
<p>The aim of the research is to change from using highly-<strong>enriched</strong> uranium, which can be used to make bombs, to a safer choice.</p>
<p>Since 2018, the U.S. government has been exploring how to use low-enriched fuel that cannot be used as an explosive in weapons. It is doing this to help decrease the proliferation risks of keeping stores of highly-enriched uranium.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The U.S. nuclear-powered submarine USS Annapolis is anchored at a naval base on Jeju Island, South Korea, July 24, 2023. (The Defense Ministry/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e78e1538-b8cb-4e91-8af0-48022f351059_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The U.S. nuclear-powered submarine USS Annapolis is anchored at a naval base on Jeju Island, South Korea, July 24, 2023. (The Defense Ministry/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>Proliferation means a fast increase in the amount of something. Nuclear proliferation is the spread of nuclear weapons or materials that can be used to make nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>The National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) sent a report to the U.S. Congress last year. It said the research program progressed from a planning stage to an experimental campaign stage during the 2021 <strong>fiscal</strong> year. It added that early findings represent progress in what could be a 20- to 25-year design effort.</p>
<p>The documents were recently seen by Reuters reporters.</p>
<p>The issue of highly-enriched uranium is critical because of a defense technology partnership between the U.S., Australia and Britain. The $245-billion partnership, called AUKUS, permits the sale of U.S. nuclear-powered submarines. It also permits the sharing of nuclear-<strong>propulsion</strong> technology with Australia. The partnership is in answer to China's growing power in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Non-proliferation experts say sending submarines to Australia that use highly-enriched uranium could lead to other countries using the fuel.</p>
<p>The NNSA document said the low-enriched uranium fuel program seeks to meet certain U.S. Navy requirements. The document added that the fuel development process would be long and costly. Success, it said, is not guaranteed.</p>
<p>The document also noted a 2016 report's findings that it could cost more than $1 billion to develop <strong>alternative</strong> fuel. That report also said low-enriched fuel would hurt <strong>reactor</strong> strength, ship costs and operational effectiveness.</p>
<p>The NNSA's 2022 report warned the costs could take away from the higher aim of non-proliferation and naval propulsion research and development.</p>
<p>Still, head of the NNSA Jill Hruby said in the document she was pleased with progress the program has made in this difficult effort.</p>
<p>NNSA did not immediately respond to questions about the documents when asked by Reuters.</p>
<p>Congress has given the program $100 million since 2016. But governmental financial support is in question after a group in the Republican-controlled House of Representatives this year voted to stop it. The Senate has approved financial support and the Senate and House of Representatives are expected to work together to decide on any <strong>funding</strong>.</p>
<p>Alan Kuperman is a professor at the University of Texas at Austin. He works at the Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Project. He has pushed the government to accept low-enriched uranium for Navy ships.</p>
<p>Kuperman also looked at the documents from NNSA. He said the documents make three things clear. First, the program is very important in preventing the spread of nuclear weapons. Second, it is making quick progress. And third, it will go into use only if it can keep the current performance of U.S. Navy ships.</p>
<p>He said the possible $1-billion cost for the fuel was small compared to trillions of dollars spent on all the Navy's nuclear ships.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Timothy Gardner reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>enrich </strong>– <em>v</em>. to improve the quality of (something)</p>
<p><strong>fiscal </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to money and especially to the money a government, business, or organization earns, spends, and owes</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong>– <em>n</em>. the force that moves something forward</p>
<p><strong>alternative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not usual or traditional</p>
<p><strong>reactor </strong>– <em>n</em>. a large device that produces nuclear energy</p>
<p><strong>fund </strong>– <em>v</em>. to provide money for (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reviewing Pet Descriptions  (2023/12/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/reviewing-pet-descriptions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>A few weeks ago, we asked our readers and listeners to describe their pets. We asked them to practice using <strong>multiple</strong> adjectives in a certain order. One reader, Maria from Argentina, wrote to us about her dog, Ceferina.</p>
<p>In this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will <strong>review</strong> Maria's message describing her dog. And we will give some grammar suggestions.</p>
<p><strong>Maria's Message about her Pet</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5e22-08dbf6776a4c_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p><em>I have five dogs, three cats and one<strong> rooster</strong>. I love animals very much but I am going to describe only one of them. My female dog called Ceferina. She is a senior big dog. </em></p>
<p><em>I meet her at the street. She was very ill and sad. Now is a <strong>cute</strong> dog. </em></p>
<p><em>Her colors is black and her eyes brown. She is a friendly dog. She looks like brave but she is lovely dog. </em></p>
<p><strong>Review of Maria's message</strong></p>
<p>Let's start with the first two sentences.</p>
<p><em>I have five dogs, three cats and one rooster. I love animals very much but I am going to describe only one of them.</em></p>
<p>These two sentences are almost perfect. Maria uses number adjectives to describe how many pets she has. Maria has nine pets total! She then says that she will only choose one.</p>
<p>We suggest adding "my" before "animals" because Maria then refers to her animals as "them" in the second half of the sentence. The choice "my" is a more specific choice. We also suggest adding a comma before "but" to separate the two clauses.</p>
<p><em>I love my animals very much, but I am going to describe only one of them.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto the next two sentences.</p>
<p><em>My female dog called Ceferina. She is a senior big dog. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, Maria describes the <strong>gender </strong>of the dog. We recommend adding "is" before "called." This is a <strong>passive</strong> sentence, so we must use a form of "be" plus the verb in the past participle form.</p>
<p><em>My female dog is called Ceferina.</em></p>
<p>The next sentence has two adjectives: "senior" and "big." This is where we should pay attention to the order of adjectives. When we use two or more adjectives from different categories, we must order them a certain way in the sentence.</p>
<p>The order of the adjective categories is as follows: quantity, opinion, size, age, shape or length, color, <strong>origin, </strong>material, and purpose.</p>
<p>We recommend changing the order of the adjectives "senior" and "big" based on the order of adjectives rule. Size adjectives come before age adjectives.</p>
<p><em>She is a big senior dog.</em></p>
<p>Note that we do not need a comma between the adjectives because these are cumulative adjectives. In other words, they build on each other. They are from different adjective categories so they cannot be separated by a comma.</p>
<p>Let's look at the next few sentences.</p>
<p><em>I meet her at the street. She was very ill and sad. Now is a cute dog. </em></p>
<p>First, instead of "meet," you can use the verb "find" to say that you first discovered or saw your dog. You should use the past tense of "find" because you are talking about a time in the past.</p>
<p>Next, we suggest changing the preposition "at" to either the preposition "in" or "on."</p>
<p>"In the street" means that you found her in the middle of the street. "In" is used for talking about an enclosed space. "On the street" means that you found her somewhere along the street. "On" is used for general location.</p>
<p>Maria did a great job separating the adjectives "ill" and "sad" with the conjunction "and." These are opinion adjectives and carry equal importance in the sentence. This makes them coordinating adjectives, so we can use "and" or only a comma to separate them. We can also change their order and keep the same meaning.</p>
<p>In the next sentence, we need a subject. We can use the pronoun "she." We also suggest adding a comma after "now."</p>
<p><em>I found her on the street. She was very ill and sad. Now, she is a cute dog. </em></p>
<p>And finally, we have the last three sentences.</p>
<p><em>Her colors is black and her eyes brown. She is a friendly dog. She looks like brave but she is lovely dog. </em></p>
<p>In the first sentence, we have some subject-verb agreement issues. Since Maria's dog is black, "color" can be singular.</p>
<p>We need the verb "are" in the second half of that sentence to go after "eyes."</p>
<p><em>Her color is black and her eyes are brown. </em></p>
<p>Finally, in the last sentence we suggest a different word for "brave." We want another word that is the opposite of "lovely." We could say that Ceferina looks "fierce," which is like "brave" and "intense" combined.</p>
<p>We can also remove "like" because we are not making a comparison, just a contrast. And finally, we need to add the indefinite article "a" before dog.</p>
<p><em>She looks fierce, but she is a lovely dog. </em></p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today, we looked at Maria's message about her dog, Ceferina. We talked about the order of adjectives, commas, and subject verb agreement. We learned about coordinating and cumulative adjectives and their connection to the order of adjectives.</p>
<p>Thank you, Maria, for telling us about Ceferina! We are happy she found such a loving home.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Mateo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in the Story</h2>
<p><strong>rooster</strong> – <em>n.</em> an adult male chicken</p>
<p><strong>cute </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having a pleasing, youthful appearance</p>
<p><strong>gender </strong>– <em>n.</em><strong> </strong>the state of being male or female</p>
<p><strong>passive </strong><em>– adj. the quality of not being active or not taking action and letting things happen</em></p>
<p><strong>origin </strong>–<em> n. </em>the place that a person or thing comes from</p>
<p><strong>clause </strong>– <em>n</em>. (grammar) a part of a sentence that has its own subject and verb</p>
<p> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: 2023 Would Be Warmest Year on Record  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/scientists-2023-would-be-warmest-year-on-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>European Union scientists said on Wednesday that 2023 would be the warmest year on record. The average world temperature for the first 11 months of the year hit the highest level on record, 1.46 degrees Celsius above the 1850 to 1900 average.</p>
<p>The record comes as governments are in negotiations at the COP28 meeting in Dubai. Governments are deciding whether to gradually stop the use of coal, oil and gas, the main source of warming <strong>emissions</strong>.</p>
<p>The temperature for the January to November period was 0.13 degrees higher than the average for the same period in 2016, currently the warmest calendar year on record. That information comes from the Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S).</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A person rests under an umbrella as the sun sets, Sept. 12, 2023, in Newport Beach, Calif. European Union scientists said 2023 would be the warmest year on record. (AP Photo/Ryan Sun, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9a496d05-7fb3-43ad-a654-d987de31a7e9_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A person rests under an umbrella as the sun sets, Sept. 12, 2023, in Newport Beach, Calif. European Union scientists said 2023 would be the warmest year on record. (AP Photo/Ryan Sun, File)</span></div>
<p>November 2023 was the warmest November on record worldwide. The average surface air temperature was 14.22 degrees, 0.85 degrees above the 1991 to 2020 average for November. It was 0.32 degrees above the previous warmest November, in 2020, C3S added.</p>
<p>Samantha Burgess is deputy director of C3S. She said in a statement that the "November temperatures, including two days warmer than 2C above <strong>preindustrial</strong>, mean that 2023 is the warmest year in recorded history."</p>
<p>The autumn in the Northern Hemisphere from September to November was also the warmest on record by a large amount. The average temperature was 15.3 degrees, 0.88 degrees above average, EU scientists said.</p>
<p>The 2015 Paris climate agreement set a goal of limiting worldwide temperature rise to 1.5 degrees above pre-industrial times. Above that limit, scientists warn of severe effects on weather, health and agriculture.</p>
<p>Diplomats, scientists, activists and others have been meeting in Dubai to find ways to limit warming to those levels. But the planet is not cooperating. They say Earth is on its way to reach 2.7 to 2.9 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial times.</p>
<p>C3S records go back to 1940. United States government records go back to 1850. Using information from ice cores, tree rings and corals, scientists have said this is the warmest 10-year period Earth has seen in about 125,000 years. That dates back to the time before human civilization.</p>
<p>Scientists say there are two driving forces behind the six straight months of record hot temperatures. One is human-caused climate change from the burning of coal, oil and gas. And El Nino, the natural warming of surface waters in the Pacific, is making it worse.</p>
<p>"2023 is very likely to be a cool year in the future unless we do something about our dependence on <strong>fossil fuels</strong>," Burgess said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters and The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>preindustrial </strong><em>— adj. </em>relating to a time before industrialization</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>— n. </em>a fuel such as coal, oil, or natural gas that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>System Tested in US Can Charge Electric Vehicles as they Drive  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/system-tested-in-us-can-charge-electric-vehicles-as-they-drive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Officials in the American city of Detroit, Michigan, have equipped a piece of road with technology designed to charge electric vehicles (EVs) on the path.</p>
<p>The roadway is meant to serve as a demonstration project for the technology, which could be expanded to larger road systems. Leaders of the project say it is believed to be the country's first public wireless charging roadway built for EVs.</p>
<p>The system uses a series of copper wires placed underneath the road. These wires have the ability to send electricity through a magnetic field to charge an EV's battery. Charging can happen while the car is driving or sitting above the equipment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An electric van drives past a visible in-road wireless charging coil to be installed in a street in Detroit, Wednesday, Nov. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2fbd-08dbf4fc2697_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An electric van drives past a visible in-road wireless charging coil to be installed in a street in Detroit, Wednesday, Nov. 29, 2023. (AP Photo/Paul Sancya)</span></div>
<p>The technology was created by an Israeli company called Electreon, a developer of wireless charging solutions for EVs. The company currently has contracts to build similar roadways in Israel, Sweden, Italy and Germany.</p>
<p>Stefan Tongur is Electreon's vice president of business development. He told <em>The Associated Press</em> EVs require special equipment to receive the wireless signal. "The technology is smart," Tongur said, and "knows who you are..."</p>
<p>The system was recently demonstrated to the public at a technology development center in Detroit. The center seeks solutions to transportation issues facing cities. The effort, which includes several development projects, is where Ford Motor Company is building a factory to develop self-driving vehicles.</p>
<p>The electrified road stretches about one half-kilometer. It will be used to test and improve the technology in preparation for wider releases, said Michigan's Department of Transportation (<strong>DOT</strong>)<strong>.</strong></p>
<p>Tongur said the project aims to "demonstrate how wireless charging unlocks widespread EV <strong>adoption</strong>, addressing limited range, <strong>grid</strong> limitations, and battery size and costs."</p>
<p>He looks forward to a future in which, in his words, "EVs are the <strong>norm</strong>, not the exception."</p>
<p>Electreon says the electric road system is safe for people and animals walking over it and does not harm drivers.</p>
<p>Michigan's DOT signed a five-year agreement with Electreon to develop the roadway charging system. Officials have said they plan to build another electrified stretch of road in another part of the city.</p>
<p>American President Joe Biden is seeking to build a nationwide network of EV charging stations in the United States. His administration plans to establish at least a half-million sites along highways in the United States by 2030.</p>
<p>Michigan transportation officials say the wireless-charging roadway project has helped position the state and city of Detroit as national leaders in EV technology. "In Michigan, we want to stay <strong>ahead of the curve</strong>," Michigan DOT Director Bradley C. Wieferich told the <em>AP</em>. He added, "We want to lead the curve."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>adopt </strong><em>– v. </em>to accept or start using something</p>
<p><strong>grid </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of connected wires used to supply electrical power to large areas</p>
<p><strong>norm </strong><em>– n. </em>the usual way that something happens</p>
<p><strong>ahead of the curve </strong><em>– phr. </em>to have a deeper or developing understanding of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Venezuela’s Claims on Guyana’s Territory Raise Concerns  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/venezuela-s-claims-on-guyana-s-territory-raise-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Venezuela has increased pressure on its claim that the territory of Essequibo belongs to the country. However, the government of President Nicolás Maduro has little to no support from neighbors or intergovernmental organizations for the claim.</p>
<p>Essequibo is an area that makes up most of the South American country of Guyana, the neighbor to the east of Venezuela.</p>
<p>On Sunday, the Venezuelan government held a vote asking the Venezuelan people if they believed the country should declare Essequibo a Venezuelan state.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - View of Kaieteur, the world's largest single drop waterfall, located in the Potaro-Siparuni region of Guyana, on April 12, 2023. (Photo by Mart&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;237;n SILVA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d9356fc8-312b-4b83-be36-d00db18c681c_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - View of Kaieteur, the world's largest single drop waterfall, located in the Potaro-Siparuni region of Guyana, on April 12, 2023. (Photo by Mart<i>&amp;#</i>237;n SILVA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Despite media reports that showed nearly empty voting centers and other signs of low voter turnout, the Maduro government claimed that 10.5 million people voted. That is more than the last presidential election. Of those, it said 95 percent agreed in declaring Essequibo part of Venezuela.</p>
<p>The claim has been criticized by governments in both South America and the Caribbean. And there have been warnings from the International Court of Justice.</p>
<p>Last week, the court ruled that Venezuela must avoid taking any action which would change Guyana's current control of the territory.</p>
<p>In recent months, Venezuela has further increased <strong>tensions</strong> by deploying its military to the border with Guyana. And it has announced that it has plans to install a landing for planes in the area to provide support for the development of Essequibo.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, Guyana President Mohamed Irfaan Ali said his country does not plan to surrender any territory to Venezuelan control. And he called on the Maduro government to moderate its behavior.</p>
<p>Ali said to his countrymen, "I want to advise Venezuela that this is an <strong>opportunity</strong> for them to show <strong>maturity</strong>, an opportunity for them to show responsibility, and we call upon them once more [to] join us in ..." permitting the rule of law to work and to decide the outcome of these tensions.</p>
<p><strong>Publicity stunt gone wrong</strong></p>
<p>Christopher Sabatini works for Latin America at the London-based foreign policy group Chatham House. He told VOA that the vote in Venezuela had all the signs of a <strong>publicity stunt </strong>that got out of control. And it now threatens to turn into serious conflict.</p>
<p>Sabatini told VOA that the vote was mostly for those within the country, but the Maduro government has started something "... and we don't know where it's going to go."</p>
<p><strong>Roots of the dispute</strong></p>
<p>Essequibo is an area of 160,000 square kilometers with little development. It makes up the western two-thirds of Guyana, a country on South America's northern Atlantic coast.</p>
<p>The Venezuelan government has long claimed Essequibo. That is despite the fact that the area has been recognized by the international community, first as part of British Guiana and then as part of present-day Guyana, for more than 100 years.</p>
<p>The Venezuelan claim is largely based on the fact that during the colonial period, Essequibo and Venezuela were both administered by Spain. As part of a settlement reached by an international group, Essequibo was ruled to be part of British territory. All of modern-day Guyana gained independence in 1966.</p>
<p>The International Court of Justice is currently considering Venezuela's claim in a request brought forward by the Maduro government in 2018. But it is believed to be years away from issuing a decision.</p>
<p>The border dispute gained importance in 2015. That was after oil company ExxonMobil proved that there are billions of <strong>barrels </strong>worth of oil that could be reached off the coast of Essequibo in Guyana's territorial waters.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Rob Garver reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tension </strong>– <em>n</em>. a state in which people, groups, or countries disagree with and feel anger toward each other</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>– <em>n</em>. an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>maturity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the state of being fully developed in the body or the mind</p>
<p><strong>publicity stunt </strong>– <em>n</em>. something done just to get the attention of the public</p>
<p><strong>barrel </strong>– <em>n</em>. a unit of measurement of volume equal to 159 liters of oil</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Agency Aims to Remove Stray Cats from Puerto Rico’s Historic Fortress  (2023/12/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/agency-aims-to-remove-stray-cats-from-puerto-rico-s-historic-fortress.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The US National Park Service recently announced a plan to remove hundreds of <strong>stray</strong> cats that <strong>wander</strong> historic Old San Juan on the island of Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Local people and <strong>tourists</strong> consider the cats a joy, but some are bothered by them while others worry about disease.</p>
<p>There are about 200 cats that live on about 30 hectares surrounding the old <strong>fortress</strong> at the San Juan Historic Site. The U.S. federal agency operates the site because Puerto Rico is a territory of the United States.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A stray cat sits on a wall in Old San Juan, Puerto Rico, Wednesday, Nov. 2, 2022. The U.S. National Park Service has announced a plan to remove them. (AP Photo/Alejandro Granadillo, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/154d77e2-3cf5-4849-895f-21a7265619ab_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A stray cat sits on a wall in Old San Juan, Puerto Rico, Wednesday, Nov. 2, 2022. The U.S. National Park Service has announced a plan to remove them. (AP Photo/Alejandro Granadillo, File)</span></div>
<p>The park service said it will pay an animal <strong>welfare </strong>organization to remove the cats. If the organization does not remove the cats within six months, the park service said it will have the cats removed.</p>
<p>Cat lovers are disappointed with the plan. However, the agency said that the cats can spread diseases to humans. The plan said that the removal will be of value to visitors by reducing the possibility of disease.</p>
<p>Ana Maria Salicrup works for the nonprofit group Save a Gato. "Gato" is the Spanish word for "cat." The group has helped care for the cats for years and hopes the agency will choose it to do the work. However, Salicrup said that the six-month time limit is not realistic.</p>
<p>"Anyone who has worked with cats knows that is impossible. They are setting us up for failure," Salicrup said.</p>
<p>There are many different kinds of cats with different behaviors that wander along the fortress known as "El Morro" which was built in the 1500s. The fortress is by the ocean and the island's capital, San Juan.</p>
<p>The cats are believed to have come from the time when Puerto Rico was a colony of Spain. But some were brought to the capital to kill rats in the mid-1900s by Mayor Felisa Rincon de Gautier, the first female mayor elected in the Americas.</p>
<p>The cats have since increased in number over the years. Visitors to Old San Juan often take pictures with the cats, and residents and volunteers with Save a Gato take care of them. The group feeds, <strong>sterilizes</strong>, and places them for <strong>adoption</strong>.</p>
<p>Federal officials said two years ago that area was overpopulated with cats. The smell of waste and the behavior of the cats was "inconsistent with the cultural landscape," the agency said.</p>
<p>Last year, the National Park Service offered two possibilities during a public meeting: remove the animals or do nothing.</p>
<p>Those in attendance rejected removing the cats. One man described the cats as "one of the wonders of Old San Juan." The local people have even created a statue of the cats in the historic area.</p>
<p>Danna Wakefield works in the solar industry and moved to Puerto Rico in 2020. She visits the cats weekly. She told the Associated Press, "These cats are <strong>unique</strong> to San Juan. Me and many other people love that walk because of the cats."</p>
<p>In the removal plan, the agency said that cat feeding areas are to be removed unless they are used to trap cats. It said that feeding the cats is not permitted and attracts rats. Feeding the cats also causes people to leave their own unwanted cats in the area because they know their cats will be fed.</p>
<p>The plan says that the animal welfare organization that is chosen will be responsible for deciding whether the cats will be adopted, placed in a temporary home, kept in a shelter or destroyed.</p>
<p>The National Park Service said that the six-month time limit to trap the cats might be extended if progress is made. If that does not happen, then the current plan would end, and the service would pay for a removal agency.</p>
<p>Salicrup said finding a home for so many cats is difficult. Save a Gato has talked with animal shelters on the U.S. mainland. They are unwilling to take the cats.</p>
<p>"The response always is, 'You cannot bring 100 cats here,'" she said.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>Danica Coto <em>reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stray </strong>– <em>adj. </em>to describe going in a direction that is away from a group or from the place where you should be</p>
<p><strong>wander </strong>– <em>v. </em>to move from one place to another without a particular direction or destination</p>
<p><strong>tourist </strong>–n. a person who travels for pleasure and not for business</p>
<p><strong>fortress </strong>–n. a structure for defense against military attack</p>
<p><strong>welfare </strong><em>– n. </em>the state of being happy, healthy, or successful; well-being</p>
<p><strong>sterilize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make a living thing unable to produce children or offspring</p>
<p><strong>adopt </strong>–v. to legally take another person's child or pet as your own</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong><em> </em>– <em>adj</em>.<em> </em>used to say that something or someone is unlike anything or anyone else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Growing Plants to Save Australia's Koalas  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/growing-plants-to-save-australia-s-koalas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Lucy was rescued from a rural property in New South Wales, Australia, two years ago. She was suffering from chlamydia, a disease widespread among koalas.</p>
<p>Today, she is one of the lucky animals living in tree <strong>corridors</strong> that have been created to protect koalas and other animals by saving their quickly shrinking habitat, or natural environment.</p>
<p>The corridors, planted by the local conservation group Bangalow Koalas, are made up of large systems of plants. They are a lifeline for koalas and other animals like the glossy black cockatoo, gliders, possums, and wallabies. All of them are endangered, or at risk of becoming <strong>extinct</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Lucy, an adult female Koala sits in a eucalyptus tree planted by Bangalow Koalas in Australia. (Saul Goodwin/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a24f4482-d48d-424c-b0e6-3c2c373822c7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Lucy, an adult female Koala sits in a eucalyptus tree planted by Bangalow Koalas in Australia. (Saul Goodwin/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The corridors provide a safe path across the koala's increasingly broken habitat. This permits increased genetic mixing and protection from human threats.</p>
<p>"Our corridors are actually trying to get them away from humans, from cars, from dogs," said Linda Sparrow, president of Bangalow Koalas. "They can safely move across the <strong>landscape</strong> and not have to put up with us humans."</p>
<p>The koala is predicted to be extinct in the wild in New South Wales by 2050. Some of the biggest threats include wildfires and habitat loss through land clearing for development. Koalas have already been declared endangered in several Australian states.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019, Bangalow Koalas has planted over 336,000 trees on 119 properties, helping koala conservation and improving the local ecosystem. The group, which depends on community volunteers, aims to plant 500,000 trees by 2025.</p>
<p>"The neighbor would want to join and then another neighbor will want to join," Sparrow said, describing increasing the number of people involved in the corridor.</p>
<p>Volunteer Lindy Stacker, who has been planting trees for over five years, said the activity is good for mental health and has brought the community together.</p>
<p>A recent report by the Australian Koala Foundation said the animal was worth an estimated $3.2 billion per year to the <strong>tourism</strong> industry.</p>
<p>However, the World Wildlife Fund-Australia reported concerning declines in koala populations in Australian states, with a 50 percent drop in Queensland and a 62 percent drop in New South Wales since 2001.</p>
<p>Sparrow remains committed to the cause.</p>
<p>"I can't imagine a world where there's no koalas in the wild," she said.</p>
<p>"We're going to do everything we can possibly to make sure that doesn't happen."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Jill Gralow reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>corridor</strong>–<em>n</em>. land that connects and provides a way through</p>
<p><strong>extinct</strong>–<em>adj</em>. no longer existing</p>
<p><strong>landscape</strong>–<em>n</em>. the qualities that you can see in an area of land</p>
<p><strong>tourism</strong>–<em>n</em>. travel for vacation or pleasure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some US Schools Operate outside State Education System  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/some-us-schools-operate-outside-state-education-system.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Nearly 9,000 private schools in the American state of Louisiana do not need state approval to give high school <strong>diplomas</strong>.</p>
<p>Public schools, formal homeschooling programs and traditional private schools all need state approval. Nearly all of the schools lacking approval were created to serve a single homeschooling family. But some have buildings, classrooms, teachers and many students.</p>
<p>A small percentage of Louisiana's students have ties to unapproved schools. The schools are being called Louisiana's <strong>off-the-grid</strong> school system. Some observers say they are a growing example of the nation's continuing effects of COVID-19 because families appear to be leaving traditional education.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Salutatorian Alasia Baker, 17, center, and Khyli Barbee, 15, following Baker, leave a graduation ceremony for Springfield Preparatory School at Victory in Christ church in Holden, La., Saturday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Matthew Hinton)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-12ae-08dbf4e6e30f_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Salutatorian Alasia Baker, 17, center, and Khyli Barbee, 15, following Baker, leave a graduation ceremony for Springfield Preparatory School at Victory in Christ church in Holden, La., Saturday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Matthew Hinton)</span></div>
<p>U.S. public school <strong>enrollment</strong> fell by more than 1.2 million students in the first two years of the pandemic. Many families sent their children to private school or told their state they were homeschooling. But the Associated Press (AP) and its partners say thousands of other students are unaccounted for.</p>
<p>The students in Louisiana's "off-the-grid" school system are not missing. But there is no way to know what kind of education they are getting.</p>
<p>The AP and <em>The Advocate</em>, a Louisiana newspaper, say that over 21,000 students are enrolled in the state's unapproved schools. That is nearly double the number from before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Supporters of the system want to avoid state <strong>oversight</strong>. They say Louisiana's unapproved schools are an extension of the idea of parental rights in education.</p>
<p>One such school in Louisiana is Springfield Preparatory School. The school calls itself an <strong>umbrella</strong> school for Christian homeschoolers. Most students there attend the school to get an education through classes or <strong>tutoring</strong>.</p>
<p>However, school leader Kitty Sibley Morrison is also willing to give a diploma to anyone whose parents say they were homeschooled, even years earlier.</p>
<p>"Sometimes it takes two or three times to explain to them that they are free," Sibley Morrison said. "Their parents are in charge of them, not the state."</p>
<p><strong>A different choice for homeschooling</strong></p>
<p>Sibley Morrison said she is not selling diplomas; she is selling lifetime services for homeschooling families.</p>
<p>"We're not here to make money," she said.</p>
<p>Yet a list of prices is placed on the front window of the school building: $250 for diploma services, a $50 application fee, $35 for a diploma cover and $130 to take part in a ceremony.</p>
<p>The number of students in unapproved schools like Springfield has nearly doubled. State records show there were 11,600 students in the 2017 to 2018 school year and over 21,000 in 2022 to 2023.</p>
<p>There is little information available about these schools. The state calls them "nonpublic schools not seeking state approval." To start one, an adult must only report their school's name and address, their contact information and how many students they have.</p>
<p>Most of the schools are small, single-family home schools. However, last year, 30 of Louisiana's unapproved schools reported they had at least 50 children enrolled.</p>
<p>Laura Hawkins says there is no way for the government to know whether the schools are safe, good, or even whether they exist. Hawkins is a former official of the Louisiana Department of Education who worked on its school choice efforts until 2020.</p>
<p>The department warns parents on its website that it cannot confirm whether these organizations even meet the legal definition of a school.</p>
<p>Louisiana has two <strong>options</strong> for homeschooling.</p>
<p>Parents who want their child to receive a state-recognized high school diploma can <strong>apply</strong> for the official home study program. They must apply using test scores or copies of the student's work. The work must show their child has received 180 days of schooling of the same quality as a public school's.</p>
<p>The state-recognized diploma is more widely accepted by colleges. It also permits students to be considered for a popular in-state scholarship program.</p>
<p>Families can also choose to set up their own private school without asking for state approval. There are no requirements to prove a child is getting an education. The schools do not even have to provide the names of students who are attending.</p>
<p>At least two unapproved schools have had abuse <strong>scandals</strong>. But the state Department of Education says it has no legal power to do anything.</p>
<p>Today, over 12 states permit families to open a private school as a form of homeschooling, including California, Illinois and Texas. Around half the states require those schools to teach basic subjects such as math and reading. Louisiana is not one of them.</p>
<p><strong>‘I take their word for it'</strong></p>
<p>Springfield Preparatory occupies two buildings on Springfield's main street. State records say 250 students attend, but Sibley Morrison said the school does not keep the number.</p>
<p>Some homeschooling families come for art or science. Others attend services like career guidance, test preparation and "explanation and support in their parental rights," said Sibley Morrison. Some, such as Arliya Martin, go straight for a diploma.</p>
<p>Martin was expelled from high school in 10th grade after getting in a fight. She tried a military-style program for at-risk youths but finished without her GED. The GED test provides what is equal to a high school diploma.</p>
<p>"At 17, I was already by myself. I had my son at 18, and it was just work, work, work," she said.</p>
<p>Within days of meeting Sibley Morrison, Martin visited her office and got a diploma.</p>
<p>The document was backdated to 2015, when she would have graduated high school. It also said she had completed a program for graduation "approved by the Louisiana Board of Education," which is not true. After questions from AP, Sibley Morrison said there had been a mistake and that the document would be corrected.</p>
<p>Signs at the school advertise "state-approved" diplomas although the state has not approved the school. Sibley Morrison said she can use those words because she pushes families in her program to also sign up for the state-approved home study program.</p>
<p>After learning that her diploma is not approved by the state and might not be accepted by some colleges, Martin said she did not feel bad. Friends and family members have gotten diplomas from the same school and have gone on to college and successful careers, she said.</p>
<p>Sibley Morrison said parents are the only people who can decide if and when someone is properly educated.</p>
<p>"When parents say, ‘My child is ready to go into the real world' — I take their word for it," Sibley Morrison said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Sharon Lurye reported this story for the Associated Press. Charles Lussier contributed to it. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>off-the-grid </strong><em>— adj. (informal) </em>not connected to a formal or official system</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enrollment </strong><em>— adj. </em>the process of getting accepted to an institution such as a school or college and providing all necessary documents</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>oversight </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of overseeing and activity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>umbrella </strong><em>— adj. </em>describing a group that includes many other groups that might be quite different or in different places<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>option </strong><em>— n. </em>a choice or possibility to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor </strong>–v. to teach only one or a very small group of students</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diploma </strong><em>— adj. </em>a document that is given to people who complete their classes and course of study at a high school, college or university</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scandal </strong>–n. something that happens because it is shocking, morally or legally wrong</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>COP28 Meeting in Dubai Centers on ‘Phase Out’ or ‘Phase Down’ of Fossil Fuels  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/cop28-meeting-in-dubai-centers-on-phase-out-or-phase-down-of-fossil-fuels.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The world's climate negotiators are meeting this month in Dubai for the COP28 United Nations Climate Conference. Activists, scientists and U.N. officials want the representatives to make plans to "<strong>phase</strong> out" the use of fossil fuels as an energy source.</p>
<p>However, some representatives are using the term "phase down" instead.</p>
<p>To "phase out" means to end something slowly through a planned series of steps. But to "phase down" means to slowly reduce the use of something instead of stopping completely.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="International leaders at the United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP28), in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Thaier Al-Sudani)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/efc339a4-e39a-4965-948d-3abf41b78707_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">International leaders at the United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP28), in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, December 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Thaier Al-Sudani)</span></div>
<p>The concern, say climate scientists, is that the time for a "phase down" is over.</p>
<p>Bill Hare is a climate scientist and the CEO of Climate Analytics. He said unless the result of the meeting is a "phase out," there is unlikely to be an "improvement in temperature."</p>
<p>The COP28 meeting runs until December 12. During last year's COP27 event, negotiators agreed to plans that would limit <strong>global</strong> temperature warming to only 2.4 degrees Celsius over pre-industrial times.</p>
<p>But a recently updated report found that the world is going in the wrong direction. The report, called the Climate Action Tracker, found that the world is on target for a 2.5-degree rise. It added that several nations, including Indonesia and Iran, have increased their use of fossil fuels. These increases are part of why the world is warming more quickly.</p>
<p>Adnan Amin is the leader of COP28. He is former Director-General of the UN's International Renewable Energy Agency. He said the negotiators have so far produced a "pretty <strong>comprehensive</strong>" <strong>draft</strong> for a central outline of the meeting. The draft is called the Global Stocktake. He said he expects a "very intensive <strong>engagement</strong> process" between the negotiators during the next week of meetings.</p>
<p>The draft is 24 pages long and covers a number of issues. However the greatest concern is the choice between a "phasedown of ... coal power" or "an orderly and just phase out of fossil fuels."</p>
<p>Amin noted that, coming into the event, he did not believe it would be possible to even include "phase out" language in the document. He said some countries are not prepared to agree to a phase out because they require fossil fuel energy to grow their economies.</p>
<p>Critics and activists note that some countries signed on to last year's plan but moved forward with expanding their use of fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Ana Missirliu is an <strong>analyst</strong> at the New Climate Institute. She said she has seen "worrying announcements" in the last year. She pointed to the host nation of COP28 – the United Arab Emirates – announcing a $150-billion expansion of its oil and gas industry. She also pointed to expansions in the United States, Britain and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Several protest groups are in Dubai. They are holding up signs in "action zones" near the UN event. The protesters are asking the representatives to push for a "phase out."</p>
<p>Although there may be some nations pushing for language that does not require a "phase out," many countries are planning to increase their use of renewable energy. More than 100 countries say they will <strong>triple</strong> their ability to create clean energy and double their energy <strong>efficiency</strong> by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>phase </strong>(out or down)<strong> </strong>–v. to introduce something slowly</p>
<p><strong>global </strong>–adj. having to do with the whole world</p>
<p><strong>comprehensive </strong>–adj. including many, or most, things</p>
<p><strong>draft </strong>–n. writing or a document that is the first version of something, not the final</p>
<p><strong>engagement </strong>–n. the act or state of being involved with something</p>
<p><strong>analyst </strong>–n. a person who studies a topic and then makes a recommendation</p>
<p><strong>triple </strong>–v. to increase something by 300 percent or three times</p>
<p><strong>efficiency </strong>–n. the ability to do something or produce something without wasting resources</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More Rohingya Refugees Fleeing Bangladesh by Boat This Year  (2023/12/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/more-rohingya-refugees-fleeing-bangladesh-by-boat-this-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>The number of Rohingya taking risky boat trips to flee refugee camps in Bangladesh is rising even higher than last year. Human rights groups and aid agencies told VOA that those numbers could keep rising.</p>
<p>The Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, UNHCR, said in a statement that a boat with 150 Rohingya on board landed in western Indonesia Saturday morning. Amnesty International's Indonesia office told VOA it had confirmed the landing as well.</p>
<p>That brings the total number of Rohingya fleeing across the Andaman Sea by boat to 3,722 so far this year, says the UNHCR.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Children of newly-arrived Rohingya refugees are seen at a beach on Sabang island, Aceh province, Indonesia, on December 2, 2023. (Photo by CHAIDEER MAHYUDDIN / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4c7d951a-6c71-446b-a217-38cd71bcf74b_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Children of newly-arrived Rohingya refugees are seen at a beach on Sabang island, Aceh province, Indonesia, on December 2, 2023. (Photo by CHAIDEER MAHYUDDIN / AFP)</span></div>
<p>In its statement, the refugee agency said it had also received several reports of two more boats with broken engines <strong>stranded </strong>in the Andaman Sea. Those boats hold 400 or more people. The agency issued an <strong>urgent</strong> search and rescue call to countries in the area.</p>
<p>In 2022, the UNHCR counted 3,705 Rohingya who tried to flee. That was the most for any year since 2015.</p>
<p>December is a time when the waters are somewhat calm. And it is the time when most Rohingya try to leave. UNHCR spokesperson Babar Baloch noted, "We can't <strong>predict</strong> what is going to happen in December, but if we look at last year, 2022, the last three months were the ... busiest."</p>
<p><strong>More to come</strong></p>
<p>The Rohingya is a mostly Muslim minority from Buddhist-majority Myanmar. Nearly 1 million currently live in several large refugee camps in eastern Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Most arrived in 2017, fleeing what the U.N. calls a campaign of "<strong>genocidal intent</strong>" by the Myanmar military.</p>
<p>Now, some try to flee by boat to Malaysia or Indonesia, both Muslim-majority countries. Several hundred have died attempting to flee on old and overcrowded boats. Entire boats filled with refugees are believed to have been lost at sea.</p>
<p>Chris Lewa is with the Arakan Project, a group that closely follows the issue. She told VOA, "I believe there will be a lot more people on the way, but to [give] a <strong>figure</strong> ... is impossible."</p>
<p><strong>Reasons for the increase</strong></p>
<p>Aid groups and the Rohingya blame worsening conditions in the camps in Bangladesh for the increase in attempts to flee. The refugees complain of rising <strong>gang</strong> violence, a lack of jobs and schools, and little food.</p>
<p>The U.N. World Food Program is the main source of food aid for the refugees. In June, it reduced the amount of monthly food aid, for the second time, to $8 per person per month. The agency blamed lack of <strong>donor </strong>support for the cuts.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Rohingya are losing hope that they will be able to return safely to Myanmar where they are mostly denied citizenship.</p>
<p>Mohammed Rezuwan Khan is a Rohingya refugee. He said, "...All these things [are] driving the people to take the dangerous sea <strong>journeys</strong>." Khan said his sister and niece knew the risks but still fled by boat last year. They made it to Indonesia.</p>
<p>In years past, the boats carried mostly single men and women. But the UNHCR says more families with children are now traveling together. This year nearly a third of those making the dangerous trip are children.</p>
<p><strong>Losing their lives</strong></p>
<p>UNHCR spokesperson Babar Baloch says Indonesia is the only country willing to take in the Rohingya. A 2016 presidential decision in Indonesia ordered officials to aid any boats at risk in the country's waters and to let them land.</p>
<p>However, that may be starting to change. Last month, a boat that reached Aceh in Indonesia was reportedly pushed back out to sea twice. On the third try, it made it to land.</p>
<p>A representative of Amnesty International blamed this on the national government's failure to assist local officials in their efforts to help the refugees.</p>
<p>Should Indonesia stop helping, experts say more Rohingya will die when they cannot reach land at all. The UNHCR counted 348 dead or missing among those who set out in 2022 and 225 so far this year.</p>
<p>Baloch said, "We saw last year the <strong>consequences</strong> of not having a safe port or a safe place to <strong>disembark</strong>. These people risk losing their lives."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Zsombor Peter reported on this story in Bangkok, Thailand for VOA News. Anna Matteo adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stranded </strong><em>– v. </em>left without the means to move from somewhere.</p>
<p><strong>urgent</strong> <em>– adj.</em> calling for immediate attention</p>
<p><strong>predict</strong> <em>– v. </em>to declare in advance <strong>: </strong>foretell on the basis of observation, experience, or reasoning</p>
<p><strong>genocidal </strong><em>– adj.</em> the deliberate and systematic destruction of a racial, political, or cultural group<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>intent </strong><em>– n. </em>a usually clearly formulated or planned</p>
<p><strong>figure </strong><em>– n. </em>a number symbol</p>
<p><strong>gang</strong> <em>– n. </em>a group of persons associated together to do something illegal</p>
<p><strong>donor </strong><em>– n. </em>one that give money or other resources</p>
<p><strong>journey </strong><em>– n.</em> an act or instance of traveling from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>consequence </strong><em>– n. </em>something produced by a cause or necessarily following from a set of conditions</p>
<p><strong>disembark </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove to shore from a ship</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Extreme Sleep Behavior of Antarctic Penguins  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/extreme-sleep-behavior-of-antarctic-penguins.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Almost all new parents struggle to get enough sleep while caring for their newborns. For some penguin parents, though, periods of sleep are especially short.</p>
<p>Penguins are birds that cannot fly but use their wings for swimming. They live in or near the Antarctic.</p>
<p>Researchers recently found that Chinstrap penguins only sleep for about four seconds at a time in order to protect their eggs and newborn chicks. They do this thousands of times throughout the day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Won Young Lee shows wild chinstrap penguins on King George Island, Antarctica. (Won Young Lee via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/34b8efbd-95d2-4db8-abcc-fa3ddcd07ff8_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Won Young Lee shows wild chinstrap penguins on King George Island, Antarctica. (Won Young Lee via AP)</span></div>
<p>A study on the findings recently appeared in the publication <em>Science.</em></p>
<p>The short "microsleeps" total around 11 hours each day. The microsleeps appear to be enough to keep the parents going for many weeks.</p>
<p>Niels Rattenborg is a sleep researcher at the Max Planck Institute for Biological Intelligence in Germany. He helped write the new study. He said these penguins <strong>blink</strong> "... their eyes open and <strong>shut</strong>, and they do it 24/7 for several weeks at a time."</p>
<p>"What's surprising is that they're able to function okay and successfully raise their young," he said.</p>
<p>Chinstrap penguins usually lay their eggs in November in <strong>nests</strong> made up of small rocks. As with many other kinds of penguins, mated pairs share parenting responsibilities. One parent usually watches the eggs and chicks alone while the other goes off fishing for family meals.</p>
<p>Adult penguins do not face many natural <strong>predators</strong> in the mating season. But large birds called brown skuas eat the penguin eggs and small chicks. Other adult penguins may also try to steal the small rocks from nests. So, penguin parents must always be on guard.</p>
<p>For the first time, scientists followed the sleeping behavior of Chinstrap penguins in an Antarctic mating colony. They did this by attaching devices that measure brain waves. They collected data on 14 adults over 11 days on King George Island off the coast of Antarctica.</p>
<p>Won Young Lee is a biologist at the Korean Polar Research Institute. He thought of the idea for the study when he saw mating penguins often blinking their eyes and possibly sleeping during his long days of field observations. But the team needed to record brain waves to confirm the animals were sleeping.</p>
<p>"For these penguins, microsleeps have some <strong>restorative </strong>functions," he said. He added that they would not survive without it.</p>
<p>The researchers did not collect sleep data outside the mating season. But they suspect that the penguins may sleep for longer periods at other times of the year.</p>
<p>Paul-Antoine Libourel is a sleep researcher at the Neuroscience Research Center of Lyon in France. He also helped write the study. He said scientists do not yet know if the gains from microsleep are the same as gains from longer periods of time. Scientists also do not know if other kinds of penguins sleep in such short periods.</p>
<p>Researchers have documented a few other animals with special sleeping <strong>adaptations</strong>. For example, frigatebirds can sleep with one half of their brain at a time while flying.</p>
<p>But researchers say the Chinstrap penguin microsleeps appear to be a new extreme.</p>
<p>Daniel Paranhos Zitterbart studies penguins at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study. He noted that penguins mate in crowded colonies and their predators are around at the same time. He described microsleeping as "an <strong>amazing </strong>adaptation" that permits the penguins to be nearly always on guard.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>blink </strong>– <em>v</em>. to close and then open your eyes very quickly</p>
<p><strong>shut </strong>– <em>v</em>. to close (something)</p>
<p><strong>nest </strong>– <em>n</em>. the place where a bird lays its eggs and takes care of its young</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong>– <em>n</em>. an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals: an animal that preys on other animals</p>
<p><strong>restore </strong>– <em>adj</em>. large in amount, size, or number</p>
<p><strong>adaptation </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having the ability to make a person feel strong or healthy again</p>
<p><strong>amazing </strong>– <em>adj</em>. causing great surprise or wonder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Africa, Colombia Aim to Get Lower-Cost Drugs for TB, HIV  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/south-africa-colombia-aim-to-get-lower-cost-drugs-for-tb-hiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>South Africa and Colombia are among the countries aiming to push drug companies to permit low-cost versions of drugs for deadly diseases. The drugs are for people with drug-resistant versions of tuberculosis (TB) and with HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>One target is the drug bedaquiline. It is used for treating people with drug-resistant tuberculosis. In South Africa, TB was blamed for the deaths of more than 50,000 people in 2021, making it the country's leading cause of death.</p>
<p>Johnson &amp; Johnson is a U.S.-based drug and medical technology company. The company owns a patent for the drug bedaquiline. Patents legally protect a company's right to manufacture and sell a product that it developed or owns for a limited time. The legal protection prevents other companies from making the same drug without permission.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Scientists conduct reserach at an Afrigen Biologics and Vaccines facility in Cape Town, South Africa, Tuesday Oct. 19, 2021. (AP Photo/Jerome Delay, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-9336-08dbf1b3d2d3_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Scientists conduct reserach at an Afrigen Biologics and Vaccines facility in Cape Town, South Africa, Tuesday Oct. 19, 2021. (AP Photo/Jerome Delay, File)</span></div>
<p>In recent months, activists have protested efforts by Johnson &amp; Johnson to protect its patent. In March, TB patients asked the Indian government to make a lower cost copy of bedaquiline. The government agreed, saying Johnson &amp; Johnson's patent could be broken.</p>
<p>In July, the time limit for Johnson &amp; Johnson's patent on the drug ran out in South Africa. The company extended the patent until 2027 under South African law. However, activists became angry and accused Johnson &amp; Johnson of trying to make a lot of money from the drug.</p>
<p>The South African government then began investigating the company's pricing policies. South Africa had been paying about $282 per treatment course: a full group of treatments. This was more than twice as much as poor countries involved in the Swiss-based Stop TB Partnership paid.</p>
<p>In September, about a week after South Africa's investigation began, Johnson &amp; Johnson announced it would not enforce its patent in more than 130 countries. This would permit other drug makers in those countries to copy the drug.</p>
<p>Christophe Perrin is a TB expert at Doctors Without Borders. He called the decision "a big surprise." He said protecting patents is central to how most drug companies plan their businesses.</p>
<p>In October, Colombia announced that it would permit a third party to make the HIV drug dolutegravir without permission from the drug's patent-holder, Viiv Healthcare. The decision came after more than 120 groups asked the government to let more people use the drug, which is supported by the World Health Organization (WHO).</p>
<p>Peter Maybarduk is with the Washington, D.C., non-profit group Public Citizen. He thinks the Colombian government is trying to take control of its treatment of HIV after not having enough vaccines for COVID-19. He noted that Brazilian activists are pushing their government to do the same.</p>
<p><strong>More changes needed</strong></p>
<p>However, some experts say more needs to change before poor countries can produce their own medicines.</p>
<p>Petro Terblanche is managing director of the biotechnology company Afrigen Biologics based in Cape Town, South Africa. She said African countries produced less than one percent of all vaccines made around the world when the COVID-19 pandemic hit. But, Terblanche said, Africa used more than half of the world's supply.</p>
<p>Afrigen Biologics is part of a WHO-supported effort to produce a COVID vaccine using the same mRNA technology as those made by U.S.-based drug makers Pfizer and Moderna.</p>
<p>Terblanche also noted that African countries need to improve their ability to <strong>deliver</strong> vaccines. "If we can't get (vaccines and medicines) to the people who need them, they aren't useful," she said.</p>
<p>Lynette Keneilwe Mabote-Eyde is a health care activist who has ties to the nonprofit Treatment Action Group based in New York City. She noted that South Africa has no clear law permitting the government to take legal action against a patent or a patent extension.</p>
<p>The South African department of health did not answer questions from the Associated Press about patents.</p>
<p><strong>Fighting tuberculosis</strong></p>
<p>In its yearly report on TB released in November, the WHO said there were more than 10 million people sickened by the disease in 2022 and 1.3 million deaths.</p>
<p>After COVID-19, tuberculosis is the world's deadliest infectious disease. It is also now believed to be the main cause of death of people with HIV. The WHO says only about 40 percent of people with drug-resistant TB are being treated.</p>
<p>Zolelwa Sifumba, a South African doctor, found she had drug-resistant TB in 2012. She went through 18 months of treatment, taking about 20 pills every day in addition to daily injections. These left her in severe pain and resulted in some hearing loss. Bedaquiline was not a standard treatment in South Africa until 2018.</p>
<p>"I wanted to quit (treatment) every single day," she said. Since her recovery, Sifumba has been pushing for better TB treatment. She said it makes little sense to charge poor countries, which have more cases of TB, high prices for necessary medicines.</p>
<p>She questioned why poor countries would have to pay a lot for medicine. "If the lower income countries can't get it, then what's the point? Who are you making it for?" she said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Gerald Imray and Maria Cheng wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>deliver </strong><em>–v.</em> to take something from one place to the place where it is supposed to go</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Biden to US Congress: Ukraine Is 'Out of Money, Out of Time'  (2023/12/5) | 拜登督促国会批准尽快对乌克兰援助</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/biden-to-us-congress-ukraine-is-out-of-money-out-of-time.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The administration of American President Joe Biden warned lawmakers Monday against rejecting a military aid proposal for Ukraine.<br/>
美国总统乔·拜登政府星期一警告议员不要否决对乌克兰军事援助的提案。</p>
<p>Shalanda Young is the director of the United States Office of Management and Budget. She sent an open letter to the leaders of the U.S. Senate and House of Representatives.<br/>
莎兰达·杨是美国管理和预算办公室主任。她向美国参众两院领导人发出了一封公开信。</p>
<p>Young said if the current budget measure is rejected, U.S. military aid to Ukraine would be gone by the end of the year.<br/>
杨说，如果目前的预算提案被否决，美国对乌克兰的军事援助将在今年年底前不复存在。</p>
<p>The aid permits Ukraine to buy weapons for its defense against Russia.<br/>
这项援助允许乌克兰购买武器抵抗俄罗斯。</p>
<p>Young noted that the U.S. also provides financial aid to the Ukrainian economy, and that money is already gone. She wrote: "If Ukraine's economy collapses, they will not be able to keep fighting...."<br/>
杨指出，美国还向乌克兰经济提供财政援助，这些钱已经花光了。她写道：“如果乌克兰经济崩溃，他们将无法继续战斗……”</p>
<p>With less than one month to go in 2023, she added: "We are out of money – and nearly out of time."<br/>
距离2023年还有不到一个月的时间，她补充道：“我们没有钱了，而且几乎没有时间了。”</p>
<p>Biden has asked Congress for more than $100 billion in aid that would go to Ukraine, Israel and others. Some lawmakers oppose the measure unless there are conditions attached. They say the Biden administration must find solutions to the migrant problem at the U.S. southern border.<br/>
拜登已要求国会向乌克兰、以色列和其他国家提供1000多亿美元的援助。一些立法者反对这项提案，除非有附加条件。他们说，拜登政府必须找到解决美国南部边境移民问题的办法。</p>
<p>The House of Representatives already approved a military assistance bill for Israel. The Senate has not.<br/>
众议院已经批准了一项对以色列的军事援助法案。参议院没有。</p>
<p>The U.S. sent $111 billion to Ukraine in 2023. About $67 billion went to military needs. Another $27 billion went toward economic and civil assistance and $10 billion supported humanitarian aid.<br/>
2023年，美国向乌克兰提供了1110亿美元。大约670亿美元用于军事需求。另有270亿美元用于经济和民事援助，还有100亿美元用于人道主义援助。</p>
<p>Only three percent of the fund remains, Young wrote. She urged lawmakers to approve more money.<br/>
杨写道，这笔专款只剩下3%。她敦促议员们批准更多资金。</p>
<p>"This isn't a next year problem. The time to help a democratic Ukraine fight against Russian aggression is right now. It is time for Congress to act," the letter reads.<br/>
这份公开信写道：“这不是明年的问题。帮助民主乌克兰对抗俄罗斯侵略的时机就是现在。国会是时候采取行动了。”</p>
<p>The letter followed a closed meeting on November 29 among U.S. congressional, military and national security officials. The security officials told the lawmakers that Ukraine aid needed to continue. Biden's recent proposal includes $61 billion for Ukraine.<br/>
这封信是在11月29日美国国会、军方以及国家安全官员举行非公开会议后发出的。安全官员告诉议员们，对乌克兰援助需要继续。拜登最近的提案包括向乌克兰提供610亿美元。</p>
<p>Chuck Schumer attended the meeting. He is the Majority Leader of the U.S. Senate and a Democrat. He said the American military experts "were clear that Ukraine needs the aid soon."<br/>
查克·舒默出席了会议。他是美国参议院多数党领袖以及民主党人。他说，美国军事专家“清楚乌克兰很快需要这笔援助。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US States Push to End Food Waste  (2023/12/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-states-push-to-end-food-waste.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>When Sean Rafferty first worked in a food store 40 years ago, anything that was not sold got thrown out.</p>
<p>But on a recent day at his store near the New York City area, he was preparing boxes of bread, vegetables, and milk products to be picked up by a food bank. It is part of a program in New York State requiring larger businesses to donate food, and, if possible, reusing small, leftover pieces of food.</p>
<p>New York is among a growing number of states trying to limit food waste. They are concerned that it is taking up space in landfills and adding to <strong>global warming</strong>. A landfill is a place for putting <strong>garbage</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Driver Carlos Quezada loads rice on a pallet for distribution at Feeding Westchester in Elmsford, N.Y., Wednesday, Nov. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e9cc-08dbf0f79b38_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Driver Carlos Quezada loads rice on a pallet for distribution at Feeding Westchester in Elmsford, N.Y., Wednesday, Nov. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>Food waste including meat and vegetables releases methane gas after being put in a landfill. And saving unwanted food helps to feed hungry families.</p>
<p>Worldwide, about a third of food is wasted. In the United States, it is 40 percent. The U.S. spends about $218 billion each year growing and producing food that is wasted. About 57 million metric tons goes to waste, including 47.5 million metric tons that ends up in landfills.</p>
<p>"What's shocking to people often is not only how much we waste ... but also the <strong>impact</strong>," said Emily Broad Leib. She is a Harvard University professor and director of the school's Food Law and Policy Clinic. "Food waste causes about 8 percent to 10 percent of global <strong>greenhouse gas emissions</strong>."</p>
<p>In 2015, the U.S. Department of Agriculture and the Environmental Protection Agency announced a goal of 50 percent food waste reduction by 2030.</p>
<p>That has led to a number of state government efforts, along with smaller, nonprofit efforts.</p>
<p>Ten American states and Washington, D.C. have passed legislation or created policies to reduce, <strong>compost</strong> or donate waste.</p>
<p>The states of California and Vermont have programs for turning people's food waste into compost or energy. Connecticut requires businesses, including larger food sellers and <strong>supermarkets</strong>, to reuse food waste. Farmers in Maryland can get a tax credit of up to $5,000 per farm for food they donate.</p>
<p>Several states have joined New York in creating systems for food donation. Rhode Island requires food sellers servicing schools and universities to donate any unused food to food banks. And Massachusetts limits the amount of food that businesses can send to landfills.</p>
<p>As of late October, New York had sent 2.3 million kilograms of food, about 4 million meals, through its Feeding New York State program. The program supports the state's 10 area food banks and is hoping to double that number next year.</p>
<p>"Certainly, we should be reducing the amount we waste to start with, but then we should be feeding people before we throw food away..." said Sally Rowland. She is with the New York Department of Environmental Conservation.</p>
<p>Despite New York's success, some worry not enough is being done to meet the 2030 goal. Broad Leib and others have called for a national effort to <strong>coordinate</strong> the various state and local policies.</p>
<p>Kathryn Bender is a University of Delaware assistant professor of economics. She said donation programs are helpful. But she worries they might put the responsibility on nonprofits, instead of businesses.</p>
<p>"The best solution for food waste is to not have it in the first place," Bender said. "If we don't need to produce all that food, let's not put all the resources into producing that food."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>global warming </strong><em>— n. </em>the recent increase in the world's temperature that is believed to be caused by the increase of certain gases in the atmosphere</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>garbage </strong><em>— n. </em>things that are no longer useful or wanted and that have been thrown out</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>impact </strong><em>— n. </em> the act or force of one thing hitting another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>greenhouse gas </strong><em>— n.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>compost </strong><em>— n. </em>a decayed mixture of plants that is used to improve the soil in a garden</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>supermarket </strong><em>— n. </em>a store where customers can buy a variety of foods and usually household items</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coordinate </strong><em>— n. </em>to make arrangements so that two or more people or groups of people can work together properly and well</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Continues Mars Helicopter Experiments, Tests New Design on Earth  (2023/12/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/nasa-continues-mars-helicopter-experiments-tests-new-design-on-earth.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>As the American space agency NASA continues to carry out tests of its Ingenuity helicopter on Mars, it is also testing a future aircraft design on Earth.</p>
<p>NASA's Ingenuity has been making test flights on the Red Planet for the past two-and-a-half years. The experimental helicopter arrived on Mars along with NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover, in February 2021.</p>
<p>Both the rover and helicopter have been collecting images and data as they explore an area known as Jezero Crater. The goal of the exploration effort is to search for signs of ancient life on Mars.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-05e9-08dbf1ebe005_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Ingenuity made history on Mars</strong></p>
<p>Ingenuity made history in April 2021 by becoming the first aircraft to complete a powered, controlled flight on another planet. NASA officials have said the helicopter has performed far above expectations. Agency engineers planned on Ingenuity completing just five experimental flights on Mars. But the helicopter has so far performed 66 flights. It has provided NASA with valuable data on building future aircraft to fly in space.</p>
<p>Travis Brown is Ingenuity's chief engineer at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in California. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-uses-two-worlds-to-test-future-mars-helicopter-designs">said</a> in a statement that with nearly every flight, the helicopter has progressed in new ways. Brown noted that over the past nine months, Ingenuity had doubled its top speed and height records. In addition, the aircraft's operating speed and landings improved.</p>
<p>Most Ingenuity flights only last two to three minutes. This is because the helicopter has energy and temperature limitations.</p>
<p>NASA engineers say they have also been careful not to try to fly Ingenuity too fast because this can cause problems with its <strong>navigation</strong> system. The helicopter uses a camera to identify rocks and other things on the surface as it travels. If the aircraft goes too fast, it might not be able to navigate the best way forward.</p>
<p>Controllers on the ground have said that to help with this issue, they have sent commands to Ingenuity to fly at higher levels. This way the aircraft has less chance of losing its way because surface objects stay in view longer.</p>
<p>NASA says Ingenuity established a new height record, on flight 61, of 24 meters as it examined Martian wind conditions. On flight 62, the helicopter set a new speed record of 10 meters per second. During this flight Ingenuity also identified a new place for the Perseverance rover to carry out science experiments.</p>
<p><strong>Testing new helicopter design on Earth</strong></p>
<p>As that testing continues on Mars, teams on the ground have been experimenting with new <strong>rotor blades</strong>. These could be used in the future with a new generation of Mars helicopters. During the tests, engineers reported the rotor blades had reached speeds nearly equal to Mach 1, the speed of sound.</p>
<p>The blades tested on Earth are made of carbon material and are more than 10 centimeters longer than Ingenuity's. The blades were designed to be both faster and stronger. NASA has said such rotor blades should be able to support bigger, more complex helicopters. The team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-uses-two-worlds-to-test-future-mars-helicopter-designs">said</a> in a statement the helicopter design must reach the right balance. If the blades spin too fast, this causes control issues that can increase the risk of crashes.</p>
<p>The Earth-based tests were carried out in September inside a space <strong>simulator</strong> at NASA's JPL. For these experiments, the simulator aimed to establish a Mars-like environment. The team was measuring tests of the rotor blades with sensors, cameras and other equipment. Many different speeds were tested and the blades were repeatedly repositioned to observe the best results.</p>
<p>"We spun our blades up to 3,500 rpm, which is 750 revolutions per minute faster than the Ingenuity blades have gone," said Tyler Del Sesto, a leader of the JPL testing. "These more <strong>efficient</strong> blades are now more than a <strong>hypothetical</strong> exercise. They are ready to fly," he added.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>navigate </strong><em>– v. </em>to find the right direction to travel in by using maps of other equipment</p>
<p><strong>rotor blade </strong><em>– n. </em>thin, flat pieces of material that spin to make aircraft lift off the ground and travel</p>
<p><strong>simulator </strong><em>– n. </em>a machine used to practice operating a vehicle or piece of equipment without having to actually use those things</p>
<p><strong>efficient </strong><em>– adj. </em>working well and not wasting time or energy</p>
<p><strong>hypothetical </strong><em>– adj. </em>a situation or idea has been suggested but does not yet really exist or has not been proven to be true</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Company Works with Google to Provide Energy from the Earth’s Heat  (2023/12/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/company-works-with-google-to-provide-energy-from-the-earth-s-heat.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google recently announced that it has begun using carbon-free electricity from a <strong>geothermal</strong> project to power data centers in the state of Nevada.</p>
<p>Tim Latimer is chief and co-founder of Fervo Energy based in Houston, Texas. His company is working with Google on its geothermal project.</p>
<p>Latimer said that getting electricity on the <strong>grid</strong> from geothermal resources is an event many new energy companies never reach.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A drill rig stands at a Fervo Energy geothermal site under construction near Milford, Utah, Sunday, Nov. 26, 2023. In Nevada, Fervo's first operational project has begun sending electricity to the state's grid to power Google data centers. (AP Photo/Ellen Schmidt)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/620a0d26-728d-4bac-a87b-b6e5624a03d2_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A drill rig stands at a Fervo Energy geothermal site under construction near Milford, Utah, Sunday, Nov. 26, 2023. In Nevada, Fervo's first operational project has begun sending electricity to the state's grid to power Google data centers. (AP Photo/Ellen Schmidt)</span></div>
<p>He added that he believes geothermal energy will become more well-known than in the past.</p>
<p><strong>Geothermal partnership </strong></p>
<p>The International Energy Agency (IEA) has long suggested geothermal could be an answer to climate change. The IEA said in a 2011 document that geothermal could reach 3.5 percent of global electricity production each year by 2050. The Paris-based international group says geothermal energy could prevent almost 800 million tonnes of<strong> carbon dioxide emissions</strong> per year.</p>
<p>Fervo Energy is using this first test to launch other projects that will provide more electricity to the grid. The company is currently completing some work in southwest Utah for a 400-megawatt project.</p>
<p>Google and Fervo Energy started working together in 2021 to develop geothermal power. The plant near Winnemucca, Nevada, is now operating and is sending about 3.5 megawatts to the grid. There are three wells there.</p>
<p>However, the data centers require more electricity than that. So, Google signed other agreements for solar energy and electricity storage too. The company has two plants in Nevada, one near Las Vegas and the other near Reno. Michael Terrell leads climate efforts at Google. He said the company is considering using geothermal energy for other data centers worldwide.</p>
<p>"We're really hoping that this could be a<strong> springboard</strong> to much, much more advanced geothermal power available to us and others around the world," he said.</p>
<p>Google announced in 2020 that it would use what it calls "carbon-free" energy every hour of every day, wherever it operates, by 2030.</p>
<p>Many energy experts believe huge companies like Google can play a part in increasing the use of clean energy.</p>
<p>Terrell noted the company was also an early supporter of wind and solar projects, helping those markets grow to where they are today.</p>
<p>"It's a very similar situation. Now that we've set a goal to be 24/7 carbon-free energy, we have found it will take more than just wind, solar and storage," Terrell said.</p>
<p><strong>The path ahead </strong></p>
<p>The United States leads the world in using heat from the Earth for electricity production. But geothermal makes up less than half a percent of the nation's total electricity production, says the U.S. Energy Information Administration. In 2022, that geothermal power came from California, Nevada, Utah, Hawaii, Oregon, Idaho and New Mexico.</p>
<p>Those are states thought to have geothermal possibilities because they have large amounts of steam or very hot water close to the surface.</p>
<p>U.S. Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm said earlier this year that advances in new geothermal systems will help introduce this form of energy to areas where it has been thought to be impossible.</p>
<p><strong>Technologies </strong></p>
<p>Some geothermal companies, including Fervo, are now going deeper below ground. This makes it possible to find energy in more places. Latimer is a former drilling engineer in the oil and gas industry.</p>
<p>Drilling technology got much better during the <strong>shale boom</strong> that turned the United States into a top oil and gas producer and exporter. But very little new technology has gone from the oil and gas industry to geothermal, said Fervo official Sarah Jewett.</p>
<p>In October, Latimer gave a presentation at ClimateTech 2023, at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Latimer told the conference about how Fervo is developing<strong> horizontal </strong>drilling in geothermal <strong>reservoirs</strong>. By drilling horizontally, Fervo can reach more of the hot reservoir, instead of drilling many wells straight down.</p>
<p>Both Fervo and Google said geothermal is valuable as a clean energy technology that is always available. Fervo's next project, in Beaver County, Utah, is to begin providing clean power to the grid in 2026 and reach full production in 2028.</p>
<p>"This is unlocking something deeply sought after in the market today...and that is, round-the-clock <strong>renewable</strong> energy," Jewett said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell. </p>
<p><em>Jennifer McDermott reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>geothermal</strong> <em>– adj</em>. of, relating to, or using the natural heat produced inside the Earth</p>
<p><strong>grid</strong> <em>– n.</em> a network of equipment that supplies electricity to a large area</p>
<p><strong>carbon dioxide</strong> <em>– n.</em> a gas that is produced when certain fuels are burned</p>
<p><strong>emission</strong><em> – n. </em>something sent out or given off</p>
<p><strong>springboard </strong><em>– n.</em> something that helps you start a process</p>
<p><strong>shale boom </strong><em>– n.</em> refers to the combination of technologies and drilling methods that greatly increased recovery of oil and natural gas in the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>horizontal</strong> <em>–adj.</em> positioned from side to side rather than up and down (vertical)</p>
<p><strong>reservoir</strong> <em>–n.</em> a place where something is stored in large amounts by design: for example, a man-made lake is a reservoir of water</p>
<p><strong>renewable</strong> <em>– adj.</em> restored or replaced by natural processes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Walmart Shifts to India, Cuts China Imports  (2023/12/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/walmart-shifts-to-india-cuts-china-imports.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Walmart, the world's largest store, is importing more goods to the United States from India and reducing its dependence on China.</p>
<p>Between January and August this year, Walmart shipped 25 percent of its U.S. imports from India. That compares to just 2 percent in 2018. Import Yeti, a data company, shared the information with Reuters.</p>
<p>The same data shows that only 60 percent of Walmart's imports came from China during the same period, down from 80 percent in 2018. China is still Walmart's biggest country for importing goods.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Walmart worker organizes products for the Christmas season at a Walmart store in Teterboro, New Jersey, U.S. on October 26, 2016. (REUTERS/Eduardo Munoz//File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5ea05dd4-b26f-4fea-8a84-4d11a34a11c3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Walmart worker organizes products for the Christmas season at a Walmart store in Teterboro, New Jersey, U.S. on October 26, 2016. (REUTERS/Eduardo Munoz//File Photo)</span></div>
<p>The <strong>shift</strong> shows how the rising cost of importing from China and increased tension between China and the U.S. are leading American companies to import from other countries. Those countries include India, Thailand, and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Andrea Alright is Walmart's executive vice president of sourcing. She said, "We want the best prices." She added that Walmart has to deal with natural disasters to shortages in materials and cannot be dependent on any one supplier or area for products.</p>
<p>Walmart said the import information did not mean that it was reducing dependence on any of its markets. "We're a growth business and are working to <strong>source</strong> more manufacturing <strong>capacity</strong>," the company said in a statement. And Albright added that India has become an important part of Walmart's efforts to build that manufacturing capacity.</p>
<p>Walmart has been increasing growth in India since 2018. It bought 77 percent of shares in the online company Flipkart. Two years later, it promised to import $10 billion worth of goods from India each year by 2027. That is a target it is on the way to meet, Albright said. It is currently importing around $3 billion worth of goods from India each year.</p>
<p><strong>India's workforce and technology </strong></p>
<p>Walmart is importing goods including toys, electronics, sporting equipment, and medications from India. Foods like packaged food, dry grains, and pasta are also popular imports from India, Albright told Reuters.</p>
<p>India, whose stock market has risen to record highs this year, is viewed as the country best equipped to outperform China in low-cost and large amounts of manufacturing.</p>
<p>The South Asian country also has a growing workforce and increasing technological developments. China, however, recently reported its first population decrease in sixty years.</p>
<p>Walmart started its sourcing operations in the Indian city of Bangalore in 2002. Now, the company employs more than 100,000 people, including temporary workers, around the country.</p>
<p><strong>Rising costs from China</strong></p>
<p>The rising cost of shopping goods from China has also added to the shift to India, supply chain experts say.</p>
<p>Chris Rogers is a researcher at S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence's supply chain research group Panjiva. He said, "Sourcing from mainland China has become less competitive because of rising labor costs <strong>versus</strong> other manufacturing centers."</p>
<p>China's minimum wage ranges between $198.52 to $376.08 monthly. Meanwhile, average wages for unskilled and semi-skilled workers in India are between $108.04 and $180.06.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic showed weaknesses in worldwide supply chains, showing U.S. importers were over-dependent on a small number of markets.</p>
<p>Albright said planning for an event like the pandemic is like planning for a natural disaster. She said, "What I can control is where my product is coming from and how do I make sure that Christmas still happens if something happens in our supply chain."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Julie Steenhuysen reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>supply chain </strong>– <em>n</em>. a network of businesses that supply the materials and parts needed to provide people with products and goods</p>
<p><strong>shift </strong>– <em>v</em>. to move or to cause (something or someone) to move to a different place or position</p>
<p><strong>source </strong>– <em>v</em>. to get something from a particular place</p>
<p><strong>capacity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the amount of something that can be produced or managed by a factory or company</p>
<p><strong>draw </strong>– <em>n</em>. someone or something that causes a lot of people to come to a place</p>
<p><strong>versus </strong>– <em>prep</em>. used to indicate two different things or choices that are being compared or considered</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some Migrants Switch from American Dream to Mexican One  (2023/12/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/some-migrants-switch-from-american-dream-to-mexican-one.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Walter Banegas is a refugee from the Central American country of Honduras. He now lives in the northern Mexican city of Saltillo. There, he works in a factory, making aluminum parts for machines.</p>
<p>But Mexico is not the first country Banegas, 28, has tried to call home. To avoid violent drug <strong>gangs</strong> in Honduras, he first fled to the United States as a <strong>teenager</strong>. But he was deported in 2014. Hoping to seek asylum, he re-entered the U.S. in 2020, only to be deported once again.</p>
<p>So when Banegas fled Honduras once more in 2021, he aimed for Mexico instead of the U.S. He was granted refugee status and with help from a United Nations refugee program, moved to Saltillo. There, he was connected to a job at Pace Industries, a U.S.-based metal manufacturer with plants in the U.S. and Mexico.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Walter Banegas, 28, originally from Honduras, poses for a picture during his shift at the Pace Industries aluminum injection molding plant, his formal job after settling in Mexico as a refugee, in Saltillo, Mexico October 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Daniel Becerril)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-640d-08dbef780fe4_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Walter Banegas, 28, originally from Honduras, poses for a picture during his shift at the Pace Industries aluminum injection molding plant, his formal job after settling in Mexico as a refugee, in Saltillo, Mexico October 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Daniel Becerril)</span></div>
<p>In the last five years, Mexico has seen an increase in the number of refugees choosing to stay in the country. There, the asylum system is less strict than in the U.S., and refugees can find jobs because companies in Mexico need more workers.</p>
<p>Banegas said he is earning about $800 a month at Pace Industries. This is less than he thought he would make in the U.S. But it is enough to send at least $50 a month home to his family. He says he likes his Mexican co-workers and is proud his six-month-old son, David, is a Mexican citizen.</p>
<p>"I feel at peace here," he said. "It's not necessary to go to the United States. You can also get ahead here, in Mexico."</p>
<p><strong>A good choice for some refugees</strong></p>
<p>About ten years ago, only a few hundred people received asylum in Mexico each year. By 2021, the number rose to 27,000, according to Mexico's refugee agency. Mexico will likely approve at least 20,000 asylum cases this year, with most of the arrivals coming from Honduras, Haiti, Venezuela, El Salvador and Cuba.</p>
<p>A large majority of migrants entering Mexico continue north toward the U.S. The U.S. had more than 700,000 individual asylum claims last year.</p>
<p>But the head of the U.N. refugee agency (UNHCR) in Mexico, Giovanni Lepri, said Mexico is becoming a good choice for refugees, in part because of its high need for workers.</p>
<p>Coparmex studies Mexico's economy and social issues. The organization says Mexico has more than one million job openings nationwide. In a recent study of more than 2,500 businesses in Mexico, it says 85 percent of employers in manufacturing report trouble finding workers, more than in any other employment area.</p>
<p>U.S., Mexican and U.N. officials have called for cooperation to help migrants resettle in places such as Mexico, Costa Rica and Colombia, aiming to reduce illegal migration to the U.S.</p>
<p>Arturo Rocha is the migration director for Mexico's foreign ministry. He said the government is trying to expand work visa programs and connect employers with migrants looking for jobs.</p>
<p>Mexico is working with Guatemala's government to bring up to 20,000 workers to Mexico each year. Mexico also aims to expand the program to Honduras and El Salvador.</p>
<p>Jose Medina Mora, the head of Coparmex, praised the U.N. program that helped Banegas <strong>relocate</strong> to Saltillo. He also urged the Mexican government to expand work visa programs so more migrants can be quickly <strong>matched</strong> with employers.</p>
<p>The U.N. program helps refugees relocate from southern Mexico, where most complete their asylum process, to cities in central and northern Mexico. The program gives money and helps with finding jobs. It also helps refugees find childcare, schools and healthcare. It helped connect 5,500 refugees with a job in 2022, and nearly 3,000 so far this year.</p>
<p><strong>"Couldn't ask for more"</strong></p>
<p>Fernando Hernandez, 24, fled Honduras for southern Mexico last year with his partner and young daughter. He planned to cross the country as quickly as possible to reach the U.S.</p>
<p>But then he saw social media posts of children drowning in the river at the U.S. border. He imagined his two-year-old daughter also dying in the water. And he thought about his mother, who migrated to the U.S. in 2017. She lives in a small mobile home in the state of Texas and uses most of her pay for housing.</p>
<p>So, Hernandez decided to seek asylum in Mexico. After it was approved in February, the U.N. helped his family relocate to the northern industrial city of Monterrey. There, Hernandez began working at a small store that sells food, drink, and other things people need.</p>
<p>Hernandez quickly learned that there were job openings everywhere, he said. He got a job in a factory, and then became a cook at P.F. Chang's, earning about $225 a week.</p>
<p>"Here we have everything: a house, food and family," he said. "I couldn't ask for more."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Anna Mateo.</p>
<p><em>Laura Gottesdiener and Daina Beth Solomon wrote this story for Reuters News. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gang </strong><em>-n. </em>a group of criminals who work together to commit crimes</p>
<p><strong>teenager </strong><em>-n. </em>a young person between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p><strong>relocate </strong><em>-v. </em>to move to a different city or country</p>
<p><strong>match </strong><em>-v. </em>to connect with another in a way that works well</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>International Students in US Experience American Holidays  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/international-students-in-us-experience-american-holidays.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett and Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers report that more than one million foreign students attended college or university in the United States last year. The data comes from the government-supported study called Open Doors Report on International Educational Exchange.</p>
<p>Nearly one-third of those students were studying in the U.S. for the first time.</p>
<p>Just as they are getting comfortable with their classes, classmates, professors and speaking English full-time, school stops for three major American holidays: Thanksgiving, Christmas and New Year's.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Sarah Mannix and her students from the English Language Center at Old Dominion University celebrate Thanksgiving at her house. (Photo courtesy of Sarah Mannix)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4046-08dbf1d17cca_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Sarah Mannix and her students from the English Language Center at Old Dominion University celebrate Thanksgiving at her house. (Photo courtesy of Sarah Mannix)</span></div>
<p>What do students do when their <strong>routine</strong> gets <strong>interrupted</strong>? VOA Learning English recently spoke with a number of international students to find out.</p>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving</strong></p>
<p>Most universities take a short break so students can celebrate Thanksgiving, which falls on the fourth Thursday of November.</p>
<p>American students leave school for four or five days to spend time with their families. But international students do not often have the money to travel home during breaks, so they find themselves on an empty<strong> campus</strong>.</p>
<p>Lucky ones, however, get to experience the holidays with Americans. Aimee Sanata is from the Dominican Republic. She is studying at the English Language Center at Old Dominion University in Norfolk, Virginia.</p>
<p>Sanata celebrated the holiday with her boyfriend's family. Before the break, she watched some videos on YouTube to learn about the history of the holiday.</p>
<p>"The videos are created for children, so there they explain everything clearly so that anybody can understand it," she said.</p>
<p><strong>First taste of turkey</strong></p>
<p>Many international students say they are excited to celebrate an American Thanksgiving because they have never tasted turkey. Turkeys are large birds mostly raised on farms. Some can weigh more than 10 kilograms. They can take three to five hours to cook.</p>
<p>Sarah Mannix is one of the English instructors at Old Dominion University. She knows it can be difficult for students to find something to do during school breaks. So Mannix invited a number of her students to celebrate Thanksgiving with her.</p>
<p>"They were all really excited when we took the turkey out of the oven because they had never seen cooked turkey before," she said. "Overall, I think they enjoyed it."</p>
<p>In fact, one student has been in the U.S. for six years, but had never tried Thanksgiving turkey before this year.</p>
<p>Victoria Stepanyants grew up in Russia and the Mediterranean island of Cyprus. She studied at Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore, Maryland and is now in medical school in Cleveland, Ohio. So she has a lot of experience with the school holiday breaks.</p>
<p>She often spent Thanksgiving with other international students and friends. They did not usually prepare <strong>traditional</strong> foods. But this year was different.</p>
<p>"That was actually the first time that I've been to Thanksgiving, where the food was, like, ‘Thanksgiving food,'" Stepanyants said. "It was the food I expected to see based on the way the media covers American Thanksgiving."</p>
<p>International students are not just at universities. Sofia Montanari is from Bologna, Italy and is in high school in the Midwestern state of Missouri. She said she knows sharing meals are a good way to connect with new people. So she brought food from Italy to the Thanksgiving she spent with an American family.</p>
<p>"I really like (the idea) that they show me some of their culture and I show some of mine back," she said.</p>
<p>One part of the Thanksgiving culture she enjoyed was the idea of giving thanks. People often talk about what they are thankful for before the Thanksgiving meal.</p>
<p>"It's always good to be thankful for what you have," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Long breaks, dark and cold days</strong></p>
<p>After Thanksgiving, students get back to school to attend classes and take exams, but about three weeks later, another break starts. Most schools close from mid-December until the last week of January.</p>
<p>That long period was hard, at first, for Stepanyants. Cyprus has a warmer climate. She said the island has over 300 sunny days per year. Her experience in the U.S. was very different.</p>
<p>"As soon as it hit October, November," she said, "the sunlight is gone. It gets colder. I think it's <strong>automatically</strong> <strong>depressing</strong> for anyone who is not used to it."</p>
<p>For international students, she said, it is important to maintain a regular schedule and spend time with people.</p>
<p>International students should speak up if they are concerned about being <strong>lonely</strong> during school breaks. For Stepanyants, such discussions came naturally as she got to know other international students. At that point, they would make plans to spend time together during the breaks.</p>
<p>When she lived in Baltimore, she would take day trips with other international students to nearby cities such as Washington, D.C. and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>Sometimes, Stepanyants said, the breaks can be <strong>boring</strong>. But if students talk about their concerns they can make plans.</p>
<p>"If you have other international student friends, it's good to just bring it up because they end up in a similar situation then actually, like, the long breaks can be a lot of fun."</p>
<p>At Miami University in Oxford, Ohio, the campus is closed during the last week of December. But international students are permitted to stay in their rooms during the winter break.</p>
<p>Dan Sinetar is a part of the staff that works to help international students feel at ease. He said people who live close to the university can take part in a program to make tasty "holiday treats" for international students.</p>
<p>Students who are staying at the university during the break can also take short winter term classes.</p>
<p>Stepanyants said, students should be sure to talk with someone at their university's international student office about activities for the holidays such as Christmas and New Year's during the long breaks.</p>
<p>"For example, at my school, they would sometimes do whole celebrations that international students could come to and just like have events over the long breaks for people to not feel super <strong>isolated</strong>, which was nice."</p>
<p class="paragraph"><strong>Visitors from home and trips to see family</strong></p>
<p class="paragraph">Students at Montanari's school are not permitted to stay on the campus during Christmas break. They have to make other plans. Last year, her parents came to visit the U.S. for two weeks. They visited New York and Washington, D.C. together. They also spent some time in the town where Sofia attends school.</p>
<p class="paragraph">The rest of the break Sofia spent with a <strong>host</strong> family.</p>
<p class="paragraph">Stepanyants, the medical student, has a younger sister who is attending college in the U.S. In recent years, they have been able to see each other during breaks, which makes them both feel better and less lonely.</p>
<p>Other students do make it back home. Sanata is traveling to the Dominican Republic for Christmas break because her brother is getting married. She is thankful because she misses her family so much. She said she also misses speaking Spanish.</p>
<p>For students who cannot get home, they try to stay connected to family. New Year's is the most important winter holiday for Stepanyants. When she could not get home, she would have meals with her family by video call after cooking traditional foods.</p>
<p>"It's a very huge meal that you cook all day. And presents happen on New Year's too. Then, there are fireworks," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett and Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>routine </strong>–n. something that happens regularly or daily</p>
<p><strong>interrupt </strong>–v. to stop something from happening</p>
<p><strong>campus </strong>–n. the location of school or university buildings and residences for students</p>
<p><strong>traditional </strong>–adj. a way of doing things that has taken place for many years</p>
<p><strong>automatic </strong>–adj. something that happens without deliberate thought</p>
<p><strong>depressing </strong>–adj. a condition of unhappiness</p>
<p><strong>lonely </strong>–adj. the feeling of being alone or without other humans</p>
<p><strong>boring </strong>–adj. a dull feeling or lack of excitment</p>
<p><strong>isolated </strong>–adj. the condition of being alone or far away from others</p>
<p><strong>host </strong>–n. a person who welcomes others to an event or puts on an activity</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. What would you do during school breaks if you were studying in the U.S.?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US City Wants Woman to Clean up Rock Art  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-city-wants-woman-to-clean-up-rock-art.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Iris Logan was having a hard time growing grass at her home in St. Paul, Minnesota. So, she covered the space with stones, statues, and other art.</p>
<p>More than 30 years later, it is something of a local <strong>landmark</strong>. But to a city inspector, it is a problem.</p>
<p>Logan, who is 70, has been told to clean up the different objects, like wood and large rocks, noted after a recent inspection, the <em>St. Paul Pioneer Press, </em>a local newspaper<em> </em>reported. The City Council will look at the issue on December 6.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this undated photo provided by the City of St. Paul, Minnesota, the front exterior of Iris Logan's home is pictured. (City of St. Paul, Minnesota via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3f34cf31-9acb-4786-9190-7763896c4ced_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this undated photo provided by the City of St. Paul, Minnesota, the front exterior of Iris Logan's home is pictured. (City of St. Paul, Minnesota via AP)</span></div>
<p>Logan said the city's actions forced her to create the art in the first place. She said city workers who were fixing the road dug so deep around one of her trees that its roots were open to the air. So, she brought in dirt, planted flowers, and added stones – and just kept adding.</p>
<p>Logan said that if she likes a rock, she will try to bring it home. "I'm a rock lover," the former farmer from Mississippi added.</p>
<p>Logan recently received written <strong>notice</strong> that a city official will suggest to the City Council that she be given until December 22 to clean things up. She wrote six pages of note by hand to appeal the order. The stones do not enter the street or block city vehicles, Logan wrote to answer one of the inspector's concerns.</p>
<p>"I just want to make a stand for the next person," Logan said.</p>
<p>Casey Rodriguez is a spokeswoman for the St. Paul Department of Safety and Inspections. She said about 16 other properties on the same street also received letters advising them to remove objects blocking the street to agree with city laws.</p>
<p>She said in an email to the <em>Pioneer Press</em> that large roads, called boulevards, should be clear of objects that can block <strong>access</strong> to power and water lines. She added that it also keeps the tree roots clear and provides a place for snow in the winter.</p>
<p>Justin Lewandowski is a community organizer who lives near Logan. He said that 150 people signed their support on a <strong>petition</strong> "in just a few hours." He is hopeful that the city will soon clear up their rules.</p>
<p>"The quick support from our neighbors has been a clear signal of how much this art means to our community," Lewandowski said. He said it is not just about how it looks; it is about their identity and how they work with each other and with city policy.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>landmark </strong>– <em>n</em>. an object or structure on land that is easy to see and recognize</p>
<p><strong>notice </strong>– <em>n</em>. information that tells you or warns you about something that is going to happen</p>
<p><strong>access </strong>– <em>n</em>. a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p><strong>petition </strong>– <em>n</em>. a written document that people sign to show that they want a person or organization to do or change something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>It's Time to 'See the Light'  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/it-s-time-to-see-the-light.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>In many places, the holiday season in December can be a magical time. During this month, many cultures celebrate with festivals of lights. From Amsterdam in the Netherlands to Sydney, Australia; from Lyon, France to many cities in Japan -- lights are used to lift the spirits and to celebrate.</p>
<p>So, today we will talk about a few expressions that use the word "light."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Light Up festival in Ashburn, Virginia (Photo by Iacopo Luzi/VOA)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1F21CED2-DB0A-4887-AE6F-D8CE024A23BF_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Light Up festival in Ashburn, Virginia (Photo by Iacopo Luzi/VOA)</span></div>
<p>The first is to be a <strong><u>beacon</u></strong><u> of light</u>. A beacon of light gives hope and happiness to others. If you have ever been called a beacon of light, take it as a big <strong>compliment</strong>. A person who is a beacon of light makes things better for everyone around them. A beacon of light can be a person who helps guide others to safety, much like a lighthouse does for ships and boats.</p>
<p>These people can even <u>cast light on the darkness</u> in our lives. When we <u>cast light on something,</u> we make it better. The expression can also mean that we explain something more fully or <strong>expose</strong> some unknown parts of an issue or problem. Some people like to say, "Let me cast a little light on the subject," before they explain something.</p>
<p>After someone casts light on a complex or difficult issue, you might begin <u>to see the light</u>. If you see the light, you understand something. Often, you have realized a difficult truth. For example, years ago my friend refused to believe that her boyfriend had a drinking problem. But when he was arrested for drunk driving, she began to see the light. She got him help and now he has been alcohol-free for many years. So, he saw the light, too.</p>
<p>This expression is very different from <u>seeing the light of day</u> --although they sound similar.</p>
<p>When something sees the light of day, it is made available to others. For example, some people write stories and poems. But these works never see the light of day. They stay hidden in a desk drawer or notebook.</p>
<p>To see the light of day can also mean to be born or to come into existence. Let's say you worked on a big project for many months or even years. You will probably feel very excited when it finally sees the light of day.</p>
<p>Now, let's talk about "bad light."</p>
<p>Bad lighting can make even the most beautiful person look bad in a picture or video. So, it is not surprising that seeing something <u>in a bad light</u> means to form a bad opinion of something or someone.</p>
<p>Sometimes our <strong>habits</strong> and <strong>attitudes</strong> can be seen in a bad light. For example, a scientist was seen in a bad light by her coworkers. They said she was not a team player.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear these some of these expressions used in a discussion between two friends.</p>
<p><em>A: Wow, you look awful. Are you sick?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. I haven't slept in a week.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Why? What's wrong?</em></p>
<p><em>B: My roommate started playing the bag pipes. They are SO loud. And she plays late at night!</em></p>
<p><em>A: The bag pipes?! Oh, that's too bad. Well, have you told her to stop?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. She's a really nice person. So, I don't want her to <u>see me in a bad light</u>. I mean, we all do annoying things, right?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Yes. But, we all don't play the bag pipes late at night. Look, you need to do something. You need your sleep! You could hide her bag pipes. Hide them somewhere so they will never see the light of day again!</em></p>
<p><em>B: You are so mean! But you are also right. I'm beginning <u>to see the light</u>. I'll say something later. But for now (yawn) can I <strong>crash </strong>on your couch. I'm <strong>beat</strong>!</em></p>
<p>And that's the end of this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>beacon </strong><em>–n.</em> a very bright light such as a light on a lighthouse</p>
<p><strong>compliment </strong><em>–n.</em> a comment on how good something is or an expression of praise</p>
<p><strong>expose </strong><em>–v.</em> to show something that was unknown or covered up earlier</p>
<p><strong>habit </strong><em>–n.</em> a regular behavior</p>
<p><strong>attitude </strong><em>–n.</em> a way of feeling or thinking that affects a person's behavior</p>
<p><strong>crash </strong><em>–v. (informal idiom)</em> to go to sleep after being very tired</p>
<p><strong>beat </strong><em>–adj. (informal)</em> very tired</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ronald Reagan: Communicator  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-ronald-reagan.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Ronald Reagan. He was president for two terms, and served from 1981 to 1989. Before that, he was the governor of California, worked as an actor and led a labor union.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Ronald Reagan" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/bae5644b-91f7-4b84-bf84-8a1f4c44415d_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Ronald Reagan</span></div>
<p>As president, Reagan is credited for changing the direction of the country. He tried to establish a feeling of <strong>confidence</strong> in the American people.</p>
<p>Although not everyone profited equally from his policies, the president rarely suffered in public opinion polls. Reagan was called the "Great Communicator" because he was able to connect with many Americans, and to speak persuasively about conservative values.</p>
<p>He is remembered warmly by many Republican Party politicians and voters especially.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Ronald Reagan is often linked to California and the American West. But he was born and raised in Illinois, in the center of the United States.</p>
<p>His father sold shoes, and his mother mostly took care of Ronald and his older brother, Neil. The entire family supported the Democratic Party, especially President <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html" target="_blank">Franklin Roosevelt</a>.</p>
<p>While the boys were growing up, the Reagans did not have much money, and the father suffered from alcoholism.</p>
<p>But Ronald was energetic and took part in many activities.</p>
<p>He played football and basketball; ran on the track team; swam; acted in plays; led student groups; wrote for school newspapers and yearbooks; and worked several jobs to help pay for his education and support his parents.</p>
<p>He attended Eureka College in Illinois, and completed his studies in 1932.</p>
<p>One of his first jobs out of college was as a sports announcer for a radio station. He had an appealing voice and a natural way of talking that was a good <strong>fit</strong> for radio.</p>
<p>Reagan was also good-looking, and a dependable worker. In time, he was offered a chance to act in movies and moved to California.</p>
<p>During his acting career, Reagan made more than 50 films. He also married actress Jane Wyman and had two children with her. But after several years, the relationship ended. Their marriage ended in <strong>divorce</strong>.</p>
<p>Four years later, Reagan married another actress. Her name was Anne Robbins, but she was called Nancy Davis. They also had two children.</p>
<p>As he was starting his second family, Reagan began another part of his career. He served as <strong>host</strong> of a popular television series about the American West. He also became president of a labor union, the Screen Actors Guild. It represented actors, announcers, and others working in the film and television industry.</p>
<p>During that time, Reagan's political beliefs changed. He increasingly supported conservative ideas. During public appearances, he often spoke in support of business interests. He also expressed concern that the federal government was limiting Americans' freedom.</p>
<p>The message was well-received by many Americans. Although the Democratic Party was in power for most of the 1960s, a number of Americans were becoming increasingly conservative.</p>
<p>Reagan won national recognition in 1966 when he successfully ran for governor of California as a Republican. In 1970, voters re-elected him to the position.</p>
<p>But Reagan had set his sights on the presidency. He sought the Republican nomination in both 1968 and 1976.</p>
<p>Finally, in 1980, he won the office. By that time, he had already had several careers, as well as a long life. At age 69, he was the oldest person until then to be elected president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When Reagan took office, he made improving the U.S. economy his highest concern. One way to do that, he believed, was to reduce the influence of the federal government.</p>
<p>He wanted especially to cut some of the government programs that former president <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-lyndon-johnson/4095890.html" target="_blank">Lyndon Johnson</a> had put in place to help poor people. Reagan believed that cutting taxes – especially on big businesses – would help strengthen the economy, and in time help everyone.</p>
<p>In a speech after taking office, Reagan noted that, "Government is not the solution to our problem; government is the problem."</p>
<p>At first, the economy continued to struggle. But in a few years, Reagan's policies appeared to work. Unemployment dropped, the stock market rose, and many industries grew quickly. Americans often remember Reagan's presidency as a time of economic growth.</p>
<p>Not everyone <strong>benefited</strong> equally, however. Reagan's critics observed that his policies largely helped people who were already wealthy. The divide between rich and middle-class Americans increased during Reagan's presidency.</p>
<p>And Reagan did not reduce government spending in all areas. In fact, he sharply increased military spending.</p>
<p>One result was a large national debt. Another result, Reagan's supporters say, was a quicker end to the Cold War.</p>
<p>One of Reagan's major foreign policy goals was to end the <strong>stand-off</strong> with the Soviet Union. He believed that building up the U.S. military was the best way to pressure the Soviets to reach an agreement on arms control.</p>
<p>Reagan also spoke out strongly against communism. In his second term, he famously appealed to the new Soviet leader, Mikhail Gorbachev, to tear down the Berlin Wall. For some, the wall was a sign of communism.</p>
<p>Many historians say Reagan's policies worked. For sure, Reagan and Gorbachev improved relations between their countries. And in time, the Soviet leadership permitted the Berlin Wall to come down.</p>
<p><strong>Assassination attempt and Iran-Contra scandal</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the economy and the Cold War, Reagan is often remembered for his likable personality. He spoke easily with the public, often had a <strong>positive</strong> message about the country, and usually appeared cheerful.</p>
<p>He won even more public approval after a man with mental problems tried to kill him.</p>
<p>The bullets seriously injured several people nearby, and just missed Reagan's heart.</p>
<p>Yet, shortly after he was shot, the president joked with his wife and with his doctors. Opinion polls showed that the recovered president was more popular than ever.</p>
<p>Reagan's political image also survived a <strong>scandal </strong>known as Iran-Contra. In brief, Congress found that a number of government officials secretly sold U.S. weapons to Iran as part of a deal to free hostages. Then, the officials used some of the money to help rebels in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>The actions violated congressional rules. They also <strong>challenged</strong> Reagan's promise that he had not traded weapons for hostages.</p>
<p>The president apologized for any part he had played in the events. Polls showed that, in general, the American public accepted his apology and continued to trust him.</p>
<p>Unlike most U.S. presidents, who lose public support during their terms, Reagan finished his time in office as he had taken it – with the support of more than half of Americans.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Reagan retired to his home in California with his wife, Nancy. For several years, he wrote about his life and helped organize his presidential library.</p>
<p>But in a few years, the former president announced that he suffered from Alzheimer's. The disease affects people's ability to think, remember, and express themselves.</p>
<p>Soon, Reagan disappeared from public life. He died in 2004.</p>
<p>But he is well-remembered as an able politician who could work effectively with many people. He is also remembered – by both supporters and critics – for being a powerful voice for conservative ideas and traditional values.</p>
<p>His influence extended beyond his two terms. Later generations of leaders and voters called themselves Reagan Republicans.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>________________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>confidence</strong> - <em>n. </em>a feeling or belief that you can do something well or succeed at something</p>
<p><strong>fit</strong> -<em> adj.</em> having the necessary skills</p>
<p><strong>divorce</strong> - <em>n.</em> the ending of a marriage by a legal process</p>
<p><strong>host</strong> -<em> n.</em> a person who talks to guests on a television or radio show</p>
<p><strong>benefit</strong> -<em> v.</em> to be useful or helpful to</p>
<p><strong>standoff </strong>-<em> n.</em> an argument or contest in which there is no winner</p>
<p><strong>positive</strong> - <em>adj.</em> hopeful or optimistic</p>
<p><strong>scandal</strong> -<em> n.</em> an occurrence in which people are shocked and upset because of behavior that is morally or legally wrong</p>
<p><strong>challenge</strong> - <em>v.</em> to say or show that (something) may not be true, correct, or legal</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Life Expectancy Rises after Drops Linked to COVID-19  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-life-expectancy-rises-after-drops-linked-to-covid-19.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Life expectancy in the United States rose by about one year in 2022 following earlier decreases linked to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Life expectancy predicts the average number of years a baby born in a given year can expect to live. Federal data showed that in 2022, U.S. life expectancy rose from 76.4 years to 77.5 years.</p>
<p>Researchers from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said 2022's increase came largely because of disappearing COVID-19 cases.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, a couple walks through a park at sunset, March 10, 2021, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-bc1d-08dbf1bcbd0b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, a couple walks through a park at sunset, March 10, 2021, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel, File)</span></div>
<p>For many years, life expectancy for Americans generally rose a little bit nearly every year. But about 10 years ago, the rate flattened and even decreased in some years. Those drops were blamed on drug overdose deaths and suicides.</p>
<p>The number of U.S. suicides reached an all-time high last year, a separate CDC report found. The national suicide rate also saw its highest level since 1941. U.S. drug overdose deaths rose slightly in 2022 after much larger increases during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, U.S. life expectancy dropped from 78 years and 10 months in 2019 to 77 years in 2020. Then, in 2021, the rate dropped further, to 76 years and 5 months.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Arias is a researcher for the CDC who worked on the latest report. She told The Associated Press the U.S. life expectancy rate was clearly hurt by COVID-19 and will take "some time before we're back to where we were in 2019."</p>
<p>But Arias noted there were several favorable developments. For example, "all the groups by race and sex experienced increases in life expectancy," she said.</p>
<p>Steven Woolf, a life expectancy researcher at Virginia Commonwealth University, said he expects the U.S. to one day get back to pre-pandemic levels. But he added, "That is not a great place to be."</p>
<p>Life expectancy in 2022 increased the most for American Indian and Alaska Native non-Hispanic newborns. The rate went from 65.6 to 67.9, followed by an increase of 2.2 years for Hispanic newborns, from 77.8 to 80.</p>
<p>The life expectancy for Black non-Hispanic Americans increased by 1.6 years, from 71.2 to 72.8. Researchers noted that people in that group were more severely affected by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Life expectancy increased by 1 year for Asian non-Hispanic babies to 84.5 years, and by 0.8 years for White non-Hispanic babies, to 77.5.</p>
<p>Life expectancy in the U.S. remains longer for females. In 2020, the difference between the two sexes reached 6 years, a level not seen since 1996. In 2022, the difference narrowed to 5.4 years, down from 5.8 years in 2021.</p>
<p>Life expectancy in the U.S. continues to be lower than that of numerous other countries. And the latest report shows that the U.S. did not <strong>rebound</strong> as quickly after the pandemic as some other countries, including France, Italy, Spain and Sweden.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rebound </strong><em>– v. </em>to recover from a difficult or frustrating situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Grinch Is Back with a New Christmas Story  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-grinch-is-back-with-a-new-christmas-story.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>One year has passed since the Grinch stole Christmas from the town of Whoville. Now, the green creature is back in a follow-up book called <em>How the Grinch Lost Christmas!</em></p>
<p>And he wants to prove to the Whos of Whoville that he has changed.</p>
<p>The Grinch is a<strong> character</strong> from the 1957 children's book <em>How the Grinch Stole Christmas! </em>by Dr. Seuss. In that story, the Grinch tries to ruin Whoville's Christmas by stealing their gifts, <strong>ornaments</strong> and food. But later he learns that the holiday is about spending time with family and friends.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An image provided by Dr. Seuss Enterprises shows a page from the new book How the Grinch Lost Christmas! (Photo/TM &amp; &lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;169; 2023 Dr. Seuss Enterprises, L.P., All Rights Reserved, via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/76e08e28-983e-4695-bda1-bfe4a7680537_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An image provided by Dr. Seuss Enterprises shows a page from the new book "How the Grinch Lost Christmas!" (Photo/TM &amp; <i>&amp;#</i>169; 2023 Dr. Seuss Enterprises, L.P., All Rights Reserved, via AP)</span></div>
<p>Dr. Seuss's book sold millions of copies and was <strong>translated</strong> into several languages. The story has been turned into a television program, two movies and even a Broadway musical.</p>
<p>Random House, the book's publisher, said in a statement, "One of the most asked questions we receive from Seuss fans of all ages is 'What do you think happened to the Grinch after he stole Christmas?'"</p>
<p>So, the decision was made to write a new book to follow up on the story.</p>
<p>The new book,<em> How the Grinch Lost Christmas!, </em>starts a year later in Whoville. The Grinch wants to prove that his heart has grown to love the holiday.</p>
<p><em>The Grinch had been patiently waiting all year,</em><br/>
<em>To celebrate Christmas and bring the Whos cheer,</em><br/>
<em>And to show every Who he was DIFFERENT now. </em><br/>
<em>"I've changed!" thought the Grinch, </em><br/>
<em>"And I'll prove it! But HOW?" </em></p>
<p>So, the Grinch tries to win a Whoville's Christmas award by making the largest and the best Christmas tree the Whos have ever seen.</p>
<p>But, things do not go as planned. Young Cindy-Lou Who wins the contest. The Grinch is shocked and his heart turns ice cold. The green creature threatens to leave Whoville for real this time. Cindy-Lou reaches out and tells the Grinch that her tree has ornaments from everyone in Whoville except one. In the end, the Grinch returns with an ornament for Cindy-Lou and regains his spirit of giving.</p>
<p>Dr. Seuss, whose real name was Theodor Seuss Geisel, died in 1991. So, Alastair Heim, who has worked on several Dr. Seuss' books, wrote the new story. And Aristides Ruiz provided the illustrations.</p>
<p>Heim told <em>The Associated Press</em> in an email last February, "All throughout writing the story, I couldn't fully believe that I was actually getting to play in the amazing creative sandbox Dr. Seuss created all those decades ago."</p>
<p>Ruiz said he jumped at the chance to draw for the book. But he said the work on the new book was "difficult" because it is such a big part of the Christmas tradition in the United States.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English with additional reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>character </strong>- n. a person who appears in a story, book, play, movie or show</p>
<p><strong>ornament</strong> - n. a small object that are hung on Christmas Tree</p>
<p><strong>translate</strong> - v. to change words from one language to another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Congress Member Expelled  (2023/12/2) | 美国国会议员被投票驱逐</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-congress-member-expelled.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The U.S. House of Representatives voted to remove Republican Congressman George Santos of New York on Friday.<br/>
周五，美国众议院投票决定罢免纽约州共和党众议员乔治·桑托斯。</p>
<p>The House voted 311 to 114 to immediately remove Santos. A two-thirds majority is required to expel a member from the House. Santos became just the sixth member to be removed in the history of the United States. Three lawmakers were removed for disloyalty during the U.S. Civil War. And two were removed after being found guilty of crimes in federal court.<br/>
众议院以311票对114票决定立即罢免桑托斯。将议员逐出众议院需要三分之二多数票。桑托斯成为美国历史上第六位被罢免的议员。三名议员因在美国内战期间不忠而被免职。还有两人被联邦法院判决有罪后被免职。</p>
<p>The vote to remove Santos came after a House ethics report accused him of defrauding donors and using campaign money for his personal use. The 56-page report contained "overwhelming evidence" of lawbreaking, violations of ethics and "misstatements" during his 2022 campaign.<br/>
在投票罢免桑托斯之前，众议院的一份道德报告指控他欺诈捐赠者，并将竞选资金用于个人用途。这份56页的报告包含了他在2022年竞选期间违法、违反道德和“错误陈述”的“压倒性证据”。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">A long record of wrongdoing<br/>
一长串不法行为记录</span></p>
<p>The 35-year-old Santos has been accused of wrongdoing since he was first elected to Congress in November 2022.<br/>
现年35岁的桑托斯自2022年11月首次当选国会议员以来，一直被指控有不当行为。</p>
<p>Santos admitted that he made up his life story following several newspaper reports. He falsely claimed that his grandparents were Jewish and that they escaped the Holocaust. But his mother's immigration record said they were born in Brazil.<br/>
桑托斯承认，他的人生故事是在几篇报纸报道后编造的。他谎称他的祖父母是犹太人，他们逃过了大屠杀。但他母亲的移民记录显示他们出生在巴西。</p>
<p>Santos claimed that his family owns and collects rent money on 13 properties. There are no records of Santos or his family ever owning any property. And Santos himself has been brought to court repeatedly for not paying rent.<br/>
桑托斯声称，他的家族拥有并收取13处房产的租金。没有桑托斯或他的家人拥有任何财产的记录。而桑托斯本人也多次因不付房租而被送上法庭。</p>
<p>Newspaper reports discovered that Santos also lied about his education at New York University, his work history with financial companies Goldman Sachs and Citigroup, and his involvement in a check fraud case in Brazil. There were no records of Santos ever going to college or working at the companies. Santos later admitted to the crime and paid money in the case in Brazil.<br/>
报纸报道发现，桑托斯还谎报了他在纽约大学的教育经历、他在金融公司高盛和花旗集团的工作史，以及他参与巴西一起支票欺诈案。没有桑托斯上过大学或在这些公司工作的记录。桑托斯后来在巴西的案件中认罪并交付罚款。</p>
<p>He is currently facing federal criminal charges including stealing public money, misuse of campaign money, credit card fraud and making false statements. Santos has pleaded not guilty to those charges. But two former campaign aides have pleaded guilty to related charges.<br/>
他目前面临联邦刑事指控，包括盗窃公款、滥用竞选资金、信用卡欺诈和虚假陈述。桑托斯对这些指控表示不认罪。但两名前竞选助手已对相关指控表示认罪。</p>
<p>A bipartisan congressional investigation last month found that he used congressional campaign money to pay for almost $4,000 in spa treatments, including Botox, a kind of beauty injection. He also spent more than $4,000 of campaign money on luxury goods and made "smaller purchases" from OnlyFans, an online website known for sexual material.<br/>
上个月，国会两党的一项调查发现，他用国会竞选资金支付了近4000美元的水疗费用，其中包括肉毒杆菌毒素，这是一种美容针。他还将4000多美元的竞选资金花在了奢侈品上，并从以性材料闻名的在线网站OnlyFans上进行了“小额购买”。</p>
<p>Santos rejected repeated calls for him to resign. Before the House vote to remove him, Santos said, "The people of the Third District of New York sent me here. If they want me out, you're going to have to go silence those people and go take the hard vote."<br/>
桑托斯拒绝了多次要求他辞职的呼声。在众议院投票罢免他之前，桑托斯说：“纽约第三区的人民把我送到这里。如果他们想让我下台，你就必须让那些人噤声，然后进行艰难的投票。”</p>
<p>His expulsion will shrink the Republican's narrow majority. And New York State Governor Kathy Hochul of the Democratic Party now has 10 days to call a special election for the seat representing part of Long Island.<br/>
他的驱逐将缩小共和党的微弱多数。民主党的纽约州州长凯西·霍楚尔现在有10天的时间为这个代表长岛部分地区的席位举行特别选举。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Price vs. Rate  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/price-vs-rate.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between the words "price" and "rate."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA Learning English,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Price vs. Rate" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7fc2-08dbf13034ad_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Price vs. Rate</span></div>
<p>I am confused by the words "price" and "rate." Could you please explain these words for me?</p>
<p>Irfan from Pakistan</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, Irfan. Both words can describe an amount of money in exchange for either goods, services or a certain amount of time spent. We use them in different situations. "Rate" has more meanings and uses as well.</p>
<p>Let's start with "price."</p>
<p><strong>Price</strong></p>
<p>"Price" is a noun that can be countable or singular. As a countable noun, it means the amount of money that is exchanged for something. It can also be the amount asked for or paid.</p>
<p><em>The price for twelve eggs was almost $5.00. </em></p>
<p><em>The asking price of the house was $300,000, but it was sold for under $289,000 after negotiations. </em></p>
<p>As a singular noun, "price" is the cost, result or loss that is paid to get something else.</p>
<p><em>Amanda's loss of a <strong>flexible </strong>schedule is the price of going back to school.</em></p>
<p>We can also use "price" as a verb that takes a direct object.</p>
<p><em>Marc priced his used TV at $200. </em></p>
<p>Let's look more closely at "rate" now.</p>
<p><strong>Rate</strong></p>
<p>A "rate" is a cost or value per unit for services or time. This is different from the "price" of something.</p>
<p>For example, you hire a <strong>gardener,</strong> and their rate is $50 an hour. If the gardener worked three hours at a rate of $50 per hour, then the total price is $150.</p>
<p>"Rate" can also be used to talk about amounts, degrees, or speed of something in comparison to something else.</p>
<p><em>Your heart rate is the number of beats per minute. </em></p>
<p><em>The United States <strong>obesity</strong> rate is almost double that of Italy. </em></p>
<p>"Rate" can also be a verb that means to apply a value, worth, strength or estimation. It can take a direct object or not.</p>
<p><em>Finland, Demark and Iceland rate their happiness level as very high.</em></p>
<p><em>Saratoga Springs is rated as one of the best small cities in the U.S. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Irfan.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>flexible</strong> – <em>adj</em>. readily changed or changing</p>
<p><strong>gardener </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who cares for a garden</p>
<p><strong>obesity </strong><em>– n. </em>the state of being overweight in an unhealthy way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korean City Turns to Matchmaking to Increase Low Birth Rates  (2023/12/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/south-korean-city-turns-to-matchmaking-to-increase-low-birth-rates.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>While Christmas music played, 100 South Korean men and women gathered at a hotel near the capital of Seoul with their names written for others to see.</p>
<p>They were hoping to find love. The government hopes they will make babies.</p>
<p>The young men and women were at a blind dating event held by the city of Seongnam. Blind dating is when two people who do not know each other meet in hopes of forming a relationship.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin speaks during a mass blind date event in Seongnam, South Korea on November 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cacab718-c0ea-4146-9171-042057e32efc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin speaks during a mass blind date event in Seongnam, South Korea on November 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)</span></div>
<p>The local government is attempting to fight the falling birth rate in a country where the popularity of marriage and parenthood has fallen.</p>
<p>Those who joined were in their 20s and 30s. They sat quietly next to one another until a relationship expert started the event with a game called rock-paper-scissors. People soon began to talk and laugh.</p>
<p>The city appeared set on making a <strong>match</strong>. It prepared food and drinks like red wine and chocolate. There were also games, free beauty services, and even services to look into people's <strong>backgrounds</strong> for the singles that joined.</p>
<p>Lee Yu-mi is 36 and works for the city government. She said she registered to join three times before she was finally accepted to join the event.</p>
<p>"I had no idea it would be this competitive," she said.</p>
<p>After five such gatherings this year, 198 people among 460 left the event as "<strong>couples</strong>", agreeing to exchange contact information, the city said.</p>
<p>The South Korean capital Seoul had considered a similar event but put the plan on hold after facing criticism. Some said the event was a waste of taxpayers' money and it failed to deal with the reasons people were choosing to not marry and have babies. Those reasons include the high costs of housing and education.</p>
<p>Hwang Da-bin took part in a September event. He said it saved him the cost of joining other social events or signing up for professional match-making services.</p>
<p>"We are facing a real <strong>demographic</strong> crisis and the government needs to do whatever it can. I don't understand people <strong>complaining</strong> over this," Hwang said.</p>
<p>The average number of children born to each South Korean woman, called the fertility rate, fell to 0.78 last year. The country has the lowest fertility rate in the world.</p>
<p>The number is far below 1.66 in the United States and 1.3 in Japan in 2021. The average rate among countries in the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development, a group of 37 democracies with market economies, was 1.58 that same year.</p>
<p>Jun Jae-hoon teaches social welfare at Seoul Women's University. He said it was "nonsense" to expect these events to lead to higher birth rates.</p>
<p>"You need to spend more money directly on supporting pregnancy, child delivery and parenting to call it a policy..." to increase<strong> </strong>birth rates, Jung said.</p>
<p>But even with criticism, thousands of people have signed up for this year's blind-dating events held by the Seongnam city.</p>
<p>Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin said spreading good views on marriage would at some point help raise the birth rates. He said that the blind-dating events are just one of many policies his city has created to deal with the falling rates.</p>
<p>"Low birth rates cannot be <strong>resolved</strong> with a single policy," Shin said. "It's also the city's job to create the environment for people who want to marry find their partners."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Soo-Hyang Choi reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>match </strong>– <em>n</em>. two people or things that are suited to each other</p>
<p><strong>background </strong>– <em>n</em>. the experiences, knowledge, and education in a person's past</p>
<p><strong>demographic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to the study of changes that occur in large groups of people over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong>– <em>v</em>. to say or write that you are unhappy, sick, uncomfortable or that you do not like something</p>
<p><strong>resolve </strong>– <em>v</em>. to find an answer or solution to (something): to settle or solve (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Famed Diplomat Henry Kissinger Dies at 100  (2023/12/1) | 著名外交官基辛格百岁高龄去世</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/famed-diplomat-henry-kissinger-dies-at-100.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>American former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger died Wednesday at his home in Connecticut. He was 100 years old.<br/>
美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格星期三在康涅狄格州的家中去世。享年100岁。</p>
<p>Kissinger was famed for helping restore ties between the United States and China and negotiating the U.S. withdrawal from Vietnam.<br/>
基辛格以帮助恢复美中关系和谈判美国从越南撤军而闻名。</p>
<p>The German-born Jewish refugee served as national security advisor and secretary of state under two presidents, Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford.<br/>
这位出生于德国的犹太难民曾在理查德·尼克松和杰拉尔德·福特两任总统任期中担任国家安全顾问和国务卿。</p>
<p>During the 1970s, Kissinger led U.S. diplomacy and was involved in many world-changing events.<br/>
20世纪70年代，基辛格领导了美国外交，并参与了许多改变世界的事件。</p>
<p>He led the first "shuttle diplomacy" to improve ties between Israel and its Arab neighbors. He started secret talks that led to the recognition of Communist China and its return to the world community. His policy of "détente" led to arms control agreements with the former Soviet Union.<br/>
他领导了第一次“穿梭外交”，以改善以色列与其阿拉伯邻国之间的关系。他开始了秘密会谈，最终导致美国承认了中华人民共和国的地位及其重返国际社会。他的“缓和”政策促成了与前苏联的军备控制协议。</p>
<p>He negotiated the 1973 Paris Peace Accord to get the U.S. out of the conflict in Vietnam. The effort won him a Nobel Peace Prize. Vietnamese Communist forces won control of the country two years later.<br/>
他通过谈判达成了1973年的《巴黎和平协议》，以使美国摆脱越南冲突。这一努力为他赢得了诺贝尔和平奖。两年后，越南共产党军队赢得了对该国的控制权。</p>
<p>On Thursday, many world leaders praised Kissinger for his life's work. However, others sharply criticized the former diplomat for damaging the world in the process. And on social media, many posts described him as a war criminal.<br/>
周四，许多世界领导人赞扬了基辛格毕生的工作。然而，其他人尖锐地批评这位前外交官在这个过程中损害了世界。在社交媒体上，许多帖子将他描述为战犯。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Praise<br/>
赞扬</span></p>
<p>Former U.S. President George W. Bush said, "America has lost one of the most dependable and distinctive voices" on foreign relations.<br/>
美国前总统布什说，“美国失去了外交事务上最可靠、最独特的声音之一”。</p>
<p>French President Emmanuel Macron praised Kissinger in a post on the social media site X, formerly Twitter. He wrote: "Henry Kissinger was a giant of history. His century of ideas and of diplomacy had a lasting influence on his time and on our world."<br/>
法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙在社交媒体网站X（前身为推特）上发帖赞扬了基辛格。他写道：“亨利·基辛格是一位历史巨人。他一个多世纪以来的思想和外交成就对他的时代和我们的世界产生了持久的影响。”</p>
<p>China's state broadcaster CCTV said that President Xi Jinping sent U.S. President Joe Biden a message of sympathy Thursday. It said, "Dr. Kissinger will always be remembered and missed by the Chinese people." China's Foreign Ministry spokesperson called Kissinger an "old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of China-U.S. relations."<br/>
中国中央电视台表示，习主席向美国总统拜登发去唁电。电文称：“基辛格博士将永远被中国人民铭记和怀念。”外交部发言人称基辛格是“中国人民的老朋友、好朋友，是中美关系的开拓者和建设者”。</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said in a message to Kissinger's wife that his foreign policy led to "the most important Soviet-American agreements" in strengthening world security.<br/>
俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在给基辛格妻子的一封信中表示，他的外交政策促成了加强世界安全的“最重要的苏美协议”。</p>
<p>In a message to Kissinger's family, Germany's President Frank-Walter Steinmeier wrote, "with his détente and disarmament policy, Henry Kissinger laid the foundation for the end of the Cold War and the democratic transition in eastern Europe" which led to Germany's reunification.<br/>
德国总统弗兰克·沃尔特·施泰因迈尔在给基辛格家人的一封信中写道，“凭借他的缓和政策和裁军政策，亨利·基辛格为冷战的结束和东欧的民主过渡奠定了基础”，这导致了德国的统一。</p>
<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog told U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken in Tel Aviv that Kissinger "laid the cornerstone of the peace agreement, which (was) later signed with Egypt, and so many other processes around the world I admire."<br/>
以色列总统艾萨克·赫尔佐格在特拉维夫告诉美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯，基辛格“奠定了后来与埃及签署的和平协议的基石，以及我钦佩的世界各地的许多其他进程。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Criticism<br/>
批评</span></p>
<p>However, criticism of Kissinger was especially strong for his actions during the war in Vietnam.<br/>
然而，对基辛格在越南战争期间的行为的批评尤其强烈。</p>
<p>The policy of "Vietnamization" was meant to shift the fighting against North Vietnam from U.S. forces to the South Vietnamese. It included a massive bombing campaign of North Vietnam and the mining of the Northern ports. The U.S. also bombed in Cambodia and Laos in 1969 although Kissinger kept that secret. The attacks in those countries intensified the civil war in Vietnam.<br/>
“越南化”政策旨在将对北越的战斗从美军转移到南越。其中包括对北越的大规模轰炸和对北部港口的挖掘。1969年，美国还轰炸了柬埔寨和老挝，尽管基辛格对此保密。对这些国家的袭击加剧了越南内战。</p>
<p>Kissinger also was criticized for his part in Angola's civil war, Pakistan's aggression toward Bangladesh, and the U.S. involvement in Chile, which ended with a government overthrow in 1973.<br/>
基辛格还因参与安哥拉内战、巴基斯坦对孟加拉国的侵略以及美国对智利的干预而受到批评，1973年智利政府被推翻。</p>
<p>Sophal Ear is a Cambodia expert at Arizona State University. He wrote in the online publication The Conversation: "Henry Kissinger's bombing campaign likely killed hundreds of thousands of Cambodians — and set (a) path for the ravages of the Khmer Rouge."<br/>
索法尔·厄尔是亚利桑那州立大学的柬埔寨问题专家。他在网络出版物《对话》中写道：“亨利·基辛格的轰炸行动可能导致数十万柬埔寨人死亡，并为红色高棉的蹂躏开辟了道路。”</p>
<p>"The cluster bombs dropped on Cambodia under Kissinger's watch continue to destroy the lives of any man, woman or child who happens across them," Sophal Ear added.<br/>
索法尔·厄尔补充道：“在基辛格注视下投向柬埔寨的集束炸弹继续摧毁着炸弹周围任何男人、女人或孩子的生命。”</p>
<p>Reporting the diplomat's death, the magazine Rolling Stone published this headline: "Henry Kissinger, war criminal beloved by America's ruling class, finally dies."<br/>
在报道这位外交官的死讯时，《滚石》杂志发表了这样的标题：“深受美国统治阶级爱戴的战犯亨利·基辛格终于去世了。”</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar for Giving Gifts  (2023/12/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/grammar-for-giving-gifts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>We are now in between two major American holidays: Thanksgiving and Christmas. This is the most important time of the year for giving gifts.</p>
<p>So, in the holiday spirit, we will explore some common questions that connect to gift giving. Please note that what we explore in this lesson is not connected only to American holidays - it can be used more generally to describe any kind of gift-giving event.</p>
<p><strong>Questions </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6a66-08dbf103c425_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Imagine you want to get a gift for a family member. You need some advice from another family member or friend. How would you ask for such advice?</p>
<p>That question leads us to the first point in today's lesson. We are asking about what others want in terms of a gift.</p>
<p>One way to ask this question is by using a "what" question.</p>
<p>This is a kind of open-ended question. In other words, you are asking a question that requires more information than a simple answer of yes or no.</p>
<p>You might use <strong>modals</strong> or helping verbs in your question. You might also want to report who is going to receive the gift and the occasion that the gift is for.</p>
<p>Let's take an example to clarify these points.</p>
<p>Imagine you are doing Christmas shopping for your brother. Let's say his name is Tom. Here is how you might ask another person – say your mother – about a gift for Tom. You could ask: "What would Tom like for Christmas?"</p>
<p>Here, we have the "what" question word along with the modal "would" and then the name Tom followed by the verb "like." Please note that we also generally use the structure "for + holiday" where the holiday is a noun or noun <strong>phrase</strong>. In this case, the holiday is Christmas.</p>
<p>Another way you might ask the question is with the helping verb "do." The basic structure is the same as our example containing "would" and "like." But in this question, we replace those words with "do" and "want." So, you might ask, "What does Tom want for Christmas?"</p>
<p>Please note that the two questions we have discussed so far have almost the same meaning:</p>
<p><em>What would Tom like for Christmas?</em></p>
<p>And</p>
<p><em>What does Tom want for Christmas?</em></p>
<p><strong>Locations and nouns</strong></p>
<p>Now let us consider questions about places to get gifts. In such questions, we generally use the question word "where" along with the modal "can." We often use "find" as the main verb. And we often use nouns with similar meanings such as "sales," "deals," or "specials."</p>
<p>Let's explore three examples, all of which have a similar meaning.</p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday sales?</em></p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday deals?</em></p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday specials?</em></p>
<p>Note that the question word always comes first. The modal "can" comes between the question word and the subject "I."</p>
<p>And then we have the main verb "find" along with the noun phrases such as holiday specials, holiday deals, and so on.</p>
<p>Once you find the correct location, then discussions about price might come. We explored that subject <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-and-the-economy-prices/7117170.html" target="_blank">in an earlier lesson</a>, which you can find in the Everyday Grammar area of our website, www.51voa.com.</p>
<p><strong>Quiz </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Imagine you are considering what gift to get for your mother for her birthday. How might you ask another family member about what to get?</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here are two possible answers:</p>
<p><em>What would Mom like for her birthday?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>What does Mom want for her birthday?</em></p>
<p>In our answers, we used the question word "what." Either the structure "...would Mom like..." or "...does Mom want..." will work.</p>
<p>What is important is that after the short word "for," we have the noun phrase "her birthday." This noun phrase provides information that makes the question clearer.</p>
<p>Future lessons will explore gift giving in greater detail.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>modal </strong><em>– n. </em>a verb (such as can, could, shall, should, ought to, will, or would) that is usually used with another verb to express ideas such as possibility, necessity, and permission</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express an idea but do not form a complete sentence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google to Start Removing ‘Inactive’ User Accounts  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/google-to-start-removing-inactive-user-accounts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google is about to start <strong>deleting</strong> accounts considered "inactive."</p>
<p>The company plans to start removing inactive accounts that users have not used or signed into for more than two years on December 1.</p>
<p>Google announced the policy in May, saying it could begin removing affected accounts in December 2023. User data that could be deleted includes content stored within Google Drive, Docs, Gmail and other services.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1dd2-08dbf0fa624e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>Google says users with accounts at risk of being deleted should have already received email messages explaining the policy and the steps required to keep accounts active.</p>
<p>The company said the deletion process will start with Google accounts that were created, but never used again. Google is urging users who want to save their accounts and related data to take some form of action by the end of this week.</p>
<p><strong>Why is Google deleting inactive accounts?</strong></p>
<p>Google has said its policy to delete old, unused accounts is designed to remove security risks related to those accounts.</p>
<p>In its announcement, Google <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/updating-our-inactive-account-policies/">said</a> accounts that go long periods of time without activity are "more likely to be <strong>compromised</strong>." The reasons for this include the fact that forgotten or unused accounts often depend on old or reused passwords.</p>
<p>Another thing that puts such accounts at risk is the lack of two-step security processes that became popular in recent years to help users keep their accounts secure. This security tool, called "two-factor authentication," aims to reduce the risk of internet attackers taking over personal accounts and stealing data.</p>
<p>In addition, old and unused accounts "receive fewer security checks by the user," Google said.</p>
<p><strong>How can I prevent my account from being deleted?</strong></p>
<p>Google says the best way to keep a user account active is to sign into it at least once every two years.</p>
<p>But there are some other actions that meet the requirements for keeping a Google account active. These include sending or looking at emails, using Google search and watching videos on Google-owned YouTube. The user must be signed in to their Google account when performing these actions.</p>
<p>The policy covers Google Photos as well. The company <a class="wsw__a" href="https://support.google.com/photos/answer/10100180">explains</a> that the simplest way to avoid losing saved pictures and videos is "to visit Google Photos on the web or through the <strong>app</strong>." When signed in, users just need to perform some activity. For example, they can look through an image collection, share a photo or video or back up content in Photos.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any exceptions to the policy?</strong></p>
<p>Google says it only plans to delete old or unused accounts for personal users. Accounts that were set up for organizations, such as schools or businesses, will not be affected.</p>
<p>Other exceptions include Google accounts controlled by an adult for a child or accounts that have been used to buy goods or services on an ongoing basis.</p>
<p>Google has also noted there are no current plans to delete accounts with YouTube videos.</p>
<p><strong>How can I save data from my Google account?</strong></p>
<p>Google does offer users some tools to help them save and backup stored data. One of them is called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://takeout.google.com/">Takeout</a>. This service permits users to download and export account data outside of Google at any time. An account holder can use this method to back up stored data or to use it with a service outside of Google.</p>
<p>In addition, Google offers a tool, called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3036546?hl=en">Inactive Account Manager</a>, which permits users to choose what would happen to their accounts and data if it does become inactive. The choices for activating this service include having files sent to a set of trusted contacts or requesting that the whole account be deleted.</p>
<p>Google also asks that all its users provide a recovery email for their account. This can be an important method for getting a user back into a locked account and can also be helpful for sending inactive account messages and other communications.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Google reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>delete </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove something, especially from a computer's memory</p>
<p><strong>compromise </strong><em>– v. </em>to agree to something that is not exactly what you want</p>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>No Easy Solution for Carbon Capture  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/no-easy-solution-for-carbon-capture.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Countries are gathering for the 28th United Nations climate change conference in the United Arab Emirates at the end of November. Many will pay special attention to carbon capture to meet international commitments to decarbonize by mid-century.</p>
<p>Here are some details about the carbon capture industry as well as some of the issues facing its future.</p>
<p><strong>Different kinds of carbon capture </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Carbon dioxide storage tanks are seen at a cement plant and carbon capture facility in Wuhu, Anhui province, China September 11, 2019. (REUTERS/David Stanway/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0d75c659-9498-4d42-b0e1-010d95203b76_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Carbon dioxide storage tanks are seen at a cement plant and carbon capture facility in Wuhu, Anhui province, China September 11, 2019. (REUTERS/David Stanway/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>There are two main kinds of carbon capture technology: carbon capture and storage (CCS) and carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS).</p>
<p>CCS, the most common form of carbon capture technology, involves capturing the gas from a source like an industrial <strong>smokestack</strong>. From there, the carbon can be moved directly to underground storage.</p>
<p>CCUS involves capturing the gas and using it in another industrial activity before storage.</p>
<p>There are currently 42 CCS and CCUS projects across the world. The Global CCS Institute says these projects can store 49 million metric tons of <strong>carbon dioxide</strong> each year. That amount is about 0.13 percent of the world's roughly 37 billion metric tons of yearly energy and industry-related carbon dioxide <strong>emissions</strong>.</p>
<p>Another form of carbon capture is <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36K3XK&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">direct air capture</a> (DAC), in which carbon emissions are captured from the air.</p>
<p>About 130 DAC facilities are being planned around the world, says the International Energy Agency (IEA).</p>
<p>In August, the United States announced $1.2 billion in financing for two DAC projects in the states of Texas and Louisiana that promise to capture 2 million metric tons of carbon per year. However, a final investment decision on the projects has not been made.</p>
<p><strong>High costs </strong></p>
<p>Cost is one issue facing carbon capture technology.</p>
<p>CCS costs can go from $15 to $120 per metric ton of captured carbon depending on the emissions source. DAC projects are <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/nMT1ECMIIE17OJYQX7ZZG2PTI9IZJIAEOWT" target="_blank">even more</a> costly, between $600 and $1,000 per metric ton.</p>
<p>Some CCS projects in countries like <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36T56T&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Norway</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL1N3AW2X7&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Canada</a> have been paused for financial reasons.</p>
<p>Developers say they need a carbon price, either in the form of a carbon tax, trading system or tax break, that makes it profitable to capture and store the carbon. Without that, only carbon capture projects that increase money in a different way - like through increased oil output - are profitable.</p>
<p>Countries including the U.S. have announced<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36E3E7&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank"> public <strong>subsidies</strong></a> for carbon capture projects. The Inflation Reduction Act, passed in 2022, offers a $50 tax credit per metric ton of carbon captured for CCUS and $85 per metric ton captured for CCS. The law also offers $180 per metric ton captured through DAC.</p>
<p>Although those are meaningful offers, companies may still need to take on some added costs to move CCS and DAC projects ahead, said Benjamin Longstreth, worldwide director of carbon capture at the Clean Air Task Force.</p>
<p><strong>Locations </strong></p>
<p>Where captured carbon can be stored is limited by geology – the land and processes of land formation in an area. The best storage places for carbon are in parts of North America, East Africa, and the North Sea, the Global CCS Institute says.</p>
<p>That means getting captured carbon to storage areas could require large pipeline networks or even shipping <strong>fleets</strong>. Developing such networks can create new difficulties.</p>
<p>In October, for example, a $3 billion CCS pipeline project proposed by <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL1N3BQ1NF&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Navigator CO2 Ventures</a> in the U.S. was canceled amid community concerns about possible leaks and damage during the building process.</p>
<p>Companies investing in carbon removal need to take seriously community concerns about new<strong> infrastructure</strong> projects, said Simone Stewart of the National Wildlife Federation.</p>
<p>"Not all technologies are going to be possible in all locations," Stewart said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Leah Douglas reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>smokestack</strong> <em>– n. </em>a tall chimney on a factory, ship, etc., for carrying smoke away</p>
<p><strong>carbon dioxide</strong> <em>– n.</em> gas that is produced when certain fuels are burned</p>
<p><strong>emission</strong> <em>– n.</em> something sent out or given off</p>
<p><strong>subsidy </strong><em>– n. </em>money that is paid usually by a government to keep the price of a product or service low</p>
<p><strong>fleet</strong> <em>– n. </em>a group of ships or vehicles that move or work together</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>-- n. </em>the basic equipment (such as roads and bridges) that are needed for a country to function</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Passenger Jet Fueled by Cooking Fat Crosses the Atlantic  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/passenger-jet-fueled-by-cooking-fat-crosses-the-atlantic.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>British Businessman Richard Branson and Britain's Department of Transport organized a flight crossing the Atlantic Ocean by a jet using fuel made from animal fat.</p>
<p>The Boeing 787 passenger airplane flew from London to New York on Tuesday using what the organizers called <strong>sustainable</strong> jet fuel.</p>
<p>Branson founded Virgin Atlantic airlines. The airline said it used a fuel made from waste fats, including animal fat used in cooking. The transport department spent over $1.2 million for the flight.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt=" Virgin Atlantic's Flight100 Lands at JFK Airport in New York City from London Heathrow, Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2023 in New York. (Jason DeCrow/AP Images for Virgin Atlantic Airways Ltd)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/99e3ce64-535f-4786-ac03-55d609b2d2bd_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"> Virgin Atlantic's Flight100 Lands at JFK Airport in New York City from London Heathrow, Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2023 in New York. (Jason DeCrow/AP Images for Virgin Atlantic Airways Ltd)</span></div>
<p>Branson was on the plane, along with reporters, engineers and government officials as it crossed the Atlantic Ocean. There were no paying passengers.</p>
<p>"The world will always <strong>assume</strong> something can't be done, until you do it," Branson said.</p>
<p>The transport department called the trip "a huge step towards jet zero." "Jet zero" is a play on words. It means the trip did not use traditional jet fuel that comes from oil. Some officials in the international air travel industry say they hope their companies can reach what is called "net zero" by 2050. "Net zero" is a proposed balance between the release of carbon gases into the atmosphere and the capture of those gases.</p>
<p>However, organizers admit the mix of fuel used on Tuesday's trip will not be widely available anytime soon.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Energy says sustainable <strong>aviation</strong> fuel is the best way to reach the "net zero" target by 2050. The government says sustainable aviation fuel cuts the release of greenhouse gases, gases said to cause warming, by 70 percent. However, the Department of Energy said the 2050 goal is "aspirational." That means it is unlikely to be reached.</p>
<p>In the U.S., sustainable jet fuel production increased from about 8 million liters in 2016 to about 60 million liters in 2022. But that is only about 0.1 percent of the fuel used by major airlines. In 2018, the Federal Aviation Administration set a goal of producing about 15 billion liters per year.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden's administration said in 2021 that it wanted three times that amount by 2030 and for commercial airlines to fly on 100 percent sustainable fuel by 2050. In Britain, the goal is for 10 percent of jet fuel to come from what it calls sustainable sources by 2030.</p>
<p>Holly Boyd-Boland is an official with Virgin Atlantic. She said Tuesday's flight shows a sustainable flight is possible, but the difficulty is in producing enough of the new fuel "so that we're flying more sustainable aviation fuel every day."</p>
<p>Cait Hewitt is the policy director for the British non-profit group Aviation Environment Federation. The group is interested in reducing the effect of the aviation industry on the environment.</p>
<p>She said, "the idea that this flight somehow gets us closer to <strong>guilt</strong>-free flying is a joke." She said it will be difficult to increase production of sustainable jet fuel to the point that it makes a difference.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong>–adj. related to ideas about using resources without using them up completely</p>
<p><strong>assume </strong>–v. to think something is true without knowing that it is true</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong>–n. things related to flight and aircraft</p>
<p><strong>guilt </strong>–n. a feeling of shame over something you do or have done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Former Somali Refugee Wins UN Refugee Award  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/former-somali-refugee-wins-un-refugee-award.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency has named a former child refugee from Somalia winner of this year's Nansen Refugee Award.</p>
<p>The U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) recognized Abdullahi Mire for providing 100,000 books to Somali refugees in camps in Kenya. Mire is now 36 years old.</p>
<p>"Last year, 2022, Angela Merkel, the former Federal Chancellor of Germany, won the award and today a young refugee from Dadaab. The sky is not the limit," Mire told VOA Somalia.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This handout picture taken on Nov. 8, 2023, shows Abdullahi Mire, winner of the U.N. refugee agency's prestigious Nansen Award posing for a picture in one of the libraries he established in Kenya's Dadaab refugee camp. (AFP Photo/UNHCR)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-4d6c-08dbf0605025_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This handout picture taken on Nov. 8, 2023, shows Abdullahi Mire, winner of the U.N. refugee agency's prestigious Nansen Award posing for a picture in one of the libraries he established in Kenya's Dadaab refugee camp. (AFP Photo/UNHCR)</span></div>
<p>Filippo Grandi is the president of the UNHCR. He said Mire is living proof that "<strong>transformative</strong> ideas" can come out of displaced communities.</p>
<p>"He has shown great <strong>resourcefulness</strong> and <strong>tenacity</strong> in strengthening the quality of refugee education," Grandi said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mire was born in southern Somalia in 1987. In 1991, his family fled the country because of Somalia's civil war.</p>
<p>"I fled from Qoryooley in the Lower Shabelle region in 1991 with my mother and grew up and lived in the Dadaab refugee camps for 23 years," Mire told VOA.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>The Dadaab complex in northeastern Kenya today has a population of more than 240,000 refugees, most from Somalia. Over half of the camp's population are children.</p>
<p>Mire finished elementary and secondary schooling while living in the camp. He went on to earn a college degree in public relations and <strong>journalism</strong> from Kenya's Kenyatta University. He said his mother gave him help and support to become, in his words, "a voice for my <strong>vulnerable</strong> population."</p>
<p>Mire got a job with the United Nations International Organization for Migration in Somalia. He worked in the capital Mogadishu and the southern cities of Baidoa and Kismayo.</p>
<p>He said his childhood in Dadaab and professional experience taught him the importance of his education. So, he decided to <strong>dedicate</strong> his professional life to helping his fellow refugees.</p>
<p>In early 2018, he started an organization called Refugee Youth Education Hub. The organization centers on refugee education and youth development.</p>
<p>After shortly living in Norway, he returned to Dadaab to help.</p>
<p>"I had a <strong>yearning</strong> to serve my community that drew me back to the camp," he said.</p>
<p>A refugee woman who was studying medicine in Dadaab <strong>inspired</strong> him to collect books for refugee camps, Mire said.</p>
<p>"She told me about 20 girls normally shared one biology book. That inspired me to use social media for a book collection and donation campaign till we reached 100,000 books."</p>
<p>Mire is not the only Somali who has won the Nansen Refugee Award. In 2012, the UNHCR presented Hawa Aden Mohamed with the award for her work to help Somali refugee and displaced females.</p>
<p>The award is named for the Norwegian explorer, scientist, diplomat and humanitarian, Fridtjof Nansen.</p>
<p>"The win is not for me alone," Mire said in a statement. "It is for all the volunteers I work with... It is for the children in the schools."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Mohamed Olad Hassan wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transformative </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing or able to cause a change</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resourceful </strong><em>— adj. </em> able to deal well with new or difficult situations and to find solutions to problems</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tenacious </strong><em>— adj. </em>very determined to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>— adj. </em>easily hurt or harmed physically, mentally, or emotionally</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dedicate </strong><em>— v. </em> to use time, money, energy, attention, etc. for something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>yearn </strong><em>— v. </em>to feel a strong desire or wish for something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inspire </strong><em>— v. </em>to make want to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reports: World Is ‘Off Track’ in Fighting Climate Change  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/reports-world-is-off-track-in-fighting-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Three recent reports say the world is failing in its fight to slow climate change.</p>
<p>The medical publication <em>The Lancet</em> released its yearly report called The Countdown. The study measures human health in connection with climate change. The 2023 report says more people are dying due to heat waves than in the past. It says the numbers will rise sharply as temperatures continue to rise.</p>
<p>Researchers also released another report called <em>State of Climate Action</em>. Several groups took part in producing the report including the World Resources Institute, Climate Action Tracker, and the Bezos Earth Fund. The report says the world is failing in 41 of 42 important climate measurements. It said six <strong>indicators</strong> show the world is heading the wrong way – noting the way some governments are still helping fund the use of <strong>fossil fuels</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c81130a-45bf-401c-9ab1-c37cc02f3c11_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)</span></div>
<p>And the U.S. government recently produced a 2,200 page National Climate Assessment that looked at how warming is harming America.</p>
<p><em>The Lancet's</em> report noted that deaths due to heat among people 65 or older were 85 percent higher in the last 10 years than from 1991 to 2000. There were 23,200 heat deaths of older people in 2022, the report found.</p>
<p>A computer program showed that the numbers would be much lower if the Earth had not warmed to its current levels.</p>
<p>"We are already seeing climate change claiming lives and livelihoods in every part of the world," said Countdown chief, Marina Romanello. But, the effects reported today could be, in her words, "an early symptom of a very dangerous future."</p>
<p>Romanello said that people also are increasingly reporting hunger because of<strong> drought</strong> and heat waves.</p>
<p>Dr. Jonathan Patz is the former director of the Global Health Institute at the University of Wisconsin and was not part of the study. He praised the study as the most thorough yearly scientific examination of climate change and health. Patz called its findings "<strong>stark</strong>."</p>
<p>Paul Elkins is an economics professor at University College of London. He worked on <em>The Lancet</em> report. He said the harms produced by the fossil fuel industry are "extremely <strong>relevant</strong>." He said its pollution is "killing people and making them ill."</p>
<p>The report also directly criticizes banks that loan money to the industry. It compared the fossil fuel business to the tobacco industry.</p>
<p><em>The Countdown </em>names 68 countries that it says gave more than $300 billion combined in assistance to companies that produced fossil fuels in 2020.</p>
<p>The <em>State of Climate Action</em> report also discusses such financial support. It described the business aid as one of six main signs that the world is going in the wrong direction on climate change.</p>
<p>Joe Thwaites is an expert with the Natural Resources Defense Council and one of the writers of the <em>State of Climate Action</em>.<em> </em>Thwaites said fossil fuel industry aid "reached an all-time high last year, over $1 trillion, driven by the war in Ukraine and the resulting energy price <strong>spikes</strong>."</p>
<p>Kelly Levin is with the Bezos Earth Fund. She said the financial aid for fossil fuels is an indicator that recently changed. That means, until recently, there was less financial aid available to pay for fossil fuels.</p>
<p>The State of Climate Action report noted five other areas where the world's progress has reversed: the high energy cost of making steel, the fuel efficiency of passenger cars, the sale of electric buses, the loss of mangrove forests and the amount of food waste.</p>
<p>The only improving measurement is that sales of electric vehicles are rising around the world.</p>
<p>Levin said the time for "<strong>tinkering</strong>" is over and instead asked for "<strong>radical</strong> decarbonization."</p>
<p>Levin's report went on to show all of the many changes that are needed to prevent a global temperature rise that many nations agreed to in Paris in 2015.</p>
<p>Justin Mankin is a climate scientist at Dartmouth College who was not involved in the reports. He said the first step in making changes should be "low-hanging fruit." That means countries should work together to make the easiest changes. He noted, however, that the reports show "we're really struggling to pick the low-hanging fruit."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> an environmental condition that comes from a long period without rain</p>
<p><strong>indicator </strong><em>–n.</em> a piece of information that provides an idea about a larger topic of concern</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuels </strong><em>–n.</em> a fuel (such as coal, oil, or natural gas) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>stark </strong><em>–adj.</em> an unpleasant and difficult to accept experience</p>
<p><strong>relevant </strong><em>–adj.</em> information that is connected and important to a larger concern</p>
<p><strong>spike </strong><em>–n.</em> a sharp rise in the price or cost of something</p>
<p><strong>tinker </strong><em>–v.</em> to work on something little by little</p>
<p><strong>radical </strong><em>–adj.</em> a serious or extreme idea or path to complete a job</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Market Grows for Costly ‘Fine Water’  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/market-grows-for-costly-fine-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>At a meeting in April in Athens, Greece, drink experts looked carefully at the liquid in their glasses. They held them up to the light. They tasted and, sometimes, spit them out into containers. And they discussed the mineral content and <strong>purity</strong>.</p>
<p>But these experts were not tasting wine. Instead, they were tasting "fine water."</p>
<p>The experts are members of the Fine Water Society. They had come together in Athens for the yearly tasting competition. Their activity reflects the growing market for <strong>luxury</strong> water—with some bottles costing over $100 per liter.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mineral water sommelier Martin Riese, right, examines a glass of fine water during an International Water Tasting Competition, in Athens, Greece, on Wednesday, April 26, 2023, accompanied by Michael Mascha, founder of the Fine Water Society. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-9ce4-08dbeb69c2a6_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mineral water sommelier Martin Riese, right, examines a glass of fine water during an International Water Tasting Competition, in Athens, Greece, on Wednesday, April 26, 2023, accompanied by Michael Mascha, founder of the Fine Water Society. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)</span></div>
<p>Companies collect the so-called "fine water" from sources such as volcanic rock in Hawaii, melting ice from glaciers in Norway, and drops of <strong>mist</strong> from forests in the Amazon or the island of Tasmania. The most costly water is sold in bottles made with special glass painted with artwork.</p>
<p>At their meeting, Fine Water Society members learned about the environments from which the water is collected. And they compare the total <strong>dissolved</strong> solids, or TDS.</p>
<p>Waters with a low TDS are like rain that has not yet touched the earth. Those with high TDS — such as Vichy mineral water from hot springs in France and Catalonia, in northeastern Spain — have high mineral content that may include calcium, magnesium, potassium or sodium, among others.</p>
<p>A few restaurants in countries such as Spain and the United States now have <strong>menus</strong> that match food with certain kinds of fine water. Water with high TDS, for example, might go with beef. Low TDS, more like rainwater, might go with fish.</p>
<p>Ganesh Iyer is an Indian businessman who has worked in the beverage, or drink, industry for years. After he saw increased interest in non-alcoholic drinks, he studied to become a drink expert, also known as a water sommelier.</p>
<p>He is now the <strong>managing</strong> partner of Veen Waters India. The company bottles natural mineral water in the Himalayan country of Bhutan and sends it by truck to India. Veen Waters is mostly served in costly hotels and restaurants. It costs $6 a bottle, about a day's pay for an Indian laborer.</p>
<p>Veen Waters is exporting about 240,000 bottles of water into India each month. Iyer thinks the company has reached only about 10 percent of the possible market so far.</p>
<p><strong>Water-stressed India</strong></p>
<p>The story of water, however, is very different for many people in India.</p>
<p>The World Bank reports that India is one of the most water-stressed countries in the world. To get more water, the country has built huge plants to remove salt from seawater. Other countries, including Singapore, are collecting and cleaning up storm and wastewater to try to solve their water problems.</p>
<p>But these kinds of solutions are only used in some places, and the increasing need for water could lead to more disagreements.</p>
<p>At the same time, those in the fine water industry see their activity as part of an effort to protect the environment and its clean water.</p>
<p>Michael Mascha is a co-founder of the Fine Water Society. He told <em>The Associated Press</em>, "I think what we do is we raise the <strong>awareness</strong> of water — and if you <strong>cherish</strong> something, you're more likely to protect it."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith</p>
<p><em>Martha Irvine wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>purity</strong> <em>-n. </em>clearness, being without unwanted elements or aspects</p>
<p><strong>luxury </strong><em>-n. </em>something expensive which is not necessary but which gives pleasure</p>
<p><strong>mist </strong><em>-n. </em>very small drops of water in the air, similar to fog</p>
<p><strong>dissolved </strong><em>-adj. </em>mixed into a liquid</p>
<p><strong>menu </strong><em>-n. </em>a list of food and drink at a restaurant</p>
<p><strong>manage </strong><em>-v. </em>to direct or be in charge of</p>
<p><strong>awareness </strong><em>-n. </em>knowledge of something and having it in mind</p>
<p><strong>cherish </strong><em>-v. </em>to highly value or appreciate</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Media Program Helps Young People in Washington, DC  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/media-program-helps-young-people-in-washington-dc.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A 17-year-old student in Washington, D.C. recently got the chance to <strong>interview </strong>retired American basketball star Magic Johnson. As a result, Magic offered to pay for the student's college education – all of it.</p>
<p>Jordan Williams studies at Bard High School Early College, a D.C. public school. The teenager is also in the city's Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, run by D.C.'s Parks and Recreation Department.</p>
<p>As a member of the Deanwood media program, Jordan attended a <strong>press conference</strong> at The Boy's and Girl's Club to interview Magic Johnson, a co-owner of the city's Washington Commanders football team.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Jordan Williams, a student in the Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, interviews basketball legend Magic Johnson in Washington, D.C. (Courtesy Photo) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-fe3a-08dbebc5a880_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Jordan Williams, a student in the Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, interviews basketball legend Magic Johnson in Washington, D.C. (Courtesy Photo) </span></div>
<p>Standing with professional reporters, Jordan asked the famous athlete why he wanted to visit a youth club in Washington, D.C. Magic answered that he "wanted to make a difference." And he meant it. He offered Jordan a full scholarship on the spot.</p>
<p>Jordan: "You never know who's in the room. You never know who's watching. You never know who's listening. The fact that I was able to ask that question, that people were able to hear it and Magic Johnson was so impressed by it ... he was able to give me a scholarship."</p>
<p>VOA Learning English recently spoke with Jordan as well as Salih Williams (no relation to Jordan), the director of the media program.</p>
<p><strong>Why start a youth media program?</strong></p>
<p>Williams established the Deanwood program to address what he describes as a "<strong>language barrier</strong>" between local media and teenagers in two areas of the city -- Ward 7 and Ward 8. Crime is higher in those wards than in others.</p>
<p>"I knew the value of developing young voices. ... So, in the beginning it was just to develop communication skills but also to <strong>engage</strong> them in news ... because I felt a lot of times, the only time that people in Ward 7 and Ward 8 engage with media people was when there was a tragedy or a death."</p>
<p>Students in the program learn researching, communication, and interviewing skills as well as how to engage with the news media. The students complete 30 to 40 interviews a year. Williams says these skills will help the students whether they decide to stay in journalism or go into a different field.</p>
<p>The program has also become a<strong> gateway</strong> to college. Since the program began in 2016, 38 of its students have gone to college -- 23 on full scholarships.</p>
<p><strong>Network &amp; community</strong></p>
<p>Ayonlah Carter is a graduate of the program.</p>
<p>"I feel like, it kind of gives us the opportunity to kind of express ourselves or just voice our opinions. And in a bigger sense, this is a group with, you know, Black and Brown kids. That carries weight in itself. So, it's nice to be in a space where we're uplifted. But it also feels like we're making a difference. And I feel like in 10, 15 years from now we're going to see a lot more Black journalists or just people in media."</p>
<p>She says one of the best things about the program is the community of students. She says they look out for each other and have become "found family."</p>
<p>"I think we all just reach out and look out for each other. And I think that's what valued most. You know, some of us don't have the best backgrounds. But we still kind of pull each other up or help out where we can."</p>
<p>Ayonlah said her mother died when Ayonlah was only 10 years old. When she turned 17, she said her family situation changed so much that she had to leave. She wasn't sure what she was going to do. She said the media program and its founder Salih Williams gave her life direction.</p>
<p>"Coming upon, like, going to college, I really didn't know where I was going to go or what I was going to do. But (through) this program and (through) Salih ... I was able to go to college on a full scholarship and everything was taken care of."</p>
<p>A saying<strong> </strong>Salih Williams likes to use with the students is: "Your network is your net worth." Jordan agrees. He adds that connections are important in succeeding and growing.</p>
<p>"Just being treated like we matter. There (are) people there to listen to us, listen to our questions. Anything we need, they're there to help. I think that's what makes the program so special."</p>
<p>Jordan says he enjoys hearing success stories from people who share a similar background. Jordan hasn't even started college, but he already has his sights on being a <strong>role model</strong> some day, like those he has learned from.</p>
<p>Ayonlah Carter says she is also excited about her future ... wherever she ends up.</p>
<p>"I think, I'm just more excited to see where I end up at. Will I be on the news? Will I be writing my own books? Like, I genuinely don't know. And I think I'm in a space now where I <strong>trying my hand at</strong> everything."</p>
<p>The media program began as part of Washington, D.C.'s Summer Youth Employment Program. Now, it also includes a winter program which is administered by the Department of Employment Services' Office of Youth Programming.</p>
<p><strong>U.S. Congressional connection </strong></p>
<p>The Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program partners with the Congressional Award Foundation.</p>
<p>Its website <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.congressionalaward.org/cafe-radio-podcast/">CongressionalAward.org</a> explains that "students will gain direct access to members of the Board of Directors, who will serve as <strong>mentors</strong> and guide the students through the Congressional Award program."</p>
<p>If students finish the required number of hours within the Congressional Award program, they can earn Congressional Award Certificates and Medals.</p>
<p>From Washington, D.C., I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>interview </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>a meeting at which information is obtained (as by a reporter) from a person</p>
<p><strong>press conference</strong> <em>– n. </em>an interview or announcement given by a public figure to the press by appointment</p>
<p><strong>language barrier </strong><em>– n. </em>a difficulty for people communicating because they speak in different ways or speak different languages</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong><em>– v. </em>to deal with especially at length</p>
<p><strong>gateway </strong><em>– n. </em>a passage into or out of a place or state</p>
<p><strong>role model</strong> <em>– n. </em>a person whose behavior in a particular role is imitated by others</p>
<p><strong>try your hand at (something) – </strong><em>idiom </em>To attempt to do something new; to try something for the first time.</p>
<p><strong>mentor </strong><em>– n. </em>a trusted counselor or guide</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>All Trapped Workers Pulled from Collapsed Tunnel in India  (2023/11/29) | 印度坍塌隧道被困工人获救</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/all-trapped-workers-pulled-from-collapsed-tunnel-in-india.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rescuers pulled out all 41 workers who were trapped for 17 days in a mountain tunnel in northern India on Tuesday.<br/>
周二，救援人员救出了印度北部一条山区隧道中被困17天的41名工人。</p>
<p>A crowd of people around the tunnel cheered and shouted, "Long live mother India." Officials put flowers around the necks of the workers as the crowd celebrated with firecrackers.<br/>
隧道周围人群欢呼着喊道：“祖国万岁。”当人群用鞭炮庆祝时，官员们把鲜花戴到工人的脖子上。</p>
<p>Nitin Gadkari, the minister of road transport and highways, said on X, "I am very happy that all the 41 trapped workers have come out and their lives have been saved."<br/>
印度道路运输和公路部长尼廷·加德卡里在X上说：“我很高兴41名被困工人全部出来了，他们的生命得到了拯救。”</p>
<p>The workers were pulled out through a passageway made from welded pipes that had been pushed through dirt and rocks to reach them.<br/>
工人们被从一条由焊接管道制成的通道中拉了出来，这些管道穿过了泥土和岩石到达他们身边。</p>
<p>One of the rescuers, Devender, told New Delhi Television that "the trapped workers were overjoyed when they spotted us in the tunnel. Some rushed toward me and hugged me."<br/>
其中一名救援人员德维德告诉新德里电视台，“被困工人在隧道里看见我们时欣喜若狂。一些人冲过来拥抱我。”</p>
<p>A landslide on November 12 caused part of a tunnel they were building in Uttarkashi to collapse. And they were stuck about 200 meters from the entrance. The men survived for more than two weeks on food and oxygen that was sent through steel pipes only 15 centimeters wide.<br/>
11月12日的山体滑坡导致他们在乌塔卡什修建的一条隧道部分坍塌。他们被困在离入口大约200米的地方。这些人靠通过只有15厘米宽的钢管输送的食物和氧气存活了两个多星期。</p>
<p>Kirti Panwar is a state government spokesperson. Panwar said a large drilling machine opened up about 47 of the 60 meters needed to reach the workers before it broke down on Friday. Rescuers then worked by hand overnight from Monday into Tuesday using digging tools and drills.<br/>
科尔蒂·潘瓦尔是州政府发言人。潘瓦尔说，周五一台大型钻机打开了工人所需的60米中的47米，然后发生了故障。从周一到周二，救援人员使用挖掘工具和钻机连夜徒手工作。</p>
<p>Many of the workers who were trapped are migrant workers who came from around India for the job. As word spread that the workers were close to freeing the trapped men, family members traveled long distances to gather at the tunnel and waited to see their loved ones.<br/>
许多被困的工人都是来自印度各地的外来工。随着工人们即将救出被困人员的消息传开，他们的家人长途跋涉聚集在隧道旁，等待见到他们的亲人。</p>
<p>Officials said the rescued workers were treated inside the 13-meter-wide tunnel. After a first health check, they were taken to a hospital about 30 kilometers away.<br/>
官方表示，获救的工人在13米宽的隧道内接受了治疗。在第一次健康检查后，他们被送往大约30公里外的一家医院。</p>
<p>"Their condition is first-class and absolutely fine ... just like yours or mine." said Wakil Hassan, a rescue team leader.<br/>
救援队队长瓦基勒·哈桑说：“他们的情况很好，绝对健康……就像你我一样。”</p>
<p>The tunnel is part of the Char Dham highway. It is one of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's largest projects. The plan is to build a network of roads covering almost 900 kilometers to connect four important Hindu religious sites. Some building experts, however, are concerned about the project. They say the work could create more landslides and hurt some small towns in the Himalayas which are already built on top of landslide debris.<br/>
该隧道是查尔丹高速公路的一部分。这是总理纳伦德拉·莫迪最大的项目之一。该计划是建立一个覆盖近900公里的道路网络，以连接四个重要的印度教宗教场所。然而，一些建筑专家对该项目表示担忧。他们说，这项工作可能会造成更多的山体滑坡，并伤害喜马拉雅山脉的一些小镇，这些小镇本身已经建在滑坡废墟上。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Return to Alzheimer's Vaccines  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/researchers-return-to-alzheimer-s-vaccines.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers are renewing efforts to find Alzheimer's disease treatments that remove harmful proteins from the brain. Such vaccines could possibly offer an easier and lower-cost choice for millions of people, several scientists and industry leaders say.</p>
<p>The brain-wasting disease causes thinking and memory problems.</p>
<p>The U.S. government website ClinicalTrials.gov shows that at least seven possible Alzheimer's vaccines are in human testing or have completed such trials. The experimental treatments are designed to use the body's natural defense system<strong> </strong>to destroy Alzheimer's-linked proteins in the brain. The proteins are beta amyloid and tau.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A doctor points out evidence of Alzheimer's disease on PET scans at the Center for Alzheimer Research and Treatment (CART) at Brigham And Women's Hospital in Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., March 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1a2ec41a-e74a-4f60-9b2f-5d5cd4a7f6fc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A doctor points out evidence of Alzheimer's disease on PET scans at the Center for Alzheimer Research and Treatment (CART) at Brigham And Women's Hospital in Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., March 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)</span></div>
<p>The renewed interest in Alzheimer's vaccines follows a promising first attempt more than 20 years ago. That vaccine work halted after six percent of study volunteers developed a life-threatening brain condition called meningoencephalitis.</p>
<p>Researchers then found a safer method using closely targeted <strong>synthetic</strong> <strong>antibodies </strong>in patients. These antibodies avoid extreme <strong>immune system</strong> reaction.</p>
<p>Health care companies Eisai and Biogen launched a new medication called Leqembi and health care company Eli Lilly launched Donanemab. American government drug experts are reviewing the treatments.</p>
<p>The reported success of the drugs has strengthened the theories that amyloid removal is critical to fighting Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Scientists believe they now understand what went wrong with the first vaccine. They are testing shots they hope will cause an immune reaction without causing too much <strong>inflammation. </strong></p>
<p>Dr. Reisa Sperling is an Alzheimer's researcher at Mass General Brigham in Boston. She said she believes vaccines will play an important part as researchers look to prevent Alzheimer's. She said, "I'm very <strong>keen</strong> that that's where we need to go."</p>
<p>Sperling is leading a <strong>trial </strong>in people with Alzheimer's proteins in their brains but showing no signs of related problems. She is considering vaccines for her next study in people who have Alzheimer's proteins in their blood, but not enough to show on imaging of the brain.</p>
<p>Alzheimer's vaccines are still in the early stages and will require large, years-long trials to show they work.</p>
<p>But a vaccine given two or four times a year could offer a lower-cost solution than Leqembi. Leqembi is given twice a month. That could expand available treatment among the estimated 39 million people around the world with Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Dr. Walter Koroshetz is director of the part of U.S. National Institutes of Health that deals with disorders involving the brain. He said of the vaccines, "They could be worldwide, and not that expensive."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Julie Steenhuysen reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. made by combining different substances: not natural</p>
<p><strong>antibodies </strong>– <em>n</em>. a substance produced by the body to fight disease</p>
<p><strong>immune system </strong>– <em>n</em>. the system that protects your body from diseases and infections</p>
<p><strong>inflammation </strong>– <em>n</em>. a condition in which a part of your body becomes red, swollen, and painful</p>
<p><strong>keen </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very excited about and interested in something</p>
<p><strong>trial </strong>– <em>n</em>. a test of the quality, value, or usefulness of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What the White House Looks Like for Christmas  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/what-the-white-house-looks-like-for-christmas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. first lady Jill Biden wants everyone who visits the White House around Christmas to feel like a kid again.</p>
<p>On Monday, Biden held a gathering to show the White House Christmas <strong>decorations</strong>. "Magic, Wonder and Joy" is the <strong>theme</strong> this year. It will be the Bidens' third Christmas holiday in the White House.</p>
<p>"Each room on display is designed to capture the...<strong>delight</strong> and imagination of our childhoods," the first lady said. She also thanked some 300 people who volunteered to decorate the White House.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Holiday decorations adorn the Grand Foyer of the White House for the 2023 theme Magic, Wonder, and Joy, Monday, Nov. 27, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-2980-08dbef7720c1_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Holiday decorations adorn the Grand Foyer of the White House for the 2023 theme "Magic, Wonder, and Joy," Monday, Nov. 27, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)</span></div>
<p>There are oversized holiday candies and other sweets in the hallway. There is a Santa Clause with eight reindeer suspended near the entrance.</p>
<p>Throughout two floors of the public area of the White House are reminders from the poem popularly known as <em>‘Twas the Night Before Christmas</em>. The U.S. Library of Congress helped with copies of the poem from the past 200 years.</p>
<p>The traditional gingerbread White House includes a large sugar cookie copy of the book opened to a page that says, "Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night." The book contains 40 sheets of sugar cookie dough. Another 40 sheets of gingerbread dough are used for the house with 14 kilograms of chocolate and 23 kilograms of royal icing.</p>
<p>The oversized decorations are meant to bring feelings of joy to children at this time of the year, White House aides said. Children of military families were among the first members of the public to see the decorations. And they were also treated to an afternoon performance of the Disney musical performance <em>Frozen</em>.</p>
<p>One of the first Christmas trees visitors will see upon entering the White House is decorated with golden wooden stars. The ornaments include the names of fallen service members.</p>
<p>The official White House Christmas tree is a 5.6-meter-tall tree that stands in its usual place in the Blue Room. The tree is decorated with cheerful pictures from across the country. A toy train runs around its base.</p>
<p>The State Dining Room has been turned into Santa's workshop. There are workbenches for Santa's helpers, the elves. Stools and ladders circle Christmas trees and gifts-in-progress round out the display.</p>
<p>In the library, the moons and the stars are ready to honor the tradition of bedtime stories. The China Room has been turned into a shop of baked goods. The Vermeil Room celebrates music with a display of a toy Marine Band.</p>
<p>In her prepared remarks, the first lady said she knows that magic, wonder and joy can be hard to find, especially as the days grow shorter, the weather turns colder. She said, "Our hearts grow heavy in the face of a <strong>tumultuous</strong> world."</p>
<p>"But it's in these times, when we are searching for hope and healing, that we need those points of light the most, that we need each other the most," she said. "It's in these times that I hope you remember, if even just for a moment or a season, how you saw the world as a child."</p>
<p>Overall, the White House uses 98 Christmas trees, nearly 34,000 ornaments, over 22,000 bells and more than 350 candles for the display. And they are lit with 142,500 lights.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Darlene Superville reported this for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>decoration</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>an object or ornament that is used to make a place more attractive and interesting</p>
<p><strong>theme</strong> <em>–v.</em> the main subject or repeated idea that is shown with objects in a place or with words in a piece of writing</p>
<p><strong>delight </strong><em>–n.</em> a feeling of happiness</p>
<p><strong>tumultuous </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving violence, confusion and disorder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Merriam-Webster Chooses ‘Authentic’ as Word of the Year  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/merriam-webster-chooses-authentic-as-word-of-the-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The <strong>dictionary</strong> company <em>Merriam-Webster</em> chose the word "authentic" as its word of the year for 2023.</p>
<p>Something that is authentic is real or true.</p>
<p>The publisher celebrated its 20th anniversary of choosing a word of the year on Monday. Speaking to <em>The Associated Press,</em> or AP, dictionary editor Peter Sokolowski said the world is in a "crisis of authenticity" in 2023. "What we realize," he said, "is that when we question authenticity, we value it even more."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Merriam-Webster dictionary sits atop their citation files at the dictionary publisher's offices on Dec. 9, 2014, in Springfield, Mass. Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2023 is " authentic.="" file="" photo="" savoia="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/32ea75dd-2180-4c01-8c34-4a9ae45c8b33_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Merriam-Webster dictionary sits atop their citation files at the dictionary publisher's offices on Dec. 9, 2014, in Springfield, Mass. Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2023 is "authentic." (AP Photo/Stephan Savoia, File)</span></div>
<p>Sokolowski said the word is often looked up on <em>Merriam-Webster</em>'s website, but in 2023 it was searched for even more than usual.</p>
<p>He noted that authentic is an important word in a world where artificial intelligence software permits people to create "deepfakes" or false videos that look real.</p>
<p>Often, Sokolowski said, words become "words of the year" because searches <strong>match</strong> world events. However, this year, there was a general increased interest in the word "authentic."</p>
<p>The AP noted that authenticity was a popular subject for discussion in 2023. People such as Taylor Swift and Prince Harry looked for authenticity in their performances and writing. Even businessman Elon Musk discussed authenticity at an event in February when he urged company leaders and politicians to operate their own social media accounts in order to "speak authentically."</p>
<p>Authenticity is important in education, Sokolowski said. He said we are in a time when students can use artificial intelligence tools such as ChatGPT to complete writing assignments to avoid work.</p>
<p>"We don't always trust what we see anymore," he said.</p>
<p>The dictionary includes a number of descriptions to help people understand the word's meaning. It notes something that is authentic is "not false," "true to one's own <strong>personality</strong>," and "something made or done the same way as an <strong>original</strong>."</p>
<p><strong>How the word is picked</strong></p>
<p>Merriam-Webster says it filters out some common search words such as "effect" and "affect" that are always among the top searches. The online word game "Wordle" also increases searches for some words as players check letters and words before they play them.</p>
<p>Some other possible words for 2023 included "X" after Musk changed the name of the social media service formerly known as Twitter. Others include "EGOT" after the actress Viola Davis won a Grammy award and "elemental" after Pixar released a new movie in June.</p>
<p>However, the company settled on authentic one year after choosing "gaslighting." Gaslighting is a word that is used to discuss the act of misleading someone over a long period of time. In a way, it is the opposite of authentic.</p>
<p><strong>Other popular words</strong></p>
<p>Other words that were popular in 2023 but did not win "word of the year" included "rizz," a slang word that has to do with charm or appeal. It is a shortened form of the word charisma.</p>
<p>"Implode" became a popular search in 2023 after a vessel used for undersea exploration was lost in June. Experts say the Titan vessel likely imploded or broke apart because of the high water pressure in the deep sea.</p>
<p>"Coronation" was looked up often in May when Charles III was crowned King of England.</p>
<p>"Kibbutz" is a word that came up in recent weeks after the terror group Hamas attacked the Israeli "communal farms or settlements" near Gaza on October 7.</p>
<p>You can visit Merriam-Webster's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/wordplay/word-of-the-year">website</a> to look at more words that did not quite <strong>make the cut</strong> to become "word of the year."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on The Associated Press story.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dictionary </strong>–n. a book that contains definitions of words in a language</p>
<p><strong>match </strong>–v. to have two things that are related to each other or are linked in some way</p>
<p><strong>personality </strong>–n. the qualities that make a person who they are</p>
<p><strong>original </strong>–adj. something that is produced for the first time and is not a copy of something else</p>
<p><strong>make the cut </strong>–v. (phrasal) to continue to the next level of a competition; to do enough to continue</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Deal Reached to Extend Cease-fire in Israel-Hamas War  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/deal-reached-to-extend-cease-fire-in-israel-hamas-war.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Negotiators have reached a deal to extend a cease-fire between Israeli and Hamas forces in Gaza.</p>
<p>A Qatari official <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/majedalansari/status/1729177252473274539">announced</a> Monday on the social media service X the agreement would continue an existing truce for another two days. Qatar and Egypt have led the negotiations surrounding the ongoing conflict.</p>
<p>The new deal came on the final day of a four-day ceasefire. Negotiators said they were also preparing for new exchanges of hostages and prisoners.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Palestinian walks in Gaza City on Monday, Nov. 27, 2023. on the fourth day of the temporary ceasefire between Hamas and Israel. (AP Photo/Mohammed Hajjar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-72e0-08dbef850349_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Palestinian walks in Gaza City on Monday, Nov. 27, 2023. on the fourth day of the temporary ceasefire between Hamas and Israel. (AP Photo/Mohammed Hajjar)</span></div>
<p>Israel had no immediate comment on the new truce. But Israeli officials had said the country would be open to extending the cease-fire by one day for every 10 additional hostages released. Hamas confirmed it had agreed to a two-day cease-fire extension.</p>
<p>Hamas freed 17 more hostages on Sunday – 14 Israelis and three Thais – in a third exchange under the earlier four-day truce. Israel released 39 Palestinian prisoners in the latest exchange.</p>
<p>About 240 hostages were captured by Hamas in its October 7 attack in southern Israel that started the war. So far, 62 hostages have been released. One was freed by Israeli forces and two were found dead inside Gaza. At least 117 Palestinians were freed under the latest truce.</p>
<p>An Israeli government spokesperson said the total number of hostages still held in Gaza as of Monday was 184. This included 14 foreigners and 80 Israelis with <strong>dual</strong> nationality.</p>
<p>Last week's cease-fire agreement – which was set to end Monday night – brought the first halt in fighting between Israel and Hamas in Gaza.</p>
<p>The Hamas-controlled Health Ministry in Gaza says more than 13,300 Palestinians have been killed since the start of the war, many of them women and children. The ministry does not differentiate between civilians and military-force deaths.</p>
<p>Israeli officials have said about 1,200 people have been killed in Israel, mostly during the first attacks by Hamas. At least 77 soldiers have been killed in Israel's ground offensive in Gaza.</p>
<p>An Egyptian official told Reuters news agency the new truce would permit the release of about 20 Israeli hostages in exchange for 60 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>
<p>The European Union's foreign policy chief, Josep Borrell, told reporters he hopes a truce extension will permit the international community to work on a lasting political solution.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said the country planned to push ahead with the war at the end of the cease-fires.</p>
<p>Wide areas of Hamas-ruled Gaza have been destroyed by Israeli air strikes and bombings. The war also led to a humanitarian crisis because of shortages of food, fuel, water and medicine.</p>
<p>The latest truce did lead to some increased shipments of fuel and supplies into Gaza. But aid groups say much more is needed to help the immediate needs of the 2.3 million Palestinians there.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dual </strong><em>– adj. </em>having two parts</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Laser Communication Test Gets Data from 16 Million Kilometers Away  (2023/11/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/nasa-laser-communication-test-gets-data-from-16-million-kilometers-away.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>NASA has successfully tested a laser-based communication method that sent data over 16 million kilometers. The American space agency hopes the system will greatly improve data links between Earth and spacecraft exploring deep space.</p>
<p>The method, called Deep Space Optical Communications (DSOC), is being tested aboard NASA's Psyche spacecraft. The agency <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-to-launch-spacecraft-to-observe-metal-rich-asteroid/7298628.html">launched</a> Psyche last month to observe a mostly metal <strong>asteroid.</strong></p>
<p>DSOC uses lasers to send large amounts of data very long distances. Traditionally, NASA has depended on radio frequency communications to send data to, and collect data from, deep space. But now the agency seeks to improve its systems to support new technologies and future trips to the moon and beyond.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="NASA's Psyche spacecraft is shown in a clean room at the Astrotech Space Operations facility near the agency's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Dec. 8, 2022. (NASA/Ben Smegelsky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8988-08dbeba6d103_cx5_cy2_cw94_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">NASA's Psyche spacecraft is shown in a clean room at the Astrotech Space Operations facility near the agency's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Dec. 8, 2022. (NASA/Ben Smegelsky)</span></div>
<p>Laser communications, also known as optical communications, enable the fast <strong>transmission</strong> of data over long distances. In an explanation of lasers, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/technology/laser-communications-empowering-more-data-than-ever-before/">explained</a> the technology will permit "up to 100 times more data to be transmitted back to Earth than current radio frequency systems."</p>
<p>NASA estimates it would take about nine weeks to transmit a complete map of Mars back to Earth with current radio frequency systems. But with a laser-based method, the time would be cut to nine days. Also, laser communications equipment takes up less space in spacecraft and uses less energy.</p>
<p>Scientists from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory in California recently announced a successful test of the DSOC method. The team said a device<strong> </strong>on the Psyche spacecraft was able to successfully send and receive data messages with a telescope in Southern California. NASA said the laser system works with signals that exist at near-infrared wavelengths.</p>
<p>The data transmitted by laser takes the form of bits – the smallest pieces of data a computer can process. These bits are <strong>embedded</strong> inside the laser's photons.</p>
<p>The NASA team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/psyche-mission/nasas-deep-space-optical-comm-demo-sends-receives-first-data/">described</a> the successful data signal transmissions as "first light." The experiment represented "the farthest-ever demonstration of optical communications," at about 16 million kilometers.</p><p>Trudy Kortes is the director of Technology Demonstrations for the Space Technology Mission Directorate at NASA Headquarters in Washington. She said in a statement she sees the first light event as one “of many critical DSOC <strong>milestones</strong>” to look forward to in the coming months. The communication success is another step forward, she said, “in support of humanity’s next ... goal: sending humans to Mars.”</p>
<p>Optical communication has already been demonstrated in low Earth orbit and on the moon. But the research team working on the DSOC project said it was the first time this method has been successfully tested in deep space.</p>
<p>Abi Biswas is a project technologist on the DSOC team. He called the latest laser test “a tremendous <strong>achievement</strong>.” The team was, Biswas said, “able to send some data, meaning we were able to exchange ‘bits of light’ from and to deep space.”</p>
<p>The team said laser communication over long distances can be difficult as it requires complete exactness in following signals and linking up transmitters and receivers over millions of kilometers.</p>
<p>Project leaders say when Psyche is at its farthest from our planet, DSOC’s near-infrared photons will take about 20 minutes to travel back to Earth. During the successful experiment on November 14, DSOC took about 50 seconds to send the data from Psyche to Earth.</p>
<p>Jason Mitchell is a director in NASA’s Space Communications and Navigation program. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/psyche-mission/nasas-deep-space-optical-comm-demo-sends-receives-first-data/">called</a> optical communication “a <strong>boon</strong> for scientists and researchers who always want more from their space missions.” Mitchell said better data transmission methods will improve human exploration of deep space” and lead to many more data discoveries in the future.</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story, based on reports from NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>transmit </strong><em>– v. to send</em></p>
<p><strong>embed </strong><em>– v. </em>to fix something firmly into a substance</p>
<p><strong>milestone</strong><em> – n. </em>an important event in history or the development of something or someone<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>achievement </strong><em>– n. </em>something good that you achieve: to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
<p><strong>boon</strong><em> – n. </em>something helpful that improves your life</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Toymakers Aim More Products at Older People  (2023/11/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/toymakers-aim-more-products-at-older-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Toymakers are developing new games – and changing old ones – to target a different group: people over 65 years old.</p>
<p>Toy producers suggest the products could help older people increase their brain skills as well as reduce loneliness. However, some experts have raised doubts about their claims.</p>
<p>Toymaker Hasbro signed a deal with Ageless Innovation — which designs toys with older people in mind — to come out with new versions of games such as Scrabble, Trivial Pursuit and Life. The products offer larger letters that are easier to see and bigger game pieces.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Scrabble game with larger tiles is displayed at the 2023 Toy Fair, in New York's Javits Center, Monday, Oct. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2073d852-1559-4393-86a5-a7f24222e383_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Scrabble game with larger tiles is displayed at the 2023 Toy Fair, in New York's Javits Center, Monday, Oct. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>The new versions of Life and Trivial Pursuit also have developed their content so that younger and older people alike can play. For example, the answer to a question in Trivial Pursuit about exercise can be Jack LaLanne or Zumba, depending on the player's age.</p>
<p>Jack LaLanne was a famous health and exercise person for a large part of the 20th century. Zumba has become a more popular exercise in recent times.</p>
<p>Educational Insights, which produces educational toys for young children, is including images of older people in its marketing efforts. The move came after the company noticed last year that its toys like Kanoodle and BrainBolt were popular with older customers in online reviews. Next year, Educational Insights will release a new BrainBolt Boost that has bigger buttons and is more simplified.</p>
<p><strong>Changes in behavior </strong></p>
<p>The new products come as the pandemic has changed toy-buying behaviors in the United States. Long before the pandemic, many adults purchased Legos or collectible items to connect with their inner child.</p>
<p>But the pandemic not only increased the <strong>trend</strong>, it also increased feelings of loneliness among adults when they were in lockdown. Many toy companies found adults using animals and robotic pets as companions.</p>
<p>Market research company Circana reports that toy sales are increasingly targeted toward adult buyers. About 5 percent of the total U.S. toy sales are for males ages 35 and over, up 13 percent since last year. About 4 percent of total U.S. toy sales are for females ages 35 and over, up 9 percent since last year.</p>
<p>While Circana does not examine sales data for the over -65 group, it estimated grandparents who bought a toy for their grandchild have big spending power. These grandparents made up 19 percent, or $7.8 billion, of total toy sales in the 12 months that ended in September. And grandparents spent on average 7 percent more per toy than the total market during the fourth quarter of 2022, the highest amount spent across all buyer groups.</p>
<p><strong>Can new games help? </strong></p>
<p>Ben Swartz, 92, lives with his 85-year-old wife in a retirement community in Des Moines, Iowa. Swartz ran 14 toy stores in the 1970s. He has noticed some of the new offerings from the toy industry, and he approves of the moves.</p>
<p>Swartz plays games five days a week, including bridge and poker with his friends. He said the games help his mind, otherwise, he said, he would worry that his "mind would start to go a little bit <strong>stale</strong>."</p>
<p>Still, while some scientists welcome toymakers paying attention to older buyers, they also warn of these products' <strong>limitations</strong>.</p>
<p>Neil Charness and Walter Boot, both of Florida State University, worked together to test the idea that brain games like crossword puzzles help <strong>preserve </strong>mental abilities such as reasoning or thinking, also known as cognitive function.</p>
<p>They found that people get better in the specific skills of the game if they play over and over again. But the games do not translate to the cognitive skills needed for everyday living activities, such as job performance or maintaining independent living, they said.</p>
<p>The researchers also said that there is limited evidence to date that playing games can greatly reduce loneliness.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Anne D'Innocenzio reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>trend </strong><em>– n.</em> a general direction of change</p>
<p><strong>stale</strong> <em>– adj.</em> not as strong, effective, or energetic as before</p>
<p><strong>limitation</strong> <em>– n.</em> something that controls how much of something is possible or allowed</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong><em>– v.</em> to keep (something) in its original state or in good condition</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
