<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Minnesota Named Second-most Educated US State  (2024/1/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/minnesota-named-second-most-educated-us-state.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Minnesota has the second-highest education level in the U.S. as measured by the <strong>scholarship</strong> research website Scholaroo.com.</p>
<p>A representative from Scholaroo told VOA Learning English that the state has a high percentage of <strong>residents</strong> with <strong>advanced degrees</strong>. It is ranked above Connecticut and just behind Massachusetts overall.</p>
<p>The state is number one in the percentage of residents with <strong>doctoral</strong> degrees, Schoolaroo says. The top study programs there are in education, medicine and law.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Akhil Kollengode, a student at the University of Minnesota-Rochester. (Courtesy photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b37b-08dc12fa5791_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Akhil Kollengode, a student at the University of Minnesota-Rochester. (Courtesy photo)</span></div>
<p>VOA Learning English talked with students and college supporters to learn why they think Minnesota is a good place for higher education.</p>
<p><strong>Next gen med</strong></p>
<p>Akhil Kollengode is an undergraduate student at the University of Minnesota-Rochester. He is in a new program that offers an undergraduate degree in two and a half years compared to the traditional four.</p>
<p>His study program is in health sciences. It is called NXT GEN MED, which deals with medical administration. He hopes to move from studying to working at the nearby Mayo Clinic, a well-known hospital based in Rochester.</p>
<p>"It is a big reason why I chose to stay in Minnesota," he said.</p>
<p>Kollengode is in his second year of college. He said he and his classmates saw how the COVID-19 pandemic took away some of the in-person college experience from their older friends. He said, "We felt a little more motivation because we understood how much it could be <strong>taken for granted."</strong></p>
<p>He also saw the example of his parents working in the medical field and wanted to follow their path.</p>
<p>Kollengode said many young people in Minnesota think they can only reach their goals by moving away.</p>
<p>"These younger students are always told ‘oh everything is so good when you leave home and when you can finally live on your own. But you can do all of those things when you're still in your hometown. Saving money, getting the same education and sometimes maybe better education if you're in your hometown."</p>
<p><strong>College in three</strong></p>
<p>Lori Carrell is the chancellor, a top official, at the University of Minnesota-Rochester. She said a number of universities in the U.S. are part of a new program testing "college in three." It aims to get students a degree in three, not four years.</p>
<p>She said many students in the U.S. are questioning the value of college because of the cost. They also are concerned about finding a good job when they finish.</p>
<p>Schools like hers are working to help students complete their degrees with a good job and not a lot of debt. Students stay in school all year and work at the Mayo Clinic, which is close by, Carrell explained.</p>
<p>She said, "We need people to come to Minnesota:"</p>
<p>"There are a lot of needs for people with advanced degrees in Minnesota, making this three-year undergrad option even more attractive."</p>
<p>Once people finish their undergraduate degree, she said, they can move on to advanced degrees and find a good job in Minnesota.</p>
<p><strong>Out of State</strong></p>
<p>Students from other states like Minnesota, too.</p>
<p>Siya Sakhardande came from Texas to study psychology at the University of Minnesota's main campus, in Minneapolis and St. Paul, known as the "twin cities."</p>
<p>She said she considered schools in California, Michigan and the rest of the U.S. But the combination of a strong educational program and a good financial aid offer brought her to Minnesota.</p>
<p>She said she and her classmates consider undergraduate degrees just the start.</p>
<p>"I plan to go to law school. I have friends who want to go to medical school at the university. I have friends who want to get their master's and their graduate degrees at the university. The university definitely encourages that and like uses whatever resources they can to like, help us plan a future and a career beyond just going to school there."</p>
<p>But she also said the school wants students who come from families that might not be considering college.</p>
<p>Sakhardande noted the university's scholarship for Native American students, called the Native American Promise Tuition Program. It started last year. The university says it pays for 100 percent of school fees for students from recognized Native American tribes in Minnesota.</p>
<p>In addition, Sakhardande helped with a recent campaign by a state lawmaker to push the state to pay low-income students' costs for attending a Minnesota public college. She said the North Star Promise scholarship program will make sure all students in Minnesota think about college.</p>
<p><strong>Community college ‘saved me'</strong></p>
<p>The state senator who worked on the project was Omar Fateh, whose <strong>district</strong> is in Minneapolis. He said he is not surprised Minnesota ranks high in education.</p>
<p>"Minnesotans have long seen the value of higher education as a path to economic <strong>mobility</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Fateh said it is important to make higher education possible for all students in the state. He said the scholarship he is supporting can be used at both two-year and four-year colleges.</p>
<p>Fateh's parents were immigrants from Somalia. His father came to the U.S. to study at Montana State University. He grew up in Washington, D.C., and Northern Virginia. But he was not a good student in high school. He said he was saved by a school program.</p>
<p>"... a program called the Pathways Program, which recruited students that were <strong>deemed</strong> to be ‘at risk youth' into Northern Virginia Community College. That's why I'm a big supporter of community colleges because I believe it really it really helped me and saved me."</p>
<p>Carrell said Minnesota clearly values higher education: "There's a great appreciation for advanced degrees and higher education in the state of Minnesota." She added that education leaders there feel a responsibility to give students a good ROI, or return on investment, for their time in school.</p>
<p>Sakhardande thinks students from inside and outside of the U.S. should consider Minnesota schools.</p>
<p>"It's just a little bit less recognized than states like California and the Ivy Leagues. But I think once you get to Minnesota, you understand that there are great things to do here."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scholarship </strong><em>–n.</em> an amount of money given to a student to reduce the cost of their education to them</p>
<p><strong>resident </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who lives in a particular place</p>
<p><strong>advanced degree </strong><em>–n.</em> a degree higher than a bachelor's degree</p>
<p><strong>doctoral </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to the highest degree given by a university</p>
<p><strong>take for granted </strong><em>–v.</em><em> </em>to fail to recognize the value of something</p>
<p><strong>deem </strong><em>–v.</em> to think of something in a certain way</p>
<p><strong>district </strong><em>–n. </em>an area established by a government for a certain purpose</p>
<p><strong>mobility </strong><em>–n.</em> the quality of being able to move around or go to a different level</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Walk Before You Can Run  (2024/1/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/walk-before-you-can-run.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, notes on usage, and sometimes we use them in short conversations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A child runs as beach-goers enjoy New Year's Day in the rain, on the beach in Durban, South Africa January 1, 2024. (REUTERS/Rogan Ward)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ca994bd7-60ae-4800-ad82-3fcf58e8ec1c_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A child runs as beach-goers enjoy New Year's Day in the rain, on the beach in Durban, South Africa January 1, 2024. (REUTERS/Rogan Ward)</span></div>
<p>Today we talk about the process of learning to do something.</p>
<p>For example, if you want to play a musical instrument, you need to learn how. You must take small steps. You learn how to hold or sit at the instrument. You learn how to read notes and how to play basic chords. Then you progress to short, easy songs.</p>
<p>In other words, you need to take baby steps.</p>
<p>Babies can look funny when they are learning to walk. Their steps are unsure; their knees do not quite bend fully. They do not walk straight and often fall down. The more they walk, the <strong>steadier</strong> they get on their feet. Soon their unsteady baby steps lead to a smoother, often speedy, <strong>gait</strong>.</p>
<p>We often use the term to describe how to reach a complex goal. Small baby steps can lead to the bigger goal.</p>
<p>We will often use the term to suggest that someone slow down and be patient.</p>
<p>A similar English expression goes, "You have to walk before you can run."</p>
<p>Let's listen as two friends use these idioms.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, how are your piano lessons going?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Slowly. I want to play a real song. But my teacher has me working on these same set of chords over and over again! They are difficult and <strong>boring</strong> at the same time.</em></p>
<p><em>A: I've been playing piano for years, and <strong>chords</strong> are important. They are the foundations of music. You need to know how to walk before you can run.</em></p>
<p><em>B: I know, I know! But I also MUST be able to play a song by next month.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Why are you in such a hurry? Learning music requires patience. Take baby steps!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Please no more advice! I told a friend I could play the piano. And now she wants me to play at her children's birthday party.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Oh, in that case. I have other advice for you.</em></p>
<p><em>B: What's that?</em></p>
<p><em>A: You reap what your sow.</em></p>
<p><em>B: Thanks a lot. ... Hey what are you doing next month...?</em></p>
<p>Learning a language is a lifelong process. To keep yourself from burning out, take baby steps. Learn a little every day, and soon your English will be <strong>fabulous</strong>!</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>!</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>basic </strong>- <em>adj. </em>simple, not difficult</p>
<p><strong>chord </strong>- <em>n. </em>a group of three or more musical notes that are played or sung at the same time</p>
<p><strong>steady </strong>- <em>adj. </em>balanced and stable</p>
<p><strong>gait </strong>- <em>n. </em>another word for the way a person or animal walks</p>
<p><strong>boring </strong>- <em>adj. </em>not fun, exciting or interesting</p>
<p><strong>fabulous </strong>- <em>adj. </em>impressive or exciting</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Joe Biden: Oldest  (2024/1/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/joe-biden-oldest.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 January 2024</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">VOA Learning English presents <em>America's Presidents</em>.</p>
<p class="MsoBodyText">Today we are talking about Joe Biden. He took office in 2021, becoming America's 46th President. A member of the Democratic Party, Biden had been in national politics for a long time before he got to the White House.</p>
<p>He served 36 years in the United States Senate representing Delaware. After that, he held two terms as the nation's vice president, serving under President Barack Obama.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Joe Biden" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7671-08dc11e7f2c7_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Joe Biden</span></div>
<p>Because Biden's presidency is so recent, this report will not discuss his time in office. Instead, it will discuss his earlier life.</p>
<p>Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr. was born in 1942 in Scranton, Pennsylvania. His family moved to Delaware when he was 10 years old.</p>
<p>The Bidens were Roman Catholics of Irish ancestry. Joe was educated in private Roman Catholic schools as a youth. Later, he attended the University of Delaware. He received a degree in political science and history in 1965.</p>
<p>He also fell in love at Delaware with fellow student Neilia Hunter. The two married the following year. Over the next few years, the couple had three children. Joe Biden also received his law degree from Syracuse University College of Law in New York.</p>
<p>In 1972, at age 29, Joe Biden was elected to the U.S. Senate, representing Delaware. A few weeks later, Biden faced tragedy. Neilia and their children were in a car accident. She and daughter Naomi were killed in the crash. Sons Beau and Hunter were injured.</p>
<p>Biden was suddenly a single father. He briefly considered leaving his Senate seat. But he decided to stay in office. Unlike most lawmakers, however, he did not move to Washington. He did not want to uproot his little boys. Instead, he traveled daily to and from Washington, D.C. on the train so he could be home with his sons every night. The senator continued this custom for 36 years.</p>
<p>Also during that time, Biden met Jill Jacobs, an English teacher. They fell in love and married in 1977. Daughter Ashley was born in 1981.</p>
<p>Biden was a candidate for president in 1987 and 2007. After Barack Obama was nominated as the Democratic Party's 2008 presidential candidate, he asked Biden to join the campaign as his running mate. They won election and Biden began serving as vice president. Four years later, Obama and Biden were re-elected for a second term.</p>
<p>Most political experts say Biden was an especially powerful vice president. He and Obama worked closely together and Biden was influential in policy decisions. The president sought Biden's help in establishing a national economic <strong>stimulus</strong> program, for example. Biden also traveled the world as vice president and led diplomatic <strong>missions</strong> in troubled <strong>regions.</strong> He is widely considered one of the most successful vice presidents in American history.</p>
<p>During his second term as vice president, Joe Biden faced another family tragedy. His adult son Beau died of brain cancer in 2015.</p>
<p>Joe Biden had considered running for president in 2016. But after Beau died, the Vice President decided against it. The death of his son was too recent and the grief was too great to spend time on a campaign.</p>
<p>Biden announced his candidacy for president in April of 2019. At 77, he was among the oldest presidential candidates ever. His age became an issue of debate during the campaign. But his main competitor, President Donald Trump, was just three years younger.</p>
<p>Joe Biden called the presidential race "a battle for the soul of America." He won that battle when Americans went to voting stations on November 3, 2020.</p>
<p>U.S. election officials announced later that week that Joe Biden and his vice presidential running mate, Kamala Harris, had defeated President Donald Trump and Vice President Mike Pence.</p>
<p>Biden received 81 million votes in all --- more than any other American presidential candidate in history. Trump won about 74 million. However, Trump rejected the official vote count as incorrect and dishonest, calling the election "stolen." Many of Trump's supporters took the same position, causing severe division in the country.</p>
<p>On January 20,<sup> </sup>2021, Joe Biden was sworn in as President of the United States. In a speech that followed, he called on the American people to seek unity with one another. He described unity as one of the most "<strong>elusive</strong>" qualities in a democracy.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stimulus </strong>- <em>n. </em>something that incites or stirs to action</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong>- <em>n. </em>a task, job or goal</p>
<p><strong>region </strong>- <em>n. </em>a broad geographic area</p>
<p><strong>elusive </strong>- <em>adj</em>. hard to find or capture</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hawaiian Salt Makers Aim to Protect Tradition  (2024/1/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/hawaiian-salt-makers-aim-to-protect-tradition.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Last summer on the Hawaiian Island of Kauai, Tina Taniguchi was working close to the ground. Her coconut leaf hat covered most of her thick brown hair. Wet soil had gotten on her clothes and her smiling face.</p>
<p>Taniguchi smiles a lot while working on the Hanapepe salt <strong>patch</strong> on the west side of Kauai. It is a piece of land about half a hectare in size with pools of salty water. The salt becomes <strong>crystals</strong> as the water dries.</p>
<p>"It's hard work, but for me it's also play," Taniguchi said with a laugh.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pi'ilani Taniguchi Butler carries a bucket of wet clay to her family's salt beds on Wednesday, July 12, 2023, in Hanapepe, Hawaii. The salt beds or loi are smoothed out using river rocks. The beds are then lined with this rich black clay. (AP Photo/Jessie Wardarski)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6bc0-08dc12a83208_cx17_cy20_cw82_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pi'ilani Taniguchi Butler carries a bucket of wet clay to her family's salt beds on Wednesday, July 12, 2023, in Hanapepe, Hawaii. The salt beds or "loi" are smoothed out using river rocks. The beds are then lined with this rich black clay. (AP Photo/Jessie Wardarski)</span></div>
<p><strong>Spiritual tradition</strong></p>
<p>Taniguchi's family is one of 22 families who make "paakai," the Hawaiian word for salt, following a cultural and spiritual tradition. Hanapepe is one of the last remaining salt patches in Hawaii. Its holy salt can be traded or given away but must never be sold. Hawaiians use it in cooking, healing, <strong>rituals</strong> and as protection.</p>
<p>Taniguchi drives a car for about an hour to get to the salt patch. For her, it is like religion and play at the same time. It is the time when she makes a spiritual connection to the land.</p>
<p>"This would be a religious practice of mine for sure," Taniguchi said. "My dad raised us saying that these mountains are his church, and the ocean is where you get <strong>cleansed</strong>."</p>
<p>Malia Nobrega-Olivera is another salt maker. She is also an educator and activist who leads efforts to preserve this old tradition. Her grandfather helped form the group of salt-making families called Hui Hana Paakai. The organization's goal, she said, is to communicate with the landowner, the state of Hawaii, whenever problems arise. Nobrega-Olivera said the salt patch is part of the lands taken away from Native Hawaiians after the U.S.-supported overthrow of Hawaii's monarchy in 1893.</p>
<p><strong>Native claims to the land</strong></p>
<p>"Regardless of what a piece of paper might say, we are <strong>stewards</strong> of the area," she said.</p>
<p>Over the past 10 years there have been several threats to this field. They include development, pollution from a neighboring airfield, damage to the sand from vehicle traffic and waste left by visitors to the nearby beach. In addition, rising sea levels and weather might stop the practice.</p>
<p>Nobrega-Olivera believes Western science and native knowledge can combine to combat the effects of climate change and save the salt patch. The steps she takes include building up the wells' edges, so water won't cover the salt beds. Another step is to prevent damage to the beach from vehicle traffic.</p>
<p>"Some ask us why we can't move this practice to a different location," she said. "That's impossible because our cultural practice is particular to this land. There are elements here that make this place special for making this type of salt. You cannot find that anywhere else."</p>
<p><strong>The process of making salt</strong></p>
<p>The process of turning sea water into salt can be slow. The season begins once the rain stops, and water starts to disappear from the salt beds. Ocean water travels underground and enters the wells. Each family has their own well. As water enters the well, so do tiny, red brine shrimp. These small ocean animals give Hanapepe salt its unusual, sweet taste, said Nobrega-Olivera.</p>
<p>The families first clean the salt beds and line them with black <strong>clay</strong>. Then they move water from the wells into the beds. There, salt crystals form. The top level, or layer, is the whitest. It is used for table salt. The middle layer is pinkish and is used in cooking, while the bottom layer, which is a deep red color, is used in blessings and rituals.</p>
<p>Fires on the island of Maui in August claimed 100 lives. After the fires, salt makers began sending their salt to survivors, so they can "make their food delicious and bring some of that joy into their lives," Nobrega-Olivera said.</p>
<p><strong>Keeping traditions alive</strong></p>
<p>Interest in Hawaiian culture and language has recently grown on the islands, Nobrega-Olivera said. She now thinks about how to teach her knowledge to younger generations.</p>
<p>One way she honors the Hanapepe salt patch is by writing Hawaiian songs and <strong>chants</strong>. She recently taught some school children one of those chants using the words <em>aloha aina</em>, which means "love of the land."</p>
<p>"<em>Aloha aina</em> captures our <strong>philosophy</strong>, the reason we do this," Nobrega-Olivera said. "You take care of the land, and the land takes care of you."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p>And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Deepa Bharath reported on this story for the Associated Press. Jill Robbins adapted it for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>patch</strong> – <em>n.</em> a small area of land where a particular plant or crop grows or is produced</p>
<p><strong>crystal</strong> – <em>n. </em>a small piece of a substance that has formed naturally into a regular symmetrical shape.</p>
<p><strong>ritual</strong> - <em>n.</em> a religious service or other ceremony which involves a series of actions performed in a fixed order</p>
<p><strong>cleanse</strong> – <em>v.</em> to make clean, pure</p>
<p><strong>steward</strong> – <em>n. </em>someone who has the responsibility for looking after property</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong>– <em>v.</em> to save or protect something from damage or decay</p>
<p><strong>clay</strong> – <em>n.</em> a kind of earth that is soft when it is wet and hard when it is dry</p>
<p><strong>blessing</strong> – <em>n.</em> a prayer asking God to look kindly upon the people who are present or the event that is taking place</p>
<p><strong>chant </strong>–n. to sing a word or phrase repeatedly usually in connection with prayers or a religious ceremony</p>
<p><strong>philosophy </strong>–n. a system of ideas about truth and meaning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Miners Find Mammoth Remains Buried in North Dakota  (2024/1/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/miners-find-mammoth-remains-buried-in-north-dakota.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The first person who saw it was working overnight. The worker, a <strong>shovel</strong> operator, saw something white as he placed a large amount of dirt into the back of a truck.</p>
<p>The driver of the truck put the dirt in the road. Another worker operating a <strong>bulldozer</strong> was ready to flatten it. But the worker stopped for a closer look when he, too, saw a piece of white.</p>
<p>Only then did the mining workers realize they had found something special: a 2-meter-long mammoth <strong>tusk</strong> that had been buried for thousands of years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image provided by Coleman Fredricks, coal miners unearthed a mammoth tusk in May 2023 at the Freedom Mine near Beulah, N.D. (Coleman Fredricks via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/00326b24-0b33-407d-91e9-df92694589a1_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image provided by Coleman Fredricks, coal miners unearthed a mammoth tusk in May 2023 at the Freedom Mine near Beulah, N.D. (Coleman Fredricks via AP)</span></div>
<p>A mammoth is a kind of animal that lived in ancient times and had very long tusks. The animal went extinct, or disappeared, about 10,000 years ago in what is now the American state of North Dakota.</p>
<p>The miners unearthed the tusk at the Freedom Mine near Beulah, North Dakota. The mine produces up to 14.5 metric tons of coal each year.</p>
<p>"We were very <strong>fortunate</strong>, lucky to find what we found," said David Straley. He is an executive of North American Coal, which owns the mine.</p>
<p>After finding the tusk, the workers stopped digging in the area and called in experts. The experts estimated the tusk to be anywhere from 10,000 to 100,000 years old.</p>
<p>Jeff Person is a paleontologist with the North Dakota Geologic Survey. A paleontologist is an expert on ancient remains. Person was one of the experts that examined the tusk. He said it was "<strong>miraculous</strong>" that the tusk had not been more damaged, considering the large equipment that miners use at the site.</p>
<p>Another dig at the discovery site found more bones. Experts found more than 20 bones. It is likely the most complete mammoth found in North Dakota, where it is more common to find one mammoth bone, tooth or piece of a tusk.</p>
<p>Person said it is not a lot of bones compared to how many make up the animal's skeleton. But he said, "...it's a lot more than we've ever found of one animal together."</p>
<p>Mammoths once were found across parts of Africa, Asia, Europe, and North America. Paul Ullmann, a University of North Dakota paleontologist, said mammoth remains have been found throughout the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>The discovery at the mine is somewhat rare in North Dakota and in the area. Many remains of the animals alive during the last Ice Age were destroyed by movements of ice sheets, Ullmann said.</p>
<p>Other areas have produced more mammoth remains, such as in Texas and South Dakota. People have even found frozen mammoth bodies in Canada and Russia, Ullmann added.</p>
<p>The tusk weighs more than 22.6 kilograms and can break easily. Experts covered the tusk in plastic in order to control how fast the tusk loses water. If it loses water too quickly, the bone could break apart, Person said.</p>
<p>The experts covered the other bones in plastic and stored them. The bones will remain in plastic for at least several months until the scientists can get the water out safely. The paleontologists will identify what kind of mammoth the tusk came from later, Person said.</p>
<p>The mining company plans to donate the bones to the state for educational purposes.</p>
<p>"Our goal is to give it to the <strong>kids</strong>," Straley said.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jack Dura reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>shovel </strong>– <em>n</em>. a tool with a long handle that is used for lifting and throwing dirt, sand, or snow</p>
<p><strong>bulldozer </strong>– <em>n</em>. a powerful and heavy vehicle that has a large curved piece of metal at its front and that is used for moving dirt and rocks and pushing over trees and other structures</p>
<p><strong>tusk </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very long, large tooth that sticks out of the mouth of an animal (such as an elephant, walrus, or boar)</p>
<p><strong>fortunate </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having good luck</p>
<p><strong>miraculous </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very wonderful or amazing like a miracle</p>
<p><strong>kid </strong>– <em>n</em>. a young person</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Adverbs, Gerunds, Participles  (2024/1/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/adverbs-gerunds-participles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from an English learner named Sidra.</p>
<p>Sidra asks:</p>
<p>I want to know the difference between adverb[s] of frequency and degree and...between participle[s] and gerunds.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Adverbs, Gerunds, Participles" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5f80-08dc1129f966_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Adverbs, Gerunds, Participles</span></div>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Sidra. First, let's answer your question about adverbs.</p>
<p><strong>Adverbs</strong></p>
<p>Different adverbs show different kinds of information.</p>
<p>Adverbs of time tell us four things: when, how long, how often, and relationship in time.</p>
<p>When something takes place. For example:</p>
<p><em>I finished the project <u>yesterday</u></em>.</p>
<p>How long something lasts, or duration.</p>
<p><em>The class seemed to last <u>forever</u>.</em></p>
<p>Frequency, or how often something happens.</p>
<p><em><u>Sometimes</u> I skip breakfast.</em></p>
<p>And, the relationship of two things in time.</p>
<p><em>He <u>still</u> has my laptop.</em></p>
<p>Adverbs of degree answer the questions "How much/many?" or "To what <strong>extent</strong>?" For example,</p>
<p><em>She's staying with us for <strong><u>a bit</u></strong>.</em></p>
<p><em>We're <u>fairly</u> certain it's a good idea.</em></p>
<p>Degree adverbs can also demonstrate intensity. Some show high intensity. These kinds of adverbs are known as amplifiers.</p>
<p><em>The food was <u>completely</u> gone.</em></p>
<p>Others show low intensity, called diminishers.</p>
<p><em>I'm <u>almost</u> finished with the book.</em></p>
<p>So, adverbs of frequency tell how often, and adverbs of degree tell how much or to what extent.</p>
<p>Now for the second question – the difference between participles and gerunds.</p>
<p><strong>Participles and gerunds</strong></p>
<p>We know that verbs can end in <em>–ing</em>. Participles and gerunds are also words that end in <em>–ing</em>. Let's look at the differences.</p>
<p>When a verb ends in <em>–ing</em>, it is the progressive or continuous aspect. That means the event is incomplete or temporary.</p>
<p><em>We are <u>listening</u> to the podcast.</em></p>
<p><em>She was <u>studying</u> at the library</em>.</p>
<p>Gerunds also have an <em>–ing</em> ending, but they do not act like verbs. A gerund is a noun. This means it can be the subject or object of a sentence. For example:</p>
<p><em><u>Listening</u> to music is my favorite hobby.</em></p>
<p><em>She loves <u>running</u>.</em></p>
<p>Participles have an <em>–ing</em> ending, too. They also do not act as verbs. A participle is an adjective. We usually use a participle when we are describing an experience that makes us feel certain emotions. For example:</p>
<p><em>Her answer was <u>surprising</u>.</em></p>
<p>In this sentence, the participle "surprising" describes how you feel about "her answer."</p>
<p>Some other words that are often used as participles are <em>amazing</em>, <em>boring</em>, <em>calming</em>, <em>exciting</em>, and <em>worrying</em>.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Sidra.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>a bit</strong>—<em>adv</em>. a little, a small amount</p>
<p><strong>extent</strong>–<em>n</em>. the size or amount of something; how much it covers</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>WHO: More COVID Deaths after Holiday Gatherings  (2024/1/12) | 世卫组织称节日后新冠肺炎死亡人数增长</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/who-more-covid-deaths-after-holiday-gatherings.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The World Health Organization (WHO) says holiday gatherings and the spread of a new COVID-19 variant led to increased hospitalizations and deaths last month.<br/>
世界卫生组织表示，节日聚会和一种新冠肺炎新变种的传播导致上个月住院人数和死亡人数增加。</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said Wednesday that nearly 10,000 deaths were reported in December. He added that hospitalizations during the month jumped 42 percent in nearly 50 countries.<br/>
世界卫生组织总干事谭德塞周三表示，12月报告了近1万例死亡病例。他补充说，该月近50个国家的住院人数增加了42%。</p>
<p>Tedros said, "Although 10,000 deaths a month is far less than the peak of the pandemic, this level of preventable deaths is not acceptable."<br/>
谭德塞说：“尽管每月1万人死亡远低于疫情高峰期，但这种可预防的死亡水平是不可接受的。”</p>
<p>Tedros said it was "certain" that cases of COVID-19 were increasing in other places that have not been reporting case numbers.<br/>
谭德塞表示，“可以肯定”的是，在其他没有报告病例数的地方，新冠肺炎病例也在增加。</p>
<p>Tedros said the JN.1 variant is now the most common in the world. Since it is an Omicron variant, current vaccines should still provide some protection. Health officials in the U.S. say there is no evidence that JN.1 causes more severe disease than recent variants.<br/>
谭德塞说，JN.1变种目前是世界上最常见的。由于它是奥密克戎变异株，目前的疫苗应该仍能提供一些保护。美国卫生官员表示，没有证据表明JN.1变种会导致比近期变种更严重的疾病。</p>
<p>In the United States, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reports that there have been at least 110,000 hospitalizations and 6,500 deaths from the flu since October.<br/>
美国疾控与预防中心报告称，自10月以来，美国至少有11万人因流感住院，6500人死亡。</p>
<p>The agency added that COVID-19 illnesses were not increasing as quickly flu illnesses. Still, COVID-19 is putting more people in the hospital than the flu.<br/>
该机构补充说，新冠肺炎疾病的增长速度没有流感疾病那么快。尽管如此，新冠肺炎住院人数仍多于流感。</p>
<p>Maria Van Kerkhove is the technical lead at WHO for COVID-19. She said there is an increase in respiratory diseases around the world due to COVID-19, flu and pneumonia.<br/>
玛丽亚·范·科克霍夫是世界卫生组织新冠肺炎方面的技术负责人。她说，由于新冠肺炎、流感和肺炎，世界各地的呼吸道疾病有所增长。</p>
<p>"We expect those trends to continue into January through the winter months in the northern hemisphere," Van Kerkhove said. She added there have also been increases in COVID-19 in the southern hemisphere, where it is now summer.<br/>
范·科克霍夫说：“我们预计这些趋势将持续到北半球的整个冬季。”她补充说，新冠肺炎在南半球也有所增加，那里现在是夏天。</p>
<p>WHO officials suggest that people get vaccinated, wear face coverings, and make sure air can move in and out of indoor areas.<br/>
世界卫生组织官员建议人们接种疫苗，戴口罩，并确保室内区域空气流通。</p>
<p>Michael Ryan is the head of emergencies at the WHO. He said, "The vaccines may not stop you from being infected, but the vaccines are certainly reducing significantly your chance of being hospitalized or dying."<br/>
迈克尔·瑞安是世界卫生组织紧急情况负责人。他说：“疫苗可能无法阻止你被感染，但疫苗肯定会显著降低住院或死亡的几率。”</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.<br/>
我是阿什利·汤普森。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In 2024, More Than 60 Nations to Hold National Elections  (2024/1/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/in-2024-more-than-60-nations-to-hold-national-elections.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>2024 will go down as one of the most politically important years in history. More than 60 countries will hold national elections representing half of the world's population.</p>
<p>Here is a look at six of the year's most important elections.</p>
<p><strong>United States</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In 2024, national elections will be held in more than 60 countries representing half the world's population. (VOA graphic)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-2498-08dc1087e84c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In 2024, national elections will be held in more than 60 countries representing half the world's population. (VOA graphic)</span></div>
<p>The U.S. presidential election looks to be a rematch between President Joe Biden and former President Donald Trump. The two front-runners have very different opinions on America's place in the world. The results in November's race may decide how tough the U.S. will be on China, Russia and other international rivals.</p>
<p>Joseph S. Nye Jr. is the former U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense. He told VOA that Trump's "America First" position is attempting to bring <strong>isolationism</strong> back in foreign policy. That could leave U.S. allies in a difficult position as the Russia-Ukraine and Israel-Hamas wars continue.</p>
<p>"On Russia," Nye said, "Trump is likely to be more favorable to Putin. That means pressure to reduce support for Ukraine is very likely."</p>
<p>As president, Biden has sent military aid packages to Ukraine and Israel, even as he faces opposition from both parties.</p>
<p>Biden is currently behind Trump in the polls in a possible rematch.</p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 9pt;">Russia</strong></p>
<p>Russia will hold its presidential election in March. Following its invasion of Ukraine nearly two years ago, Russia has become the most <strong>sanctioned</strong> country in the world. The sanctions have harmed its economy and driven Russia closer to China.</p>
<p>Experts do not expect Russian President Vladimir Putin to lose in 2024. His top political rivals are jailed, exiled, missing or dead.</p>
<p>If Putin wins another six years, Russia will continue "the same <strong>brutal</strong> <strong>agenda</strong> in Ukraine and increasingly <strong>autocratic</strong> policies at home," said Sergey Radchenko. He is a professor of Soviet history at Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies.</p>
<p>Experts say the level of success Putin sees in his war with Ukraine may depend on who wins the U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p><strong>European Union</strong></p>
<p>The European Union is heading for elections in June. Anti-immigration leaders with soft positions on Russia and China are set to push the European Parliament to the right. The Parliament, though, plays only a supervisory <strong>role</strong> in the EU.</p>
<p>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen has yet to announce whether she is running for reelection. She has shown strong support to Ukraine.</p>
<p>If reelected, von der Leyen would serve as an equalizing force in an increasingly <strong>populist</strong> European Union. She would work to balance the often-conflicting interests of different member nations with her goal of containing Russia.</p>
<p>The election results will decide is how much pushback von der Leyen's pro-Ukraine agenda will face from incoming right-wing European lawmakers. That is especially important as Ukraine gets closer to becoming an EU member nation.</p>
<p><strong>India</strong></p>
<p>India holds its general elections this spring. Critics of Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his ruling BJP party say the country's religious minorities are facing widespread <strong>persecution</strong>, or unfair treatment. Modi's Hindu nationalist agenda has gained popularity. Violence against Sikh and Muslim Indians has become increasingly common.</p>
<p>Modi's government stands accused of killing a Sikh <strong>expatriate</strong> in Canada last summer and a failed plot to kill a Sikh activist living in New York City in November. Those incidents have affected India's diplomatic ties with the West.</p>
<p>Modi has a very high approval rating among Indian voters and appears likely to earn a third five-year term. If he wins, Modi is expected to build on the relationships he has made with both Trump and Biden during his time as prime minister.</p>
<p><strong>South Africa</strong></p>
<p>South Africa's ruling party is at its weakest point since it came to power in 1994. The African National Congress (ANC) is at risk of losing its majority in the legislature. To stay in power, the ANC will likely be forced to form a coalition with other parties.</p>
<p>South Africa is the most industrialized nation in Africa. But with a one-third unemployment rate and power shortages across the nation, some young South Africans are turning away from the ANC.</p>
<p>Still, it is likely that the ANC will stay in charge for the next five years, said Daniel Silke. He is a South African political expert.</p>
<p>The Democratic Alliance (DA) is the largest opposition party. If the DA wins an unlikely victory, there would be "improvement in relations between South Africa and the West," Silke said.</p>
<p>Silke said the ANC remaining in power could make way for an even stronger connection between South Africa and China.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>And I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Gabriel Levy wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>isolation </strong><em>— n. </em>the state of being in a place or situation that is separate from others</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>— n. </em>a material or object that allows some electricity or heat to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sovereignty </strong><em>— n. </em>unlimited power over a country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>approach </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of dealing with something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sanction </strong><em>— n. </em>an action that is taken or an order that is given to force a country to obey international laws by limiting or stopping trade with that country, by not allowing economic aid for that country, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>brutal </strong><em>— adj. </em>extremely cruel or harsh</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>autocratic </strong><em>— adj. </em>a person who rules with total power</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>role </strong><em>— n. </em>a part that someone or something has in a particular activity or situation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>populist </strong><em>— n. </em>of or relating to a political party that claims to represent ordinary people</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>persecute </strong><em>— v. </em>to treat cruelly or unfairly especially because of race or religious or political beliefs</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>expatriate </strong><em>— n. </em> a person who lives in a foreign country</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dispute over Government Pay in Papua Leads to Deadly Rioting  (2024/1/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/dispute-over-government-pay-in-papua-leads-to-deadly-rioting.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The government of Papua New Guinea declared a state of emergency on Thursday after at least 16 people were killed in rioting.</p>
<p>After declaring the emergency, Prime Minister James Marape told a news conference that the government would take steps to prevent further "lawlessness."</p>
<p>Speaking directly to the people of the South Pacific country, Marape said, "This is your country as much as it's my country. Breaking the law does not <strong>achieve</strong> certain outcomes."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="People run with merchandise as crowds leave shops with looted goods amid a state of unrest in Port Moresby on Jan. 10, 2024. (Andrew Kutan—AFP/Getty Images)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-def8-08dc1289279f_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">People run with merchandise as crowds leave shops with looted goods amid a state of unrest in Port Moresby on Jan. 10, 2024. (Andrew Kutan—AFP/Getty Images)</span></div>
<p>The unrest began Wednesday in the capital, Port Moresby, after hundreds of police officers, soldiers and other government workers walked off their jobs. The workers had discovered an unexpected pay cut. Government officials later said the reduction was a mistake — calling it a glitch. They said it would be fixed.</p>
<p>Australian state broadcaster ABC reported that at least 16 people were killed in the unrest. Rioting in Port Moresby killed nine people, while seven were reported dead in the northern city of Lae.</p>
<p>Local video showed thousands of people in the streets of Port Moresby, Reuters news agency reported. Many carried what appeared to be<strong> looted </strong>goods as black smoke rose over the city.</p>
<p>The French news agency AFP reported at least 25 people were treated with gunshot wounds at a hospital in the capital. In addition, at least six people were treated for knife injuries, AFP said.</p>
<p>Marape told reporters there was evidence that "organized rioting" had taken place. He promised the government would "secure democracy" and the "rule of law." He said about 1,000 military troops were standing by to be deployed to areas experiencing further unrest.</p>
<p>Reuters reported that violence had eased in the capital Thursday. Many stores, banks and other businesses were closed as owners sought to repair property damage.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said his government was watching the situation but had not received any requests for help. "We continue to urge calm at this difficult time," he told reporters. Australia has in the past supported policing efforts in Papua and the two nations recently signed a security agreement.</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea is home to 10 million people and about 800 languages. Farming is an important industry, but the country also holds rich resources including gold and copper.</p>
<p>Tensions in the country have been rising along with unemployment and living costs. This has led to an increase in violent crime over the past year. Marape has said improving the security situation will help bring in more foreign investment.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>achieve </strong><em>– v. </em>to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
<p><strong>loot </strong><em>– v. </em>to steal from shops or homes during a period of war or violence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Grammar of ‘Share:’ Social, Economic Uses  (2024/1/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/the-grammar-of-share-social-economic-uses.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Consider a time when you heard or read news about business, investments, or politics.</p>
<p>Now consider a happy time when you gathered with friends or family. You ate food, had something to drink, and perhaps smiled and laughed.</p>
<p>What word might appear often in discussions about our two situations – the news and the family meal?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-97c3-08dc12bcef02_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>The answer is one word that comes in a verb or noun form: share.</p>
<p>Share will be the subject of today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>. You will learn about the word's meanings as well as commonly used structures in everyday situations.</p>
<p>Let's start with some definitions.</p>
<p><strong>Definitions </strong></p>
<p>As we said before, the word "share" has both a noun and verb form.</p>
<p>We can compare it to a superhero. Consider Peter Parker. He is a normal young man. But sometimes he becomes Spiderman - and Spiderman is all about action!</p>
<p>Just as Peter Parker has a normal side and an active side, the word "share" has a noun form and an active verb form.</p>
<p><strong>Noun form</strong></p>
<p>Let's start with the noun form.</p>
<p>When you read business or even political news, you are highly likely to see the noun form.</p>
<p>Share suggests the idea of division or splitting something.</p>
<p>So, a share can involve value, interest or ownership that has been divided into parts.</p>
<p>For example, a person might buy<strong> stock</strong> shares in a company. This means that a person is buying partial ownership of a business.</p>
<p>Any time you read news about the stock market, for example, the value of the shares of businesses is a central point of interest.</p>
<p>Now consider a story about a political dispute. A <strong>scandal</strong> might happen, and one politician might be forced to accept his or her share of the blame for something that went wrong. In this usage, the politician is getting an amount of something - blame - that he or she deserves or is responsible for.</p>
<p>You might use the noun form of "share" when you talk about gatherings with family and friends. For example, friends might get together and decide to pay their share of the bill for a meal at a restaurant.</p>
<p>In this case, the friends might divide the bill and pay what they owe individually.</p>
<p><strong>Verb form </strong></p>
<p>What about the verb form of share, you might ask?</p>
<p>We often use it to talk about politics.</p>
<p>Political parties might share power in a country, for example.</p>
<p>We also might use the verb "share" to describe social gatherings.</p>
<p>Family or friends might share food. In this case, the family or friends are coming together and dividing or splitting food among themselves. Everyone gets to eat and drink.</p>
<p><strong>Common structures </strong></p>
<p>Now we can ask the question: What are the most commonly used structures with both the noun and verb forms of share?</p>
<p>The most common words that come before "share" are "to" and "a." That is what Google's Ngram Viewer tells us. It is a database that contains information from thousands of books.</p>
<p>But Ngram Viewer also gives us an important finding: "to share" is far more common than "a share."</p>
<p>So, we are very likely to read a sentence like this:</p>
<p><em>The two sides agreed to share power.</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>The children decided to share the toys.</em></p>
<p>We are somewhat less likely to read a sentence like this:</p>
<p><em>He bought a share of Microsoft stock.</em></p>
<p>What words are likely to come after "share?"</p>
<p>The two most common structures, Google's Ngram Viewer tells us, are "share of" and "share the."</p>
<p>So, think back to our earlier examples:</p>
<p><em>He bought a share of Microsoft stock.</em></p>
<p><em>The children decided to share the toys.</em></p>
<p><strong>Quiz: </strong></p>
<p>Let's end this lesson with a quiz. Fill in the blank with the correct word or words.</p>
<p><em>The countries agreed ___________ the profits made from the shipping canal. </em></p>
<p>Here is one possible answer:</p>
<p>The countries agreed to share the profits made from the shipping canal.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stock</strong> <em>– n. </em>a share of the value of a company which can be bought, sold, or traded as an investment</p>
<p><strong>scandal</strong> <em>– n.</em> an occurrence in which people are shocked and upset because of behavior that is morally or legally wrong</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Top Technology Products at CES 2024  (2024/1/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/top-technology-products-at-ces-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>One of the world's largest technology events, CES, is happening this week in Las Vegas, Nevada. The show is produced by the Consumer Technology Association which is based in Arlington, Virginia. CES presents the latest technology offerings from companies across the world.</p>
<p>Here is a look at some top products presented at CES 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Transparent televisions</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="People look at an exhibit of LG Signature OLED T 4K transparent wireless TV's at the LG booth during the CES tech show Tuesday, Jan. 9, 2024, in Las Vegas. (AP Photo/John Locher)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4c2a-08dc1220d875_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">People look at an exhibit of LG Signature OLED T 4K transparent wireless TV's at the LG booth during the CES tech show Tuesday, Jan. 9, 2024, in Las Vegas. (AP Photo/John Locher)</span></div>
<p>Electronics manufacturers LG and Samsung brought televisions to CES that have a <strong>transparent</strong> screen design. The TVs use OLED technology. They are designed to be hidden in a room when not in use.</p>
<p>David Park, from LG's Home Entertainment Division, described OLED to the Associated Press (AP) as a "material that we can <strong>print</strong> on any type of surface." In this case, Park said OLED was printed onto a piece of glass.</p>
<p>When not in the transparent setting, the TVs have a traditional, black background. The companies presenting the TVs did not provide pricing information, but experts say the transparent models are likely to cost tens of thousands of dollars.</p>
<p><strong>AI for Hyundai and Kia vehicles</strong></p>
<p>South Korea's Samsung <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cbtnews.com/samsung-hyundai-partner-up-to-enhance-home-to-car-connectivity/">announced</a> it was cooperating with automaker Hyundai to develop "home-to-car" and "car-to-home" services for all Hyundai and Kia vehicles.</p>
<p>This artificial intelligence (AI)-powered system will permit users of Samsung's SmartThings service to <strong>remotely</strong> set their vehicle's temperature or open its windows. And users can control lights and connect to devices inside the home when inside the car.</p>
<p><strong>Car parking robot</strong></p>
<p>South Korean electric automotive company HL Mando demonstrated a parking robot called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.hlmando.com/en/solution/robot/parkingrobot.do">Parkie</a>. It is designed to operate independently in parking structures. The robot can move underneath parked vehicles, lift the cars up and transport them to different spaces or return them to their drivers.</p>
<p><strong>Robot pet sitter</strong></p>
<p>Robotics developer Ogmen presented a new machine designed to assist pets. The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://orobuddy.com/">ORo robot</a> is equipped with a food container to feed animals. It can also play with pets, record health details and capture images and video of animals' daily activities.</p>
<p><strong>Body power to charge a phone</strong></p>
<p>Sports equipment developer LifeSpan introduced an <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.lifespanfitness.com/products/ampera-under-desk-bike">exercise bicycle/desk combination</a> that uses human power to charge phones or other devices. The Ampera bike is designed to be used with a "standing" desk table. LifeSpan says at a speed of 60 rpms, the bike can produce up to 65 watts of electricity per hour.</p>
<p><strong>Streaming from vinyl</strong></p>
<p>Record player manufacturer <a class="wsw__a" href="https://stream.victrola.com/?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiAnfmsBhDfARIsAM7MKi2gDBtuvAxnn0wylrVrxVWOQ41OIjPasJ2FpR34-wfb50uoC-0_VpkaAt-EEALw_wcB">Victrola</a> presented a new turntable model that can send, or stream, music to a sound system or personal device. The Sapphire player targets music lovers who favor <strong>vinyl</strong> over digital sound. It sells for about $1,500 and will go on sale in the spring.</p>
<p><strong>Add walking power </strong></p>
<p>South Korea's WIRobotics introduced a wearable robot that provides walking assistance to users. The company's WIM model is designed for anyone who feels the need for an extra "push" when walking. An <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.wirobotics.com/pages/main.php">online description</a> explains the robot can help individuals "walk farther, faster and healthier." The price for such assistance is high, though, with the WIM selling for about $2,500.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p><strong>‘Smart' mirror for better mental health</strong></p>
<p>French health product developer Baracoda presented what it described as "the world's first AI-powered smart <strong>mirror</strong> for mental wellness." The company's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://baracoda.com/resources/press/baracoda-unveils-bmind-smart-mirror-for-mental-wellness">BMind</a> model is built to work in any bathroom and does not need a device app to operate.</p>
<p>The product was designed to use cameras and sensors to collect data on a person's movements, expressions and language. Creators of the device claim it can identify a user's <strong>moods</strong> and sense other possible mental health issues. The electronic mirror can then suggest different treatments or activities to help the user, or even guide forms of <strong>meditation</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Homemade ice cream in 2 minutes</strong></p>
<p>The ColdSnap company introduced a machine that can make single servings of ice cream in about two minutes. The machine uses small containers, called pods, just like Keurig coffeemakers. The company points out the pods for its ColdSnap machine can be kept at room temperature, saving energy costs. The machines can be taken anywhere and are simple to operate.</p>
<p><strong>Robotic lawnmower</strong></p>
<p>Chinese robotics developer Mammotion demonstrated a new version of its self-driving<strong> lawnmower</strong>. The latest, all-wheel-drive Luba 2 includes new wireless abilities and tools to deal with <strong>obstacles</strong> in the grass. The robot mower is already available and sells for just over $2,000.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and other online sources. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transparent </strong><em>– adj. </em>clear and easy to understand or recognize</p>
<p><strong>print </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce writing or images on paper or other material with a machine</p>
<p><strong>remote </strong><em>– adj. </em>from a distance or far away</p>
<p><strong>vinyl </strong><em>– n. </em>a kind of very strong plastic that is used to produce records</p>
<p><strong>mirror </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of glass with a shiny metallic material on one side that produces an image of anything that is in front of it</p>
<p><strong>mood </strong><em>– n. </em>the way someone feels at a particular time</p>
<p><strong>meditation </strong><em>– n. </em>to think calming thoughts for a long period of time in order to relax or improve spirituality</p>
<p><strong>lawnmower </strong><em>– n. </em>a motorized machine used for cutting grass</p>
<p><strong>obstacle </strong><em>– n. </em>something that blocks movement or makes it difficult</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Computer Keyboards to have AI Key  (2024/1/11) | 电脑键盘新增AI专用键</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-computer-keyboards-to-have-ai-key.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Starting this month, some new personal computers that run Microsoft's Windows 11 operating system will have a special "Copilot key." The key will launch the software company's AI chatbot.<br/>
从本月开始，一些运行微软Windows 11操作系统的新个人电脑将拥有一个特殊的“Copilot键”。该按键将会启动该软件公司的人工智能聊天机器人。`</p>
<p>Getting computer makers like Dell to add an AI key is the latest move by Microsoft to make use of its close partnership with ChatGPT-maker OpenAI. With the development, Microsoft is turning its software into an opening for generative AI technology.<br/>
让戴尔等计算机制造商添加人工智能按键是微软利用其与ChatGPT制造商OpenAI密切合作关系的最新举措。随着这一发展，微软正在将其软件转变为生成性人工智能技术的入口。</p>
<p>Most people now connect to the internet and many AI applications by phone rather than computer. But the announcement is the start of what is expected to be a competitive year for technology companies and AI.<br/>
大多数人现在通过手机上网和使用许多人工智能应用程序，而不是通过电脑。但这一公告是科技公司和人工智能竞争激烈的一年的开始。</p>
<p>Many companies still have not answered all of AI's ethical and legal questions. The New York Times last month brought legal action against both OpenAI and Microsoft. The news organization argued that tools like ChatGPT and Copilot — formerly known as Bing Chat — are infringing on copyrighted news articles.<br/>
许多公司仍然没有回应人工智能的所有道德和法律问题。《纽约时报》上个月对OpenAI和微软都提起了法律诉讼。该新闻机构辩称，ChatGPT和Copilot等工具（前身为Bing Chat）侵犯了受版权保护的新闻文章。</p>
<p>The keyboard design will be Microsoft's biggest change to PC keyboards since it introduced a special Windows key in the 1990s.<br/>
这一键盘设计将是微软自20世纪90年代推出特殊的Windows键以来对PC键盘的最大改变。</p>
<p>The newest AI key will have a Copilot logo and be placed near the space bar. On some computers, it will replace the right "CTRL" key, while on others it will replace a menu key.<br/>
最新的人工智能键盘将有一个Copilot标志，并设置在空格键附近。在某些计算机上，它将替换右边的“CTRL”键，而在其它计算机上，则会替换菜单键。</p>
<p>Microsoft is not the only company with special keys. Apple started the idea in the 1980s with its "Command" key. Google has a search button on its Chromebooks. Google was also the first to try an AI-specific key to launch its voice assistant on its now-discontinued Pixelbook.<br/>
微软并不是唯一一家拥有特殊按键的公司。苹果公司在20世纪80年代想出了这个办法，设置了“命令”键。谷歌在其Chromebook上设置了一个搜索按钮。谷歌也是第一个尝试使用人工智能专用键在现已停产的Pixelbook上启动语音助手的公司。</p>
<p>But Microsoft has a much stronger hold on the personal computer market through its agreements with computer makers like Lenovo, Dell and HP. About 82 percent of all desktop computers, laptops and workstations run Windows. Just 9 percent use Apple's operating system and just over 6 percent for Google's, says market research firm IDC.<br/>
但微软通过与联想、戴尔和惠普等电脑制造商的协议，对个人电脑市场的控制要强大得多。大约82%的台式电脑、笔记本电脑和工作站运行Windows系统。市场研究公司IDC表示，只有9%的人使用苹果的操作系统，略高于6%的人使用谷歌的操作系统。</p>
<p>Last week, Dell Technologies was the first to announce a Copilot key on its newest XPS laptops.<br/>
上周，戴尔科技公司率先在其最新的XPS笔记本电脑上发布了Copilot按键。</p>
<p>Microsoft has not yet said which other computer makers will use the Copilot key beyond Microsoft's own Surface devices. It said several companies are expected to show their new models at the CES show in Las Vegas.<br/>
微软尚未说明，除了微软自己的Surface设备之外，还有哪些电脑制造商会使用Copilot按键。微软表示，预计有几家公司将在拉斯维加斯的消费电子展上展示他们的新机型。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>WEF: Misinformation, Weather Top Worldwide Risks  (2024/1/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/wef-misinformation-weather-top-worldwide-risks.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A report from the World Economic Forum says misinformation and disinformation are the most severe risks facing the world over the next two years.</p>
<p>The group released its latest Global Risks Report Wednesday.</p>
<p>The report said artificial intelligence (AI) can increase false or misleading information and is an immediate risk to the worldwide economy. The World Economic Forum (WEF) report warned that bad information threatens to weaken democracy and <strong>polarize </strong>groups of people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A ChapGPT logo is seen on a smartphone in West Chester, Pa., on December 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/61614eb9-0130-41bc-9610-6cc42daa49f0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A ChapGPT logo is seen on a smartphone in West Chester, Pa., on December 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke, File)</span></div>
<p>The report is based on a <strong>survey</strong> of nearly 1,500 experts, industry leaders, and politicians. It is being released before the yearly WEF meeting in the vacation town of Davos, Switzerland.</p>
<p>The writers are concerned that the fast progress of AI technology like ChatGPT might mean that groups can be <strong>manipulated </strong>by people without any specialized skills.</p>
<p>AI will be discussed next week at the Davos meeting. Technology company leaders including OpenAI chief Sam Altman, Microsoft head Satya Nadella, and industry experts like Meta's chief AI scientist, Yann LeCun, are expected to attend.</p>
<p>The report says misinformation and disinformation that is created using AI is becoming a risk just as billions of people in several countries are going to vote this year and next year. Those countries include the United States, Britain, Indonesia, India, Mexico, and Pakistan.</p>
<p>Carolina Klint is a risk expert at Marsh, whose parent company Marsh McLennan co-wrote the report with Zurich Insurance Group. She said people can use AI to make deepfakes and to really affect large groups "...which really drives misinformation."</p>
<p>Deepfakes are videos that contain realistic images which are false and show people doing and saying things that never happened.</p>
<p>"<strong>Societies</strong> could become further polarized" as people find it harder to tell what is true, she said. False information also could be used to fuel questions about whether governments are elected fairly. Klint said, that "... means that democratic processes could be <strong>eroded</strong>, and it would also drive societal polarization even further."</p>
<p>The rise of AI brings other risks, she said. It could give power to harmful actors by making it easier to carry out online attacks.</p>
<p>Klint said with AI, a person does not need to be intelligent to become a harmful actor.</p>
<p>It can even affect data that is taken from the internet to develop other AI systems. She said this is difficult to correct and could result in further <strong>bias</strong> in AI systems.</p>
<p>The report said extreme weather is the second most worrying short term risk.</p>
<p>The report also said that, over the next 10 years, extreme weather events were more important than misinformation and disinformation. Weather was followed by environmental risks that include changes to the Earth's systems; loss of wildlife and collapse of natural systems; and shortages of natural resources.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gregory Stachel adapted this story for VOA Learning English using information from Reuters and The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>polarize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to cause (people or opinions) to separate into opposing groups</p>
<p><strong>survey </strong>–n. a kind of study in which a group of people are asked their opinions about a subject</p>
<p><strong>manipulate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to deal with or control (someone or something) in a clever and usually unfair or selfish way</p>
<p><strong>society </strong>– <em>n</em>. people in general thought of as living together in organized communities with shared laws, traditions, and values</p>
<p><strong>erode </strong>– <em>v</em>. to gradually destroy something or make it weaker over a period of time; to be destroyed or made weaker in this way</p>
<p><strong>bias </strong>– <em>n</em>. a tendency to support one side of an argument over another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Ecuador, Gunmen Take over Live Broadcast  (2024/1/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/in-ecuador-gunmen-take-over-live-broadcast.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Officials in Ecuador say men with face coverings broke into the set of a public television channel in Ecuador waving guns and explosives during a live broadcast on Tuesday.</p>
<p>That led the president to declare that the country had entered an "internal armed conflict."</p>
<p>The men were armed with guns and what looked like sticks of <strong>dynamite.</strong> They entered the set of the TC Television network in Guayaquil during a nationwide news program. The men shouted that they had bombs. Noises similar to gunshots could be heard.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This screen grab of live video from the TC Television network shows a masked, armed person standing over journalists during a live broadcast, in Guayaquil, Ecuador, Tuesday, Jan. 9, 2024. (TC Television network via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1c90-08dc11f4e304_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This screen grab of live video from the TC Television network shows a masked, armed person standing over journalists during a live broadcast, in Guayaquil, Ecuador, Tuesday, Jan. 9, 2024. (TC Television network via AP)</span></div>
<p>No one died in the attack. Officials later said all the 13 <strong>intruders</strong> had been arrested and would face terrorism charges.</p>
<p>Officials have not said who was behind the television station attack. They also have not said who was behind a series of other recent attacks.</p>
<p>But the violent incidents follow the escapes from prison of two leaders of Ecuador's most powerful drug gangs.</p>
<p>President Daniel Noboa on Monday declared a national state of emergency. The measure lets officials suspend people's rights and use the military in places like prisons.</p>
<p>The government has not said how many attacks have taken place since Los Choneros gang leader Adolfo Macías was found missing from his low-security prison cell Sunday. He was supposed to be moved to a high-security facility that day.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Ecuadorean officials announced that another gang leader, Fabricio Colón Pico of the Los Lobos group, had escaped from prison. Colón Pico was captured on Friday as part of a kidnapping investigation. He has also been accused of trying to murder one of the nation's lead <strong>prosecutors</strong>.</p>
<p>Other attacks have included an explosion near the house of the president of the National Justice Court. On Monday night, four police officers were kidnapped.</p>
<p>Will Freeman is a political expert at the Council on Foreign Relations. He said gangs in Ecuador have assassinated a presidential candidate and set off car bombs in front of government buildings in the past. But he said Tuesday's events marked a new peak in violence in the country.</p>
<p>Ecuador sits between Peru and Colombia, the world's largest cocaine producers. In recent years, Ecuador has become a key passage point for cocaine. Much of the violence in the country comes as drug gangs fight each other and the government for control of ports and <strong>smuggling</strong> points.</p>
<p>Freeman said that Ecuador's government will have to find ways to control prisons, where gang leaders continue to lead their operations. It might have to consider <strong>extraditing</strong> some of the top criminal leaders to the United States.</p>
<p>Ecuador, a nation of 20 million people, might also have to make judicial changes to give judges greater safety.</p>
<p>"If these guys can storm a TV station or kill a presidential candidate you as a judge will not go up against them," without promises of safety, Freeman said.</p>
<p>Los Choneros is one of the gangs that officials consider responsible for the increase in violence. It reached a new level of violence last year with the assassination of presidential candidate Fernando Villavicencio. Officials say the gang has links with Mexico's Sinaloa cartel.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of Macías are unknown. Prosecutors opened an investigation and charged two guards in connection with his apparent escape. But neither the police, the prison system, nor the federal government confirmed whether the prisoner fled the facility or might be hiding in it.</p>
<p>In February of 2013, he escaped from a high-security facility but was recaptured weeks later.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dynamite </strong><em>— n. </em>a powerful explosive that is often used in the form of a stick</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>intruder </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who is not welcome or wanted in a place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>prosecutor </strong><em>— n. </em>a lawyer who represents the side in a court case that accuses a person of a crime and who tries to prove that the person is guilty</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>smuggle </strong><em>— v. </em>to move from one country into another illegally and secretly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extradite </strong><em>— v. </em>to send to another state or country for trial</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Agency: 2023 Broke Global Heat Record  (2024/1/10) | 气象机构称2023年打破全球高温记录</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/climate-agency-2023-broke-global-heat-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Copernicus, the European climate agency, says 2023 broke records for global warmth.<br/>
欧洲气候机构哥白尼气候变化服务局表示，2023年打破了全球变暖的记录。</p>
<p>The average temperature for the year was 1.48 degrees Celsius above the world's pre-industrial temperature.<br/>
今年的平均气温比全球工业化前的温度高1.48摄氏度。</p>
<p>World climate experts agree that an average increase up to 1.5 degrees or higher could lead to extreme climate disasters. They set the 1.5 degree Celsius mark at a 2015 climate conference in Paris.<br/>
世界气候专家一致认为，平均气温上升1.5度或更高可能导致极端气候灾害。他们在2015年巴黎气候大会上设定了1.5摄氏度的目标。</p>
<p>However, January 2024 is measuring so warm that it is likely to average at or beyond the 1.5 mark for the month, says Samantha Burgess. She is Deputy Director of Copernicus. Scientists have repeatedly said an average of 1.5 degrees of warming over as much as thirty years would violate the limit.<br/>
然而，萨曼莎·伯吉斯表示，2024年1月的气温非常温暖，该月的平均上升气温可能达到或超过1.5摄氏度。她是哥白尼气候变化服务局的副局长。科学家们一再表示，30年内平均升温1.5度将违反这一限制。</p>
<p>The 1.5 degree goal "has to be (kept) alive because lives are at risk and choices have to be made," Burgess said.<br/>
伯吉斯说，1.5摄氏度的目标“必须维持下去，因为生命处于危险之中，人类必须做出选择”。</p>
<p>The record heat made life difficult and sometimes deadly in Europe, North America and China, among other places. Climate scientists say heat is not the only problem related to temperature rise. They say severe weather events such as heavy rains that cause flooding, along with wildfires and extreme dry conditions are connected to the rising temperatures.<br/>
创纪录的高温使欧洲、北美和中国等地的生活变得艰难，有时甚至是致命的。气象学家表示，高温并不是与气温上升相关的唯一问题。他们说，导致洪水的暴雨、野火和极端干旱等恶劣天气事件与气温上升有关。</p>
<p>For the first time, nations meeting on climate late in 2023 agreed that the world needs to move away from polluting fossil fuels.<br/>
2023年末举行的各国气候会议首次一致认为，世界需要摆脱有污染的化石燃料。</p>
<p>Copernicus said the average temperature in 2023 was one-sixth of a degree Celsius above the past record, set in 2016. The average temperature was 14.98 degrees Celsius.<br/>
哥白尼气候变化服务局表示，2023年的平均气温比2016年创下的历史纪录高出六分之一摄氏度。今年平均气温为14.98摄氏度。</p>
<p>"It was record-breaking for seven months. We had the warmest June, July, August, September, October, November, December," Burgess said. "It wasn't just a season or a month that was exceptional. It was exceptional for over half the year."<br/>
伯吉斯说：“有七个月破了纪录。我们经历了最热的6月、7月、8月、9月、10月、11月和12月。这不仅仅是一个季度或一个月的异常情况。在半年多的时间里都是异常情况。”</p>
<p>Malte Meinshausen is a climate scientist at the University of Melbourne in Australia. He says about 1.3 degrees Celsius of the warming comes from greenhouse gases, with another 0.1 degrees from usual weather conditions such as El Nino.<br/>
毛特·迈因斯豪森是澳大利亚墨尔本大学的气象学家。他说，大约1.3摄氏度的变暖来自温室气体，另外0.1摄氏度来自厄尔尼诺等常见气象条件。</p>
<p>Copernicus records only go back to 1940. Other organizations will announce climate reports for 2023 on Friday. The groups include the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in the U.S. and Great Britain's Meteorological Office.<br/>
哥白尼气候变化服务局的记录只能追溯到1940年。其他组织将于周五公布2023年的气候报告。这些组织包括美国国家海洋和大气管理局以及英国气象局。</p>
<p>While some national weather offices only have records going back to the 1940s, many scientists agree that this is the warmest period for the Earth in over 100,000 years.<br/>
虽然一些国家气象局的记录只能追溯到20世纪40年代，但许多科学家一致认为，今年是地球10多万年来最热的时期。</p>
<p>Copernicus said there were two and nearly three days in 2023 where the world's average temperature was at least 2 degrees above that of the pre-industrial period. In addition, for more than half the year, the world average temperature was 1.5 degrees warmer than in the mid-1800s.<br/>
哥白尼气候变化服务局表示，2023年有两到近三天，世界平均气温比工业化前至少高出2度。此外，在大半年的时间里，世界平均气温比19世纪中期高1.5度。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Young People’s English Language Skills Decreasing  (2024/1/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/young-people-s-english-language-skills-decreasing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A recent index that measures English language ability around the world finds that young people's English language <strong>proficiency</strong> is decreasing.</p>
<p>The 2023 <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.ef.edu/epi/" target="_blank">EF English Proficiency Index</a> (EPI) ranks countries and areas by English proficiency. The index is based on test results from 2.2 million people in 113 countries. The test is published by EF Education First, a private company based in Switzerland. VOA Learning English has a partnership with EF Education First to provide the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/4272901.html" target="_blank">online test</a> to English learners.</p>
<p>The EPI found that while young people's English skills are decreasing, working adults continue to increase their proficiency in English. There are different opinions about why the difference exists. Some people blame the COVID-19 pandemic, but others say artificial intelligence (or AI) tools could also be a reason.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A teacher gives an English lesson in a private school of Birkhadem, outside Algiers, Wednesday, Sept.21, 2022. English proficiency in Algeria has remained stable since 2021. (AP Photo/Fateh Guidoum)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e5827407-b9ed-4d2a-9ac7-b67fbe3c2e18_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A teacher gives an English lesson in a private school of Birkhadem, outside Algiers, Wednesday, Sept.21, 2022. English proficiency in Algeria has remained stable since 2021. (AP Photo/Fateh Guidoum)
</span></div>
<p>EF Education First released the 2023 index last November. EF EPI author Kate Bell warned that the 2023 index gives a false sense of global <strong>stability</strong>, meaning English speakers' proficiency stays about the same. But the truth is that gains in some countries are being offset by losses in others, Bell said in an <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/worldwide-english-proficiency-index-reveals-growing-gender-gap-trend-declining-english-skills-among-young-adults-301977055.html" target="_blank">EF Education First press release</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Results by age group</strong></p>
<p>Results were reported by age group for the first time in 2015. Since that time, the English proficiency of young people has decreased by 89 points. The EPI defines young people as being 18 to 20 years of age.</p>
<p>However, the EPI notes that the 18 to 20 group was mostly stable with big decreases in a few large countries. India, Indonesia, Mexico, and Japan showed the largest proficiency decreases among youth.</p>
<p>Kansuke Ikebe is a 21-year-old student from Shiga, Japan. He told VOA Learning English that the results are "really surprising. In my opinion, I've never felt it is decreasing. It is maybe because there are many youth who can speak English in my university."</p>
<p>The EPI report noted that the decrease appears to have taken place when the COVID-19 pandemic interfered with normal education. The report said, "It is not yet clear if learning loss due to Covid will self-correct over time," but increased scores are expected in the future.</p>
<p>The EPI said the problem is more difficult in countries where proficiency has been decreasing over time and "where education systems are teaching English less well than before."</p>
<p>There has been a decrease in proficiency in Japan for nearly 10 years. Ikebe said he could believe the EPI results because of the way English is taught in Japan. "It makes nobody want to learn English more. It is not <strong>practical</strong> at all and really <strong>boring</strong>."</p>
<p>However, working adults, people 26 years old and older, have been improving their English since 2015. The EPI said this might be because the value of a shared language is most recognized in the workplace. English creates possibilities for individuals and productivity for organizations.</p>
<p><strong>Results by gender</strong></p>
<p>Results from the index also show a difference between men and women, what it calls a <strong>gender gap</strong>. The gender gap among those aged 18 to 25 is three times bigger than it is among working adults. Men's proficiency has improved by 14 points since 2015, while women's has decreased by 19 points.</p>
<p>The lack of women in international jobs could be one reason for the gender gap the EPI said. But the gender gap among those aged 18 to 25 might demonstrate "a problem <strong>engendered</strong> by educational systems themselves or a societal problem schools are failing to address," the report said.</p>
<p>An exception was the Middle East. The average score for women in that area has increased by 44 points, placing them ahead of men there.</p>
<p><strong>Lower average scores</strong></p>
<p>One notable trend in the 2023 EF EPI is that all the very high proficiency countries and many of the high proficiency countries had lower average scores than in 2022. This could be a possible effect of the pandemic on learning, travel and in-person communication.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic is one country whose score dropped in 2023.</p>
<p>Sabina Wyrob is with the Czech office of EF Education First. She told <a class="wsw__a" href="https://brnodaily.com/2023/11/08/news/czech-republic-drops-three-places-in-ef-english-proficiency-index/" target="_blank">the Czech News Agency</a> online teaching during the pandemic affected children's English skills. Schools and students are trying to catch up on what was missed, she told the news organization, but they are still not moving forward.</p>
<p><strong>The reach of AI</strong></p>
<p>The EPI report says that learning a language provides understanding of new ideas as well as better understanding of people. These skills, the report said, remain beyond the reach of AI, or artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>But Ikebe said in Japan: "now AI and <strong>translation</strong> are being developed well. So, they don't need to learn English if they just do their homework. I think they don't use it as a tool to communicate, just a subject to pass the entrance exam."</p>
<p>Jeannie Tse is a country manager at EF Hong Kong and Macau. She <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.thestandard.com.hk/breaking-news/section/4/210157/English-level-among-HK-youth-sees-sharp-decline-as-the-city-trailing-Singapore,-Philippines-and-Malaysia:-survey" target="_blank">spoke to The Standard</a> newspaper in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Tse said that while AI has changed the way young people work and learn, the importance of schools, teachers, and face-to-face instruction remains. "I do not believe that AI can completely replace language learning," Tse said, "but educators can <strong>harness</strong> AI to <strong>enhance</strong> language learning methods."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for VOA Learning English using information from EF Education First and other sources.</em></p>
<p><em>How well does your country speak English? Do you agree with the report's findings? We want to hear from you. Write to us in the Comments Section, on Facebook or Instagram."</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>proficiency</strong>–<em>n.</em> ability to use or knowledge of a language</p>
<p><strong>stable</strong>—<em>adj</em>. remain the same</p>
<p><strong>practical</strong> –<em>adj</em>. related to what is real rather than what is imagined or is a possibility</p>
<p><strong>boring</strong> –<em>adj</em>. not interesting</p>
<p><strong>gender</strong>—<em>n</em>. the sex of a person; male or female</p>
<p><strong>gap</strong>—<em>n</em>. a space between two things</p>
<p><strong>engender</strong>—<em>v</em>. to cause</p>
<p><strong>translation</strong> –<em>n</em>. changing writing from one language to another</p>
<p><strong>harness</strong>—<em>v</em>. to control and make use of</p>
<p><strong>enhance</strong> –<em>v</em>. to improve or add to something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Spanish Tapestry Factory Creating Pieces after 300 Years  (2024/1/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/spanish-tapestry-factory-creating-pieces-after-300-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Spain's Royal Tapestry Factory has been providing clothes, called carpets for the floor and tapestries for the wall, for <strong>palaces</strong> and public buildings for more than 300 years.</p>
<p>Found on a quiet street in Spain's capital Madrid, its artisans combine long-held knowledge of the work with new methods to create cloth-based products.</p>
<p>The factory was opened in 1721 by Spain's King Felipe V. He brought in Catholic artisans from Flanders, an area found in today's Belgium, to get it started. At the time, the area had been under Spanish control.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Staff workers clean a tapestry at the Royal Tapestry Factory in Madrid, Spain, Friday, Nov. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Manu Fernandez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a077c54b-91cb-48a7-b996-13d3e37f42c8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Staff workers clean a tapestry at the Royal Tapestry Factory in Madrid, Spain, Friday, Nov. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Manu Fernandez)</span></div>
<p>Cloth like wool can be found in all colors in the factory. And tools like bobbins and spinning wheels are everywhere in the factory. Some of the original wooden machines are still in use.</p>
<p>Alejandro Klecker de Elizalde is the factory's general director. "Here the only products we work with are silk, wool, jute, cotton, linen," he said. "And these small leftovers that we create, the water from the <strong>dyes</strong>, or the small pieces of wool, everything is <strong>recycled</strong>, everything has a double, a second use."</p>
<p>The factory also brings old pieces that have been damaged through time back to good condition. And it keeps some of the most important cloth and material records in Europe.</p>
<p>Now, 70 percent of its buyers are individuals from Latin America, Europe, and the Middle East.</p>
<p>The factory recently received one of its biggest orders, 32 tapestries for the Palace of Dresden in Germany. The order is worth more than 1 million dollars and it will provide work for up to five years, Klecker de Elizalde said.</p>
<p>In 2018, the factory finished a tapestry for a Lebanese buyer based on the work <em>Sabra and Shatila Massacre</em> by Iraqi artist Dia al-Azzawi. The cloth shows the 1982-83 violence by Christian Phalangist militia in Palestinian refugee camps that were guarded by Israeli troops.</p>
<p>Creating a tapestry is a difficult process that takes several weeks or months of work for each square meter.</p>
<p>A tapestry begins with "cartoons," or drawings on paper that are later copied onto a system of material called <strong>warps</strong> which are then <strong>woven</strong> over.</p>
<p>One of the factory's well-known cartoonists was master painter Francisco Goya, who began working there in 1780. Some of the tapestries he designed are now found in the nearby Prado Museum and Madrid's Royal Collections Gallery.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Irene Yagüe reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>palace </strong>– <em>n.</em> the official home of a king, queen, or president</p>
<p><strong>dye </strong>– <em>n</em>. a substance used for changing the color of something (such as hair or cloth) usually permanently</p>
<p><strong>recycle </strong><em>– v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
<p><strong>warp </strong><em>– n.</em> the threads that run up and down on a loom or in a woven fabric</p>
<p><strong>weave </strong><em>– v.</em> to make something (such as cloth) by crossing threads or other long pieces of material over and under each other</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Disaster in the Air Narrowly Avoided  (2024/1/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/disaster-in-the-air-narrowly-avoided.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Passengers are describing what happened when part of a passenger jet came off at the start of a flight from Portland, Oregon last Friday.</p>
<p>The incident resulted in no serious injuries, and the plane returned to Portland Airport soon after the dangerous incident. But had a few details been different, the flight could have ended in disaster.</p>
<p>Kelly Bartlett was one of the passengers on Alaska Airlines flight 1282 from Portland. She told The Associated Press (AP) that, at first, passengers did not know what was happening. "We didn't know if it meant we were going to crash," she said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Kelly Bartlett shows passengers near a hole in the fuselage of an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 Max 9, Flight 1282, on Friday, Jan. 5, 2024. (Kelly Bartlett via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e317-08dc11514480_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Kelly Bartlett shows passengers near a hole in the fuselage of an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 Max 9, Flight 1282, on Friday, Jan. 5, 2024. (Kelly Bartlett via AP)</span></div>
<p>The incident happened six minutes into the flight from Portland to Southern California's Ontario International Airport. The jet, a Boeing 737 MAX 9, was traveling at about 640 kilometers an hour. It had reached an <strong>altitude</strong> of 4.8 kilometers. That detail is important. The plane was still far below its cruising altitude.</p>
<p>Flight attendants had just told the 171 passengers that they could again use their electronic devices. Then, a piece of the airplane body 61 centimeters by 122 centimeters behind the left wing blew out.</p>
<p>The piece called a door plug, was meant to be a cover over an emergency <strong>exit</strong> that was not used on that MAX 9 version of the airplane. The cover permits extra seats to be put where an emergency exit would be. Air safety rules require airliners to have enough exits to permit all passengers and crew to get out of the aircraft in 90 seconds.</p>
<p>The AP noted, <strong>as fate would have it</strong>, nobody was sitting in the two seats next to the blown-out hole.</p>
<p>Emergency <strong>oxygen masks</strong> dropped immediately. At the same time, wind rushed into the <strong>cabin</strong> making it difficult for the flight attendants to walk or hear. But they moved toward the hole and began moving passengers away from the dangerous area. The sound made communication difficult.</p>
<p>The force from the loss of pressure in the cabin was strong enough to tear the shirt off the body of a teenager sitting nearby.</p>
<p>His <strong>seatbelt</strong> "kept him in his seat and saved his life," Bartlett said. Flight attendants moved the young person next to Bartlett. She asked him if he was hurt. He said he was OK and thanked her for her kindness.</p>
<p>The pilots and the flight attendants have not made public statements and their names have not been released. However, they spoke to National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) investigators. They said they followed their training. The pilots' goal was to get the plane back to Portland quickly. The flight attendants worked to keep the passengers safe and calm.</p>
<p>NTSB Chair Jennifer Homendy said the actions of the flight crew were "incredible." Bartlett also praised the crew. She said she felt like the situation was under control.</p>
<p>The pilots used an emergency handbook next to the captain's seat. The co-pilot contacted air traffic controllers declaring an emergency and the need to descend to 3,000 meters. The lower altitude would give passengers more oxygen to breathe.</p>
<p>Homendy said the attention of the flight attendants immediately turned to five children who were traveling without adult supervision and two babies being carried by their parents.</p>
<p>Evan Granger was sitting close to the hole in the plane. He told NBC News, "There were so many things that had to go right in order for all of us to survive."</p>
<p>Homendy said that if the blowout had happened just a few minutes later when the plane would have reached its cruising height, the incident might have been a tragedy.</p>
<p>NTSB agents recovered the door plug that blew out, finding it completely <strong>intact</strong>. Many other things that flew out of the airplane were also recovered including a cellphone that was still working.</p>
<p>Now the agency will investigate why the cover over the unused exit hole came off.</p>
<p>The incident happened days after a Japan Airlines Airbus 350 struck a coast guard plane on a runway at Tokyo's Haneda Airport and caught fire on January 3.</p>
<p>In that incident, four on the coast guard plane died. But 379 passengers and the crew of the airliner safely got out of the passenger plane before it burned up. However, reports say getting everyone out of the plane took about 18 minutes.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Terry Spencer and Claire Rush reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted this report for VOA Learning English with other sources from AP and Reuters. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>altitude</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>the height of something above sea level</p>
<p><strong>exit</strong> <em>–n.</em> a doorway out of a building or vehicle</p>
<p><strong>as fate would have it </strong><em>–idiom</em> meant to express that something happened that is beyond human explanation</p>
<p><strong>oxygen mask </strong><em>–(industry)</em> an emergency device on large airplanes that deploys if air pressure inside gets too low</p>
<p><strong>cabin </strong><em>–n. (in aviation)</em> the inside of an airplane</p>
<p><strong>seatbelt </strong><em>–n.</em> a thin piece of material that is meant to protect against injury in a crash</p>
<p><strong>intact </strong><em>–adj. </em>whole and in one piece, not broken or damaged</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Company Launches First Private Mission to the Moon  (2024/1/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/us-company-launches-first-private-mission-to-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>An American company successfully launched a <strong>mission</strong> Monday to explore the moon. The launch of a robotic lander marked the first time a private space vehicle has been sent to the lunar surface.</p>
<p>However, the company reported a serious fuel leak about seven hours after the launch. The 1.9-meter-tall lander, called Peregrine, launched at 07:18 UTC from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station in Florida.</p>
<p>The spacecraft was built by Astrobotic Technology, a company based in the eastern U.S. state of Pennsylvania. It was carried into space on a Vulcan Centaur rocket. The rocket was built by American space launch company, United Launch Alliance (ULA), a joint <strong>venture</strong> of Boeing and Lockheed Martin.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image made from NASA video, United Launch Alliance's Vulcan rocket with Astrobotic Technology's lander onboard is launched from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station in Florida, Monday, Jan 8, 2024. (NASA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8f00-08dc107d8354_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image made from NASA video, United Launch Alliance's Vulcan rocket with Astrobotic Technology's lander onboard is launched from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station in Florida, Monday, Jan 8, 2024. (NASA via AP)</span></div>
<p>Earlier, Astrobotic chief executive John Thornton said if all goes as planned, Peregrine will attempt to land on the moon February 23.</p>
<p>However, Astrobotic said in a statement it is currently assessing possible changes to the mission to see what might be possible. If the fuel issue is serious, it "threatens the ability of the spacecraft to soft land on the moon," the company said.</p>
<p>Astrobotic <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.astrobotic.com/astrobotic-peregrine-fueled-ready-for-lunar-mission/">said</a> in a press release Peregrine is loaded with 20 research experiments involving seven different countries. It is equipped to collect data on radiation and materials found on the moon's surface.</p>
<p>The lander also carried a small robotic explorer and other materials. These included a physical bitcoin, a piece of rock from Mount Everest and the ash remains of famous space lovers Gene Roddenberry and Arthur C. Clarke. Roddenberry was creator of the popular science fiction television show <em>Star Trek</em> and Clarke was a science fiction writer.</p>
<p>The Navajo Nation recently sought to have the launch delayed because of the inclusion of the remains. The head of the Native American group called the sending of remains a "<strong>desecration</strong>" because Native Americans consider the moon a <strong>sacred</strong> space.</p>
<p>In a message on X, formerly Twitter, Navajo Nation President Buu Nygren said, "The suggestion of <strong>transforming</strong> (the mission) into a resting place for human remains is deeply <strong>disturbing</strong> and unacceptable to our people and many other tribal nations."</p>
<p>Astrobotic's Thornton answered the criticism by saying the Navajo's Nation's objections came too late to reach an agreement on the issue. But he promised to try to find "a good path forward" with the Navajo Nation for future missions.</p>
<p>So far, only four nations have successfully landed spacecraft on the moon: the United States, China, the Soviet Union and India. The last time the United States landed on the moon was in 1972 with its Apollo 17 mission.</p>
<p>NASA is currently moving ahead with its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-announces-moon-mission-astronauts/7040276.html">Artemis program</a>, which aims to return astronauts to the moon.</p>
<p>Astrobotic is trying to be the first private business to successfully land on the moon in an effort to support the Artemis Program. But The Associated Press reports another space company's lander might beat Peregrine to the lunar surface.</p>
<p>This is because that lander, called Nova-C, is set to take a more direct path to the moon. It plans to launch next month on a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket. Nova-C was built by Texas-based space company <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.intuitivemachines.com/lunar-access-services">Intuitive Machines</a>. The company also plans to send the lander to the moon for another mission later this year.</p>
<p>Private companies from Japan and Israel tried in the past to land spacecraft on the moon, but those attempts failed.</p>
<p>Japan's space agency will attempt another moon landing in mid-January. The agency, JAXA, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/what-is-the-goal-of-japan-s-new-moon-mission-/7259385.html">launched</a> the SLIM spacecraft on its way to the moon in September. SLIM's goal is to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets.</p>
<p>Another Astrobotic lander, called Griffin, is set to launch to the moon's south pole in late 2024. It will be carrying an exploring robot, or rover, called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/mission/viper/">VIPER</a>. VIPER is designed to search for water sources on the moon.</p>
<p>All the private space missions were developed through NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Services (CLPS) program. The program aims to turn over the country's major missions to private companies in an effort to operate at reduced costs.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and NASA reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
<p><strong>joint venture </strong>–n. a new business activity involving two or more businesses that aim to combine their resources</p>
<p><strong>desecrate </strong><em>– v. </em>to damage or show a lack of respect toward something holy or highly respected</p>
<p><strong>sacred </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to religion or considered to be holy</p>
<p><strong>transform </strong><em>–v.</em> to change something from one form to another</p>
<p><strong>disturbing </strong><em>– adj. </em>making you feel worried or upset</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Italian Man Might Regain Use of Hand after Nerve Operation  (2024/1/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/italian-man-might-regain-use-of-hand-after-nerve-operation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A man in Italy might regain the use of his hand after having a new kind of medical operation.</p>
<p>Doctors in northern Italy said the <strong>surgery</strong> used a nerve from the man's partly <strong>amputated </strong>leg to repair a damaged nerve in his hand. His hand became <strong>paralyzed</strong> after a severe driving accident.</p>
<p>Surgeons at Turin City Hospital took part of the man's sciatic nerve from his leg. That is the nerve which helps control movement in the foot. The doctors <strong>transferred</strong> part of the man's sciatic nerve to his brachial plexus. That is a network of nerves connecting the spinal cord to the shoulder, arm, and hand.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gaviglio had a nerve transplanted from his amputated foot to restore use of his paralyzed hand, Dec. 27, 2023. (REUTERS/Massimo Pinca)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f3f6-08dc08881374_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Gaviglio had a nerve transplanted from his amputated foot to restore use of his paralyzed hand, Dec. 27, 2023. (REUTERS/Massimo Pinca)</span></div>
<p>"It's the first time that someone [has transferred] a <strong>component </strong>of the sciatic nerve to the brachial plexus," said Paolo Titolo. He was one of the surgeons who performed the operation. He recently spoke with Reuters news agency.</p>
<p>The patient is Marcello Gaviglio, a 55-year-old healthcare worker. He had half of his left leg amputated after he was hit by a motorbike five months ago. The accident happened while he was travelling to work on his small, motorized bike called a moped.</p>
<p>He suffered serious injuries to his brachial plexus as well as his leg. The damage to his upper body left him unable to use both of his hands.</p>
<p>Because the part of the sciatic nerve that controlled his left foot was no longer needed, it could be transferred to the shoulder area. On December 21, doctors carried out the operation. They hope it will give him the ability to use his left hand.</p>
<p>Gaviglio will need about five months of special care after the operation. For now, he is still unable to move the hand at all.</p>
<p>Nerve transfer surgery is not new. But normally it does not involve moving a nerve that controls the foot to an area that controls the hand. For that reason, doctors involved in the operation are calling it "<strong>pioneering</strong>."</p>
<p>"We think this is pioneering surgery because if it works it means that the brain<strong> plasticity</strong> can control ... other parts of the body that we didn't expect," Titolo said. He added that the surgery opens new fields in nerve studies.</p>
<p>The aim is to restore "some grasp function" to the hand. That means the ability to hold objects. Titolo explained that this can help the other hand to do things.</p>
<p>The operation was the result of four years of research. It was published in the medical journal <em>Injury</em>.</p>
<p>Gaviglio, the patient, said he had given little thought to the pioneering part of the operation. He said he just felt that there was a chance for a good result. He said he thought about depending on a "team of very good doctors" and being able to move his hand again "a little bit."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Alex Fraser reported this story from Turin, Italy. Anna Matteo adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surgery </strong><em>–n.</em> a medical operation</p>
<p><strong>amputate </strong><em>–v.</em> to remove a limb, such as an arm or leg, from the body to save a patient</p>
<p><strong>paralyzed </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>being unable to move</p>
<p><strong>transfer </strong><em>–v.</em> to move from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>component </strong><em>–n. </em>a part of a larger device or system</p>
<p><strong>pioneering </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>doing something or using new ideas for the first time; to be among the earliest people doing some activity</p>
<p><strong>plasticity </strong><em>–n.</em> the quality of being able to be changed into a different form</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Oppenheimer’ Wins Big at Golden Globes  (2024/1/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/oppenheimer-wins-big-at-golden-globes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The historical film "Oppenheimer" won big at the Golden Globe awards Sunday. It won five awards, including best drama.</p>
<p>And the <strong>comedy</strong> "Poor Things" <strong>upset</strong> summer hit "Barbie," as Hollywood threw its biggest party since labor disputes shut down much of show business last year.</p>
<p>"Oppenheimer" is about the making of the atomic bomb. It won five awards, including best movie drama. Actors Cillian Murphy and Robert Downey Jr. won awards for their performances. Christopher Nolan won his first Golden Globe award for best director for the film.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Producer Emma Thomas accepts best motion picture drama award for Oppenheimer during the 81st Annual Golden Globe Awards in Beverly Hills, Calif., on Sunday, Jan. 7, 2024. (Sonja Flemming/CBS via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-3e1c-08dc105902a0_cx5_cy1_cw94_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Producer Emma Thomas accepts best motion picture drama award for "Oppenheimer" during the 81st Annual Golden Globe Awards in Beverly Hills, Calif., on Sunday, Jan. 7, 2024. (Sonja Flemming/CBS via AP)</span></div>
<p>"Poor Things" stars Emma Stone as a woman who was brought back to life by scientists. It won best movie musical or comedy. Awards watchers had widely expected that honor to go to "Barbie," the female empowerment story <strong>inspired</strong> by the famous toy.</p>
<p>"Barbie" led 2023 box office lists and went into the night with a leading nine nominations. But it went home with just two awards. One was for Billie Eilish's song "What Was I Made For." Another was for a new <strong>category</strong> called cinematic and box office achievement, created for widely seen films.</p>
<p>Lily Gladstone was the best actress winner for her role in "Killers of the Flower Moon." She began her acceptance speech by introducing herself in the Blackfeet Native American language, which she learned in school.</p>
<p>"This is an historic win," Gladstone continued in English. "It doesn't belong to just me. I am holding it right now with all my beautiful sisters."</p>
<p>She thanked director Martin Scorsese as well as Leonardo DiCaprio and Robert De Niro, her co-stars in the film. The movie was based on murders of members of the Osage Nation in the 1920s.</p>
<p>In television, "Succession" was named best drama and led all series with four wins, including a lead acting award for Kieran Culkin.</p>
<p>"The Bear," a television series about the struggles of owning a restaurant, won best TV comedy. Actors Jeremy Allen White and Ayo Edebiri both won awards for their performances in "The Bear."</p>
<p>Less serious than the Academy Awards, the Golden Globes nearly collapsed in recent years. A 2021 <em>Los Angeles Times</em> report noted a lack of <strong>diversity</strong> among the 80 members of the Hollywood Foreign Press Association (HFPA). That is the group that previously voted on the Globes. The 2022 ceremony was canceled and the HFPA was shut down. The awards returned last year but drew a small audience.</p>
<p>The awards are now voted on by a group of about 300 entertainment reporters from around the world.</p>
<p>Sunday's ceremony showed Hollywood has re-accepted the Globes. Several of Hollywood's biggest stars could be seen in the crowd, including Meryl Streep and De Niro. Pop singer Taylor Swift also joined the crowd as a nominee for her recent concert film.</p>
<p>The ceremony at the Beverly Hilton hotel started Hollywood's yearly awards season, which ends with the Academy Awards on March 10. The event brought top stars together for the first time after six months of strikes by actors and writers last year.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters and The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>upset </strong><em>— v. </em>angry or unhappy</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inspire </strong><em>— v. </em>to make want to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>category </strong><em>— n. </em>a group of people or things that are similar in some way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>marketing </strong><em>— n. </em>the activities that are involved in making people aware of a company's products, making sure that the products are available to be bought, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>contender </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who tries to win something in a contest</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Agency Investigates Passenger Jet Incident  (2024/1/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/us-agency-investigates-passenger-jet-incident.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Officials have recovered a part of an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 Max passenger jet that blew off during a flight from Portland, Oregon to Ontario, California on Friday.</p>
<p>The plane was minutes into the flight and was able to return to the Portland airport. All 171 people and six crew members were unharmed in the incident.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) ordered that all 737 MAX aircraft be grounded on Saturday. The emergency order affected all 737 MAX 9 planes around the world.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Investigator-in-Charge John Lovell examines the fuselage plug area of Alaska Airlines Flight 1282 on Sunday, Jan. 7, 2024, in Portland, Oregon. (National Transportation Safety Board via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6cca-08dc10807a43_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Investigator-in-Charge John Lovell examines the fuselage plug area of Alaska Airlines Flight 1282 on Sunday, Jan. 7, 2024, in Portland, Oregon. (National Transportation Safety Board via AP)</span></div>
<p>Reports say the part that failed was called a panel or "door plug." U.S. National Transportation Safety Board Chair Jennifer Homendy said a schoolteacher found the part in a Portland neighborhood on Sunday.</p>
<p>The investigation into the incident is likely to last months.</p>
<p><strong>What part failed?</strong></p>
<p>The 737 MAX 9 aircraft has several different designs. One can seat more than 200 passengers. This version needs to have two extra exits to meet safety rules which require all passengers to be able to escape the aircraft in 90 seconds in case of an emergency.</p>
<p>However, the Alaska Airlines plane has fewer than 180 seats. This version of the 737 MAX 9 is not required to have the extra exits. As a result, the plane has a panel, or permanent door plug, over the area on the plane's body that would normally have a door. Some other versions of Boeing 737s also have door plugs.</p>
<p>The Associated Press reports that a company called Spirit AeroSystems <strong>installed</strong> door plugs on 737 MAX 9s, including the Alaska Airlines plane.</p>
<p><strong>What are airlines doing?</strong></p>
<p>Alaska Airlines has grounded all 65 of its 737 MAX 9 aircraft. They are to be inspected and to undergo <strong>maintenance</strong>. Some of the planes were still in service on Saturday, but they were grounded after the FAA ordered all operators of MAX 9s to carry out inspections.</p>
<p>Alaska Airlines said it canceled 170 flights on Sunday. By early Monday, 20 percent of the carrier's flights were canceled, the AP reported.</p>
<p>United Airlines is the world's biggest operator of MAX 9 planes. It grounded all 79 of its planes. The two airlines are the only U.S. passenger airlines that operate the planes.</p>
<p>The AP says six other airlines also operate the Boeing aircraft. There are 215 of the planes in service around the world.</p>
<p><strong>Air travel safety</strong></p>
<p>U.S. officials have noted that air travel remains very safe. There has not been a deadly crash of a U.S. airliner since 2009. However, the FAA held a big safety meeting last year after a series of incidents.</p>
<p>The Alaska Airlines incident again brought attention to the 737 MAX aircraft. Aviation officials grounded MAX 8 aircraft around the world for nearly two years after crashes in 2018 and 2019. The 737 MAX 8 is a little smaller than the MAX 9.</p>
<p>Anthony Brickhouse is a professor of aviation safety at Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University in Florida. He said it is too soon to know if the incident is the result of a problem with the MAX 9. He said government officials and airlines will confirm that the planes are safe before returning them to service.</p>
<p>"When passengers board a flight, they should feel <strong>confident</strong> that the aircraft they are flying on is safe," Brickhouse said.</p>
<p>After the accident, Boeing released a statement saying it regretted the effects "this event has had on our <strong>customers</strong> and their passengers."</p>
<p>It said it supported the FAA's decision and was assisting investigators.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>Mario Ritter adapted this story for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and Reuters sources. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>component</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a part of a system or a machine</p>
<p><strong>install</strong> <em>–v.</em> to put something in a machine in place so that it can be used correctly</p>
<p><strong>maintenance </strong>–n. to keep something such as a machine in good working condition</p>
<p><strong>regret </strong>–v. to wish something did not happen; to feel sorry that something was done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Big Space Missions Planned for 2024  (2024/1/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/big-space-missions-planned-for-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A series of new space <strong>missions</strong> are planned for the coming year. Here is a look ahead at some of the ones to watch out for in 2024.</p>
<p><strong>Artemis II</strong></p>
<p>The American space agency NASA launched its first flight in the Artemis program in 2022. That mission, called Artemis I, sent the Orion spacecraft on a trip to fly around the moon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration shows NASA's new rocket, the Space Launch System (SLS), in its Block 1 crew vehicle setup that will send astronauts to the Moon on the Artemis missions. For the rocket's first flight on the Artemis I mission, it will send an uncrewed Ori" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/AA0FC6C3-72C8-4326-BB20-8D8BC2BA7A3E_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration shows NASA's new rocket, the Space Launch System (SLS), in its Block 1 crew vehicle setup that will send astronauts to the Moon on the Artemis missions. For the rocket's first flight on the Artemis I mission, it will send an uncrewed Ori</span></div>
<p>Artemis aims to return astronauts to the moon for the first time since NASA's Apollo 17 mission in 1972.</p>
<p>Artemis I was a test of the Orion spacecraft, or capsule, as well as NASA's huge Space Launch System (SLS) rocket that carried it into space. That mission sent Orion more than 400,000 kilometers away from Earth and completed a close fly-by of the moon. NASA officials declared Artemis I a huge success.</p>
<p>NASA plans to launch Artemis II in late 2024. It is expected to take the same path that Artemis I took around the moon, but this time it will be carrying four NASA astronauts aboard Orion.</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission/artemis-ii/#artemis">says</a> Artemis II aims "to confirm all of the spacecraft's systems operate as designed with crew aboard in the actual environment of deep space."</p>
<p><strong>Moon lander launches</strong></p>
<p>While Artemis II will not complete a landing, several other lunar landers are expected to touch down on the moon's surface in 2024.</p>
<p>The first of these launches is planned for January 8. It involves a lander named Peregrine. The 1.9-meter-tall spacecraft is made by the private, American space company Astrobotic Technology. It will launch aboard a Vulcan Centaur rocket, made by United Launch Alliance (ULA).</p>
<p>Peregrine is expected to carry 20 research experiments to the moon for seven countries. It will aim to land in an area known as Sinus Viscositatis. NASA says the area sits next to the Gruithuisen Domes, the largest dark spot on the near side of the moon.</p>
<p>Another Astrobotic lander, called Griffin, is set to launch to the moon's south pole in late 2024. It will be carrying an exploring robot, or rover, called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/mission/viper/">VIPER</a>. VIPER is designed to search for water sources on the moon.</p>
<p>In addition to those, American space company <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.intuitivemachines.com/lunar-access-services">Intuitive Machines</a> is providing two landers to NASA expected for launches next year.</p>
<p>Japan will also attempt to become the fifth nation to reach the surface of the moon in mid-January. The country's space agency <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/what-is-the-goal-of-japan-s-new-moon-mission-/7259385.html">launched</a> the spacecraft, called SLIM, in September. SLIM's mission goal is to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets.</p>
<p><strong>ESA's Hera mission</strong></p>
<p>The European Space Agency (ESA) plans to launch its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Space_Safety/Hera">Hera</a> spacecraft in October on a mission to return to an <strong>asteroid</strong> system visited by NASA's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/new-studies-show-nasa-s-asteroid-crash-test-was-highly-successful/6998173.html">DART spacecraft</a> in 2022. Hera is designed to collect data on the targeted system, called Didymos. The spacecraft is expected to closely examine the physical properties of Didymos and measure detailed effects of DART's crash.</p>
<p><strong>Europa Clipper</strong></p>
<p>NASA hopes to launch its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://europa.nasa.gov/">Europa Clipper</a> mission in October. This orbiter is designed to carry out close examinations of Jupiter's moon Europa. Specifically, the mission will look for signs that the icy moon might hold the right conditions to support life. NASA says the orbiter will fly in orbit around Jupiter and "perform repeated close flybys of the ice moon."</p>
<p><strong>Boeing's Starliner test flight</strong></p>
<p>NASA and Boeing have said they plan to launch the first crewed test flight of the company's Starliner spacecraft. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/tag/starliner-spacecraft/">says</a> it is targeting March 2024 to have Starliner ready for flight. A launch date is to be set later.</p>
<p>The spacecraft completed its first uncrewed flight test to the International Space Station (ISS) last May. But Boeing has experienced several technical difficulties with Starliner during the mission and has worked with NASA to fix the problems as it prepares for the planned crewed flight.</p>
<p><strong>SpaceX Starship test</strong></p>
<p>SpaceX, another NASA partner, has been successfully using its rockets and spacecraft to transport astronauts and materials to the ISS since 2020. But the company will be seeking a successful test flight in 2024 for its super-heavy Starship spacecraft.</p>
<p>SpaceX experienced two failed Starship tests in 2023 – one in April and the other in November – which resulted in explosions. The April blast <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/spacex-s-test-of-huge-rocket-causes-major-damage-to-launch-structure/7069480.html">caused major damage</a> to the launch structure in the state of Texas. SpaceX has said it has been examining the issues related to the explosions and plans to carry out another test of Starship as soon as possible. But it will have to wait until the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) completes its investigation of the launch site damage and approves a new test.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse and NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Consumer Reports Finds ‘Widespread’ Plastics in Food  (2024/1/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/consumer-reports-finds-widespread-plastics-in-food.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>New research from the American non-profit organization Consumer Reports finds that plastics have a "widespread" presence in food. The group called on the United States government to examine<strong> </strong>the safety of food that comes into contact with plastics during production.</p>
<p>In a report released Thursday, Consumer Reports said that 84 out of 85 food products it recently tested contained "plasticizers" called phthalates. Phthalates are chemicals used to make plastic last longer.</p>
<p>The tested food came from <strong>supermarkets </strong>and restaurants.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Various plastic goods weighing 3.15 kilograms, which is equivalent to the amount of plastic that someone could eat in ten years, are displayed on a table in this illustration taken in Tokyo, Japan, March 31, 2020. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-efb1-08dc0e001d87_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Various plastic goods weighing 3.15 kilograms, which is equivalent to the amount of plastic that someone could eat in ten years, are displayed on a table in this illustration taken in Tokyo, Japan, March 31, 2020. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>The researchers also said 79 percent of the foods examined contained bisphenol A (BPA), another chemical found in plastic, and other bisphenols. But levels were lower than in tests done in 2009.</p>
<p>Consumer Reports said all the phthalate levels were within limits set by U.S. and European regulators. However, this does not mean the chemicals are safe to eat. Deciding acceptable levels for such chemicals in food is tricky. Officials in the U.S. and Europe have set limits for only bisphenol A (BPA) and a few phthalates. All the foods tested remained within the limits, the experts said.</p>
<p>However, does that mean it is safe to eat? The researchers say no.</p>
<p>Tunde Akinleye was the lead scientist in the food testing. He says many of the limits on the chemicals are not in line with the most current scientific knowledge, he reported.</p>
<p>"We don't feel <strong>comfortable</strong> saying these levels are okay," Akinleye said.</p>
<p>Phthalates and bisphenols can interfere with the body's production and release of estrogen and other hormones. That can lead to increased risk of birth <strong>defects</strong>, cancer, diabetes, reproductive problems, developmental disorders, and other health conditions.</p>
<p>Among the tested supermarket foods, Annie's Organic Cheesy Ravioli contained the most phthalates. Del Monte peaches and Chicken of the Sea pink salmon also were high in phthalates.</p>
<p>Increased phthalate levels were also found in products including Cheerios, Gerber baby food and Yoplait yogurt. And the researchers found increased levels in hamburger, chicken and potatoes from fast food restaurants Wendy's, Burger King, and McDonald's.</p>
<p>Consumer Reports also found some wide differences in levels among similar products. For example, some chicken from McDonald's contained four times more phthalates than a similar chicken product from Wendy's.</p>
<p>"That tells us that, as widespread as these chemicals are, there are ways to reduce how much is in our foods," said James Rogers. He supervises Consumer Reports' product safety testing.</p>
<p>Polar raspberry lime seltzer was the only tested product containing no phthalates.</p>
<p>General Mills produces brands including Annie's, Cheerios and Yoplait. The company did not immediately answer requests for comment. Burger King and Wendy's also did not immediately answer such requests.</p>
<p>Chicken of the Sea and Del Monte said they do not add phthalates to their food, and that their suppliers guarantee the same.</p>
<p>Del Monte added that phthalates are "widespread in the environment."</p>
<p>Gerber and McDonald's said they follow government rules connected to their products and require testing for food packaging as well.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>supermarket </strong><em>— n. </em>a store where customers can buy a variety of foods and usually household items</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>comfortable </strong><em>— adj. </em>not causing any physically unpleasant feelings</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>defect </strong><em>— n. </em>a problem or fault that makes someone or something not perfect</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Talking Robot Helps Seniors Fight Loneliness  (2024/1/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/talking-robot-helps-seniors-fight-loneliness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Joyce Loaiza lives alone in a community for older people in the American state of Florida. When she is home, the retired office worker often talks with a friendly female voice that asks about her day.</p>
<p>A few kilometers away, the same voice helped 83-year-old Deanna Dezern when her friend died. In New York state, it plays games and music for 92-year-old Marie Broadbent. And in Washington state, it helps 83-year-old Jan Worrell make new friends.</p>
<p>The women are some of the first in the United States to receive the robot ElliQ made by Intuition Robotics. The company and other officials say it is the only device using <strong>artificial</strong> <strong>intelligence</strong> (AI) to help older Americans from loneliness.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Joyce Loazia interacts with ElliQ, left, a tabletop device that uses artificial intelligence to conduct human-like conversations, during an interview in her apartment in a senior community in Coral Springs, Florida, on December 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ce3afd86-3d42-432d-b783-68b16ae7eb3e_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Joyce Loazia interacts with ElliQ, left, a tabletop device that uses artificial intelligence to conduct human-like conversations, during an interview in her apartment in a senior community in Coral Springs, Florida, on December 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)</span></div>
<p>"It's entertaining. You can <strong>actually</strong> talk to her," said Loaiza who is 81. Her ElliQ calls her "Jellybean" for no clear reason. She said, "She'll make comments like, ‘I would go outside if I had hands, but I can't hold an <strong>umbrella</strong>.'"</p>
<p>The device looks like a small table light and it has an eyeless, mouthless head that lights up and turns. It remembers each user's interests and their talks, helping create a special experience with each new discussion. They can be as deep as the meaning of life or as light as a small joke.</p>
<p>ElliQ also plays music and provides creative or spiritual sayings. On a video screen that comes with it, it will show different cities and places of interest. The device leads exercises, asks about the owner's health, and gives reminders to take medicines and drink water. It can also support video calls and contact family, friends, or doctors in an emergency.</p>
<p>Intuition Robotics says none of the conversations are heard by the company, with the information staying on each owner's device.</p>
<p>Intuition Robotics chief executive office Dor Skuler said the idea for ElliQ came before he launched his Israeli company eight years ago. His grandfather who lost his partner needed an aide, but the first did not work out. The next person, though, understood his grandfather's love of music and his special sense of humor.</p>
<p>Skuler then thought a robot could fill the space of a friend by <strong>adapting</strong> to each person and their interests. He said, "That just did not exist anywhere."</p>
<p>The average user <strong>interacts</strong> with ElliQ more than 30 times a day and more than 90 percent report lower levels of loneliness, Skuler said.</p>
<p>The robots are mostly sent out by state agencies in New York, Florida, Michigan, Nevada and Washington. But they can also be bought individually for $600 a year plus $250 to set it up. Skuler would not say how many ElliQs have been sent out so far, but the goal is to have more than 100,000 out within five years.</p>
<p>Brigham Young University professor Julianne Holt-Lunstad studies the effects of loneliness on health. Holt-Lunstad worries that a device like ElliQ might have short-term helpful effects but it could make people less likely to seek human contact. She told <em>The Associated Press</em> that the difficult feeling of loneliness should push people to reconnect socially.</p>
<p>Skuler and state officials agreed that ElliQ is not a replacement for human contact. But some older people cannot leave home or do not have many friends.</p>
<p>Greg Olsen is director of the New York State Office for the Aging. His office has sent out 750 of the 900 ElliQs it received. He said he wished that he could "make a person show up at the home of one of the many, many older adults that don't have any family or friends."</p>
<p>Charlotte Mather-Taylor is director of the Broward County, Florida, Area Agency on Aging. She said the COVID-19 pandemic and its aftermath left many older people more disconnected. Her agency has provided 300 ElliQs which, she believes, help the situation.</p>
<p>She said, "We've seen very <strong>positive</strong> results with it. People generally like her and she makes them smile and brings <strong>joy</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>artificial intelligence </strong>– <em>n.</em> an area of computer science that deals with giving machines the ability to seem like they have human intelligence</p>
<p><strong>actually </strong>– <em>n</em>. a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p><strong>umbrella </strong>– <em>n</em>. a device that is used for protection from the rain and sun</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong>– <em>v</em>. to change (something) so that it functions better or is better suited for a purpose</p>
<p><strong>interacts </strong><em>– v.</em> to talk or do things with other people or objects</p>
<p><strong>positive </strong><em>– adj.</em> good or useful</p>
<p><strong>joy </strong><em>– n.</em> a feeling of great happiness</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Singapore to End Cat Ban in Public Housing  (2024/1/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/singapore-to-end-cat-ban-in-public-housing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Sunny is a proud Singaporean citizen who follows the laws of her country. Mostly, anyway. For the last three years, she has been illegally sheltering a cat called Mooncake.</p>
<p>A 34-year-old Singaporean law bars cats from government-built housing. Such housing is where most of the city-state's population lives - and Mooncake too, although secretly.</p>
<p>Luckily for Sunny and her cat, Singapore plans to end the feline ban later this year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Owner Sunny Leong, 30, gives cat treats to her Ragdoll cat, Mooncake, in her Housing and Development Board (HDB) flat in Singapore December 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Edgar Su)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/69248d95-095b-4c29-b1b7-0f498cc9b3f9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Owner Sunny Leong, 30, gives cat treats to her Ragdoll cat, Mooncake, in her Housing and Development Board (HDB) flat in Singapore December 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Edgar Su)</span></div>
<p>The legal change will free Sunny from the threat of a $3,007 fine or her pet's possible removal.</p>
<p>The 30-year-old works in marketing and asked to be identified only by her first name for the security of her cat. She did not want to risk officials removing Sunny from her care.</p>
<p>She wonders about the reasoning behind the ban.</p>
<p>"Cats are so much quieter than dogs. If they allow dogs, I don't understand why not cats."</p>
<p>Officials rarely enforce the ban. And the law is only for the high-rise Housing and Development Board (HDB) buildings. Eighty percent of Singapore's 3.6 million people live in the buildings.</p>
<p>The ban does, however, make life difficult for cat owners. One problem they face is health care for their animals. Medical insurance cannot be provided for illegal pets.</p>
<p>Lawmaker Louis Ng campaigned to end the ban. He said the law sometimes becomes part of disputes between neighbors.</p>
<p>"A lot of times, the cats are <strong>collateral</strong> when there's neighborly disputes," he said. One neighbor will threaten to tell police about another neighbor's cat.</p>
<p>Established in 1960, the HDB plan sells government-built housing directly to citizens for 99-year special agreements. The policy has led to one of the world's highest home-ownership rates. Still, people who live in the buildings are subject to many restrictions and laws.</p>
<p>Cats were permitted in HDB apartments until 1989 when lawmakers changed the housing law. On its website, the HDB says cats are difficult to keep contained in individual homes. It also says that cats drop hairs and other body waste in public areas and can be loud.</p>
<p>It is not clear what made the Singapore government decide to end the cat ban. But a 2022 government public opinion study may have been the turning point. The study results showed 9 out of 10 Singaporeans believed that cats were fit to keep as pets, including in HDB buildings.</p>
<p>Officials are requesting public input on a proposed cat management policy.</p>
<p>Dogs have not been subject to a similar ban, but they are limited to one per household. And, only some kinds of dogs are permitted.</p>
<p>Market research company Euromonitor International has predicted a big increase in cat ownership. It estimated Singapore's current pet population at around 94,000 cats and 113,000 dogs.</p>
<p>Lawmaker Ng, who ran an animal aid group before joining parliament in 2015, also hopes the change will lead more people to adopt rescued cats.</p>
<p>Under the new rules, HDB homeowners would be limited to two pet cats. The rules also require owners to register their pets with the government. The owners must also get special identifying electronic devices for the animals. And, owners must install protective devices on windows so cats do not get out.</p>
<p>Some cat lovers say the new laws do not go far enough.</p>
<p>Thenuga Vijakumar from the Cat Welfare Society wants the law to require <strong>sterilization</strong>. Another cat rescuer, Chan Chow Wah, urges officials to punish irresponsible owners. He said he had to take care of a cat that fell from a high window in one home. The owners refused to pay its medical bills. Wah also took care of another cat that was abandoned because he had heart disease.</p>
<p>"I end up taking over these cases. Basically, I look after them until they pass away," said Chan, estimating he spent $45,100 on cat medical expenses in 2022.</p>
<p>But for many cat owners the law will bring peace of mind.</p>
<p>Including Mooncake's: "I think it's a good thing and it's a step forward after 30 years," Sunny said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Xinghui Kok reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>collateral </strong><em>– n.</em> indirect damage that happens to someone or something that is not directly involved in a dispute or war</p>
<p><strong>sterilize </strong><em>– v.</em> to make (someone or something) unable to produce children or young animals</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Harvard President’s Ouster Leads to Concerns about Academic Freedom  (2024/1/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/harvard-president-s-ouster-leads-to-concerns-about-academic-freedom.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Harvard University's Claudine Gay recently became the second Ivy League president to step down under pressure from <strong>alumni</strong>, political activists and supporters of the University.</p>
<p>Gay was the first Black president of Harvard and second woman to lead the university. She started the job only six months ago.</p>
<p>Gay and two other presidents were widely criticized after making controversial comments to the U.S. Congress in December.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Harvard University President Claudine Gay speaks during a hearing of the House Committee on Education on Capitol Hill, Dec. 5, 2023, in Washington. Gay resigned Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Mark Schiefelbein, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ea3c2eae-4b8c-447a-9cbb-147fb1eec11c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Harvard University President Claudine Gay speaks during a hearing of the House Committee on Education on Capitol Hill, Dec. 5, 2023, in Washington. Gay resigned Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Mark Schiefelbein, File)</span></div>
<p>Gay, along with Sally Kornbluth of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Liz Magill of the University of Pennsylvania, were called to Washington to discuss American lawmakers' concerns about antisemitism on college <strong>campuses</strong>. Antisemitism is the hatred of Jewish people.</p>
<p>The U.S. House of Representatives' Committee on Education chose the presidents because their schools had "been at the center of the rise in antisemitic protests," a committee spokesperson said in a statement.</p>
<p>The protests were related to the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas.</p>
<p>Harvard graduate Elise Stefanik of New York is part of the Republican-led committee. She asked each university leader about how their school would react to calls to kill large numbers of Jews, something described as genocide.</p>
<p>Stefanik asked Magill: "Does calling for the genocide of Jews violate Penn's rules or <strong>code of conduct</strong>? Yes or no?" Penn is the University of Pennsylvania, a member of the Ivy League.</p>
<p>She asked the same question of Gay and Kornbluth.</p>
<p>None of the school leaders were able to clearly say calling for the death of Jews violated school rules.</p>
<p>The presidents were sharply criticized for their lack of clarity. Within a few days, influential members of the University of Pennsylvania community pushed Magill to resign.</p>
<p>For a time, it looked as if Gay's job was safe. She received support from some notable professors at Harvard, including legal scholar Laurence Tribe.</p>
<p>Tribe said "it is dangerous for universities to be ... <strong>bullied</strong> into <strong>micromanaging</strong> their policies." He was talking about the way some activists and politicians seemed to be pushing the universities toward their <strong>preferred</strong> result.</p>
<p>One of those activists is Christopher Rufo. Rufo is a member of the leadership group that oversees New College of Florida. With the support of Governor Ron DeSantis, Rufo and others have been pushing the small college to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/small-florida-college-worries-about-government-involvement/7037843.html">change its <strong>curriculum</strong></a>.</p>
<p>After Gay announced her resignation on January 2, Rufo wrote words of celebration on X, formerly known as Twitter. He and other conservatives believe American higher education has too many liberal people in leadership roles.</p>
<p>Gay's position at Harvard looked safe in December. So what changed?</p>
<p>In the weeks following the congressional hearing, some critics charged Gay with using "duplicative language" in academic writing. To duplicate means to make an exact copy of something.</p>
<p>They also said Gay had plagiarized -- or claimed others' writing as her own.</p>
<p>The charges, however, did not come from those working in higher education. They came from people like Rufo who are working to push out higher education leaders they do not agree with.</p>
<p>At first, Harvard said it did not consider Gay's work to be "intentional or <strong>reckless</strong>." But pressure continued.</p>
<p>Many observers believe the conservative activists felt Gay only received Harvard's presidency because she was a Black woman.</p>
<p>On X, Rufo wrote that he was establishing a "plagiarism hunting fund" as a way to oust university leaders and bring attention to the "<strong>rot</strong> in the Ivy League."</p>
<p>Gay wrote a letter to the Harvard community announcing she was leaving her position "with a heavy heart." She also said it was frightening to be attacked due to her race. Gay said she would remain at Harvard as a professor.</p>
<p><strong>Plagiarism complaints as a tool</strong></p>
<p>Academic experts who have been following the pressure campaign on Gay say the plagiarism accusations only came after it looked like she would not lose her job.</p>
<p>They worry that people who do not like the leaders of major American universities will now research their academic writing in search of duplications and poor citations.</p>
<p>Davarian Baldwin is a historian at Trinity College in Hartford, Connecticut. He writes about race and higher education. Baldwin said Gay made mistakes in her writing and noted that anti-plagiarism software will make it easy for critics to find problematic writing by college leaders and professors.</p>
<p>The tools are designed to help educators learn whether their students' writings are their own. But Baldwin said the tools can be dangerous if they fall into the hands of people who want to argue that academia is full of corrupt and incompetent people. Incompetent means someone lacks the ability to do something well.</p>
<p>Irene Mulvey is president of the American Association of University Professors. She said plagiarism investigations could be "weaponized" to push out presidents.</p>
<p>She said she is concerned that conservative activists will use the successful campaign against Gay as a method to push out other academic leaders.</p>
<p>"For presidents to be taken down like this, it does not <strong>bode</strong> <strong>well</strong> for academic freedom," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>alumni </strong><em>–n.</em> the people who graduated from a school or university</p>
<p><strong>campus </strong><em>–n. </em>the physical location of a college or university's buildings</p>
<p><strong>code of conduct </strong><em>–n.</em> rules on how to participate in a group, such as how to be a student at a university</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>–v.</em> to frighten, hurt, or threaten (a smaller or weaker person) : to act like a bully toward (someone)</p>
<p><strong>micromanage </strong><em>–v.</em> to try to control all parts of something usually in a way that is not wanted</p>
<p><strong>preferred </strong><em>–adj.</em> the better choice among multiple things</p>
<p><strong>curriculum </strong><em>–n.</em> a study plan set up for students by a professor or school</p>
<p><strong>preferred </strong><em>–adj.</em> the better choice among multiple things</p>
<p><strong>rot </strong><em>–n.</em> decay or lack of health</p>
<p><strong>bode well </strong><em>–v.</em> to feel positive about the future of something</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you think university presidents should be worried about their jobs?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Do You Color Inside or Outside the Lines?  (2024/1/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/do-you-color-inside-or-outside-the-lines.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today, let's talk about a common art activity – coloring.</p>
<p>Coloring books are common objects of play and learning for children around the world. In recent years, coloring books for adults have grown popular too.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A dandelion crayon character poses for photos during a Crayola event in New York's Times Square, March 31, 2017. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/66C958B8-DA6D-4173-BAC7-63478F1ED3C9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A dandelion crayon character poses for photos during a Crayola event in New York's Times Square, March 31, 2017. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>Children usually color with wax sticks called crayons. But, you can also use color markers, pens, and pencils.</p>
<p>Adding color to black and white images is fun and often calming. You just choose a color and fill in the space created by the lines. In fact, children are often taught to stay inside the lines when they color.</p>
<p>Apparently, this idea does not come naturally. Child development experts say very young children begin by <strong>scribbling</strong> on a coloring page. They do not pay attention to the lines of the picture. The result is a colorful but often <strong>messy</strong> looking picture.</p>
<p>Then between the ages of two and five they start coloring inside the lines. This progression shows an improvement in many skills: fine motor skills, hand-eye <strong>coordination</strong>, space and object <strong>awareness</strong>, and more.</p>
<p>Many children are taught to color inside the lines. As a result, many adults do the same. This makes this finished artwork look more organized and proper because you followed the images' guide lines.</p>
<p>That is why the expression <u>coloring inside the lines</u> means to think or act within generally accepted guidelines. If you color inside the lines, you follow the rules. You <u>stay in the lines</u> or you <u>play by the book</u> (not the coloring book ... but the rule book).</p>
<p>We can also say you <u>stick to the script</u>. A script contains the spoken words performers must say out-loud in a play, movie, or show. Sticking to the script means you do not change the lines you are given.</p>
<p>Such people can also be said to <u>toe the line</u>. That expression comes from foot racing.</p>
<p>On the other hand, people who <u>color outside the lines</u> do not follow rules. They are rebels. Rebels reject rules. They color outside the lines and <u>think outside the box</u>. Instead of sticking to the script they <u>go off script</u>. They <strong>improvise</strong>.</p>
<p>Just as with rule-followers, we have just as many word phrases and expressions for rule-breakers. They<u> break new ground</u>. They are ground-breakers. They <strong><u>buck</u></strong><u> traditions.</u> Used as a verb this way, "buck" means to oppose or resist.</p>
<p>Next time you want describe these two kinds of people you will have plenty of expressions to choose from!</p>
<p>And that's the end of this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo!</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scribbling </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>a piece of writing or a drawing that is done quickly or carelessly</p>
<p><strong>messy </strong><em>– adj. </em>lacking neatness or precision</p>
<p><strong>coordination </strong><em>– n. </em>the harmonious functioning of parts for effective results</p>
<p><strong>awareness </strong><em>– n. </em>knowledge and understanding that something is happening or exists</p>
<p><strong>improvise </strong><em>– v.</em></p>
<p><strong>buck</strong> <em>– v.</em> oppose, resist : <em>bucking the system</em></p>
<p><strong>mold </strong><em>– n. </em>the frame on, around, or in which something is constructed or shaped</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Chilean Grandmother Is a Top Video Game Player  (2024/1/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/chilean-grandmother-is-a-top-video-game-player.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Few players of the online video game Free Fire know that one of their top opponents is an 81-year-old grandmother from rural Chile.</p>
<p>From her professional gaming chair at home in a small village, Maria Elena Arevalo becomes a hunter. She shoots down opponents in a game in which tens of millions of players fight to survive on an imaginary island.</p>
<p>Arevalo does not look like her online <strong>character</strong> "Mami Nena." That is the <strong>nickname</strong> she got from her only grandson, Hector Carrasco who is 20.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mar&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;237;a Elena Ar&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;233;valo, 81, plays Free Fire, a popular online video game, at home at her home in Llay-Llay, Valparaiso Region, Chile, on Dec. 19, 2023. (Photo by Pablo Vera / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3777-08dc082fad3b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mar<i>&amp;#</i>237;a Elena Ar<i>&amp;#</i>233;valo, 81, plays Free Fire, a popular online video game, at home at her home in Llay-Llay, Valparaiso Region, Chile, on Dec. 19, 2023. (Photo by Pablo Vera / AFP)</span></div>
<p>It was Carrasco who introduced Arevalo to the digital world of gaming. It has given her a new excitement for life after falling into deep loneliness following the death of her husband of 56 years in 2020.</p>
<p>"I didn't even know what a <strong>mouse</strong> was," she told AFP at her home in the town of Llay-Llay in central Chile.</p>
<p>"Afterwards, I got excited. We started to play whenever [Carrasco] could. I felt better because I didn't think so much about my late husband anymore."</p>
<p>At first "I didn't want to hurt anyone," she added, but with time, she grew more competitive.</p>
<p>Today, Arevalo plays at the "Heroic" level. That is just one level below the highest "Grandmaster" level, which only 300 players compete in. She has 4 million followers on social media service TikTok and 650,000 on YouTube, where she shares tips with fellow players.</p>
<p>Last year, she visited Mexico City as a Free Fire ambassador for the game's anniversary celebrations. The cost-free trip was her first outside of Chile.</p>
<p>"All the kids asked me for <strong>autographs</strong>...It was beautiful. The day I die, I'll take that with me," she said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Arevalo was named one of Chile's 100 most important older people by the <em>El Mercurio</em> newspaper and the Catholic University for helping break down age <strong>stereotypes</strong>.</p>
<p>"It's totally cool, and...I feel like she's like my best friend," Carrasco said of his famous grandmother.</p>
<p>Three years after starting to play Free Fire, Arevalo said she no longer feels lonely. But a recent study found that nearly half of people over 80 in Chile say they feel lonely.</p>
<p>Older people are finding comfort in gaming. For example, a Ukrainian team known as "Young Guard" are strong Counter Strike competitors. A 93-year-old Japanese named Hamako Mori is thought to be the oldest gamer in the world. She is also known by her alias Gamer Grandma.</p>
<p>For Arevalo, gaming is becoming harder for her because of a worsening skin condition. But she is not planning to slow down.</p>
<p>"I love doing this. I'll keep going as far as I can," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Agence France-Presse. </em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>character </strong>–n. someone who appears in books, movies, stories or games</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nickname </strong><em>— n.</em> a names that is different from a real name but is used by family or friends</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mouse </strong><em>— n. (computer) </em>a device used to control a computer by pointing to images on a screen</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>autograph </strong><em>— n.</em> the name of a person writing in their own handwriting</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stereotype </strong><em>— n. </em>a believe that people all people of a certain group have one or more qualities that are usually considered bad or undesirable</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Donald Trump: Unusual  (2024/1/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/americas-presidents-donald-trump.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Donald Trump, the 45th U.S. president. He was elected in 2016. Because his presidency is so new, this program will not discuss his time in office.</p>
<p>Instead, it will discuss his early life.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Donald Trump" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-cd80-08dbfb46f4ba_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Donald Trump</span></div>
<p>And it will note a few ways that Trump's background is unusual compared to most U.S. presidents.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Donald Trump was born in Queens, a <strong>borough</strong> of New York City. He was the fourth child. He had two brothers and two sisters.</p>
<p>His mother had been born in Scotland. His father, whose relatives were German, became a successful businessman in New York.</p>
<p>Donald and his two brothers helped their father in the family business. At the time, the business was called Elizabeth Trump and Son, after his grandmother and father. The work related to building, buying, and managing property.</p>
<p>By his <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/decades-later-disagreement-over-young-trumps-military-academy-post/2016/01/09/907a67b2-b3e0-11e5-a842-0feb51d1d124_story.html?utm_term=.6adc0c8e23c5">own telling</a>, young Donald often created trouble in school. So when he was 13 years old, his parents sent him to a military-style school.</p>
<p>Donald said that, for the most part, he enjoyed the experience. Other students there remembered him as a good baseball player, as popular with girls, and as someone who wanted to succeed.</p>
<p>Trump went on to college first at Fordham University in New York, and then at the University of Pennsylvania. He earned a degree in economics.</p>
<p>He was also already investing in real estate. After he graduated, Trump quickly returned to New York City and his career.</p>
<p>In time, he became the head of the family business. He re-named it the Trump Organization. As its president, Trump developed and put his name on luxury buildings, casinos, hotels, and golf courses around the world.</p>
<p>Later, he became linked to the entertainment industry, too. He became a part owner of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.missuniverse.com/missusa/competition" target="_blank">beauty pageants</a>, hosted a <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0364782/" target="_blank">television show</a>, and wrote a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1032.Trump" target="_blank">book</a> about how to succeed in business.</p>
<p>During those years, Trump also married three times and divorced twice. The media <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.newsweek.com/donald-trumps-family-life-654724" target="_blank">wrote</a> especially about his first and second marriages because he openly had a relationship with his second wife while he was married to his first.</p>
<p>In 2005, he married <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/people/melania-trump/">Melania Knauss</a>, a former <strong>model</strong> from Slovenia. She is only the second first lady who was not born in the United States. The first was <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/meet-the-first-and-only-foreign-born-first-lady-louisa-cathernine-adams-180959149/">Louisa Adams</a>, who came from Britain in 1801.</p>
<p>All together, Trump has three sons and two daughters.</p>
<p>Because Trump has been a public figure for most of his life, many Americans were familiar with him before he ran for president.</p>
<p>To some, he is linked to success in business and <strong>branding</strong>.</p>
<p>To others, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/trump/life-presidency">notes</a> journalist Jackie Calmes, he is linked to <strong>debt</strong> and legal battles.</p>
<p>But, until he officially entered the 2016 campaign as a Republican candidate, few linked him to politics.</p>
<p>Trump is <a class="wsw__a" href="#https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/onpolitics/2016/11/08/donald-trump-experience-president/93504134/">unusual</a> among past presidents in that he had never worked in the government before. Nor has Trump served in the military. Only Presidents <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-zachary-taylor/3836070.html" target="_blank">Taylor</a>, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-ulysses-grant/3920036.html" target="_blank">Grant</a>, and<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-dwight-eisenhower/4076083.html" target="_blank"> Eisenhower</a> had no past government experience; however, they had all been generals.</p>
<p>During the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/trump-republican-nomination/3429185.html">campaign</a> for president, other candidates spent money to buy advertising. But Trump spread his message on free television, radio and social media.</p>
<p>Trump won the Republican nomination over 16 candidates. He went on to defeat Democratic Party nominee Hillary Clinton to win the presidency.</p>
<p>Trump was 70 years old when he was sworn in.</p>
<p>Trump was unusual in how he communicated with the public. As a president, he continued to use Twitter, now known as X, to communicate his thoughts directly to anyone who wanted to follow him.</p>
<p>Many earlier presidents also used changes in technology to interact with the public. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-president-woodrow-wilson/4001252.html" target="_blank">Woodrow Wilson</a> was the first to hold press conferences regularly with reporters. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html" target="_blank">Franklin Roosevelt</a> famously spoke to Americans on the radio. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-john-kennedy/4085635.html" target="_blank">John F. Kennedy</a> – and later <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-richard-nixon/4107568.html" target="_blank">Richard Nixon</a> – are credited with using television to their advantage.</p>
<p>While the long-term effects of Trump's presidency are not yet known, he will likely be remembered in part for his direct and <strong>unscripted</strong> style of communication.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this report for Learning English. Hai Do was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>borough</strong> - <em>n.</em> one of the five political divisions of New York City</p>
<p><strong>model</strong> -<em> n.</em> someone who is paid to wear clothing and jewelry so that people will see and want to buy what is being worn</p>
<p><strong>branding</strong> -<em> n. </em>promoting a product or service by linking it with a name</p>
<p><strong>debt </strong>- <em>n.</em> money that is owed</p>
<p><strong>broadcast</strong> - <em>v. </em>made public</p>
<p><strong>unscripted</strong> - <em>adj. </em>not written or planned at an earlier time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ahead of Lunar New Year, Chinese Debate Fireworks Ban  (2024/1/6) | 春节前夕烟花爆竹禁燃令引发国人热议</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/ahead-of-lunar-new-year-chinese-debate-fireworks-ban.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Chinese lawmakers recently entered a fierce online debate on whether fireworks should be used to celebrate the Lunar New year this February. They said a total ban on fireworks in the country credited with inventing the noisemakers would be hard to enforce.<br/>
中国立法者最近加入了网上一场对今年2月是否应该燃放烟花爆竹庆祝农历新年的激烈辩论。他们表示，全面禁止燃放烟花爆竹在一个被认为发明了这种热闹玩意的国家将很难执行。</p>
<p>Lawmakers said air pollution prevention and fire safety laws have led to "differences in understanding" of the ban on fireworks. However, it was never a total ban.<br/>
立法者表示，大气污染防治和消防安全法导致了对烟花爆竹禁令的“理解分歧”。然而，它从来都不是一项全面的禁令。</p>
<p>In 2017, official data showed 444 cities had banned fireworks. Since then, some of the cities have loosened the bans. They permit fireworks at certain times of the year and at special places.<br/>
官方数据显示，2017年有444个城市禁止燃放烟花爆竹。从那时起，一些城市放松了禁令。他们允许在一年中的特定时间和特殊地点燃放烟花。</p>
<p>This month, however, many counties made announcements banning fireworks, restarting discussion on the ban.<br/>
然而，本月许多县宣布禁止燃放烟花爆竹，重新引发了有关禁令的讨论。</p>
<p>"We've the right to fireworks," wrote a user of Weibo, a popular Chinese online discussion service.<br/>
“我们有权利燃放烟花，”中国流行的在线讨论网站微博的一位用户写道。</p>
<p>Chinese folklore says the earliest fireworks were invented 2,000 years ago to drive away the "nian." The nian, the story goes, was a monster that hunted people and animals before the Lunar New Year, or Spring Festival.<br/>
中国民间传说称，最早的烟花是2000年前发明用来驱赶“年兽”。据说，年兽是一种在农历新年或春节前猎杀人和动物的怪物。</p>
<p>Since then, fireworks came to be used to celebrate other events.<br/>
从那时起，烟花开始被用来庆祝其他活动。</p>
<p>Some Chinese say the fireworks bans were necessary to protect the environment.<br/>
一些中国人说，为了保护环境，禁止燃放烟花爆竹是必要的。</p>
<p>An online opinion study by the official Beijing Youth Daily found that over 80 percent of people supported fireworks during Spring Festival. The festival is the most important holiday on the Chinese calendar.<br/>
官方的《北京青年报》在网上进行的一项民意调查发现，超过80%的人支持春节期间燃放烟花爆竹。这个节日是中国日历上最重要的节日。</p>
<p>Some also said the ban was ironic after the United Nations recently named the Spring Festival an official holiday, a move supported by Chinese officials.<br/>
一些人还表示，这项禁令颇具讽刺意味，因为联合国最近将春节定为官方节日，这一举措得到了中国官员的支持。</p>
<p>"The Spring Festival belongs to the world, but China's is almost gone," wrote another Weibo user.<br/>
另一位微博用户写道：“春节属于世界，但中国的春节（传统）几乎已经消失了。”</p>
<p>Southern Hunan province is a worldwide supplier of fireworks. Its exports totaled $579 million from January to November, state media reported. That number is far greater than domestic sales.<br/>
湖南省是世界性的烟花供应商。据官方媒体报道，今年1月到11月，湖南烟花出口总额为5.79亿美元。这个数字远远超过国内销售额。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ugandan Homemade Drink Threatened by Bill, Market Changes  (2024/1/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/ugandan-homemade-drink-threatened-by-bill-market-changes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Lawmakers in Uganda are considering barring people from making a popular alcoholic drink at home.</p>
<p>The bill being considered would affect people like the Ndyanabo family.</p>
<p>At least once a week, Girino Ndyanabo's family gathers around a hole in the ground where bananas have been left to <strong>ripen</strong>. The family then <strong>peels</strong> the bananas and puts them into a wooden container shaped like a boat. The father steps in with his bare feet. The sweet banana juice he presses out is then <strong>filtered</strong>. To this he adds sorghum. The juice is then left to <strong>ferment</strong> for up to a day. This process changes the juice into an alcoholic drink.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Ndyanabo family peels bananas used for Tonto and throws them into a wooden vat carved like a boat in Mbarara, Uganda, Dec. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8e19-08dc0ca91945_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Ndyanabo family peels bananas used for Tonto and throws them into a wooden vat carved like a boat in Mbarara, Uganda, Dec. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)</span></div>
<p>The result is the home-<strong>brewed</strong> drink Ugandans call tonto, or tontomera. This word describes a drinker's poor movements.</p>
<p>Tonto is famous in Uganda. Everyone drinks it – from officials to laborers. Singers sing about it. Politicians seeking office drink it with voters. And traditional ceremonies end at sunset with tonto parties.</p>
<p>However, there are threats to the way tonto is currently produced. More people are now drinking low-cost bottled beer. Health officials want rules to limit the risks from <strong>contaminated</strong> home brews. And officials want to get tax income from the production and sale of the drink.</p>
<p>The bill in the national assembly seeks to set rules for the production and sale of alcohol. It would make the activities of home brewers of tonto a crime. It would also make the production of other traditional home brews in the East African country a crime.</p>
<p>But farmers have a more urgent concern: Not enough new banana juice <strong>cultivars</strong> are being planted to produce the drink.</p>
<p>Instead, more farmers are planting a different sort of banana. This kind is boiled and eaten as a popular dish called matooke.</p>
<p>Girino Ndyanabo farms in the western district of Mbarara. His first experience with tonto was as a little boy in the 1970s. He said he has only a few plants left of the cultivars he uses to make tonto.</p>
<p>He gets his bananas from farmers near him until he can fill the small pit on his farm. The natural underground heat ripens the bananas within days as he prepares for the weekly pressing. The event is important in the family's daily life because they sell tonto.</p>
<p>Ndyanabo said his weekly brew has regular buyers. But in recent years, he has seen both demand and supply slow. This is partly because the sale price of tonto has been largely unchanged for many years.</p>
<p>However, the process of brewing it has become more difficult. Tonto brewers must travel farther for their bananas. Also, the price of sorghum has gone up.</p>
<p>"You take a lot of time doing this work. It's not as easy as someone who cuts matooke, puts it on a bicycle and sells it for cash immediately," Ndyanabo said of the green bananas that are eaten raw by most Ugandans. The bananas used for alcohol come from very far, he added.</p>
<p>To help this situation, he has been trying to plant more of the banana juice cultivars. They grow faster. And his son, Mathias Kamukama, helps.</p>
<p>The family makes five or six 20-liter<strong> jerricans</strong> for each brewing. A jerrican's worth sells for about $8. A half-liter of tonto sells for about 27 cents, compared to 67 cents for the cheapest bottled beer.</p>
<p>Benson Muhereza is an electrician who regularly visits a small drinking place in a poor neighborhood of Mbarara.</p>
<p>"It (is) like a favorite drink when you have your lunch. It (is) like a juice. When you don't want to take beer, you come and have your tonto," Muhereza said.</p>
<p>He said it does not make him feel bad or cause his head to hurt.</p>
<p>Christine Kyomuhangi sells tonto. She said she receives two jerricans of the brew every day. She knows her business is at risk because of the bill. But she smiled, saying buyers come from all over the city.</p>
<p>"Tonto will never get finished," she added, meaning tonto will survive all of these challenges.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Rodney Muhumuza reported this story for the Associated Press. Anna Matteo adapted this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ripen </strong><em>–v</em>. when a fruit becomes ready to eat</p>
<p><strong>filter </strong><em>–v.</em> to take solid things out of a liquid using a filter</p>
<p><strong>peel </strong><em>–v.</em> to remove the skin from a fruit or vegetable</p>
<p><strong>ferment</strong> <em>–v.</em> to process certain foods such as fruit or grains so that yeast breaks down the starch in the plant to make alcohol; to change the quality of a food by adding bacteria</p>
<p><strong>brew<em> </em></strong><em>–v. </em>to add microorganisms to food to change its nature and preserve it for a future time</p>
<p><strong>contaminated</strong> <em>–adj.</em><em> </em>containing something that should not be there</p>
<p><strong>cultivar </strong><em>- n</em> a sort of plant that is one of several versions of closely related plants which gardeners or farmers grow</p>
<p><strong>jerrican </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind of container that has flat sides and is usually used to carry liquids</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Does Slender Mean?  (2024/1/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/what-does-slender-mean.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Nirmala about the meaning of the word "slender."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello Teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: What Does Slender Mean? " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8cb4-08dc0d53a6ab_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: What Does Slender Mean? </span></div>
<p>I'm Nirmala.</p>
<p>What does the word "slender" mean?</p>
<p>Thank you,</p>
<p>Nirmala</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing to us, Nirmala!</p>
<p>As the year starts, many people make new goals. A large number of them center on losing weight. This is a great time for this question! We will talk about the word "slender" and offer some <strong>synonyms</strong> to help you compare and understand this word better.</p>
<p><strong>Slender</strong></p>
<p>The word "slender" is an adjective.</p>
<p>The first meaning has to do with body shape. Something slender is small around, especially in comparison to its length. A slender person has no extra fat and little roundness, usually in an appealing way.</p>
<p>In other words, slender has a positive <strong>connotation </strong>when used to describe a person. The word "skinny" on the other hand, suggests an underweight condition that is not appealing.</p>
<p><em>The slender girl could walk through the narrow opening in the fence. </em></p>
<p><em>Many cultures considered a long, slender neck beautiful.</em></p>
<p>Some synonyms that you can use in place of "slender" include "slim," "lean" and "thin." These words all have a more positive association to them than "skinny." But what separates them from "slender" is the idea that "slender" also includes the association of "<strong>graceful</strong>."</p>
<p>Slender can also be used to describe non-physical things.</p>
<p><em>The mayoral candidate won by a slender number of votes. </em></p>
<p>In that sentence, slender means small.</p>
<p><em>Spending money is slender just before payday. </em></p>
<p>In that one, it means limited.</p>
<p><em>The slender glass tube was all that protected the rare <strong>sample</strong>.</em></p>
<p>In that last sentence, slender means small but also suggests a delicate, or easily breakable, quality.</p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Nirmala.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>synonym </strong><em>–</em> <em>n</em>. a word that is similar in meaning to another word</p>
<p><strong>connotation</strong><em> – n. </em>the feelings or ideas that words give in addition to their meanings</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– n. </em>a part (as a set of individuals chosen from a whole population) used for investigating the whole</p>
<p><strong>graceful </strong><em>– n. </em>n form or action: pleasing or attractive in line, proportion, or movement</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Forest Service Moving Trees to Save Them  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/forest-service-moving-trees-to-save-them.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Some important tree species native to the northwestern states in the U.S. are no longer growing well because of climate change.</p>
<p>As conditions change in states such as Washington, Oregon and California, trees such as the Douglas fir, Western red cedar, giant sequoia and redwood may need to move -- with the help of humans.</p>
<p>Some of the trees do not do well when temperatures rise. Others suffer during times of <strong>drought</strong>. The goal is to move the trees to areas where the climate might more <strong>suitable</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - City of Bellevue Forest Management Program Supervisor Rick Bailey holds a juvenile giant sequoia in his hands on Oct. 11, 2022, in Bellevue, Wash. (AP Photo/Manuel Valdes, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6951398f-6af4-4e04-b34b-83543276db37_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - City of Bellevue Forest Management Program Supervisor Rick Bailey holds a juvenile giant sequoia in his hands on Oct. 11, 2022, in Bellevue, Wash. (AP Photo/Manuel Valdes, File)</span></div>
<p>Forest scientists are generally in favor of moving the trees so they do not die out. However, not all of the scientists agree on the best way to do it.</p>
<p>There are three ways to move trees: assisted population <strong>migration</strong>, assisted species migration and <strong>range</strong> expansion.</p>
<p>Assisted population migration involves scientists moving a tree's seeds within its current growing range. Assisted species migration involves scientists moving a species far from its existing area. In this case, that would include moving redwoods and sequoias from California to Washington.</p>
<p>The third way, range expansion, moves trees just outside their current growing range. Each way has different results for the trees and other animals and insects that depend on the trees.</p>
<p>Michael Case is a forest <strong>ecologist</strong> at the Nature Conservancy in Virginia. He said "there is a huge difference" among the different migration methods.</p>
<p>He said the risk of failure increases "whenever you plant something in an area where it is not <strong>locally</strong> found." He said the risk is not only to the trees. There is also the risk of causing problems in the ecosystem.</p>
<p>Case is working on an assisted population migration program with Douglas fir and Western hemlock trees. He is testing whether the trees, originally from drier parts of the northwest, can do well in western Washington where there is a drought. His organization believes that assisted population migration has fewer risks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Forest Service also takes part in assisted population migration programs. Dr. David Lytle is the agency's deputy chief for research and development. He said the agency is "very very <strong>cautious</strong>" about moving plants outside of their "historic range."</p>
<p>Douglas Tallamy is a professor of entomology and wildlife ecology at the University of Delaware. He said one worry about species migration is that local caterpillars might not eat the leaves of trees that are new to the area. The caterpillars serve as food for birds and other animals, so they must have a good food source.</p>
<p>Although the concerns are documented, the city of Portland, Oregon, is working on a species migration project for 11 tree species. The project includes three oak trees: California black oak, canyon live oak and interior live oak. Tallamy said oak trees are among the most important in North America. "When you move them out of range," he said, "the things that are <strong>adapted</strong> to eating them no longer have access to them."</p>
<p>The city <strong>responded</strong> to questions from the Associated Press, and said it is using guidelines "from universities, state and federal sources" and more, in its project.</p>
<p>Another group working on species migration projects in the northwest is called PropagationNation. To propagate means to produce a new plant through the use of seeds or parts of another plant.</p>
<p>That organization is planting non-local trees around the Seattle, Washington area in hopes that they will start growing in places where Western red cedar, Western hemlock and big leaf maple are having trouble.</p>
<p>David Milarch is the leader of a group in Michigan that supports keeping old trees alive. It is called Archangel Ancient Tree Archive. Milarch said the hope is to permit redwoods and sequoias to grow in areas to the north. The hope is not to <strong>replace</strong> native trees.</p>
<p>He said his group hopes the trees "will still be here in 100 to 200 years and not join the list of trees that are going <strong>extinct</strong>."</p>
<p>The organizations that are not practicing widely accepted methods for moving species feel like the risks are worth it.</p>
<p>But Robert Slesak is not sure about either practice. He oversees population migration sites run by the U.S. Forest Service in California, Oregon and Washington.</p>
<p>He said he has concerns about assisted species migrations and assisted population migrations that lack experimental <strong>rigor</strong>. Rigor describes an activity that has been tested with high standards.</p>
<p>He said all of the ideas about how to move trees should follow experiments that have already produced strong results.</p>
<p>"Everyone knows we need to do some kind of action related to climate, but there's a real risk of making it worse."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a dry weather period</p>
<p><strong>suitable </strong><em>–adj.</em> comfortable or correct</p>
<p><strong>migration </strong><em>–n.</em> the movement of something to a new place</p>
<p><strong>range </strong><em>–n.</em> the usual area of land covered by a plant or tree (in this case)</p>
<p><strong>ecologist </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who studies living things and their environment</p>
<p><strong>locally </strong><em>–adj.</em> a small area where something is originally found</p>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>–adj.</em> careful or concerned</p>
<p><strong>adapted </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that has changed and now functions in a new place</p>
<p><strong>respond </strong><em>–v.</em> to answer</p>
<p><strong>replace </strong><em>–v.</em> to put something new in place of something</p>
<p><strong>to go extinct </strong><em>–v.</em> to die out</p>
<p><strong>rigor </strong><em>–n.</em> the quality of being exact, careful or strict</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Plane Crash in Tokyo Raises Design Concerns  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/plane-crash-in-tokyo-raises-design-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Investigators are studying what went wrong when a Japanese coast guard aircraft and a passenger jet crashed into each other on Tuesday at Haneda Airport in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Officials want to find out what caused the crash. But there are also many questions about the fire that broke out when the planes <strong>collided</strong> on the runway.</p>
<p>The body of the passenger jet, an Airbus 350, was made of carbon-<strong>composite fibers</strong>. Passenger aircraft bodies have traditionally been made of aluminum.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Japan Airlines plane is on fire on the runway of Haneda airport on Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024 in Tokyo, Japan. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e8c0-08dc0d51417e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Japan Airlines plane is on fire on the runway of Haneda airport on Tuesday, Jan. 2, 2024 in Tokyo, Japan. </span></div>
<p>The crash may become an important test of the safety of composite materials for some uses in aircraft.</p>
<p><strong>The crash</strong></p>
<p>Communications from air traffic control at the airport describe some of the events leading to the crash. The larger Japan Airlines (JAL) passenger jet was given permission to use the runway where the coast guard plane, a Bombardier Dash-8, was preparing for takeoff.</p>
<p>When they struck each other, an orange fireball exploded from the aircraft and the passenger jet continued down the runway covered in flames.</p>
<p>When the plane stopped, crew members and all 379 passengers slid down emergency<strong> chutes</strong> within 20 minutes. All survived. The captain of the coast guard plane got out, but five members of the crew died in the crash.</p>
<p>Safety experts are praising the airline's crew and the passengers for escaping the burning plane. The crew shouted, warning the passengers to run away from the plane.</p>
<p><strong>The composite material</strong></p>
<p>Composite materials have been used for many years inside commercial aircraft. But the first commercial plane to have its body, or fuselage, and wings reinforced with carbon fibers was the Boeing 787. It went into service in 2011. About 1,100 of the planes have been produced.</p>
<p>The Airbus A350 followed in 2018. About 570 have been sold.</p>
<p>Aircraft designers use composite materials because they strengthen plastics and other materials. Boeing says the material can save 20 percent of the weight of aluminum. The reduced weight saves fuel.</p>
<p>Boeing and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) tested the strength of composites to get <strong>certification</strong> for the 787 jet. But concerns remain about gases released from such materials when they burn.</p>
<p>John Goglia is a former member of the National Transportation Safety Board, which investigates aircraft accidents. He said, "There has always been a concern about composites if they catch fire." Goglia noted that the gases released when composites burn are dangerous. They can even be dangerous after the fire is put out because the fibers might remain in the air.</p>
<p>The FAA has said for more than 20 years that there are dangers related to composite materials. FAA officials say the main health dangers include sharp pieces of material, dust and poisonous gases caused by burning substances<strong> </strong>that hold the material together.</p>
<p><strong>Did it make a difference?</strong></p>
<p>Although the inside of the passenger plane filled with smoke after the explosion, all 379 passengers were able to escape.</p>
<p>John Cox, a safety expert, noted: "That fuselage protected them from a really horrific fire — it did not burn through for some period of time and let everybody get out."</p>
<p>Goglia said there is no real evidence whether composite materials or aluminum are better at resisting fire long enough to protect people.</p>
<p>However, one passenger on the JAL flight said the smoke "<strong>stung</strong>" very much.</p>
<p>Todd Curtis, a safety expert and former Boeing engineer, warned that injuries from dangerous smoke could take a long time to show up. Passengers involved in accidents usually are in shock and often do not recognize their injuries.</p>
<p>Another concern, experts noted, was the amount of time it took firefighters to put out the fire. Pictures show the JAL flight's burned wreckage near one of the runways. The body was almost completely destroyed by fire.</p>
<p>In 2013, a fire at London's Heathrow Airport involving an Ethiopian Airlines Boeing 787 was difficult to stop. Safety expert Curtis said, "putting out the fire took much more effort that a typical airliner fire." Curtis said he worried at the time about composite fuselage fires.</p>
<p>Those concerns, he said, have not gone away.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>David Koenig reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>collide</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to crash together with force, usually because both objects are in motion</p>
<p><strong>composite</strong><em>–adj.</em> made up of at least two different materials</p>
<p><strong>fiber </strong><em>–n.</em> a long thin piece of material</p>
<p><strong>certification </strong>–n. a process of official approval of a product for use by industry or the public</p>
<p><strong>resin </strong><em>–n.</em> a substance that causes things to stick together firmly</p>
<p><strong>sting </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause sharp paint</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>American Teenager Becomes First Human to Beat Video Game Tetris  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/american-teenager-becomes-first-human-to-beat-video-game-tetris.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A 13-year-old American boy has become the first person ever to beat the popular video game Tetris.</p>
<p>The young gamer, Willis Gibson, completed 157 levels of Tetris before the game technically surrendered.</p>
<p>Gamers call this kind of ending a "kill screen." The Tetris program had no more plays to make and so it crashed, freezing the video game.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image taken from video, 13-year-old Willis Gibson reacts after beating the video game Tetris. (Willis Gibson via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-addd-08dc0d4cda58_cx3_cy0_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image taken from video, 13-year-old Willis Gibson reacts after beating the video game Tetris. (Willis Gibson via AP)</span></div>
<p>Gibson lives in the Midwestern state of Oklahoma and goes by the gaming name "Blue Scuti." He can be heard repeatedly shouting "Oh my God" <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=piXi6HM_GQ4">on a video</a> recording as he beat the game.</p>
<p>"I can't feel my fingers," Gibson says in the video.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Gaming experts had long considered Tetris unbeatable. This is partly because the video game does not have a clear ending point.</p>
<p>Tetris came out in 1984 and quickly became a worldwide favorite. Its creator, Alexey Pajitnov, was a computer programs engineer at the Russian Academy of Sciences in the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>During the game, players move and join together seven different shapes of falling blocks. The goal is for players to fit the blocks together to form solid lines inside a box. The blocks fall faster as players progress through higher levels of the game.</p>
<p>On December 21, Gibson reached level 157 and dropped a final piece into place. This caused a single line of blocks to disappear and the game to enter a permanent freeze.</p>
<p>"This is unbelievable," Vince Clemente, CEO of Classic Tetris World Championship, told Reuters news agency. "Developers didn't think anyone would ever make it that far and now the game has officially been beaten by a human being." </p><p>For some time, gamers have known Tetris would eventually reach an ending point and technically shut down. But in the past, only a computer program could force such a game-ending shut-down.</p>
<p>Other fans of the game were quick to share Gibson's excitement. Classic Tetris World Champion Justin Yu – who goes by the name fractal161 – declared in his own video, "He did it, he did it!"</p>
<p>Tetris chief executive Maya Rogers joined in the celebration. She said in a statement it was fitting Gibson had beat the game just ahead of 2024, when Tetris was entering its 40th anniversary.</p>
<p>"Congratulations to 'blue scuti,'" Rogers said. She added that the "extraordinary" event "<strong>defied</strong>" any previous known limits of the game.</p>
<p>Gibson uses a "rolling" controller playing method popularized in 2021. It permits players to operate the controls in different ways to be able to keep playing longer to reach higher levels.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>defy </strong><em>– v. </em>to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Personification, Adjectives in 'Take Me Home, Country Roads'  (2024/1/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/personification-adjectives-in-take-me-home-country-roads.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many Americans have returned to work or school as the holiday season comes to an end. Some traveled far to be with loved ones for Christmas and New Year's Day.</p>
<p>Last month, we looked at the song <em>Take Me Home, Country Roads.</em> For many people from the state of West Virginia and the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/discover-americas-appalachian-trial/2766408.html">Appalachia</a> mountains, the song reminds them of home. John Denver recorded the hit song in 1971. Lana Del Rey recently recorded her version of the song.</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will continue looking at parts of Del Rey's version of the song and connect it to grammar and <strong>figurative</strong> language.<strong> </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="More Personification and Adjectives in Take Me Home, Country Roads " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-36b8-08dc0cb9bd41_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">More Personification and Adjectives in "Take Me Home, Country Roads" </span></div>
<p>Let's look at the last section of the song.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p><em>All my memories gather 'round her</em></p>
<p><em>Miner</em><em>'s lady, stranger to blue water</em></p>
<p><em>Dark and dusty, painted on the sky</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Misty</em></strong><em> taste of moonshine, teardrop in my eye</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>I hear her voice in the morning hour, she calls me</em></p>
<p><em>The radio reminds me of my home far away</em></p>
<p><em>Driving down the road, I get a feeling</em></p>
<p><em>That I should have been home yesterday, yesterday</em></p>
<p><strong>More personification </strong></p>
<p>In the first two <strong>verses </strong>of each section, West Virginia is humanized once again using personification. Personification is the humanization of a non-living thing.</p>
<p>The use of the subject and object pronouns "she" and "her" give a female quality to the state. That personification of West Virginia as a woman also appears in the <strong>chorus</strong> of the song when it is referred to as <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-and-figurative-language-in-take-me-home-country-roads-/7406288.html">"mountain mama." </a></p>
<p>"Her voice" and "she calls me" add to the female <strong>characteristics </strong>of the state.</p>
<p>"Miner's lady" and "stranger to blue water" are other personified comparisons in the song. West Virginia is known for its coal and limestone mines throughout the state. Many European immigrants came to West Virginia in the late 1800s and early 1900s to work in the mines.</p>
<p>"Stanger to blue water" is a reference to West Virginia's geographic location as a landlocked state. A stranger is an unfamiliar person. The phrase is noting that the state is not near an ocean and is unfamiliar to blue ocean waters.</p>
<p><strong>Adjectives </strong></p>
<p>And finally, we have more adjectives. Today we look at descriptive adjectives, not comparative adjectives.</p>
<p><em>Dark and dusty, painted on the sky</em></p>
<p><em>Misty taste of moonshine, teardrop in my eye</em></p>
<p>"Dark and dusty" refer to the "miner's lady" line and coal mining. Coal is a dark, natural substance found in the earth. West Virginia and other parts of the Appalachian region are rich in this resource. It also creates dusty particles that fill the air. That combination "paints" or covers the sky.</p>
<p>The line "misty taste of moonshine" also has a descriptive adjective. "Misty" has several meanings. "Mist," the noun form of the word, means water in the form of very small drops floating in the air. So, "misty" means full of mist. It can also describe something that is not clearly seen or remembered. Finally, it can describe eyes that are full of tears. In fact, "misty-eyed" means the same thing as "tearful."</p>
<p>Moonshine is a kind of alcohol that is made illegally. Making moonshine was especially common in the hills of Appalachia during Prohibition, which lasted from 1920 to 1933.</p>
<p>The alcohol was moved by car at night and the <strong>bootleggers</strong> could only see by the light of the moon. That is where it got its name.</p>
<p>It is not common to describe a taste or flavor as "misty." But there are a few possible meanings. Since "moonshine" was strong, drinking it could leave one's eyes "misty" or filled with tears. The "misty" flavor of moonshine could also refer to the illegal way of producing and transporting the alcohol without anyone knowing.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today we looked at the rest of the song <em>Country Roads</em>. We found even more personification by comparing West Virginia to a woman with words like, "miner's lady" and "her voice."</p>
<p>We found even more adjectives that were used to describe parts of Appalachian culture like "dark and dusty" for coal mining and "misty taste of moonshine" to describe a strong alcohol flavor that could bring tears to one's eyes.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>figurative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. used with a meaning that is different from the basic meaning</p>
<p><strong>misty </strong>– <em>adj</em>.<strong> </strong>full of or covered with mist.</p>
<p><strong>verse</strong> – <em>n. </em>writing in which words are arranged in a rhythmic pattern: poetry or song</p>
<p><strong>chorus </strong><em>– n.</em> part of a song that is repeated; a large organized group of singers</p>
<p><strong>characteristic </strong><em>–n.</em> a quality that a person has that makes them different, or similar, to others</p>
<p><strong>bootlegger</strong> - <em>n</em>. someone who sells products illegally, often without providing the requires taxes to government</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Experiment Breaks Record for Internet Traffic Speed  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-experiment-breaks-record-for-internet-traffic-speed.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Japanese researchers say they have broken the world speed record for sending internet data.</p>
<p>The recent experiment involved sending data over <strong>fiber-optic</strong> lines enclosed inside <strong>cables</strong>. Fiber optic technology is currently the fastest way to transport, or transmit, internet data.</p>
<p>Fiber-optic cables use signals of light to send data over long distances. The fiber material is very thin, about one-tenth the thickness of a human hair.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Fiber optic cables are seen running into a server room at Intergate.Manhattan, a data center owned and developed by Sabey Data Center Properties, during a tour of the facility in lower Manhattan, in New York, March 20, 2013. (REUTERS/Mike Sega)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-95d6-08dc0c9b0939_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Fiber optic cables are seen running into a server room at Intergate.Manhattan, a data center owned and developed by Sabey Data Center Properties, during a tour of the facility in lower Manhattan, in New York, March 20, 2013. (REUTERS/Mike Sega)</span></div>
<p>Fiber-optic technology was meant to replace an older internet transmission method that uses cables made mainly of copper wiring. This method can also carry data over the internet, but at much reduced speeds and <strong>capacity</strong> compared with fiber-optics.</p>
<p>A report released last year by the United Nations' International Telecommunication Union (ITU) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.itu.int/hub/2023/05/space-division-multiplexing/">suggested</a> current worldwide internet data transmission is reaching full capacity levels.</p>
<p>The Japanese data transmission experiment used fiber-optic cables. But the engineers involved made some changes to the cables in an effort to greatly expand speed and capacity.</p>
<p>Such methods are known as multiplexing technologies. They aim to increase the amount and speed of internet data with existing transmission equipment. These technologies combine multiple communication signals into a single transmission line.</p>
<p>One multiplexing technology – called Wave Division Multiplexing (or WDM) – aims to increase the <strong>wavelength</strong> capacity within transmission cables. Another method – called Space Division Multiplexing (or SDM) – can involve increasing the size or number of fiber-optic centers, called cores.</p>
<p>Engineers from Japan's National Institute of Information and Communications Technology (NCIT) led the researchers who carried out the experiment. The tests measured speeds in petabits. One petabit equals 1 million gigabits.</p>
<p>The record transmission demonstrated a data transmission capacity of 22.9 petabits per second in a single fiber-optic cable. The previous record for data transmission was 10.66 petabits per second, set by the same team at NCIT.</p>
<p>Major progress has been made in recent years in internet data transmission speeds. In October 2022, an international group of researchers <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.dtu.dk/english/newsarchive/2022/10/new-data-transmission-record">announced</a> they had broken the world record. That team reported they had reached a test rate of 1.8 petabits per second using a single optical cable.</p>
<p>Results of the Japanese experiment were officially presented in a paper released at the 49th <a class="wsw__a" href="https://ecoc2023.theiet.org/">European Conference on Optical Communications</a> in October. The team said it was able to beat the previous record by a large amount using new methods to expand and combine different WDM and SDM elements.</p>
<p>The method used a fiber-optic cable that contained 38 cores. The researchers said expanding the number of cores resulted in an "increased number of optical paths" for high-speed data transmission.</p>
<p>One researcher was Chigo Okonkwo of Eindhoven University of Technology in the Netherlands. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://nltimes.nl/2023/12/25/eindhoven-researchers-break-record-fastest-data-transfer-speed-ever#:~:text=Scientists%20based%20in%20Eindhoven%20have,That%20was%20achieved%20in%202020.">told</a> the country's <em>NL Times</em> the rate of 22.9 petabits per second represented "about 20 times the global internet traffic per second." Okonkwo also noted the speed is about 229 times the total capacity of the kinds of fiber-optic cables currently in use today.</p>
<p>Worldwide, the estimated average internet data transmission speed in 2023 was about 46.8 megabits per second, international research service <em>Statista</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/chart/31075/global-average-internet-download-speed/#:~:text=As%20detailed%20in%20the%20Cable,major%20differences%20between%20world%20regions.">reports</a>. The rate reached 118.7 megabits per second in Western Europe, while Northern Africa had the lowest estimated rate at 9.8, <em>Statista </em>said.<em> </em></p>
<p>The American-based Pew Research Center studies internet data transmission rates across the United States. Pew <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/fact-sheets/2022/07/how-do-americans-connect-to-the-internet">reports</a> the fastest current data transmission method available in the U.S. – called Fiber to Home – is about 10 gigabits per second. This amount is equal to about 10,000 megabits per second.</p>
<p>Most Americans receive much slower data transmission rates, an average of just under 50 megabits per second. Pew estimates Fiber to Home service only accounts for about 20 percent of the U.S. internet service market.</p>
<p>The NCIT team described its latest test results as "a major step toward the realization of future ultra-large capacity optical communication networks." But in order to reach this goal, the team said its current methods must be further perfected.</p>
<p>For example, the researchers pointed to one major issue that could delay future deployments of its super-fast fiber-optic system. This will be the need to complete "significant <strong>upgrades</strong>" to current telecommunication hardware systems in order<strong> </strong>to support the new cable technologies.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fiber optics </strong><em>– n. </em>the use of very thin glass or plastic wires through which light can travel to carry data, especially for internet and computer applications</p>
<p><strong>cable </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of wires covered by plastic coverings</p>
<p><strong>capacity </strong><em>– n. </em>the total amount of something that can be produced or contained</p>
<p><strong>wavelength </strong><em>– n. </em>the distance between two waves of energy</p>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of equipment or software that improves the quality or usefulness of a computer or machine</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lancashire Heeler: Small Dog with Big Smile  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/lancashire-heeler-small-dog-with-big-smile.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>It is a small dog with a big "smile." And it is ready to compete with 200 other kinds of dogs, known as breeds.</p>
<p>Say hello to the Lancashire Heeler.</p>
<p>The American Kennel Club (AKC) announced Wednesday that the rare dog breed can now compete in thousands of dog shows across the United States. That includes the famous Westminster Kennel Club show.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Lex, a Lancashire Heeler, sits at attention on Dec. 29, 2023, in Morristown, N.J. The breed is the latest recognized by the American Kennel Club to compete in thousands of U.S. dog shows. (Michelle Barlak via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-320f-08dc0c815fdc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Lex, a Lancashire Heeler, sits at attention on Dec. 29, 2023, in Morristown, N.J. The breed is the latest recognized by the American Kennel Club to compete in thousands of U.S. dog shows. (Michelle Barlak via AP)</span></div>
<p>The AKC <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.akc.org/dog-breeds/lancashire-heeler/">describes</a> the breed as "a medium to high energy dog." The organization says the dogs are intelligent, friendly and quick to learn new tasks. They are happy, talkative and always ready for a walk.</p>
<p>Lancashire Heelers have long bodies and short coats of hair, or fur, in black and tan. The breed stands about 30 centimeters high and weighs up to 7.7 kilograms. Historically, they helped to drive farm animals and chase away rats. The breed can also perform several dog-related sports and activities.</p>
<p>"They're <strong>gritty</strong> little dogs, and they're very intelligent little dogs," says Patricia Blankenship of Flora, Mississippi, who has bred them for many years. "It's an enjoyable little breed to be around."</p>
<p>The breed is often described as "<strong>courageous</strong>, happy, <strong>affectionate</strong> to owner." And owners say they sometimes pull back their lips into a "smile."</p>
<p>Lancashire Heeler Club President Sheryl Bradbury says the breed "has to have a job" or stay active with its owners. It is also helpful for them to meet different people and dogs.</p>
<p>Lancashire Heelers have lived in Britain for hundreds of years, but they are now at risk of dying out as a breed. Britain's Kennel Club has added an average of just 121 Lancashire heelers yearly to its registry in recent years. The AKC says only about 5,000 exist worldwide.</p>
<p>Founded in 1884, the AKC is the United States' oldest <strong>purebred</strong> dog registry. It also organizes dog shows where 201 recognized breeds compete for the traditional "best in show." To get recognized, a breed must have an official breeding <strong>standard</strong> and there must be at least 300 of the animals in at least 20 states.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Jennifer Peltz reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gritty</strong> <em>–adj. </em>showing toughness or courage</p>
<p><strong>courageous</strong> <em>–adj.</em> being brave or showing courage</p>
<p><strong>affectionate </strong>–adj. showing love or good feeling</p>
<p><strong>purebred </strong>–adj. having parents of the same breed</p>
<p><strong>standard </strong>–n. a level of quality involving observance of certain rules</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Record Half-million Migrants Crossed Dangerous Darien Gap Last Year  (2024/1/4) | 2023年穿越达连峡谷人数创新纪录</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/record-half-million-migrants-crossed-dangerous-darien-gap-last-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A record 520,000 migrants crossed the difficult and dangerous Darien Gap wilderness area between Colombia and Panama in 2023. Panamanian officials say that total is more than double the number recorded the year before.<br/>
2023年，创纪录的52万移民穿越了哥伦比亚和巴拿马之间艰难而危险的“达连峡谷”荒野地带。巴拿马官员表示，这一数字是前一年的两倍多。</p>
<p>The Panamanian government's migration agency says most of the migrants in 2023 were from Venezuela, Ecuador, and Haiti. And, agency chief Samira Gozaine said minors represented about 25 percent of the group traveling through the dense jungle.<br/>
巴拿马政府移民局表示，2023年的大多数移民来自委内瑞拉、厄瓜多尔和海地。该机构负责人萨米拉·冈萨伊内表示，在穿越茂密丛林的人群中，未成年人约占25%。</p>
<p>"This is a national security problem," she told reporters at a government event. "Unfortunately, we do not have a quick solution to solve it."<br/>
她在一次政府活动中对记者说：“这是国家安全问题，不幸的是，我们没有快速解决方案。”</p>
<p>The number of migrants crossing the Darien has sharply increased since 2019, when Laurentino Cortizo took office as Panama's president. Officials have called for international assistance to deal with the problem.<br/>
自2019年劳伦蒂诺·科尔蒂佐就任巴拿马总统以来，穿越“达连峡谷”的移民人数急剧增加。官员们呼吁国际社会提供援助以解决这一问题。</p>
<p>A major increase in Venezuelans fleeing the economic and social collapse of their country accounts for some of the migration flow. The United Nations says more than seven million Venezuelans have fled their country in recent years.<br/>
逃离本国经济和社会崩溃的委内瑞拉人大幅增加，这是移民潮的一部分原因。联合国表示，近年来已有700多万委内瑞拉人逃离本国。</p>
<p>Those who cross the Darien risk murder, rape, human trafficking, and other violence. Natural dangers include heavy rains, sudden floods, poisonous snakes and other wildlife. Migrants must cross jungle rivers as well. There are no roads, bridges or services, including police and emergency workers.<br/>
那些穿越“达连峡谷”的人有被谋杀、强奸、贩卖人口和其他暴力的风险。自然危险包括暴雨、突发洪水、毒蛇和其他野生动物。移民还必须穿越丛林河流。这里没有道路、桥梁或包括警察和急救人员在内的相关服务。</p>
<p>In September, Reuters reported that African migrants heading to the United States are flying to Nicaragua to avoid the dangers of the Darien Gap.<br/>
9月，路透社报道称，前往美国的非洲移民正飞往尼加拉瓜，以避免“达连峡谷”的危险。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Displaced Afghans Cross Borders to Survive  (2024/1/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/displaced-afghan-cross-borders-to-survive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The desert in the mountains of eastern Afghanistan is filled with hundreds of thousands of people. Some live in tents. Others live out in the open after they were forced to leave neighboring Pakistan.</p>
<p>More than 40 years of war, violence and poverty have turned 6 million Afghans into refugees. Another 3.5 million people are displaced within the country of 40 million. Many were driven from their homes by war, earthquakes and <strong>drought</strong>.</p>
<p>Afghanistan's economy collapsed after the Taliban returned to power following the withdrawal of the United States and NATO allies in 2021. Now, two-thirds of its population depends on international aid to survive.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An internally displaced woman takes care of her sick child in a camp on the outskirts of Kabul, Afghanistan, Thursday, Feb. 9, 2023. She has no money to treat her sick child. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f57b-08dc0bd04827_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An internally displaced woman takes care of her sick child in a camp on the outskirts of Kabul, Afghanistan, Thursday, Feb. 9, 2023. She has no money to treat her sick child. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)</span></div>
<p>Displaced Afghans live in camps around the country. They do not have enough food or firewood for heat in the winter. Women and children often turn to <strong>begging</strong>. Others marry off their young daughters to families willing to pay them money.</p>
<p>In May, for example, 15-year-old Shamila was married at a camp for internally displaced people outside Kabul. She stood in a bright-red dress among the women of the family who congratulated her. But the girl was unhappy.</p>
<p>"I have no choice. If I don't accept, my family will be hurt," said Shamila, whose father did not give the family's name because he feared the Taliban. The <strong>groom's</strong> family is giving her father money to pay off debts taken to support his wife and children.</p>
<p>"I wanted to study and work, I should have gone to school," Shamila said. "I have to forget all my dreams...so at least I can help my father and my family a little and maybe I can take the <strong>burden off their shoulders</strong>."</p>
<p>Last year, Pakistan decided to <strong>deport</strong> Afghans who entered the country illegally. Many Afghans lived for years in Pakistan. They were afraid of continuing conflicts at home. When Pakistan's order was announced, hundreds of thousands feared arrest and fled back to Afghanistan. The Afghans said Pakistani officials often prevented them from taking anything with them.</p>
<p>Their first stop has been the camp in Torkham, where they might spend days or weeks before Taliban officials send them to another place. With little food and little to protect them from the mountain cold, many in the camp are sick.</p>
<p>In a camp at the foot of a mountain, 55-year-old Farooq Sadiq sat with his wife and children on the ground among some of their belongings. Sadiq said he had been living in the Pakistani city of Peshawar for 30 years and owned a home there. Now they had nothing, not even a tent. He said they had been sleeping on the ground for the past eight nights.</p>
<p>"I have nothing in Afghanistan, no house, no place to live, not enough money to buy a house," he said. He hopes to settle somewhere in Afghanistan and get a visa to Pakistan so he can go sell his home there to use the money for his family.</p>
<p>The deportations from Pakistan have greatly increased the large numbers of Afghans who try to migrate into Iran, hoping to find work.</p>
<p>Every month, thousands cross into Iran at the border near Zaranj. At night, with the help of <strong>smugglers</strong>, they climb over the border wall and jump to the other side.</p>
<p>Mostly young men, from age 12 to their 20s, flee Afghanistan this way. They plan to work in Iran and send money home to their families. Many are caught by Iranian border guards and sent back.</p>
<p>Others take a longer trip by car through mountains and deserts on Afghanistan's southwestern border through Pakistan to reach Iran. There is no border wall there. But fighters from the Sunni militant group Jundallah often attack the migrants, killing or kidnapping Shiites among them.</p>
<p>Over several months, <em>Associated Press </em>photographer Ebrahim Noroozi traveled across Afghanistan from its eastern border with Pakistan to its western border with Iran to report their stories.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Ebrahim Noroozi reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a severe lack of rain for an extended period</p>
<p><strong>beg </strong><em>–v.</em> to ask people for money or food</p>
<p><strong>groom </strong><em>–n.</em> a man about to be married</p>
<p><strong>burden off (one's) shoulders </strong><em>–idiom</em> to solve a difficult problem or responsibility</p>
<p><strong>deport </strong><em>–v.</em> to legally expel a person, who is not a citizen, from a country</p>
<p><strong>smuggler </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who move goods or people from country to country secretly and illegally</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Woman, Cat Help Others through Therapy  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/woman-cat-help-others-through-therapy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Every day Juanita Mengel, a 67-year-old woman from the state of Ohio, wakes up and puts on her manufactured leg. The device is called a prosthetic.</p>
<p>Then, Mengel does the same for Lola-Pearl, her colorful five-year-old cat. Lola-Pearl is missing her back left leg.</p>
<p>Mengel has many cats. Most of them have disabilities. But Lola-Pearl is special. She is a <strong>therapy</strong> cat. And, she and Mengel are partners of a kind. They are among 200 therapy cat teams registered in the United States by the nonprofit group, Pet Partners.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image taken from video shows kitten Lola-Pearl looking up at attendees during a Amputees Coming Together Informing Others' Needs meeting on Monday, Dec. 11, 2023, in Troy, Ohio. (AP Photo/Patrick Orsagos)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fc1086e2-7ae0-414d-a684-626c301584f8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image taken from video shows kitten Lola-Pearl looking up at attendees during a Amputees Coming Together Informing Others' Needs meeting on Monday, Dec. 11, 2023, in Troy, Ohio. (AP Photo/Patrick Orsagos)</span></div>
<p>The group helps humans and pets alike by setting them up into teams to provide animal-assisted intervention. The teams visit hospitals, nursing homes and schools and assist those in need.</p>
<p>Taylor Chastain Griffin is national director of animal-assisted interventions at Pet Partners. She said, "A therapy animal is an animal who's been <strong>assessed</strong> based on their ability to meet new people and not just <strong>tolerate</strong> the interaction, but actively enjoy it."</p>
<p>Chastain Griffin is a researcher who studies the effects of therapy cats. She said there needs to be more research done in cat therapy. She said that there is a lot of research on other therapy animals like dogs, and many people are surprised to learn that cats can be therapy animals too.</p>
<p>"They go into a setting and people are like, 'Whoa, there's a cat on a <strong>leash</strong>. What's happening? It kind of <strong>inspires</strong> people to connect in a way we haven't traditionally heard talked about in other therapy animal interventions," Chastain Griffin said.</p>
<p>Besides dogs and cats, Pet Partners registers seven other species as therapy animals, including horses, rabbits, rats, guinea pigs, birds, mini pigs, and llamas and alpacas.</p>
<p>Mengel said Lola-Pearl showed signs that she would make a good therapy cat soon after the animal joined her family. Mengel took her new cat to a meeting for <strong>amputees</strong>.</p>
<p>"She was so good with people I just knew she would be a good therapy cat. People really were attracted to her, too," Mengel said.</p>
<p>Recently people who attended a support group for amputees were able to meet Lola-Pearl. They petted her as she woke up from a rest. On the side of the cat carrier she rode in was a sign: "Therapy Cat" it read.</p>
<p>Mengel was a traveling nurse when she was in a car accident that almost killed her. One of her legs could not be saved.</p>
<p>Later, she connected with a friend in the state of Missouri who had a severely injured kitten. Her legs were <strong>twisted</strong> together. An animal medical specialist worked to repair the damage but, in the end, they had to remove one of the baby cat's legs.</p>
<p>That kitten was Lola-Pearl.</p>
<p>Mengel took Lola-Pearl as her cat after talking with her friend. Despite the difficulties Mengel has faced, she is thankful for Lola-Pearl and their work together.</p>
<p>"It's a really rewarding experience," she said, "I get just as much out of it as the people that I visit."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Patrick Orsagos reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>therapy </strong>– <em>n</em>. the treatment of physical or mental illnesses</p>
<p><strong>assess </strong><em>– v. </em>to make a judgement about a person or a thing</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong><em>– v.</em> to permit something to happen; to be able to bear the results of something</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>– n.</em> a powerful or major influence or effect</p>
<p><strong>leash </strong><em>– n. </em>a long, thin piece of rope, chain, etc., that is used for holding a dog or other animal</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone want to do something</p>
<p><strong>amputee </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who has had an arm or leg cut off</p>
<p><strong>limb </strong>– <em>n.</em> a leg or arm</p>
<p><strong>twisted </strong>—<em> v. </em>to bend or turn in order to change its shape</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Childhood Education Programs at Risk  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/early-childhood-education-programs-at-risk.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) says "The period from birth to eight years old is one of <strong>remarkable</strong> brain development for children." The organization adds that it represents an important time for their development and education.</p>
<p>The U.S. National Institutes of Health says that supporting children's early learning can lead to higher test scores and a better chance of staying in school and going to college. Studies even suggest early learning can lead to fewer <strong>teen</strong> pregnancies, improved mental health, and a longer life.</p>
<p><strong>Early learning in OECD countries</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Elijah Rollings, 2, plays with a train set at Bumble Art Studio daycare center in Astoria, Ore., Friday, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Craig Mitchelldyer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ac7c-08dc0b0435db_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Elijah Rollings, 2, plays with a train set at Bumble Art Studio daycare center in Astoria, Ore., Friday, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Craig Mitchelldyer)</span></div>
<p>The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) is made up of 38 democracies with market-based economies. The organization aims to build better policies for better lives.</p>
<p>In a recent education <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/0a156279-en/index.html?itemId=/content/component/0a156279-en#:~:text=The%20highest%20enrolment%20rates%20of,primary%20education%20across%20OECD%20countries.">study</a>, the OECD found that most of its member countries provide care or education for children under 5. In countries, including Belgium, Denmark, France, Hungary, Iceland, Israel, Norway, Spain and Britain, at least 95 percent of 3-year-olds are <strong>enrolled</strong> in an early education program.</p>
<p>However, within OECD countries, there can be a large difference in enrollment. In the United States, for example, 80 percent of 3 to 5-year-olds in the capital city of Washington, D.C. are enrolled in early education programs. That is compared to 46 percent in the western state of North Dakota.</p>
<p>The differences also exist in European countries like Greece, Lithuania, and Switzerland. Places with higher rates of women in the workforce usually have higher rates of enrollment for children under 3.</p>
<p><strong>Child care and kindergarten</strong></p>
<p>During the pandemic, the U.S. government provided an additional $24 billion to help child care programs nationwide. The funding finally ended last October.</p>
<p>The Century Foundation is a research organization in New York City. It <a class="wsw__a" href="https://tcf.org/content/report/child-care-cliff/">estimates</a> that one-third of the programs could close as a result. That affects more than 2.2 million children. The organization says that child care is important for the economy at large since child care permits parents to stay at work.</p>
<p>Around the world, governments invest little in early childhood education, UNESCO says. About 6.6 percent of education budgets are put toward early education programs, 2 percent in poor countries. That is well below the target of 10 percent by 2030 suggested by the children's organization UNICEF.</p>
<p>In the U.S., parents can choose to put their children at age 5 in <strong>kindergarten</strong> or a child care program.</p>
<p>Kindergarten enrollment has dropped since the COVID-19 pandemic. Concerned about the virus or wanting to avoid online school, hundreds of thousands of families delayed the start of school for their young children.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> found that kindergarten enrollment remained down 5.2 percent in the 2022-2023 school year compared with the 2019-2020 school year.</p>
<p>Deborah Stipek is a former head of the Graduate School of Education at Stanford University. She said kindergarten is where children learn to follow directions, learn good <strong>behavior</strong>, and get used to learning. Stipek said missing that year of school can put kids at a <strong>disadvantage</strong>.</p>
<p>Last year, Aylah went to a children's program that met mainly outdoors instead of enrolling in kindergarten in the state of California. Aylah now has to <strong>adjust</strong> to being inside a classroom and learning the right way to hold a pencil.</p>
<p>"It's harder. Way, way harder," Aylah said of the new way she learned to hold a pencil.</p>
<p>Still, her mother Hannah Levy says it was the right decision to skip kindergarten. She wanted Aylah to enjoy being a child. There is plenty of time, she reasoned, for her daughter to develop study skills.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English, with additional reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>remarkable </strong><em>— adj. </em>unusual or surprising</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>teen </strong><em>— n. </em>someone who is between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enroll </strong><em>— v. </em>to enter as a member of or participant in something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>kindergarten </strong><em>— n. </em>a school or class for very young children</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>behavior </strong><em>— n. </em>the way a person or animal acts or behaves</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>disadvantage </strong><em>— n. </em>something that makes someone or something worse or less likely to succeed than others</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adjust </strong><em>— v. </em> to change in a minor way so that it works better</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Growth Slows, but World’s Population Moves Past 8 Billion to Start 2024  (2024/1/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/growth-slows-but-world-s-population-moves-past-8-billion-to-start-2024.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A U.S. government agency says the world's population grew by about 75 million people in 2023.</p>
<p>The U.S. Census Bureau notes the worldwide growth rate in the past year was just under 1 percent. The agency also said there will be 4.3 births and two deaths around the world every second in 2024.</p>
<p>The United States' growth rate is about half that of the world overall. On January 1, 2024, the U.S. had a population of 335.8 million, the Census Bureau said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A busy platform is seen at Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Terminus on World Population Day in Mumbai, India, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Rajanish Kakade)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8e81-08dc0bccffdb_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A busy platform is seen at Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Terminus on World Population Day in Mumbai, India, Tuesday, July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Rajanish Kakade)</span></div>
<p>The numbers look large. But growth rates around the world have been slowing. The United Nations notes the world population will reach 9 billion in about 15 years. That is three years longer than it took to move from 7 billion to 8 billion. The world population reached 8 billion people in November 2022.</p>
<p>If the current rate continues, the 2020s are likely to be the slowest growing decade in American history, the Census Bureau said.</p>
<p>William Frey is a population expert at the Brookings Institution, a research group based in Washington, D.C. He said the growth rate in the U.S. from 2020 to 2030 will be under 4 percent. The slowest-growing decade recorded in the U.S. took place in the 1930s, after the long economic <strong>depression</strong>. The growth rate for that decade was 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>Frey said the predicted growth rate could "<strong>tick up</strong>" in the next few years. But he said it is not likely to be higher than 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>Immigration is the reason why the U.S. will not suffer a population loss in 2024. There should be one birth every nine seconds and one death every 9.5 seconds. But there will likely be two new American immigrants every minute in 2024. As a result, every 24.2 seconds, the U.S. population will increase by one person.</p>
<p>The two most populous countries are India and China. India moved ahead of China at some point in 2023. The two countries both have more than 1.4 billion people. By 2050, China's population is expected to decrease by 2.7 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>depression <i></i>173;</strong>–n. a long period of time when a country's economy contracts instead of grows</p>
<p><strong>tick up (expression) </strong>–v. to increase by a small amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Rescuers Search for Survivors after Deadly Earthquake  (2024/1/3) | 日本救援人员搜寻地震幸存者</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-rescuers-search-for-survivors-after-deadly-earthquake.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A series of powerful earthquakes in western Japan have left at least 55 people dead and damaged thousands of buildings, automobiles and boats.<br/>
日本西部发生的一系列强烈地震已造成至少55人死亡，数千栋建筑、汽车和船只受损。</p>
<p>The first quake struck New Year's Day, registering 7.6 in magnitude, or strength. The shaking caused major damage across Ishikawa prefecture.<br/>
第一次地震发生在元旦，震级为7.6级。地震对整个石川县造成了严重破坏。</p>
<p>Japanese media reports said the quake destroyed tens of thousands of homes and cut water, power and phone services in some areas.<br/>
日本媒体报道称，地震摧毁了数以万计的房屋，并切断了一些地区的水、电和电话服务。</p>
<p>The mayor in the town of Suzu, near the quake's center, said up to 90 percent of homes may have been destroyed, Reuters news agency reported.<br/>
据路透社报道，震中附近的宿州市市长表示，多达90%的房屋可能已被摧毁。</p>
<p>The earthquake set off tsunami warnings along Japan's western coast. Officials ordered about 100,000 people to leave their homes Monday night. They were sent to schools and sports centers to take shelter. Many returned to their homes Tuesday after the warnings were lifted.<br/>
地震在日本西海岸引发海啸警报。周一晚上，官方下令约10万人离开家园。他们被送到学校和体育中心避难。警报解除后，许多人于周二返回家园。</p>
<p>Japan's Meteorological Agency said about 200 aftershocks had struck since the main quake and that more were expected in coming days.<br/>
日本气象厅表示，自主震以来，已经发生了大约200次余震，预计未来几天还会有更多余震。</p>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida told reporters the government had deployed teams that included military troops, police and local rescuers. "We have received reports that there are still many people waiting to be rescued under collapsed buildings," he said.<br/>
日本首相岸田文雄告诉记者，政府已经部署了包括军队、警察和当地救援人员在内的队伍。他说：“我们收到报告称，仍有许多人困在倒塌的建筑物下等待救援。”</p>
<p>Kishida added that saving lives is the top goal.<br/>
岸田文雄补充说，拯救生命是首要目标。</p>
<p>Japan sits on the so-called Ring of Fire, a collection of volcanoes and fault lines found around the Pacific Basin. About 20 percent of the world's earthquakes of magnitude 6 or greater happen in that area.<br/>
日本位于所谓的环太平洋火山带上，这是太平洋盆地周围发现的火山和断层带的集合。世界上大约20%的6级及以上地震发生在该地区。</p>
<p>Monday's earthquake was Japan's deadliest since 2016. Emergency teams battled fires in several cities, as rescuers searched for people trapped in wreckage.<br/>
周一的地震是日本自2016年以来死亡人数最多的一次地震。紧急救援队在几个城市灭火，救援人员正在搜寻被困在废墟中的人员。</p>
<p>Shoichi Kobayashi lives in the city of Wajima. He told Reuters he was at home celebrating New Year's with his wife and son when the quake hit and sent furniture flying across the house. "I've never experienced a quake that powerful," Kobayashi said.<br/>
小林昭一住在和岛市。他告诉路透社，地震发生时，他正在家里与妻儿庆祝新年，家具在房子里乱飞。小林说：“我从未经历过如此强烈的地震。”</p>
<p>In the city of Nanao, Fujiko Ueno said she was celebrating with about 20 people in her home when the earthquake struck. The quake caused walls to collapse onto a parked car. Ueno said no one in the group was injured. "It all happened in the blink of an eye," she said.<br/>
南尾市的上野藤子说，地震发生时，她正在家中与大约20人一起庆祝。地震导致围墙砸到一辆停着的汽车上。上野说，团队中没有人受伤。她说：“这一切都发生在眨眼之间。”</p>
<p>Toshitaka Katada is a University of Tokyo professor who specializes in disasters. He told The Associated Press that people were better prepared for this event because the area had been hit by quakes in recent years. "There is probably no people on earth other than Japanese who are so disaster-ready," Katada said.<br/>
片田敏孝是东京大学专门研究灾害的教授。他告诉美联社，人们对这一事件有了更好的准备，因为该地区近年来遭受过地震袭击。片田说：“除了日本人，地球上可能没有其他人做好了这种灾难准备。”</p>
<p>Government officials said several nuclear centers in the area were operating normally. A 2011 earthquake and tsunami caused three reactors to melt down and release large amounts of radiation at the Fukushima nuclear power center in northeastern Japan.<br/>
政府官员表示，该地区的几个核电站运行正常。2011年的地震和海啸导致日本东北部福岛核电站的三个反应堆熔毁并释放出大量辐射。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Aims to Put Human-like Robots in Space  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/nasa-aims-to-put-human-like-robots-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA's human-like robot Valkyrie looks powerful. It stands 188 centimeters tall and weighs 136 kilograms.</p>
<p>Valkyrie is named after supernatural females in Norse <strong>mythology</strong>. The robot is being tested at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>The robot is designed to operate in "...damaged human-engineered environments," like areas hit by natural disasters, NASA said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="NASA's humanoid robot Valkyrie opens a bag at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, U.S., November 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Evan Garcia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/82577d22-7057-443e-8c7d-aaf9d007bf25_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">NASA's humanoid robot Valkyrie opens a bag at the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, U.S., November 16, 2023. (REUTERS/Evan Garcia)</span></div>
<p>But robots like Valkyrie could also work in space one day.</p>
<p>Robots that look like humans, or humanoid robots, have a <strong>torso</strong>, head, two arms and two legs. Engineers believe that humanoid robots will be able to work similarly to humans and use the same tools and equipment. They just need the right software.</p>
<p>NASA Dexterous Robotics team leader Shaun Azimi said humanoid robots in space could do dangerous jobs. Such jobs include cleaning <strong>solar panels </strong>or dealing with equipment outside the spacecraft. As a result, human astronauts could pay more attention to exploration and discovery.</p>
<p>"We're not trying to replace human crews, we're really just trying to take the<strong> dull</strong>, dirty and dangerous work off their plates to allow them to <strong>focus </strong>on those higher-level activities," Azimi said.</p>
<p>NASA is partnering with robotics companies like Apptronik, which is based in Austin, Texas. The goal is to learn how humanoid robots developed for purposes on Earth could help the development of future humanoid robots meant for space.</p>
<p>Apptronik is developing Apollo, a humanoid robot whose jobs on Earth will include working in warehouses and manufacturing plants. The robot can move packages and organize objects. Apptronik plans to start providing the humanoid robots to companies in early 2025.</p>
<p>Apptronik Chief Technology Officer Nick Paine said Apollo has strengths in comparison to humans.</p>
<p>"We're targeting having this system online 22 hours a day," Paine said. "This does have a <strong>swappable</strong> <strong>battery</strong>, so you can work for four hours, swap the battery and then keep going."</p>
<p>Apptronik chief Jeff Cardenas said there are many possibilities as new software and development increase Apollo's abilities.</p>
<p>"The approach is we're starting in the warehouse and on the manufacturing floor, but then it can move into retail...to <strong>delivery </strong>and out more into what we call unstructured spaces," Cardenas said.</p>
<p>In years to come, those "unstructured" areas could include space, Azimi said. He said the robots are being designed so they can be easily changed to do many different jobs.</p>
<p>"Robots like Apollo are designed with <strong>modularity </strong>in mind to be able to adapt to many <strong>applications</strong>," Azimi said.</p>
<p>Azimi added that NASA is aiming to find out what areas it needs to look into "to bring a<strong> terrestrial </strong>system into the space environment..."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Evan Garcia reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________</em>_____________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mythology </strong><em>– n. </em>the myths of a particular group or culture</p>
<p><strong>torso </strong><em>–n.</em> the part of the human body below the neck and above the waist</p>
<p><strong>dull </strong><em>– adj. </em>not interesting</p>
<p><strong>solar panel</strong> <em>– n. </em>a flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>– v. </em>to direct your attention or effort at something specific</p>
<p><strong>swappable </strong><em>–adj.</em> describes an act of giving or taking one thing in return for another thing</p>
<p><strong>battery</strong><em> –n. </em>a device that stores electricity and provides direct electrical current to electronics</p>
<p><strong>delivery</strong> <em>–n. </em>the act of taking something from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>modularity </strong><em>– n.</em> the quality of consisting of separate parts</p>
<p><strong>application<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the ability to be used for practical purposes</p>
<p><strong>terrestrial </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to on happening on the Earth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Treatments for Sickle Cell Remain Out of Reach for Many  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-treatments-for-sickle-cell-remain-out-of-reach-for-many.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>United States health officials recently approved two new gene treatments for sickle cell disease (SCD). The treatments provide hope that the disease might be curable. But experts say high costs and limited availability will prevent many people from receiving them.</p>
<p>SCD is a genetic disorder that causes oxygen-carrying red blood cells in the body to become misshapen. The condition can block blood flow and cause severe pain and organ damage.</p>
<p>SCD is more common among Black Americans, Africans and Middle Easterners than other population groups. Many children with the most severe form of the disease die before age five, usually from an infection or severe blood loss.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Gautam Dongre, of the National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations, sits for a portrait with his daughter, Sumedha, 13, at their residence in Nagpur, India, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2775-08dc0187f1c0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Gautam Dongre, of the National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations, sits for a portrait with his daughter, Sumedha, 13, at their residence in Nagpur, India, Wednesday, Dec. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)</span></div>
<p>Worldwide, the disease is believed to affect millions. It is known to be common in places with high cases of malaria, like Africa and India. Scientific research has shown that people who have SCD seem to react less severely when they are infected with malaria.</p>
<p>While an estimated 1 million people suffer with the condition in India, many of them will not get the chance to receive the new gene treatments. The situation is not new to developing countries. Many have long faced limitations on medicines and other treatment methods for disease.</p>
<p>But the problem is even more severe with the new SCD treatments and other gene-based methods. This is mainly because of the high cost of treatment. The two methods approved in the U.S. – both of which are given as a single treatment – cost between $2.2 million and $3.1 million.</p>
<p>In addition, the treatment itself can be difficult to carry out in developing nations. This is because the process generally involves several steps and requires longer stays in well-equipped hospitals.</p>
<p>Vertex's treatment, called Casgevy, is designed to repair the genetic condition that causes misshapen cells in sickle cell sufferers. It uses a <strong>gene editing</strong> technology called CRISPR to do so. The other treatment, offered by a company called Bluebird Bio, does not use CRISPR technology. But it requires a similar treatment process as Vertex's version.</p>
<p>Dr. David Altshuler is the chief scientific officer at Vertex. He told <em>The Associated Press</em> that while there is clearly a "great unmet need" for the new SCD treatments, the process also presents "<strong>challenges</strong>."</p>
<p>Altshuler said Vertex is working to simplify the treatment process to make it be available to more people. For example, his team is seeking to develop a medication in pill form that could perform similarly to the gene editing method.</p>
<p>But experts have warned that simpler treatments will likely still be too costly for many people. This has led to calls for governments and non-profit organizations to get involved to help provide financial assistance to patients.</p>
<p>Gautam Dongre lives in the city of Nagpur in central India. His two children suffer from SCD. He told the AP he has been "praying the treatment should come to us."</p>
<p>Dongre's son is now 19 years old and his daughter is 13. They both currently take a drug called hydroxyurea. That drug has long been used to help prevent the formation of sickle-shaped red blood cells in an effort to control pain and other damaging effects.</p>
<p>Dongre leads India's National Alliance of Sickle Cell Organizations. He said many patients in rural parts of India are dying at very young ages without getting effective treatment.</p>
<p>He added that if the gene treatments for SCD one day make it to India, he would like his children to be among the first to get them.</p>
<p>But Dongre noted that people in all countries – rich or poor – should be able to get the latest treatments available. "We are all part of one single planet," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gene editing </strong><em>– n. </em>the process of changing genes using scientific methods in an effort to prevent or cure disease</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>– n. </em>something difficult that tests one's ability or determination</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Connected Are You to the World?  (2024/1/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/how-connected-are-you-to-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Saodat Sadikova is an English teacher in Jizzakh, Uzbekistan. As a young girl, she dreamed of becoming a flight attendant and traveling the world. Her parents told her she would have to learn at least three languages in order to reach that goal.</p>
<p>Although she was not able to become a flight attendant, Sadikova did study languages. She speaks Uzbek, Russian, English and Turkish.</p>
<p>Sadikova has never traveled outside Uzbekistan. Even so, she reports feeling connected to people around the world. "The whole world is for human beings," Sadikova said. She still dreams of visiting many countries.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency's Digital Map of the World Project. (Graphic: BAE Systems)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7d6c4a69-ddbc-48cf-8962-dfbdd7379717_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency's Digital Map of the World Project. (Graphic: BAE Systems)</span></div>
<p>American Trina Bright worked in education for nearly 25 years. Today, she lives in the southern U.S. state of Arkansas. During her career, she traveled to many countries, including China and South Africa.</p>
<p>Bright used stories from her travels to help her students in the U.S. understand their place in the world. She spent most of her career in a minority-serving school district. Sharing stories from her travels helped her students see value in their own cultures. "There's value in all experiences, not just <strong>typical</strong> American ones," Bright said.</p>
<p>Bright has visited more than 20 countries. But Bright, unlike Sadikova, does not report feeling connected to people around the world.</p>
<p>Bright is not alone. She is among the more than half of Americans who report they do not feel especially close to people around the world.</p>
<p>That information comes from a new report by Pew Research Center, an organization that aims to inform the public about the issues, beliefs and trends shaping the world. The report, called <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/12/06/attitudes-on-an-interconnected-world/" target="_blank">Attitudes on an Interconnected World</a></em>, was released on December 6.</p>
<p>Pew recently asked people in 24 countries a series of questions about how connected they feel to their own communities and countries as well as to people around the world. Pew researchers looked at, among other things, how international travel experience relates to feelings of connectedness.</p>
<p>About half of all <strong>respondents</strong> reported they feel at least <strong>somewhat</strong> close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>Feeling close to others around the world is more common in Europe than in most other places, the study found. In the United States, only 35 percent of the respondents said they feel at least somewhat connected to those in other countries. The percentage was even lower in Argentina (28 percent) and Indonesia (22 percent).</p>
<p>The study found that, in general, respondents who had traveled to at least one other country feel more connected to people around the world.</p>
<p>Ninety-nine percent of respondents in the Netherlands reported having visited at least one other country and about half said they had visited 10 or more countries. The Pew researchers found that 77 percent of respondents from the Netherlands said they feel at least somewhat close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>But international travel does not always mean a person feels a closeness to people around the world. Bright, the retired American schoolteacher, is one such exception. She said, "I don't know a bunch of people around the world, just some." And, she said, her connections to them are not especially deep.</p>
<p>Pew researchers found a similar case in Sweden. Ninety-nine percent of Swedish respondents said they had visited at least one other country. Yet a much smaller share of Swedish respondents – 47 percent – report feeling close to people all over the world.</p>
<p>In fact, a higher number of Indian respondents – 68 percent – report feeling at least somewhat close to people all over the world. Yet just 3 percent of respondents from India said they had traveled to another country. Such findings show that international connectedness can be formed in ways other than traveling overseas.</p>
<p>Sadikova, the Uzbek English teacher, told VOA Learning English she feels connected to people all over the world even though she has never traveled outside Uzbekistan. She said, "Some years ago it was difficult for us to get information about people in the world, but currently, because of media, it is quite easy to get <strong>acquainted with</strong> events and news."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for Learning English with additional information from Pew Research Center.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>typical</strong>–<em>adj</em>. normal</p>
<p><strong>respondent</strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who answers a question</p>
<p><strong>somewhat</strong>–<em>adj</em>. a moderate amount</p>
<p><strong>acquainted with</strong>—<em>phrasal verb</em>. to be informed about someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
