<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Israeli Scientists Announce Creation of Embryo Model in Lab  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/israeli-scientists-announce-creation-of-embryo-model-in-lab.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Israeli scientists say they have created a model of a human embryo from stem cells in a laboratory.</p>
<p>The embryo model – created without using sperm, eggs or a <strong>uterus</strong> – is designed to support research on early human development.</p>
<p>Only stem cells were used in the process. Stem cells are simple cells in the body that can develop into one of many specialized cells. Researchers say the embryo models cannot grow into babies. But they are complete enough to provide information about what happens in the embryo during a pregnancy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="PhD student, Nir Livnat, works at the laboratory on models of an early-stage human embryo, in a laboratory at the Weizmann Institute of Science in Rehovot, Israel September 7, 2023. (REUTERS/Amir Cohen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d287-08dbb2d47717_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">PhD student, Nir Livnat, works at the laboratory on models of an early-stage human embryo, in a laboratory at the Weizmann Institute of Science in Rehovot, Israel September 7, 2023. (REUTERS/Amir Cohen)</span></div>
<p>The use of embryo models permits scientists to carry out research without the <strong>ethical</strong> concerns linked to experiments using real embryos.</p>
<p>Several international research teams have been working separately on studies involving human embryo models. Scientists from the United States, Britain and China <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/stem-cells-used-to-create-embryo-models-to-study-early-human-development/7161770.html">published their research results</a> on the subject in recent months.</p>
<p>The Israeli researchers say their embryo model looks similar to a real human embryo at day 14. At this point, the embryo model has begun building inner structures. But it has not yet developed enough to start forming body organs, the team said.</p>
<p>The scientists recently reported their results <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06604-5">in a study</a> in the publication <em>Nature</em>. They also shared their research with scientists during a June meeting of the International Society for Stem Cell Research in Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>The Israeli team noted that their current research is still a long way from being able to create a full embryo in the lab.</p>
<p>Jacob Hanna was the team leader on the research. He told the Reuters news agency, "The question is, when does an embryo model become considered an embryo? When that happens, we know the <strong>regulations</strong>. At the moment we are really, really far off from that point."</p>
<p>But the researchers said the work could open the door to new ways to study early human development. For example, the embryo models could test the effect of drugs on pregnancies. They could also help scientists better understand <strong>miscarriages</strong> and genetic diseases. And they might one day be used to grow <strong>transplant</strong> tissues and organs.</p>
<p>Hanna noted that the models are not exactly like human embryos. "There are differences from human embryos, but still, this is the first time, if you open an <strong>atlas</strong> or a textbook, you can say - yeah I can really see the similarity between them," he said.</p>
<p>Hanna said his team took stem cells produced from adult human skin cells, as well as others, and let them develop in the lab. The researchers then <strong>reverted</strong> the cells to an early state, with the possibility that they could develop into different kinds of cells.</p>
<p>The team then genetically changed the cells in an effort to get them to start developing into something that looks and behaves like a real human embryo. However, the researchers said their creation is not an actual or <strong>synthetic</strong> embryo. Instead, it is considered a model that shows how a real embryo works.</p>
<p>Hanna said the process was able to start effective structure development. But he added that "the farthest we could get is day 14 in human embryo development."</p>
<p>Hanna said the team's next goal will be to extend model development to 21 days and also reach a success rate of at least 50 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>uterus </strong><em>– n. </em>(medical) a term for the organ in a woman that holds the baby during pregnancy; womb</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to what is right or wrong</p>
<p><strong>regulation </strong><em>– n. </em>an official rule that controls how something is done</p>
<p><strong>miscarriage </strong>– <em>n. </em>a situation in which a baby is born too early and dies because it has not developed enough to survive</p>
<p><strong>transplant </strong><em>– v. </em>to perform a medical operation in which an organ or other part that has been removed from the body of one person is put into the body of another person</p>
<p><strong>atlas </strong><em>– n. </em>a book of maps</p>
<p><strong>revert </strong><em>– v. </em>to go back to the way something was before</p>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong>–<em> adj. </em>a group of products made from artificial substances, often copying a natural product</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Gardeners Can Reduce Risk of Fire  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/how-gardeners-can-reduce-risk-of-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Invasive grasses might have played a part in the deadly wildfires that burned Lahaina, Hawaii recently. The grasses have taken over land that was once occupied by crops like sugar and pineapple.</p>
<p>Michele Steinberg is wildfire division director at the National Fire Protection Association. She said some plants are more <strong>flammable</strong> than others. But, she noted, "there is no such thing as a fireproof plant." All plants can catch fire under the right conditions.</p>
<p>Those conditions include poor <strong>pruning</strong>, lack of watering, and letting dry, dead plant parts remain on the soil surface in high-risk areas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by John Ruter shows pampas grass (Cortaderia selloana), an invasive, nonnative plant that is highly-flammable. (John Ruter, University of Georgia, Bugwood.org)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4409f9fa-a686-4c06-a876-be3a3ecd713c_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by John Ruter shows pampas grass (Cortaderia selloana), an invasive, nonnative plant that is highly-flammable. (John Ruter, University of Georgia, Bugwood.org)</span></div>
<p>If you are selecting plants for your <strong>garden</strong>, knowing which plants offer some fire resistance and which are more flammable can serve you well.</p>
<p><strong>Quicker to catch fire</strong></p>
<p>Plants that produce flammable substances, like aromatic oils, resins, waxes, or sap, are among the quickest to catch fire. They will often catch fire even if they have been well-watered and cared for. They include bamboo, rosemary, and eucalyptus.</p>
<p>Trees with papery <strong>bark </strong>that falls off, like river birch, are usually more flammable than those without. And fine-<strong>needled</strong> plants like pine, juniper, and spruce contain saps and resins. Their needle-like leaves increase the risk of fire when left on the ground or on the top of a house.</p>
<p>Many grasses are highly flammable. Their ability to <strong>ignite</strong> increases when they are left to stand dry over winter or during periods without rain. Additionally, too much heat dries out the soil and under such conditions, many kinds of plants turn into a fire starter.</p>
<p><strong>Native vs. non-native</strong></p>
<p>As a group, "native plants aren't necessarily less flammable" than introduced kinds of plants, Steinberg said.</p>
<p>But nonnative, invasive plants often are a greater fire risk because they spread quickly and are usually left alone by wildlife. The nonnative plants spread faster than native plants, and often <strong>tolerate</strong> heat, lack of rain and heavy rain better.</p>
<p>For the best fire resistance, choose <strong>deciduous </strong>trees, like ash, crabapple, and maple, over fine-needled trees. Plants like succulents with water-filled leaves are slow to burn. They include ice plants and sedums. Some groundcover plants, like ajuga and creeping phlox, are also slow burners.</p>
<p><strong>What to look for in plants</strong></p>
<p>The Washington State University Extension Service has published advice for choosing plants that are fire-resistant. Qualities that make a plant less likely to burn include:</p>
<p>· High water content in leaves (these ignite and burn more slowly).</p>
<p>· Little or no seasonal gain of dead plant material.</p>
<p>· Open branching (they provide less fuel for fires).</p>
<p>· Fewer total branches and leaves (again, less fuel for fires).</p>
<p>· Slow-growing, so less pruning is required (to keep open structure as noted above).</p>
<p>· Non-flammable material on the plant, like resins, oil, or wax.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>flammable </strong><em>– adj.</em> capable of being set on fire and of burning quickly</p>
<p><strong>prune </strong><em>– v.</em> to cut off some of the branches of (a tree or bush) so that it will grow better or look better</p>
<p><strong>garden </strong><em>– n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>bark <em>–</em></strong><em>n.</em> the outer surface of a tree</p>
<p><strong>needle </strong>– <em>n.</em> a leaf that is shaped like a very thin stick</p>
<p><strong>ignite </strong>– <em>v</em>. to set (something) on fire: to cause (something) to burn</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong><em>– v.</em> to experience (something harmful or unpleasant) without being harmed</p>
<p><strong>deciduous </strong>– <em>adj.</em> having leaves that fall off every year</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rescuers Work to Help Morocco Earthquake Victims  (2023/9/12) | 救援人员抓紧救助摩洛哥地震受害者</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rescuers-work-to-help-morocco-earthquake-victims.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rescue workers continue to search the wreckage of a large earthquake that struck Morocco Friday.<br/>
摩洛哥周五发生大地震，救援人员仍在废墟中搜救。</p>
<p>Officials say almost 2,500 were killed in the quake, but that they expect that number will rise. On Monday, Morocco's state news agency reported almost 2,500 others are injured. And, it reported more injured people continue to arrive at hospitals.<br/>
官方表示，地震造成近2500人死亡，但他们预计这一数字还会上升。周一，摩洛哥国家通讯社报道，另有近2500人受伤。据报道，越来越多的伤者还在被送往医院。</p>
<p>Moroccan soldiers, doctors and other aid teams are still making their way to the Al Haouz area high in the Atlas mountains, the epicenter of the earthquake. The area is about 70 kilometers from the city of Marrakech.<br/>
摩洛哥士兵、医生和其他救援队仍在前往震中阿特拉斯山脉高处的豪兹地区。该地区距离马拉喀什市约70公里。</p>
<p>The United Nations said the magnitude 6.8 earthquake affected 300,000 people. The damage was great because the starting point of the shaking was not far below the ground.<br/>
联合国表示，这场6.8级地震影响了30万人。因为震中距离地面不远，造成的损失很大。</p>
<p>The U.S. Geological Survey said it was the strongest quake to strike the North African nation since 1900. And, it is reported to be country's deadliest since 1960, when at least 12,000 people were killed in and near the city of Agadir.<br/>
美国地质调查局表示，这是摩洛哥自1900年以来遭受的最强地震。据报道，这也是自1960年以来该国死亡人数最多的一次，当时阿加迪尔市及其附近至少有1.2万人死亡。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Offers of help<br/>
提供援助</span></p>
<p>So far, Morocco has accepted assistance from four countries – Spain, Qatar, Great Britain and the United Arab Emirates. Other nations have offered help, as well.<br/>
到目前为止，摩洛哥已经接受了西班牙、卡塔尔、英国和阿联酋这四个国家的援助。其他国家也提供了援助。</p>
<p>But, the Moroccan government says it wants to avoid a "counterproductive" lack of coordination by accepting help from too many countries.<br/>
但是，摩洛哥政府表示，它希望避免接受太多国家的援助，以免因为缺乏协调而造成适得其反。</p>
<p>One survivor, Salah Ancheu, called the earthquake "a catastrophe" even as a truckload of soldiers arrived in Amizmiz to help. "We don't know what the future is. The aid remains insufficient," the 28-year-old said.<br/>
幸存者萨拉称此次地震为“一场灾难”，即便一卡车士兵抵达艾米兹米兹提供帮助。“我们不知道未来会怎样。援助仍然不足，”这位28岁的年轻人说。</p>
<p>Mountainside homes and the tower of the local mosque fell down.<br/>
山上的房屋和当地清真寺的塔楼倒塌了。</p>
<p>Groups from the Moroccan army left Monday from Amizmiz to move into the small mountain villages. Heavy equipment was sent to clear the roads and both visitors and residents lined up to give blood.<br/>
摩洛哥军队的队伍星期一从艾米兹米兹出发，进入小山村。重型设备被派去清理道路，游客和居民都在排队献血。</p>
<p>Some news reports said villagers wept as they saw dead bodies being carried through the streets.<br/>
一些新闻报道说，当村民们看到尸体被抬过街道时，他们哭了。</p>
<p>A number of nations said they were ready, but not yet permitted to send help. The group Rescuers Without Borders said about 100 teams, totaling 3,500 rescuers, are prepared to help.<br/>
一些国家表示，他们已做好准备，但尚未获准提供援助。无国界救援组织表示，大约有100支队伍，共计3500名救援人员准备提供援助。</p>
<p>France said four of its citizens died. It has offered assistance but has not been given permission to send rescuers.<br/>
法国称有四名该国公民死亡。它已经提供了援助，但没有得到派遣救援人员的许可。</p>
<p>In the Czech Republic, 70 rescuers are waiting at an airport for permission to enter Morocco. In Germany, a rescue team of 50 was sent home after waiting at an airport.<br/>
在捷克共和国，70名救援人员正在机场等待进入摩洛哥的许可。在德国，一支由50人组成的救援队在机场等候后被遣送回国。</p>
<p>A spokesperson from the German foreign ministry said Morocco's refusal of aid from some nations should not be seen as political. "I'm sure they have thought very carefully about which forces can be deployed and how they can get there," the spokesperson said.<br/>
德国外交部发言人表示，摩洛哥拒绝一些国家的援助不应被视为政治行为。这位发言人说：“我相信他们已经非常仔细地考虑了可以部署哪些队伍，以及他们如何到达那里。”</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Catherine Colonna said France has offered more than $5 million in support. She said Morocco's decision on that offer is its own to make and "must be respected."<br/>
法国外交部长凯瑟琳·科隆纳表示，法国已提供超过500万美元的援助。她说，摩洛哥对此援助的决定是他自己的事，“必须得到尊重”。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">People sleeping outside<br/>
人们露宿街头</span></p>
<p>Many people continue to sleep outside, fearing smaller earthquakes that often follow a major one.<br/>
许多人担心大地震后会发生较小的余震，从而继续露宿街头。</p>
<p>In the village of Imgdal, women and children gathered outside and some kept warm around an open fire on Monday morning.<br/>
周一早上在Imgdal村，妇女和儿童聚集在外面，一些人在明火旁取暖。</p>
<p>In another village, Tafeghaghte, Hamid ben Henna said his 8-year-old son died in the quake. He had gone to another room while the family was sharing a meal Friday. The rest of the family survived.<br/>
在另一个村庄Tafeghahte，哈米德· 本·汉拿说他8岁的儿子在地震中死亡。周五时一家人正在一起吃饭，孩子去了另一个房间。家里其他人都活了下来。</p>
<p>On a road near the town of Adassil, close to the center of the quake, one rescue worker was trying to clear the rocks that were preventing vehicles from getting by.<br/>
在靠近震中的阿达西尔镇附近的一条道路上，一名救援人员正试图清理阻碍车辆通行的岩石。</p>
<p>He said other roads were in bad shape. "We're trying to open them, too," said Ayman Koait.<br/>
他说，其他道路状况不佳。艾麦尼表示：“我们也在努力打通它们。”</p>
<p>People said they dug through the rubble of their homes looking for relatives. They also moved rocks and walls looking for important items.<br/>
人们说，他们在房屋的废墟中挖掘以寻找亲人。他们还搬动石头和墙块来寻找重要物品。</p>
<p>Many of the homes are made from wood, rock, and mud, which made them fall easily when the ground started shaking.<br/>
许多房屋是由木材、石头和泥土建造的，当地面开始震动时，它们很容易倒塌。</p>
<p>One military worker said "it is difficult to pull people out alive" because the walls turned to rubble and did not leave any space for air.<br/>
一名军事工作者表示，“很难把人活着救出来”，因为墙壁变成了瓦砾，没有留下任何呼吸的空间。</p>
<p>UNESCO, the United Nations cultural organization, said many historic buildings in both Marrakech and the areas closer to the center of the earthquake were damaged.<br/>
联合国文化组织联合国教科文组织表示，马拉喀什和震中附近地区的许多历史建筑都遭到了破坏。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Drug Traffickers Use Banana Industry in Ecuador for Shipping  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/drug-traffickers-use-banana-industry-in-ecuador-for-shipping.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ecuador is increasingly at the meeting point of two worldwide trades: bananas and cocaine.</p>
<p>The South American country is the world's largest exporter of bananas with about 6.5 million metric tons a year. Its neighbors, Peru and Colombia, are the world's largest cocaine producers.</p>
<p>Drug traffickers find containers filled with bananas the perfect vehicle to <strong>smuggle</strong> their product.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Recently harvested bananas are washed at a farm in Los Rios, Ecuador, Tuesday, Aug. 15, 2023. Bananas headed to a commercial port must meet long-established beauty standards of the export market. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-015d-08dbafe3a3ea_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Recently harvested bananas are washed at a farm in Los Rios, Ecuador, Tuesday, Aug. 15, 2023. Bananas headed to a commercial port must meet long-established beauty standards of the export market. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)</span></div>
<p>Drug trafficking has since brought extreme violence across this once-peaceful nation. Shootings, murders, kidnappings and <strong>extortions</strong> have become part of daily life. That is especially true in the Pacific port city and banana-shipping center of Guayaquil.</p>
<p>The country was shocked when Fernando Villavicencio, a presidential candidate known for his tough position on organized crime, was shot to death on August 9. He had accused the Ecuadorian Los Choneros criminal group and its imprisoned leader of threatening him and his campaign team days before the killing.</p>
<p>In addition to being close to cocaine production, drug smugglers from Mexico, Colombia and the Balkans in Europe have also set up operations in Ecuador. That is because the country uses the U.S. dollar; its laws and <strong>institutions</strong> are weak; and criminal groups like Los Choneros are ready to work.</p>
<p>A record 2,304 metric tons of cocaine was produced in 2021 around the world, mostly in Colombia, Peru and Bolivia. That year, nearly a third of the cocaine seized by officials in Western and Central Europe came from Ecuador, two times the amount reported in 2018, found a United Nations report.</p>
<p>Large drug seizures have become more common within the past month. European officials have made record-setting seizures after inspecting containers carrying bananas from Ecuador.</p>
<p>Officials on August 25 announced Spain's biggest cocaine seizure yet: 9.5 metric tons hidden among boxes of bananas from Ecuador in a <strong>refrigerated</strong> container. Dutch officials also made their country's largest-ever cocaine seizure last month — nearly 8 metric tons — in a container of Ecuadorian bananas. Officials in Greece and Italy also announced seizures of cocaine hidden in Ecuadorian bananas this year.</p>
<p>Knowingly or not, banana growers, exporters, shipping companies, port operators, private security companies, <strong>customs</strong> agents, agriculture officials, police, and buyers can be used by drug traffickers.</p>
<p>Some traffickers have created false companies to look like real banana exporters. Others have taken control of legal businesses, including plantations. They have found companies willing to cooperate in trafficking. They have also paid off, threatened or kidnapped truck drivers and other workers to help get cocaine into shipments.</p>
<p>Violent deaths in Ecuador have doubled from 2021 to 2022, when 4,600 died, the most ever recorded in a year. The country is likely to break the yearly record again, with 3,568 violent deaths recorded in the first half of 2023. In Guayaquil, people live in fear.</p>
<p>No more than 30 percent of containers are currently inspected at Ecuadorian ports. President Guillermo Lasso's government says it wants to use <strong>scanners</strong> on entire containers. Twelve of those machines were supposed to be operating already but that has not happened yet, said National Police General Pablo Ramírez. He is Ecuador's national director of anti-drug investigations.</p>
<p>Jose Hidalgo is director of the Association of Banana Exporters of Ecuador. He said the industry is more <strong>vulnerable</strong> to trafficking than other export products because of the number of containers that it uses.</p>
<p>He explained that exporters spend about $100 million yearly on security measures. That includes <strong>surveillance</strong> cameras at plantations, GPS <strong>monitoring</strong> of trucks, and the identification of land routes that require police patrols to keep criminals away.</p>
<p>Still, some exporters have been accused of being involved in trafficking cocaine. The organization behind the cocaine seizure in Spain operated through a banana exporting company in Machala, a city south of Guayaquil.</p>
<p>After this story was published in The Associated Press, agriculture and customs officials in Ecuador announced in a statement that they had removed a government-run banana export database. It removed information on export companies considered to be false or incomplete. It also canceled permits of plantations covering 16,000 hectares found to be nonexistent.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>smuggle </strong><em>— v. </em>to move from one country into another illegally and secretly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extort </strong><em>— v. </em>to get from a person by the use of force or threats</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>institution </strong><em>— n. </em>an established organization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>refrigerate </strong><em>— adj. </em>to put or keep in a refrigerator in order to make it cold or keep it fresh</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>customs </strong><em>— n. </em>an action or way of behaving that is usual and traditional among the people in a particular group or place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scanner </strong><em>— n. </em>a device that reads or copies information or images into a computer</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>— adj. </em> easily hurt or harmed physically, mentally, or emotionally</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surveillance </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of carefully watching someone or something especially in order to prevent or detect a crime</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>— v. </em>a device that is used for showing, watching, or listening to something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is the Goal of Japan’s New Moon Mission?  (2023/9/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/what-is-the-goal-of-japan-s-new-moon-mission.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Last week, Japan's space agency launched a rocket carrying a spacecraft designed to explore the moon.</p>
<p>The lunar lander is known as the Smart Lander for Investigating the Moon (SLIM). It aims to touch down on the moon's surface early next year. If successful, it would make Japan the fifth nation to land a spacecraft on the moon.</p>
<p>So far, only the United States, Russia, China and India have successfully landed spacecraft on the moon. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/india-successfully-lands-spacecraft-on-moon/7238173.html">India's landing</a> happened last month. India's landing came days after Russia failed in its attempt to return to the moon for the first time in nearly 50 years.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="An HII-A rocket blasts off from the launch pad at Tanegashima Space Center in Kagoshima, southern Japan Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023. (Kyodo News via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7083-08dbb008fc8f_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">An HII-A rocket blasts off from the launch pad at Tanegashima Space Center in Kagoshima, southern Japan Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023. (Kyodo News via AP)</span></div>
<p>In April, a private Japanese space exploration company announced its space vehicle <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/japanese-space-company-says-moon-lander-likely-crashed/7067305.html">crashed</a> while trying to land on the moon. If that landing had been successful, it would have marked the first time a private business landed on the moon.</p>
<p>In the latest launch, an H-IIA rocket lifted off on September 7 from Tanegashima Space Center in southwestern Japan, the country's JAXA space agency said. Hours after the launch, JAXA said it was receiving signals from the SLIM spacecraft, suggesting it was operating normally. It is expected to start the lunar landing process by February, the Reuters news agency reported.</p>
<p>Japanese space officials have said SLIM aims to land within 100 meters of its target area on the moon's surface. The purpose, or mission, of the lander is to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets.</p>
<p>JAXA President Hiroshi Yamakawa told a news conference the mission aims to prove that in the future, spacecraft will be able to land "where we want," rather than only landing "where we can."</p>
<p>SLIM is set to touch down in an area called Mare Nectaris, on the southeastern half of the moon. The area contains <strong>plains</strong> of solidified lava and appears as a dark area from Earth.</p>
<p>After landing, SLIM will seek to examine the mineral-rich rocks to search for clues about the moon's development. The spacecraft is not carrying a lunar explorer.</p>
<p>SLIM is a small lander. It weighs a little more than 700 kilograms. JAXA plans to use additional light spacecraft in the future to reduce launch costs and permit more missions.</p>
<p>The spacecraft uses a chemical <strong>propulsion</strong> system and is equipped with very small electronic devices to control the lander. SLIM's overall development cost about $102 million.</p>
<p>The rocket that launched SLIM also carried the X-Ray Imaging and Spectroscopy Mission (XRISM) satellite. This part of the mission is a joint project of JAXA, the American space agency NASA and the European Space Agency.</p>
<p>The lander successfully separated from the rocket about 45 minutes after the launch. Ground stations in Hawaii and Japan received signals from XRISM soon after the launch. This confirmed the satellite's solar equipment had successfully deployed, JAXA said.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse, JAXA and NASA.</em></p>
<p>The XRISM satellite is designed to take images in many wavelengths of X-rays and to study the chemicals that exist in matter at high temperatures. It can gather information on the speed and makeup of what lies between galaxies. This can help scientists better understand how stars and galaxies developed. The satellite is equipped to look at X-rays of different wavelengths, or <strong>spectra,</strong> even ones at very high energy levels.</p>
<p>JAXA is also planning a joint lunar mission with the Indian Space Research Organization sometime after 2025. This will involve Japan's H3 rocket carrying India's next lunar lander into space.</p>
<p>And Japan also aims to send an astronaut to the moon's surface in the latter half of the 2020s as part of NASA's Artemis program.</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>plain </strong><em>– n. </em>a large area of flat land</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong><em>– n. </em>a force that pushes something forward</p>
<p><strong>galaxy </strong><em>– n. </em>a very large group of stars held together in the</p>
<p>universe</p>
<p><strong>spectrum (spectra pl.) </strong>–n. the wavelengths of electromagnetic radiation that scientist use to find the chemical properties of very hot gases</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Who Are the Wealthy Investors Buying Rural California Land?  (2023/9/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/who-are-the-wealthy-investors-buying-rural-california-land.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A group of technology investors recently released its plans to create a new "green" city between San Francisco and Sacramento in California.</p>
<p>The group's name is California Forever. It posted the plans on its website of the same name. The leader is Jan Sramek, a former trader for the financial services company Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>California Forever has purchased about $800 million of land in Solano County. The county includes small cities, many farms, and an American military base.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A wind farm is seen at dusk in rural Solano County, Calif., Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;squez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/85093003-cc89-49a0-8c55-c9e0c3c8ee96_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A wind farm is seen at dusk in rural Solano County, Calif., Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V<i>&amp;#</i>225;squez)</span></div>
<p>The area is about 100 kilometers from San Francisco and 50 kilometers from the state capital of Sacramento. About 450,000 people live in the county. The cost of a mid-level home is around $600,000 while homes closer to San Francisco can be two or three times more. Housing supply is one of the greatest concerns in California, and those who work as schoolteachers, nurses or police officers cannot live close to where they work.</p>
<p>California Forever's announcement opened with this message, "Starting a conversation about eastern Solano County. A chance for a new community, good paying local jobs, solar farms and open space."</p>
<p>The post includes a lot of information about the land purchases and the group's ideas. The website includes drawings of new homes, farms, fields with solar panels, people sitting in boats and fishing and eating meals in a central city area.</p>
<p>The investment group has purchased 202 square kilometers of land since 2018. Among the investors are business leaders Laurene Powell Jobs, tech investor Marc Andreessen and LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman. California Forever's post reported that 97 percent of its investors are American. There had been some concerns that the investment group was from outside of the U.S.</p>
<p>The project sounds good to the investors, but local leaders and <strong>residents</strong> are not sure they agree.</p>
<p>To start with, many people are upset with the group's secrecy. The investors made the purchases under the name "Flannery Associates LLC."</p>
<p>Mike Thompson represents the area in the lower house of the U.S. Congress. He said the U.S. Department of Treasury and the Federal Bureau of Investigation has been working to learn who was behind the land purchases.</p>
<p>"Their secrecy has caused a lot of problems, a lot of time and a lot of <strong>expense</strong>," Thompson said.</p>
<p>The investors say they needed to keep their identities secret until they had enough land. Now that they are discussing the project, they say they want to have conversations with the residents of Solano. The group started by sending a <strong>survey</strong> to homeowners.</p>
<p>The survey asked residents about what they want for the future of Solano County. Residents' answers included lower cost of living, more good jobs, as well as improved schools and safety from crime.</p>
<p>Solano County resident Princess Washington is suspicious of California Forever's plans. Washington is the acting mayor of Suisun City, in central Solano. She says many people who live in the area do not want development. They want to keep the area close to Travis Air Force Base open.</p>
<p>She said she is concerned that the Flannery group wants to create a "city for the <strong>elite</strong>" by falsely saying they plan to build low cost homes.</p>
<p>She wondered why the group does not want to <strong>transform</strong> cities that already exist.</p>
<p>"The better thing would be to <strong>approach</strong> our city leaders and work with us within our city boundaries. Not to create a new city."</p>
<p>Flannery also faced anger earlier this year when it opened a court case against a group of landowners. Flannery said the land owners were working together to make sure they sold only at high prices.</p>
<p>Other residents say they became worried just recently, when the group sent out a survey. It asked the community about its level of support for "a major new project ... with tens of thousands of new homes."</p>
<p>Representative Thompson says he is not sure Sramek and the other investors understood Solano County or its values.</p>
<p>He said Sramek thinks his financial expertise will help the developers push the project forward faster than other California homebuilders.</p>
<p>"He doesn't have a plan, he's not there yet," Thompson said.</p>
<p>Many homebuilders say California is a difficult place to do business because there are many rules for the industry to follow.</p>
<p>Hoffman and Andreessen did not respond to emailed requests for comment, nor did Jobs through her business Emerson Collective.</p>
<p>Project developers said they will protect the military base and farmers who want to keep farming on their parcels.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>resident</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who lives in a region, city; a home or land owner</p>
<p><strong>expense</strong> <em>–n. </em>money spent to do business or work or to purchase something</p>
<p><strong>survey</strong> <em>–n. </em>a group of questions asked of many people in order to get the public's opinion about a topic</p>
<p><strong>elite</strong> <em>–adj. </em>at the highest level</p>
<p><strong>transform</strong> <em>–v. </em>to change something into something else</p>
<p><strong>approach</strong> <em>–v. </em>to come to a person and ask for something or to make an introduction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Help for Gamblers as Sports Betting Rise in US  (2023/9/11) | 美国要求体育博彩资助戒赌服务</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/help-for-gamblers-as-sports-betting-rise-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>People in the American state of Kentucky will be able to legally bet on sporting events for the first time in September. When they do, they also help to pay for the first-ever state program to help people with gambling problems.<br/>
今年9月，美国肯塔基州的人们将首次能够合法地在体育赛事上下注。当他们下注时，他们还承担了有史以来首个州级戒赌项目的费用。</p>
<p>Five years ago, the U.S. Supreme Court cleared the way for legalized sports betting. Almost three-fourths of U.S. states have since permitted sports betting but support for problem gambling services has been limited. Now, more states like Kentucky are requiring at least some sports gambling money to go toward helping addicted gamblers.<br/>
五年前，美国最高法院为体育博彩合法化扫清了道路。此后，美国近四分之三的州允许体育博彩，但对戒赌服务的支持有限。现在，更多像肯塔基州这样的州要求至少将部分体育博彩资金用于帮助上瘾的赌徒。</p>
<p>Research shows that younger, higher-educated men are among the most likely to bet on sports. Technology has made gambling much easier. In many states, people can now bet on smartphone apps, 24 hours a day. People can bet not only on the winners of games but on all sorts of events that happen during the game.<br/>
研究表明，受过高等教育的年轻男性最有可能在体育运动上下注。科技让赌博变得更加容易。在许多州，人们现在24小时可以在智能手机应用程序上下注。人们不仅可以把赌注押在比赛的获胜者身上，还可以押在比赛中发生的各种事件上。</p>
<p>For the last five years, legal sports betting brought in $3 billion in taxes for local and state governments. However, the states spent little on problem gambling services.<br/>
在过去的五年里，合法的体育博彩为地方和州政府带来了30亿美元的税收。然而，各州在戒赌服务上的支出很少。</p>
<p>In 2022, the state of Massachusetts budgeted $10 million for problem gambling services. And nine other states did not spend any. Most of the money from gambling went toward services like telephone helplines, counseling, and public awareness campaigns.<br/>
2022年，马萨诸塞州预算1000万美元用于戒赌服务。其他九个州没有任何支出。赌博带来的大部分资金用于电话求助热线、咨询和公众宣传活动等服务。</p>
<p>The federal government, which spends billions of dollars on substance abuse prevention and treatment, provides nothing for gambling problems.<br/>
联邦政府在药物滥用预防和治疗上花费了数十亿美元，却没有为戒赌提供任何帮助。</p>
<p>Kentucky is projected to spend about $575,000 in its first year on gambling problems.<br/>
肯塔基州预计第一年将在戒赌上花费约575000美元。</p>
<p>Michael R. Stone is the director of the nonprofit Kentucky Council on Problem Gambling. He said the amount of money is a good start, but "we've only got five certified gambling counselors in the state right now, and we're going to need probably five times that many..."<br/>
迈克尔·R·斯通是非营利组织肯塔基州戒赌委员会的主任。他说，这笔钱是一个良好的开端，但“我们目前在该州只有五名经过认证的戒赌顾问，我们可能需要五倍数量的……”</p>
<p>As of a year ago, 15 states and the District of Columbia had laws requiring some of the money from sports betting to go toward problem gambling services. But another 15 states did not.<br/>
截至一年前，15个州和哥伦比亚特区制定了法律，要求体育博彩的部分资金用于戒赌服务。但另有15个州没有这样做。</p>
<p>Since then, seven more states have either launched sports betting or passed laws to do so. All of those have required part of their sports betting money to go to problem gambling services, said Rachel Volberg. She is a researcher at the University of Massachusetts-Amhurst.<br/>
自那以后，又有七个州启动了体育博彩或通过了相关法律。雷切尔·沃伯格表示，所有这些州都要求将部分体育博彩资金用于戒赌服务。她是马萨诸塞大学阿姆赫斯特分校的研究员。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Newly Discovered Comet Won't Return for 400 Years  (2023/9/10) | 新发现彗星可肉眼观测</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/newly-discovered-comet-won-t-return-for-400-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A newly discovered comet is passing through our solar system for the first time in more than 400 years.<br/>
一颗新发现的彗星400多年来首次穿过我们的太阳系。</p>
<p>Scientists say star watchers across the Northern Hemisphere should look to the sky as soon as possible, either this week or early next. They say it will be another 400 years before the comet returns to our neighborhood.<br/>
科学家表示，北半球的观星者应该尽快观测天空，无论是本周还是下周初。他们说，这颗彗星还需要400年才能回到我们附近。</p>
<p>The comet's official name is C/2023 P1 Nishimura. It is about one kilometer wide. Comet Nishimura will travel to within 125 million kilometers of the Earth on September 12.<br/>
这颗彗星的官方名称是C/2023P1西村彗星。它宽约一公里。西村彗星将于9月12日到达距离地球1.25亿公里以内的地方。</p>
<p>The comet was discovered in August by a Japanese star watcher, Hideo Nishimura. He discovered the comet using 30-second-long exposures with a digital camera.<br/>
这颗彗星是由日本观星者西村秀夫于8月发现的。他用数码相机进行了30秒长的曝光，发现了这颗彗星。</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA says the comet has increased in brightness as it crosses our solar system. As the comet heads closer to the Sun, it will continue to get brighter.<br/>
美国宇航局表示，这颗彗星在穿越太阳系时亮度有所增加。随着彗星向太阳靠近，它将继续变得更亮。</p>
<p>Early risers should look toward the northeastern horizon about 90 minutes before sunrise. The comet will be less than 10 degrees above the horizon making it difficult to see.<br/>
早起者应该在日出前90分钟左右眺望东北地平线。彗星离地平线不到10度，因此很难看到。</p>
<p>Paul Chodas is head of NASA's Center for Near-Earth Object Studies. He said, "You really need a good pair of binoculars to pick it out and you also need to know where to look."<br/>
保罗·乔达斯是美国宇航局近地天体研究中心的负责人。他说：“你真的需要一副好的双筒望远镜才能把它找出来，你还需要知道去哪里看。”</p>
<p>The comet will come closest to the sun on about September 17. Then it will leave the solar system. Chodas said that the comet is "likely to survive its passage," meaning he does not believe it will burn up near the sun.<br/>
这颗彗星将于9月17日左右离太阳最近。然后它将离开太阳系。乔达斯说，这颗彗星在掠过太阳系时“很可能会幸存下来”，这意味着乔达斯认为它不会在太阳附近燃烧殆尽。</p>
<p>Italian astronomer Gianluca Masi is the founder of the Virtual Telescope Project. He said in an email to the Associated Press that the next week represents "the last, feasible chances" to see the comet from the Northern Hemisphere before it is lost in the sun's glare.<br/>
意大利天文学家詹卢卡·马西是虚拟望远镜项目的创始人。他在给美联社的一封电子邮件中说，下周是从北半球观测西村彗星的最后也是最可行的时机，之后它将“消失在太阳光芒中”。</p>
<p>"The comet looks amazing right now, with a long, highly structured tail, a joy to image with a telescope," he said.<br/>
他说：“这颗彗星现在看起来很神奇，它拖一条长长的、高度结构化的尾巴，用望远镜成像是一种享受。”</p>
<p>If it survives its passage by the sun, the comet should be visible in the Southern Hemisphere by the end of September, Masi said.<br/>
马西说，如果它在掠过太阳时没有解体，那么到9月底，这颗彗星应该可以在南半球看到。</p>
<p>Professional astronomers use powerful telescopes around the world to watch the sky. It is unusual for a non-professional sky watcher to discover a comet these days. Chodas of NASA said of Nishimura's discovery, "This is his third find, so good for him."<br/>
专业天文学家使用世界各地强大的望远镜观测天空。对于非专业的天空观测者来说，如今发现彗星是不寻常的。美国宇航局的乔达斯在谈到西村的发现时说：“这是他的第三次发现，对他来说太棒了。”</p>
<p>The comet last visited about 430 years ago, Chodas said.<br/>
乔达斯说，这颗彗星上次造访太阳系大约是在430年前。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thirteen US Universities Form a Free Speech Group  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/thirteen-us-universities-form-a-free-speech-group.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thirteen American colleges and universities recently announced the creation of a plan to support freedom of speech.</p>
<p>The plan is part of an effort designed to fight what the schools call threats to U.S. democracy.</p>
<p>Among the schools taking part are Cornell University in New York state; Rutgers University in New Jersey; Notre Dame, the Catholic university in the Midwestern state of Indiana; and Benedict College, a historically Black school in South Carolina.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this May 15, 2016 file photo, students embrace as they arrive for the Rutgers graduation ceremonies in Piscataway, New Jersey. (AP Photo/Mel Evans)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6223A73D-0D7D-4727-849B-9205E51345A5_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this May 15, 2016 file photo, students embrace as they arrive for the Rutgers graduation ceremonies in Piscataway, New Jersey. (AP Photo/Mel Evans)</span></div>
<p>The effort is called The Campus Call for Free Expression. The organizer of the group is The Institute for Citizens and Scholars based in Princeton, New Jersey. It is paid for by the Knight Foundation, a private group based in Miami, Florida. The aim is to build respect for freedom of expression in colleges. Another goal is to help students bring opposing groups together.</p>
<p>The effort for free speech comes after students at several schools blocked people invited to speak in recent years. The students said they disagreed with the writings, comments, ideas or actions of the invited speaker.</p>
<p>Jonathan Alger is the president of James Madison University in Virginia, one of the schools in the group. He said the group is concerned about "deep <strong>polarization</strong>" in the U.S. where people cannot discuss their different ideas in "<strong>constructive</strong> and civil ways." He said colleges and universities need to be an example for the nation.</p>
<p>The group started preparing for The Campus Call for Free Expression in March 2022. That was when college presidents gathered to discuss ways to get their students involved in democracy.</p>
<p>The group came up with five <strong>principles</strong> of free expression and pushed for each school to design its own programs. The principles are to be used for new student <strong>orientations</strong>, educator training and special campus gatherings called convocations.</p>
<p>The principles include developing knowledge that <strong>challenges</strong> common beliefs and <strong>assumptions</strong>; reaching decisions based on evidence; understanding one's own values and gaining respect for others who have different opinions; feeling a sense of responsibility to others and the need to work toward change; and learning that free expression has <strong>consequences</strong> and does not always lead to approval.</p>
<p>Jonathan Holloway is the president at Rutgers. He said he saw a growing lack of respect for American <strong>institutions,</strong> and he wanted to push back against those feelings. In a discussion with the Associated Press, he said he was concerned by seeing the Confederate flag marched through the U.S. Capitol building during the riot on January 6, 2021. "That's when things <strong>shifted</strong> for me," he said.</p>
<p>Holloway will lead a first-year class at Rutgers this year that looks at the meaning of democracy. The aim is for the class to create a program that will improve civic education.</p>
<p>The nonprofit groups who are supporting the presidents say they are concerned that students may not be learning about how to be good citizens while in college.</p>
<p>Rajiv Vinnakota is president of the Institute for Citizens and Scholars. He said students become part of a community with more different kinds of people than they have ever experienced while in college. He wants students to learn how to interact with people who have different opinions and experiences. And he hopes the 13 schools will be able to lead the way for others who will soon join the group.</p>
<p>Vinnakota questioned if educators can "get above" issues of free expression to get people to see that higher education "can and should" play a leading part in what he called "civic preparedness."</p>
<p>Some other colleges and universities in the group include Wellesley College in Massachusetts, Wesleyan University in Connecticut, Claremont McKenna College in California, Duke University in North Carolina and the University of Pittsburgh in Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>The Knight Foundation gave Vinnakota's institute $250,000 to organize discussions among university leaders over the next year-and-a-half.</p>
<p>Alberto Ibargüen is the head of the Knight Foundation. He said the group is interested in supporting the project because, "we believe in the free exchange of ideas...we believe in an informed citizenry..."</p>
<p>PEN America is a nonprofit group that works with colleges and universities on free expression programs. It is not involved in the Campus Call for Free Expression. Kristen Shahverdian is the group's Free Expression and Education program senior manager. She said her group tells students about writers and artists around the world who have faced attacks or suffered for their ideas.</p>
<p>"They understand the <strong>ramifications</strong> of <strong>squashing</strong> another's speech," she said.</p>
<p>Lucas Morel is a professor of politics at Washington and Lee University in Virginia who is not involved in the project. He is the head of a group called the Academic Freedom Alliance. He said more universities should work on programs that permit students to learn by discussing different evidence-based ideas. He said colleges are not just for helping students get a job, but they should help young people become citizens who care about the world around them.</p>
<p>"If we don't do a good job of helping them be careful readers and careful listeners, it stands to reason that as citizens they won't be careful listeners and careful expressers of their own thought," he said. "And it will be difficult for us to <strong>function</strong> as a self-governing society."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>polarization </strong>–n. to cause people to separate into opposing groups</p>
<p><strong>constructive </strong>–adj. useful in some way; not useless</p>
<p><strong>principles </strong>–n. (pl.) a set of ideas rules and beliefs that guide how people see right and wrong</p>
<p><strong>orientation </strong>–n. a process of giving people who are new to a job or school information and training</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong>–v. to question something or dispute it</p>
<p><strong>assumption </strong>–n. something that a person believes to be true, but that is not known to be true</p>
<p><strong>consequences </strong>–n. (pl.) the results of some action or decision</p>
<p><strong>institution </strong>–n. an established organization that has a part in society or an established belief or behavior</p>
<p><strong>shift </strong>–v. to change position</p>
<p><strong>ramifications </strong>–n. (pl.) a result of an action or decision that are not easily realized or understood</p>
<p><strong>squash </strong>–v. to crush or smash</p>
<p><strong>function </strong>–n. to operate; to do a specific job correctly</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Tennis Looks for Solutions to Tennis Ball Waste  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/tennis-looks-for-solutions-to-tennis-ball-waste.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The sport of tennis has a problem with waste that many players do not even recognize each time they open a new container of game balls.</p>
<p>The balls are not <strong>recyclable</strong>. Almost all of the 330 million balls manufactured each year end up in waste, or garbage, landfills. Once there, it can take as long as 400 years for the balls to <strong>decompose.</strong> Major professional tennis competitions go through nearly 100,000 balls during two weeks of play.</p>
<p>The problem of tennis ball waste has sent ball makers, tennis officials, and recycling companies looking for solutions.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A box of game-used tennis balls are packed in a recycling box during the U.S. Open tennis championships, Monday, Sept. 4, 2023, in New York. AP Photo/Eduardo Munoz Alvarez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e274-08dbaf191877_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A box of game-used tennis balls are packed in a recycling box during the U.S. Open tennis championships, Monday, Sept. 4, 2023, in New York. AP Photo/Eduardo Munoz Alvarez)</span></div>
<p>Nickolas J. Themelis is director of Columbia University's Earth Engineering Center.</p>
<p>"Tennis balls, like a lot of objects, are made to be indestructible, which means they're very resistant to mechanical processing," he said.</p>
<p>"But do you take a useful object that lasts forever and say people shouldn't use it because it lasts forever? That's nonsense," he added.</p>
<p>Themelis and other experts note that tennis balls make up a tiny percentage of the hundreds of millions of metric tons of garbage produced every year. He says part of the solution is finding ways to do other things with the balls.</p>
<p>"Anyone who would say you shouldn't play tennis because of the tennis balls is misinformed," said Jason Quinn, director of Colorado State University's Sustainability Research Laboratory. He added, "There are things you can do to reuse and repurpose tennis balls to lessen the impact."</p>
<p>Individual used balls sometimes become playthings for dogs or are re-used in other small ways. But, huge numbers of used balls can also be crushed<strong> </strong>to pieces for use as building material, like flooring.</p>
<p><strong>Tennis ball materials</strong></p>
<p>However, experts and environmental groups say that still does not solve the problem of tennis ball recycling. The balls' outer soft <strong>layer</strong>, called the felt, is strongly attached to a soft center. The felt is a combination of wool and nylon which cannot be recycled.</p>
<p>In addition, the center of top-level balls are made with rubber from rubber trees. Environmental groups say this leads to deforestation in the Amazon.</p>
<p>Jason Collins is chief of international <strong>racquet</strong> sports for Wilson Sporting Goods company. He said that its top-level balls use rubber directly from the trees. However, he said Wilson also makes other tennis balls that include recycled rubber material.</p>
<p><strong>Working on the problem</strong></p>
<p>The International Tennis Federation (ITF) is a governing body of professional tennis. Last year the ITF brought together manufacturers, tennis officials and recyclers to begin working on the tennis ball issue. The group is working to find answers to questions such as: Is there a way to design a fully recyclable ball? Can the ITF change rules so balls are used longer in play? How well do various kinds of balls perform at different levels of play?</p>
<p>Currently, professional players change to a new set of balls after the first seven games and then after every nine games.</p>
<p>Jamie Capel-Davies is the head of science and tech at ITF. He said there are four levels in the effort to reduce the waste.</p>
<p>"First of all, to try and reduce the number of balls that are being used. Then reuse balls as best we can. Recycling is third," he said.</p>
<p>The fourth level is disposal, meaning placing the balls in landfills. Most balls are disposed into landfills.</p>
<p>Manufacturers and recyclers have begun taking steps to reduce and reuse balls.</p>
<p>Wilson Sporting Goods introduced its Triniti ball that keeps air inside the core longer and has a stronger felt.</p>
<p>Vermont-based RecycleBalls says it expects to collect 3 million tennis balls this year from across the U.S and Canada.</p>
<p>"We believe in multiple lives for tennis balls," said RecycleBalls leader Erin Cunningham. But, the group does not want the used balls to stay forever in their storage center.</p>
<p>"We need to make sure that there's <strong>actually</strong> demand for recycled product on the back end," Cunningham said.</p>
<p>Columbia University's Themelis believes the final resting place of tennis balls should not be landfills but waste-to-energy plants that burn garbage to generate electricity.</p>
<p>However, opponents of the idea say burning the balls to create electricity also adds to air pollution. They say there are better and cleaner new uses.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>James Martinez wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recycle </strong><em>-v. </em>to process material, such as paper, glass, or plastic, in order to use it again</p>
<p><strong>decompose </strong><em>-v. </em>to chemically break down</p>
<p><strong>layer </strong><em>-n. </em>a piece of material that covers a surface or is between two other things</p>
<p><strong>racquet </strong><em>-n. </em>an oval shaped bat with strings across it, used to hit balls in sports such as tennis, squash and badminton</p>
<p><strong>actually </strong><em>-adv. </em>true in fact; in reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Warren Harding: Damaged  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-warren-harding.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Warren Harding. He was the 29<sup>th</sup> president of the United States.</p>
<p>Harding was very different from the 28th president, Woodrow Wilson.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Warren G. Harding" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6069a603-303c-4e5e-b4e2-f9337789781a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Warren G. Harding</span></div>
<p>Wilson supported change; Harding promised "a return to normalcy."</p>
<p>Wilson took steps to protect American workers; Harding often worked to protect business owners.</p>
<p>Wilson was slow in supporting voting rights for women, and in accepting African-American people as equal to whites. Harding supported women's suffrage and civil rights for African-Americans.</p>
<p>Yet both men were popular during their years in office.</p>
<p>Today, however, historians usually think of Wilson as one of America's best presidents. But Harding is remembered as one of the worst.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Warren Harding was the eighth president from the state of Ohio. His parents were both doctors.</p>
<p>Harding spoke about having a happy childhood, growing up on a farm with his brothers and sisters. Some of his favorite early activities were performing in a <strong>band.</strong></p>
<p>Later, Harding – along with two friends – bought a newspaper. The paper became successful for <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/harding/life-before-the-presidency">several reasons</a>.</p>
<p>Harding was kind to his employees and shared the company's profits with them. He also tried not to publish stories that criticized politics or politicians from any party. Finally, he married a woman who had an excellent head for business.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/florenceharding">Florence Kling Harding</a> led the newspaper's <strong>circulation</strong> <strong>department</strong>. She also helped to direct her husband's political career.</p>
<p>In time, Warren Harding became a state senator, a lieutenant governor of Ohio, and then a member of the U.S. Senate. He especially liked being a senator – and many of the other lawmakers liked him.</p>
<p>One <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/harding/life-before-the-presidency">reason</a> is because Harding rarely took a controversial position on any issue.</p>
<p>Instead, he accepted most of the ideas of the Republican Party. He was also good-looking and had an excellent speaking voice.</p>
<p>These qualities helped earn him the Republican presidential nomination in 1920. A few months later, he easily won the national election.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>President Harding took office shortly after World War I ended. He promised to make Americans feel calm again, and also improve the nation's <strong>prosperity</strong>. Two of Harding's goals were to support business and to limit immigration.</p>
<p>He succeeded on both issues. His administration reduced taxes for big businesses and wealthy people. It also increased tariffs -- taxes on foreign imports.</p>
<p>And the Harding administration put in place <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/united-states-history-of-immigration-restrictions/3700234.html" target="_blank">new rules on immigration</a>. The rules made it easier for immigrants from northern Europe to enter the country, but harder for immigrants from Russia, eastern and central Europe.</p>
<p>Harding also took steps to improve the effectiveness of the federal government.</p>
<p>But his administration is remembered mostly for its problems.</p>
<p>At the beginning of his term, Harding reportedly told friends that the job of being president was too much for him. He appeared to want to do well, and he worked hard. But he turned over most of the responsibility to his friends in the cabinet.</p>
<p>A few were very able. But some were dishonest. They abused their positions to gain wealth for themselves and their families.</p>
<p>One of the most famous examples of corruption during Harding's administration is known as the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.wyohistory.org/encyclopedia/teapot-dome-scandal">Teapot Dome Scandal</a>.</p>
<p>The name "Teapot Dome" comes from a rock in the state of Wyoming. The rock looked like a teapot. Scientists correctly believed that oil could be found in the ground underneath it.</p>
<p>At the time, the U.S. navy depended on oil to fuel its ships. So, the federal government claimed the land in case the navy needed to use the oil in an emergency.</p>
<p>But a cabinet official who was a friend of Harding took control of the land. He gave a private company permission to search for oil on it in exchange for a large amount of money.</p>
<p>Some lawmakers became suspicious. So they opened an investigation.</p>
<p>In time, lawyers proved the act of corruption. Harding's friend was the first person to be found guilty of a crime while serving as a cabinet official.</p>
<p>But President Harding did not live to see his friend go to jail.</p>
<p>The investigation was just beginning when Harding took a trip to the West Coast to campaign for his policies.</p>
<p>Some say that Harding was also trying to escape the problems in his administration. He reportedly told one reporter that worrying about what his friends were doing kept him awake at nights.</p>
<p>During the trip, Harding showed signs of not being in good health. Doctors thought he could have food poisoning or pneumonia. He was taken to a hotel in San Francisco, California. For a day, he appeared to be feeling better.</p>
<p>He was sitting up in bed. And then suddenly, his body shook and collapsed. He died <strong>instantly</strong>.</p>
<p>Reports at the time differed on the cause of Harding's death. Some even said that his wife poisoned the president to protect him from being punished for the wrongdoing in his administration.</p>
<p>But most historians think that he had long suffered from heart failure, and was struck by a heart attack. He was 57.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy </strong></p>
<p>Millions of Americans mourned over Warren Harding's death. They stood beside railroad tracks as his body traveled from California back to Washington, DC.</p>
<p>The following year, Florence Harding also died. She and her husband are buried together under a <strong>grand</strong> memorial in their hometown in Ohio.</p>
<p>But in the years after his death, Harding's public image worsened. More corruption scandals in his administration came to light. And some historians have criticized him for not having a clear idea about how he wanted to lead the country.</p>
<p>In 1927, a woman published a book saying she had a long, but secret relationship with Harding, both before and during his presidency. She also said he was the father of her daughter. Genetic testing has confirmed her claim.</p>
<p>More than 30 years after her book was published, a lawyer discovered love letters from Harding to a different woman. They confirmed that he had a long romantic affair with the wife of one of his friends. Harding had also been married at the time.</p>
<p>These reports, as well as the corruption during his administration, damaged Harding's public image. But he also seemed to know that he would not be remembered as one of the best occupants of the White House.</p>
<p>Instead, he tried to be likable and modest. He called himself "a man of limited <strong>talents</strong>" who was "not fit for the office" of president.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>____________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>band </strong>-<em> n. </em>a usually small group of musicians who play popular music together</p>
<p><strong>circulation </strong>- <em>n. </em>the average number of copies of a newspaper that are sold over a particular period</p>
<p><strong>prosperity</strong> - <em>n.</em> the state of being successful usually by making a lot of money</p>
<p><strong>instantly</strong> - <em>adv. </em>without delay; immediately</p>
<p><strong>grand</strong> - <em>adj.</em> impressive because of size or importance</p>
<p><strong>talents</strong> - <em>n.</em> special abilities that allow someone to do something well</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Biofuels a Clean Source of Energy?  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/are-biofuels-a-clean-source-of-energy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>India has proposed an alliance to speed up the development of biofuels to support energy <strong>transition</strong> worldwide.</p>
<p>Biofuel is a kind of fuel produced from agricultural products or organic waste.</p>
<p>India plans to announce the alliance at the G-20 gathering in New Delhi. It is expected that more than 15 countries will sign up to be part of the alliance. The United States, Canada, and Brazil are among a few of the countries expected to join India in such an alliance.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Sprawling fields of sugar cane are visible near Meerut, India, on August, 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/92aa66f4-81e5-4b63-9f3a-242c0970cc22_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Sprawling fields of sugar cane are visible near Meerut, India, on August, 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)</span></div>
<p><strong>What are biofuels?</strong></p>
<p>Humans have used biofuels since ancient times. For example, humans burn wood and animal waste for cooking, heating, and light. They have gained popularity in recent years for their possibility to deliver cleaner energy than some other sources.</p>
<p>Biofuels are grouped based on their source. Each group is known as a "generation." First-generation biofuels come from food crops like corn and sugar cane. Second generation come from non-food crops and agricultural waste. And third-generation come from small plants called algae.</p>
<p>Ethanol, biodiesel, and biogas are popular kinds of biofuels. They can be produced from any of these sources and are grouped based on the source from which they are produced. For example, ethanol produced from farm-grown corn is grouped as first-generation ethanol.</p>
<p><strong>Are biofuels always a source of clean energy?</strong></p>
<p>Biofuels are not always a clean source of energy. But it depends on how it is produced. A biofuel made from waste, for example, with <strong>renewable</strong> energy to power the production, would have little or no <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> production, making it a clean fuel. But when crops are grown to just produce biofuels, the fertilizer and nonrenewable fuels needed to produce the fuel make it much less clean.</p>
<p>"If you look at the full life <strong>cycle</strong> of producing biofuels, it's many times not clean," said Lydia Powell. She is an energy policy researcher at the New Delhi-based Observer Research Foundation. She has followed developments related to biofuels for over 20 years.</p>
<p>Biofuels can also mean land that could have produced food is being used for energy. They can add to deforestation when land is cleared for their production.</p>
<p>Powell noted Europe's imports of plant-based palm oil from Indonesia and other East Asian countries to make biodiesel for cars and trucks. Those imports greatly fell after the European Union banned the sale of palm oil and other palm-based products when they could be linked to deforestation.</p>
<p>"They were destroying natural forests to plant palm trees so you produce oil to export to Europe. When you destroy forests, you destroy large <strong>chunks</strong> of carbon sinks," Powell said.</p>
<p>Those problems have led to debates about exactly how sustainable biofuels are.</p>
<p><strong>What are biofuels used for?</strong></p>
<p>Biofuels are often used for transportation of people and products.</p>
<p>Experts say once they are made, biofuels produce little to no greenhouse gases when used. The same cannot be said with the <strong>fossil fuels</strong> they are mixed with.</p>
<p>But there is a hope that biofuels might completely replace fossil fuels to power airplanes and ships.</p>
<p>"They are one<strong> option </strong>among a larger set of solutions," said Jane O'Malley of International Council on Clean Transportation, a Washington-based independent nonprofit.</p>
<p>O'Malley said it is important to use the right kind of biofuel for the right purpose. She said it is important for countries using biofuels to move as quickly as possible to produce them with little to no greenhouse gas production.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Ange Adihe Kasongo and Benoit Nyemba reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transition </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to make a change from one state, place, or condition to another</p>
<p><strong>renewable</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>adj.</em> restored or replaced by natural processes</p>
<p><strong>greenhouse effect </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> the warming of the Earth's atmosphere that is caused by air pollution</p>
<p><strong>cycle </strong><em>– n.</em> a set of events or actions that happen again and again in the same order</p>
<p><strong>chunk </strong><em>– n.</em> a large amount or part of something</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuels </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> a fuel (such as coal, oil, or natural gas) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>option </strong><em>– n.</em> the opportunity or ability to choose something or to choose between two or more things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rolling Stones Announce First New Album in 18 Years  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rolling-stones-announce-first-new-album-in-18-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>
The Rolling Stones said this week that their first new collection of songs in almost 20 years comes out on October 20.</p>
<p>The album will be called <em>Hackney Diamonds</em>. The name comes from broken glass often seen on the streets of east London's Hackney area.</p>
<p>Three of the band's <strong>original</strong> members - Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood – came to the Hackney Empire, a historic theater, for the announcement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rolling Stones band members Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood attend a launch event for their new album Hackney Diamonds, at Hackney Empire in London, Britain, September 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/205a3811-7361-4e74-85db-bdc11fe5c9e9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rolling Stones band members Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood attend a launch event for their new album "Hackney Diamonds", at Hackney Empire in London, Britain, September 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)</span></div>
<p>The Rolling Stones are still traveling the world and performing concerts, but they have not made an album since 2016. That recording did not include new material.</p>
<p>Richards, 79, said the band only made a new album because Jagger wanted to sing. So they went to record new songs after almost 20 years.</p>
<p>"When you have a singer that wants to sing," Richards said, "you <strong>grab</strong> him and throw him in the studio." Richards said the songs came together with "energy and urgency."</p>
<p>Jagger, who is 80, said, "we are quite pleased," with the new album. He said the group would not have put a recording together if "we hadn't really liked it. We said we had to make a record we really love ourselves ... we hope you all like it."</p>
<p>They released the first song, called <em>Angry</em>, this week. But Jagger said the rest of the songs are not angry. He said the album contains "love songs, <strong>ballads</strong>, country..." sounds.</p>
<p>The new recording includes songs with Paul McCartney, Lady Gaga, Stevie Wonder and Charlie Watts, the Rolling Stones <strong>drummer</strong> who died in 2021. Watts recorded sounds for two songs in 2019. Steve Jordan is the drummer for the other 10.</p>
<p>"Of course, he's missed incredibly," Richards said about Watts. But he added that Jordan was Watts' suggestion for a <strong>replacement</strong>.</p>
<p>Jagger said the addition of Lady Gaga to the album was unplanned. The Stones were recording at a <strong>studio</strong> in Los Angeles and Lady Gaga just happened to be in the studio next door. So, she recorded the song <em>Sweet Sound of Heaven</em> with the band.</p>
<p>"She walked in next to me and we started singing together," Jagger said.</p>
<p>Wood said McCartney of the Beatles played the bass guitar on one <strong>track</strong>. "You know, he was loving it." McCartney's band was perhaps the Rolling Stones' biggest <strong>rival</strong> in the 1960s.</p>
<p>Taric Fioravanti was one of the fans who lined up outside hoping to see the band arrive. He is from Brazil. "I love these guys," he said. "They're 80 years old. Most bands have stopped making music by that age," he added.</p>
<p>The Rolling Stones started in 1962. They celebrated their 60th year with a tour of Europe in 2022 and they said they have plans to visit North America in 2024.</p>
<p>Wood, 76, plays guitar. He said the idea of retirement is "Impossible. You've got to keep playing," he added.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on reports by The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>resident</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who lives in a region, city; a home or land owner</p>
<p><strong>original</strong> <em>–adj. </em>the first or existing at the beginning</p>
<p><strong>grab</strong> <em>–v. </em>to quickly take hold of something with your hands</p>
<p><strong>ballad</strong> <em>–n. </em>a kind of slow, romantic song</p>
<p><strong>drummer</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who provides the beat in music, usually using drumsticks and drums to make a sound</p>
<p><strong>replacement</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who steps in if someone is not available to do a task</p>
<p><strong>studio</strong> <em>–n. </em>quiet room used to record music or voice</p>
<p><strong>track</strong> <em>–n. </em>one song of a group that are included in an album</p>
<p><strong>rival</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person or thing trying to be more successful than another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mandatory, Compulsory and Obligatory  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/mandatory-compulsory-and-obligatory.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "mandatory," "compulsory," and "obligatory."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello. My name is Nelson, and I'm from Nicaragua.<br/>
Can you help me to understand the difference between "compulsory," "mandatory" and "obligatory?"<br/>
Thank you in advance,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mandatory, Compulsory, and Obligatory " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a5ad-08dbae4c5d99_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mandatory, Compulsory, and Obligatory </span></div>
<p>Nelson.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, Nelson. These three adjectives have the same meaning, so they are synonyms. They share a basic definition of "required." But there are some slight differences in how often we use each. Let's start with the most common, "mandatory."</p>
<p><strong>Mandatory</strong></p>
<p>Mandatory comes from the word "mandate," which means to give <strong>authority</strong> to act or as a noun means an official order. Something that is "mandatory" is the result of that action or order. It usually comes from a law or rule.</p>
<p>This is the most common of the three words in question because it is often used in everyday conversations. We use it to describe something that is required by a mandate, law, or rule.</p>
<p><em>In most public high schools, there is mandatory testing every year.</em></p>
<p><em>Seatbelts are mandatory in the U.S. If you do not wear a seatbelt, you are breaking the law. </em></p>
<p><strong>Compulsory</strong></p>
<p>"Compulsory" is the second most common adjective out of the three, so it is used less often than "mandatory. It also means required by law. We often use it to describe education and military service.</p>
<p><em>Many countries in the world have compulsory military service like Ukraine, South Korea, and Egypt. </em></p>
<p><em>Massachusetts became the first place in the United States to have compulsory schooling for children in the year 1642.</em></p>
<p><strong>Obligatory </strong></p>
<p>The least common adjective is "obligatory," but it is the most formal of the three. It means the same as "mandatory" and "compulsory," but also has other meanings.</p>
<p>We use "obligatory" not just for laws or rules, but we use it to describe <strong>obligations </strong>that are based on moral or social instances.</p>
<p><em>Social media is now the obligatory way to message friends because young people do not like to talk on the phone. </em></p>
<p>Another way we use obligatory is when we are talking about something that people have stereotypically used but is not really needed.</p>
<p><em>Many movies for young people feature obligatory dance<strong> </strong>scenes at the end of the film. </em></p>
<p><em>The obligatory two-week notice before you quit your job is common in the U.S. but not required by law. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Nelson.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>authority </strong>– <em>n</em>. a leadership figure or government</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>– n. </em>something that you must do because it is morally right</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Congolese Arts Center Helps Street Children Find Their Voice  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/congolese-arts-center-helps-street-children-find-their-voice.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A small recording room outside the Congolese capital Kinshasa has become a safe space for homeless <strong>teenagers</strong>. They sing about their life on the streets and dream of a better future.</p>
<p>The homeless sing about sexual abuse, stealing, theft, and dealings with the police at the Mokili Na Poche cultural center. It is a safe space that permits young people and children to wash, eat, and learn.</p>
<p>"It really makes me happy when I sing," said 19-year-old Osé Mavakala. He has slept on the streets for years. There are more than 20,000 homeless children in Kinshasa, UNICEF, the U.N. agency, has found.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Cedrick Tshimbalanga, 32, the founder of Mokili Na Poche cultural centre, uses his phone while talking to homeless teenagers during a lunch at the cultural center in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo September 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Justin Makangara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/86272891-6fe4-4a5d-9eed-33e23ba8cc4b_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Cedrick Tshimbalanga, 32, the founder of Mokili Na Poche cultural centre, uses his phone while talking to homeless teenagers during a lunch at the cultural center in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo September 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Justin Makangara)</span></div>
<p>Other teenagers looked on with<strong> </strong>happiness as Mavakala <strong>rapped</strong> into the recording equipment at the center in late August.</p>
<p>Mavakala dreams of bigger goals after having the chance to record in a real recording space. He said, "It <strong>encourages</strong> me and I tell myself - ah, life belongs to the <strong>courageous</strong>." He added that U.S. rapper Lil Wayne and Congolese star Fally Ipupa influenced his music.</p>
<p>He has been coming to the center for the past three years, taking part in the music, art, and reading classes it offers throughout the day. Founder Cedrick Tshimbalanga hopes these skills and daily experiences will help the children build a base for their life and their voices.</p>
<p>"With music...young people are able to talk about their daily experience - everything they live through daily: rape, theft, <strong>trauma</strong>, attacks," said Tshimbalanga, who plans to release their music soon.</p>
<p>The classes are also a chance for young people to make up for lost possibilities in life. While the Democratic Republic of Congo has made progress in education, over 7 million children aged between five and 17 still do not have schooling, UNICEF found.</p>
<p>"Break free from the criminal life, my friend, it's time to see what the future holds for you," Mavakala rapped during an emotion-filled performance at the center in August.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Ange Adihe Kasongo and Benoit Nyemba reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>teenager </strong><em>– n.</em> someone who is between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p><strong>rap </strong><em>– n.</em> a type of music that has words that are spoken with the rhythm instead of being sung</p>
<p><strong>encourage</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to make (someone) more determined, hopeful, or confident</p>
<p><strong>courageous </strong><em>– adj.</em> very brave</p>
<p><strong>trauma </strong><em>– n.</em> a very difficult or unpleasant experience that causes someone to have mental or emotional problems usually for a long time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Afghans in US Face Difficulties  (2023/9/8) | 阿富汗人在美国陷入困境</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/afghans-in-us-face-difficulties.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The U.S. Department of State says that nearly 90,000 Afghans have come to the United States through a special federal program since 2021. The program is called Operation Allies Welcome.<br/>
美国国务院表示，自2021年以来，已有近9万名阿富汗人通过一项特殊的联邦计划来到美国。该项目名为“欢迎盟友行动”。</p>
<p>The U.S. government created Operation Allies Welcome to help resettle Afghans who had worked with the U.S. in Afghanistan until it withdrew.<br/>
美国政府创建了“欢迎盟友行动”项目，以帮助重新安置在美国撤军前曾在阿富汗与美国合作的阿富汗人。</p>
<p>Farzana Jamalzada fled Afghanistan after the Taliban took control of the country in August 2021. Jamalzada feared that her work with the U.S. government put her in danger.<br/>
2021年8月塔利班控制阿富汗后，法扎娜·贾马尔扎达逃离了该国。贾马尔扎达担心她与美国政府的合作会将她置于危险之中。</p>
<p>Jamalzada settled in New York City. The government program gave her permission to live and work in the U.S. for two years. She got a job with an organization that helps people in need, a charity. The job provided her with money to pay for a place to live and other necessities. But the two years ended at the end of August.<br/>
贾马尔扎达在纽约市定居。该政府项目允许她在美国生活和工作两年。她在一家帮助有需要的人的慈善机构找到了一份工作。这份工作为她提供了钱来支付房租和其他必需品。但到8月底这两年时间就结束了。</p>
<p>She and her family are waiting for an immigration interview for their application to live and work in the U.S. permanently. The document that permits this is known as a green card.<br/>
她和她的家人正在等待移民面试，以申请在美国永久生活和工作。这种许可文件被称为绿卡。</p>
<p>Reuters news agency reported that President Joe Biden's administration extended the permission for two more years in June. But the permission to stay in the country is still temporary.<br/>
路透社报道称，拜登政府于6月将该许可延长了两年。但是，留在该国的许可仍然是暂时的。</p>
<p>Difficulty with immigration documents is common for many Afghans who were resettled through Operation Allies Welcome. Their path to legally living in the U.S. permanently is not simple.<br/>
对于许多通过“欢迎盟友行动”重新安置的阿富汗人来说，通常很难获取这份移民文件。他们在美国合法永居的道路并不平坦。</p>
<p>A group of U.S. lawmakers from both political parties, men and women who served in the U.S. military and others are working to support a new law to help Afghan immigrants.<br/>
一群来自两党的美国议员，包括美国服役人员以及其他人员，正在努力支持一项帮助阿富汗移民的新法律。</p>
<p>The Afghan Adjustment Act aims to create a direct path for Afghans to live and work in the U.S. permanently. The goal would be for many Afghans to become citizens in the future.<br/>
《阿富汗调整法案》旨在为阿富汗人在美国永久生活和工作创造一条直接途径。目标是让众多阿富汗人在未来成为公民。</p>
<p>But the legislation has not made progress in the House of Representatives or in the Senate.<br/>
但这项立法在众议院和参议院都没有取得进展。</p>
<p>Danilo Zak is with Church World Service, a group that assists refugees. Zak said there are many Afghans who simply do not have money for, or cannot find, immigration assistance.<br/>
达尼洛·扎克是帮助难民的世界教会服务组织的成员。扎克说，许多阿富汗人根本没有钱或找不到移民援助。</p>
<p>Unlike some others, Jamalzada and her husband do have a path to a green card. They can request a Special Immigrant Visa. The Special Immigrant Visa is for translators, interpreters and others who assisted the U.S. government in the war in Afghanistan.<br/>
与其他人不同，贾马尔扎达和她的丈夫确实有获得绿卡的途径。他们可以申请特殊移民签证。特殊移民签证适用于在阿富汗战争中协助美国政府的翻译、口译员和其他人员。</p>
<p>But Jamalzada had to flee Afghanistan so suddenly that her visa was not fully processed. To get a green card, Jamalzada and her husband must attend a government interview on September 12. Until that time, she and her husband may not legally work.<br/>
但贾马尔扎达不得不突然逃离阿富汗，她的签证没有得到完全处理。为了获得绿卡，贾马尔扎达和她的丈夫必须在9月12日参加政府面试。在此之前，她和丈夫可能无法合法工作。</p>
<p>Jamalzada said she hopes the U.S. Congress passes the Afghan Adjustment Act. She said she wants her friends and family already in the U.S. to not have to worry about their ability to live and work in the country.<br/>
贾马尔扎达说，她希望美国国会能通过《阿富汗调整法案》。她说，她希望已经在美国的朋友和家人可以不必担心他们在美国的生活和工作能力。</p>
<p>"You never know what's gonna happen to you," she said.<br/>
她说：“你永远不知道在你身上会发生什么。”</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australian Vote Could Give 'Voice' to Indigenous Communities  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/australian-vote-could-give-voice-to-indigenous-communities.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Some of Australia's <strong>Indigenous</strong> communities are hoping a national vote that would change the country's constitution could give native people more of a voice in the government.</p>
<p>The vote, known as a referendum, would put in the nation's constitution a way for Indigenous people to advise Parliament on policies that affect their lives. The vote, officially called "Voice to Parliament," will be held on October 14.</p>
<p>Leaders of some Indigenous groups are looking to the process to help save their cultures and languages. Clark Webb is seeking to do that for his native, or Aboriginal, community, the Gumbaynggirr people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Educator Clark Webb performs a song with children including his daughter Jayalaani, at the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School, a bilingual school teaching the Gumbaynggirr language, in Coffs Harbour, Australia June 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Alasdair Pal)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fd73-08dbad6b3245_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Educator Clark Webb performs a song with children including his daughter Jayalaani, at the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School, a bilingual school teaching the Gumbaynggirr language, in Coffs Harbour, Australia June 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Alasdair Pal)</span></div>
<p>Webb recently led a class of schoolchildren as they danced to native songs. "Opening our own schools, that's <strong>sovereignty</strong> in action," Webb said.</p>
<p>He and others want to bring back the Indigenous language spoken in Coffs Harbor, a coastal town about 500 kilometers north of Sydney. "And so we need that 'Voice' there to <strong>lobby</strong> for that."</p>
<p>Webb started the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School last year. It was the first bilingual Indigenous school in Australia's most populous state of New South Wales.</p>
<p>The effort is part of an attempt to bring back dozens of languages that are close to dying out. It is being supported by federal and state governments.</p>
<p>Many of Australia's Indigenous people see the recovery of languages as very important to the survival of their cultures.</p>
<p><strong>Oldest culture</strong></p>
<p>Australia's Indigenous and Torres Strait Islander communities are perhaps the world's oldest. They have a history on the continent dating back tens of thousands of years.</p>
<p>After colonization by Great Britain in 1788, the people increasingly faced discrimination, which continued long after Australia became a nation in 1901.</p>
<p>Government officials often moved Indigenous people from their traditional lands, known as Country. They forcibly separated Indigenous children from their families, resulting in a "stolen generation" from the mid-19th century to the 1970s.</p>
<p>As late as the 1980s, officials punished Indigenous people for speaking their languages.</p>
<p>"I think, growing up, I knew there was something missing from my life," Webb said. "And as I got older, I realized that ... was our language."</p>
<p>Webb estimates there are now about 30 <strong>proficient</strong> or highly proficient speakers of Gumbaynggirr. Among them is his nine-year-old daughter.</p>
<p><strong>Language revival</strong></p>
<p>Australia has one of the world's highest rates of language loss in the world.</p>
<p>At the time of European colonization, more than 250 Indigenous languages, including 800 <strong>dialects</strong>, were believed to have been spoken on the continent.</p>
<p>But the most recent population data shows that more than 150 languages were still being spoken in 2021. However, just 9.5 percent of indigenous Australians reported speaking one or more languages at home.</p>
<p>Ray Ingrey is one of a handful of people fluent in Dharawal. It was the first language heard by British explorer Captain James Cook when he landed in Australia in 1770.</p>
<p>Ingrey heads the Gujaga Foundation. It was founded in 2019 to bring back the language. He said government policies in those days severely hurt the ability to pass the language on from one generation to the next.</p>
<p>Officials had barred the grandparents of Webb and Ingrey from speaking their native languages. And some relatives were threatened by the police for speaking it anywhere.</p>
<p>Author and teacher Jasmine Seymour is leading efforts to revive the Dharug Aboriginal language among hundreds of schoolchildren in Sydney. Most of the children are non-Indigenous.</p>
<p>Seymour is related to<strong> </strong>Maria Lock, the first Aboriginal person to marry a European settler and one of the first admitted to a school to learn English.</p>
<p>"To be at the other end of history, where my language is being <strong>revitalized</strong> in school, is completely <strong>profound</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>indigenous </strong><em>— adj. </em>produced, living, or existing naturally in a particular region or environment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sovereignty </strong><em>— n. </em>unlimited power over a country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>lobby </strong><em>— v. </em>o try to influence government officials to make decisions for or against something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>proficient </strong><em>— adj. </em>good at doing something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dialect </strong><em>— n. </em>a form of a language that is spoken in a particular area and that uses some of its own words, grammar, and pronunciations</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>revitalize </strong><em>— v. </em>to make active, healthy, or energetic again</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>profound </strong><em>— adj. </em>having or showing great knowledge or understanding</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Discussing Artificial Intelligence  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/discussing-artificial-intelligence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) has been the subject of many news reports this year. It has also been part of many everyday discussions.</p>
<p>It will likely continue to be a popular subject of discussion in the coming years, too.</p>
<p>So, how might one talk about artificial intelligence? What kinds of terms and structures should you use?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: DIscussing Artificial Intelligence" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d40f-08dbae161aba_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: DIscussing Artificial Intelligence</span></div>
<p>In this week's Everyday Grammar, we will explore a point of connection between grammar and technology. You will learn how to ask questions about artificial intelligence. You will also learn some ways to express your own opinions about AI.</p>
<p><strong>Questions – open ended </strong></p>
<p>Let's start with questions. Questions generally come in two forms – yes or no questions and open-ended questions.</p>
<p>Yes or no questions ask for a yes or a no answer.</p>
<p>Open-ended questions are seeking more information than a simple yes or no answer.</p>
<p>Open-ended questions are the secret to good discussions. By asking open-ended questions, you can learn much more about the thoughts and opinions of others.</p>
<p>We often use question words to ask open-ended questions. When we discuss artificial intelligence, a few question words will be especially useful. These are what, why, and how.</p>
<p>Consider these three questions:</p>
<p><em>What do you think of artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p><em>Why are people concerned about artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence affect our lives? </em></p>
<p>Note that there is a general structure to all of these questions. They begin with the question word. Then, they involve some kind of helping verb: do, be, or will. Then we have the subject of the sentence, the main verb, and the rest of the sentence. If we reduced these ideas into a kind of math formula, you might say the following:</p>
<p><em>Open-ended question = A question word + a helping verb + a subject + a main verb + the rest of the sentence </em></p>
<p>We can ask open-ended questions in different tenses. For example, we could ask about the past, as in:</p>
<p><em>How did you first hear about artificial intelligence?</em></p>
<p>In this case, we changed the helping verb do into its past form, did.</p>
<p>We can also ask about the future, as in:</p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence change our lives over the next 20 years? </em></p>
<p><strong>Answers</strong></p>
<p>We have explored questions. But how can we answer such questions?</p>
<p>One way to think of your answer is in terms of good, bad, and mixed. You might use terms such as positive, negative, optimistic or pessimistic.</p>
<p>Consider this question:</p>
<p><em>What do you think of artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p>You might have a positive opinion and say something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am optimistic about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>You might have a negative opinion and say something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am pessimistic about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>If your views go both ways, you might say:</p>
<p><em>I have mixed opinions about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>Of course, after all of these answers, you should be prepared to give more details. We often use the word "because" followed by a clause – a subject and predicate group.</p>
<p>So, you might say</p>
<p><em>I am optimistic about artificial intelligence because people will be more productive with it. </em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>I am pessimistic about artificial intelligence because I think it will hurt the labor force in a powerful way. </em></p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>In today's lesson, we explored a few ways to ask questions and give answers about artificial intelligence. Such discussions could take place in an everyday discussion or as part of an English test.</p>
<p>Let's end today with a homework assignment. Write an answer to the question you heard earlier in the report:</p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence change our lives over the next 20 years? </em></p>
<p>Before writing your answer, be sure to consider what views you have. Ask yourself if you see the future in a positive way, a negative way, or in a mixed way. Send us your answers at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>formula</strong> –n. a fact or rule that is expressed in letters, numbers and symbols</p>
<p><strong>optimistic </strong>– adj. expecting good things to happen</p>
<p><strong>pessimistic </strong>– adj. expecting bad things to happen</p>
<p><strong>predicate </strong>– n. the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: This Summer Has Been the Hottest on Record  (2023/9/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/un-this-summer-has-been-the-hottest-on-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The World Meteorological Organization (WMO) says Earth just had its hottest summer ever in the Northern Hemisphere.</p>
<p>Summer ends on September 22 this year in the world's northern half.</p>
<p>Last month was the hottest August ever recorded with modern equipment since 1979. It was also the second hottest month ever measured, behind only July 2023. The WMO and the European climate service Copernicus made the announcement Wednesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A man cools off from the intense heat in Lisbon, Portugal on Aug. 6, 2023. UN weather agency says Earth had the hottest summer ever in the northern hemisphere. (AP Photo/Armando Franca, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/017c3712-daa9-4249-8f2b-52fede75652c_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A man cools off from the intense heat in Lisbon, Portugal on Aug. 6, 2023. UN weather agency says Earth had the hottest summer ever in the northern hemisphere. (AP Photo/Armando Franca, File)</span></div>
<p>August was about 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer than pre-industrial averages. That is the limit world leaders have said the world must not pass. Scientists, however, are more concerned about temperature increases over many years and not just a few months.</p>
<p>So far, Copernicus said 2023 has been the second hottest year that it has recorded, behind only 2016. But the University of Maine's Climate Reanalyzer, a website, reported that daily September temperatures are higher than those recorded for the same period in earlier years.</p>
<p>The WMO also said the world's oceans were the hottest ever recorded at nearly 21 degrees Celsius. Water covers more than 70 percent of the Earth's surface.</p>
<p>"The dog days of summer are not just <strong>barking</strong>, they are biting," United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said in a statement. "Dog days of summer" is an expression used to describe the time of hot and humid weather during the summer. The expression might have come from ancient Greece when extreme heat was said to drive both dogs and humans insane.</p>
<p>Scientists blame the heat on the burning of coal, oil and natural gas and the added influence from El Nino for the warming climate. El Nino is a temporary warming of the southern Pacific Ocean that affects weather worldwide. The weather event changes weather around the world and even more so in its second year.</p>
<p>Climatologist Andrew Weaver was not surprised by the numbers. He said governments have not taken global warming seriously enough. He expressed concern that the public will forget the issue when temperatures fall again.</p>
<p>"It's time for global leaders to start telling the truth," said Weaver who is a professor at the School of Earth and Ocean Sciences at the University of Victoria in Canada. "We will not limit warming to 1.5 Celsius; we will not limit warming to 2.0 Celsius. It's <strong>all hands on deck</strong> now to prevent 3.0 Celsius global warming."</p>
<p>Copernicus Climate Change Service Director Carlo Buontempo said the high temperatures were "not only new extremes" but continuing "record-breaking conditions."</p>
<p>While the world's air and oceans were setting records for heat, Antarctica continued to set records for low amounts of sea ice, the WMO, the United Nations weather agency, said.</p>
<p>"Antarctic sea ice extent was literally <strong>off the charts</strong>, and the global sea surface temperature was once again at a new record," WMO's secretary-general, Petteri Taalas, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Taalas added, "It is worth noting that this is happening BEFORE we see the full warming <strong>impact</strong> of the El Nino event."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Jamey Keaten and Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bark</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to make a short, loud noise similar to the call of a dog</p>
<p><strong>all hands on deck</strong> <em>–idiomatic expression </em>to call for everyone in a group to become involved</p>
<p><strong>off the charts </strong><em>–idiomatic expression </em>an area that has not been explored or experienced before; unknown territory</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>–n</em>. the influence of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Removes the Poor to Prepare for G20 Gathering  (2023/9/7) | 印度赶走穷人迎接20国集团会议</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/india-removes-the-poor-to-prepare-for-g20-gathering.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>India has changed the look of its capital, New Delhi, substantially in preparation for a meeting of international leaders this week. The two-day meeting of the Group of Twenty (G20) opens Saturday.<br/>
印度大幅改变了首都新德里的面貌，为本周举行的国际领导人会议做准备。为期两天的二十国集团会议将于周六开幕。</p>
<p>The Indian government spent about $120 million on the New Delhi project. Prime Minister Narendra Modi called it a "beautification process." But, many of the city's poor say that process destroyed homes and small businesses, leaving them displaced and without a way to make money. They say they feel erased, treated like the many dogs and m<i>onkey</i>s removed from neighborhoods in the city.<br/>
印度政府在新德里项目上花费了约1.2亿美元。总理纳伦德拉·莫迪称之为“美化过程”。但是，该市的许多穷人表示，这一过程摧毁了房屋和小企业，使他们流离失所，没有办法赚钱。他们说，他们觉得自己被抹去了，受到了像城市里许多被赶出社区的狗和猴子一样的待遇。</p>
<p>About 20 million people live in New Delhi. India's total population is 1.4 billion.<br/>
大约有2000万人生活在新德里。印度总人口为14亿。</p>
<p>Since January, hundreds of houses and small roadside businesses have been destroyed, displacing thousands of people. Dozens of poor neighborhoods called shantytowns were crushed to the ground. In many cases, residents did not receive timely warnings about the planned destruction.<br/>
自1月份以来，数百所房屋和路边小企业被毁，数千人流离失所。数十个被称为棚户区的贫困社区被夷为平地。在多数情况下，居民没有及时收到关于计划破坏的警告。</p>
<p>Officials say they carried out the demolitions against illegal properties. Rights activists and the displaced citizens say the destruction has pushed thousands more into homelessness.<br/>
官员们表示，他们对非法财产进行了拆除。人权活动人士和流离失所的公民表示，这场破坏使成千上万的人无家可归。</p>
<p>Now, New Delhi roads are newly smooth and paths are brightly lit. The city's buildings have fresh paint and colorful flowers are everywhere.<br/>
现在，新德里的道路变得更加平坦，道路上灯火通明。这座城市的建筑刷上了新油漆，到处都是五颜六色的花朵。</p>
<p>The G20 includes the world's 19 wealthiest countries and the European Union. The leaders meeting, or summit, will take place at a new conference center near the famous India Gate monument.<br/>
二十国集团包括世界上最富有的19个国家和欧盟。这场领导人会议或峰会将在著名的印度门纪念碑附近的一个新的会议中心举行。</p>
<p>Similar shantytowns were also destroyed in other Indian cities where lower-level G20 meetings are taking place.<br/>
在印度其他正举行20国集团低级别会议的城市，类似的棚户区也被摧毁。</p>
<p>In July, a report by a rights activist group found that preparations for the G20 summit resulted in the displacement of nearly 300,000 people. Many were from neighborhoods where diplomats were expected to visit for G20 events.<br/>
7月，一个维权组织的报告发现，20国集团峰会的筹备工作导致近30万人流离失所。许多人来自外交官预计将前往参加20国集团活动的社区。</p>
<p>The report also said the government destroyed at least 25 shantytowns and night shelters to establish parks in their place. And, it said the government offered no shelters for the newly homeless.<br/>
报告还说，政府摧毁了至少25个棚户区和夜间避难所，在这些地方建造公园。它还说，政府没有为这些新近无家可归的人提供容身之地。</p>
<p>Abdul Shakeel is with the activist group Save Colony Forum. He said people's lives are being destroyed to better the city's "appearance."<br/>
阿卜杜勒·沙克尔是激进组织“拯救群居地论坛”的成员。他说，人们的生活正在被破坏，以改善城市的“外貌”。</p>
<p>"The money used for G20 is taxpayers' money. Everyone pays the tax," he said, including those made homeless by the demolitions.<br/>
他说：“G20用的是纳税人的钱。每个人都要纳税。”这里面就包括那些因拆迁而无家可归的人。</p>
<p>Rekha Devi lost her home in the project. She appealed to the government to save her house. She offered to provide documents to prove that generations of her family lived in the same house for almost 100 years.<br/>
瑞卡·德维在这个项目中失去了她的家。她呼吁政府保留她的房子。她主动提出提供文件，证明她家几代人在同一所房子里住了近100年。</p>
<p>The government refused to consider the papers and destroyed Devi's home.<br/>
政府拒绝考虑这些文件，并摧毁了德维的家。</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Artists Fight Back against AI Using Their Work  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/artists-fight-back-against-ai-using-their-work.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Kelly McKernan's paintings are often striking images of female figures in bright colors of green, blue, pink or purple.</p>
<p>The 37-year-old artist from Nashville, Tennessee calls her works "<strong>surreal</strong>." She says they are "dealing with <strong>discomfort</strong> in the human journey."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Refik Anadol's Unsupervised exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, Wednesday, Jan. 11, 2023, in New York. The new AI-generated installation is meant to be a thought-provoking interpretation of New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/800f0000-c0a8-0242-14b2-08dafd6113b3_cx7_cy17_cw87_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Refik Anadol's "Unsupervised" exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, Wednesday, Jan. 11, 2023, in New York. The new AI-generated installation is meant to be a thought-provoking interpretation of New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)</span></div>
<p>Surviving as an artist is difficult enough. The pandemic made it worse. But now McKernan faces another threat: artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<p>McKernan uses the pronoun they instead of his or her to call themself. About a year ago, McKernan began seeing online images strangely similar to their own. They soon learned that companies were feeding artwork into AI systems to train software programs to create similar images.</p>
<p>McKernan told the Associated Press, "I didn't give my <strong>consent </strong>for my name or work to be used this way."</p>
<p>McKernan said they even tried to contact some of the companies to say "Hey, little artist here, I know you're not thinking of me at all, but it would be really <strong>cool</strong> if you didn't use my work like this." But there was no answer.</p>
<p>In January, McKernan, and two other artists, Karla Ortiz and Sarah Andersen, started legal action against three image-<strong>generator</strong> companies: Stability AI, Stable Diffusion and Midjourney. They also named the online gallery DeviantArt in the case.</p>
<p>The artists are seeking to protect their <strong>copyrighted</strong> works and their careers. They say the AI image-generators violate the rights of millions of artists by using their artworks for training and then producing similar works that compete against the <strong>originals</strong>.</p>
<p>The artists are seeking damages and a court order to stop AI companies from using their works without permission.</p>
<p>McKernan said, "At the end of the day, someone's profiting from my work. I had <strong>rent</strong> due yesterday, and I'm $200 short... And it just doesn't feel right."</p>
<p>Stability AI would not comment to the <em>Associated Press </em>(<em>AP</em>) for the story. In a court document, the company said it uses simple words to create "new and <strong>unique</strong> images." The company added the program creates new works and does not violate copyright.</p>
<p>A Stability AI company official appeared before a U.S. Senate hearing in July. He said that artists are not paid for the images used to train AI software.</p>
<p>Midjourney and DeviantArt did not return emailed requests for comment.</p>
<p>Karla Ortiz works in the entertainment industry. Her work has been used in several well-known movies, including <em>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</em> and<em> Jurassic World</em>.</p>
<p>She feared that companies would think artists cost too much. Why, she asked, would companies employ artists if they can pay $30 a month for AI-generated works?</p>
<p>McKernan agreed: "Will I even have work a year from now?"</p>
<p>A federal judge in San Francisco will decide the case.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in a temporary win for human artists last month, another federal judge agreed with the decision by the U.S. Copyright Office not to issue copyright for AI-generated artwork.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett adapted this report for VOA Learning English from The Associated Press news report.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surreal </strong>– adj. like a dream, not real</p>
<p><strong>discomfort</strong> – n. a little unease or pain</p>
<p><strong>consent </strong>– v. permission</p>
<p><strong>cool</strong> – adj. pleasing, desired</p>
<p><strong>generator</strong> – n. something that creates or produces</p>
<p><strong>copyright</strong> – n. if something like a piece of art, music, or book has a copyright, it is illegal to produce, copy, or use it without permission</p>
<p><strong>original</strong> – n. not a copy; the first</p>
<p><strong>rent</strong> – n. money paid to live in a house or apartment</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong> – adj. different from everything else; the only one of its kind</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>TV Show Explores Teaching at an Urban Public School  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/tv-show-explores-teaching-at-an-urban-public-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American TV show called <em>Abbott Elementary</em> is a <strong>comedy</strong> about teachers in a Philadelphia elementary school.</p>
<p>The show has been praised for being funny, <strong>smart</strong> and heartwarming and for dealing with important education issues. Over two seasons of 35 <strong>episodes</strong>, the show has explored education issues like school budgets, <strong>charter schools</strong> and teacher mental health.</p>
<p>The show is on ABC, one of the biggest American television networks. The show is being aired at a time of teacher shortages and debates about how race issues and history should be taught.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Quinta Brunson plays second-grade teacher Janine on ABC's Abbott Elementary (ABC/Gilles Mingasson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ddba-08db8c806273_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Quinta Brunson plays second-grade teacher Janine on ABC's Abbott Elementary (ABC/Gilles Mingasson)</span></div>
<p>The creator and star of the show is Quinta Brunson. Brunson's mother was a public school teacher in Philadelphia. Brunson plays a young, second-grade teacher named Janine at Abbott Elementary. The show follows several other teachers at Abbott, which is a badly supervised and majority-Black school that does not have enough money. Although the teachers often run into trouble with students and the administration, they care about their jobs and try to help their students.</p>
<p>Brunson said in an interview with <em>Education Week</em> that two writers on the show are former teachers. She said she wanted all the writers to have "a healthy relationship to education."</p>
<p>She added that since the COVID-19 pandemic, education has been a subject on the minds of everyone.</p>
<p>"Three years ago, no one was talking about teachers as much as they are now," Brunson said. "And now, everywhere we look, we're talking about education...I hope that it leads us into a better place in this country with our treatment of education, specifically public education."</p>
<p>Sara Jones is a professor of elementary education at Illinois State University. Next spring, she will be teaching a class on <em>Abbott Elementary</em>. At each class, students will watch an episode of the show then discuss an issue related to urban education that appeared in that episode. The class will also read related research papers from education experts.</p>
<p>Jones is a former elementary school teacher and has researched urban education. She said the show covers many issues that come up in her research like teacher shortages, teacher training and unfair use of public money.</p>
<p>"I immediately fell in love with the <strong>characters</strong> and the storytelling and that connection to my own teaching experience," Jones told VOA.</p>
<p>The class is part of the university's honors program instead of the education school, so it will have students from different areas of study. Jones added that the show is funny and interesting but deals with issues in a simple way that people who are not involved in education can understand.</p>
<p>A repeated issue in the show's second season is the charter school movement. Charter schools receive public money but operate outside the public school system. Charter schools also receive private money. Businessmen like Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg and former Microsoft chief Bill Gates have invested money in some charter schools. In <em>Abbott</em>, a group called Legendary Charter schools threatens to turn every public school in Philadelphia into a charter school.</p>
<p>Charter schools do not have the same operating requirements as local government-operated public schools. Critics argue that charter schools receive local tax money that could go to traditional public schools.</p>
<p>In one episode, the teachers discuss the threat of Legendary charter schools. One of the older teachers, Barbara, says, charters "take our funding. Not to mention the private money from wealthy donors with <strong>ulterior</strong> <strong>motives</strong>."</p>
<p>But the principal, Ava, who is often portrayed as foolish says, "<strong>Weird</strong> cash swirling around? Don't threaten me with a good time."</p>
<p>Jones said the story explores urban school issues better than most shows on television, including the news media.</p>
<p>"I hope students will get from (this class) a deeper understanding of those issues and perhaps a shift in <strong>perspective</strong> about particularly urban schools."</p>
<p>Brunson said she hopes people who watch the show will be more likely to support schools and teachers.</p>
<p>"It's a public service," Brunson said of teaching. "Who are we without teachers? Who are we without the people who teach us how to read?"</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>comedy</strong><strong> </strong><em>— n. </em>a kind of performance meant to make people laugh</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>smart </strong><em>–adj.</em> showing a sharp mind or clever way of looking at things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>episode </strong><em>–n</em>. one in a series of television or radio shows</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>charter school </strong>–n. a school established under a charter (legal agreement) that is not part of the local government, but receives some public tax money as called for by local law</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>character </strong>–n. a person in a television show, play or other performance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ulterior motive </strong>–n. an addition reason that something is done that is usually hidden</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>weird</strong><strong> </strong><em>— adj. </em>unusual or strange</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>perspective </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of looking at an issue as it relates to other things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>West Point Time Capsule Contains More Than Just Dirt  (2023/9/6) | 西点军校直播打开近200年历史的时光胶囊</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/west-point-time-capsule-contains-more-than-just-dirt.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Officials at the U.S. Military Academy West Point in New York state recently opened a time capsule that is 195 years old live on the internet.<br/>
纽约州西点军校官员最近通过网上直播打开了一个有195年历史的时间胶囊。</p>
<p>The event on August 28 caused disappointment because the container appeared to contain nothing more than dirt. But West Point officials said last Wednesday that the box did contain hidden treasure after all.<br/>
8月28日的这次活动让人们失望，因为盒子里似乎除了泥土什么都没有。但西点军校官员上周三表示，这个盒子里确实藏着宝藏。</p>
<p>A time capsule is a container that is filled with objects and buried or hidden. The capsule is meant to be opened by people living many years in the future.<br/>
时间胶囊是指装满物体并被掩埋或藏起来的容器。这个容器将被生活在多年之后的人们打开。</p>
<p>The lead box is believed to have been put in place by West Point military students. It was discovered inside the base of a memorial to Revolutionary War hero Thaddeus Kosciuszko.<br/>
据信，这个铅盒是西点军校学生放置的。它是在独立战争英雄撒迪乌斯·科希丘什科纪念碑的基座内发现的。</p>
<p>The capsule contained six silver American coins dating from 1795 and 1828 and a medal, West Point said in a news release. The ceremonial opening of the box happened at the military school in New York state.<br/>
西点军校在一份新闻稿中表示，这个容器内装有六枚1795年至1828年的美国银币和一枚奖章。开箱仪式在这所位于纽约州的军校举行。</p>
<p>Speaking of the event, West Point archeologist Paul Hudson said: "When I first found these, I thought, man, you know, it would have been great to have found these on stage." After the opening, he took the box back to his laboratory and began carefully looking through the remains.<br/>
西点军校考古学家保罗·哈德森在谈到这次活动时表示：“当我找到这些东西时，我想，要是能在台上（直播时）发现它们就好了。”打开盒子后，他把盒子带回了实验室，然后开始仔细查看残留物。</p>
<p>He said he then found the edge of a coin in the dust inside the box. "I thought, well that's OK. That's something, that's a start," Hudson said.<br/>
他称自己随后在盒子里的灰尘中发现了一枚硬币的边缘。哈德森说：“我想，好吧，没关系。这是一个开始。”。</p>
<p>He said he felt let down like everyone else by the lack of results from the live opening. The crowd that gathered at the U.S. Military Academy hoped to see historical military objects or documents when experts opened the top and pointed a camera inside.<br/>
他说，对于在直播打开时没有发现，他和其他人一样感到失望。聚集在这所美国军事学院的人群希望在专家打开盒盖并将相机对准内部时能够看到历史军事物品或文件。</p>
<p>It was probably better to remove the coins and medal in a controlled setting, added Hudson. He still plans to study the remains for possible answers to what else might be inside.<br/>
哈德森补充道，最好在可控的环境中移去硬币和奖牌。他仍然计划研究这些残留物，以期找到答案，弄清楚里面可能还有什么。</p>
<p>It appears that moisture and possibly dirt entered the box through a damaged edge. The conditions could have destroyed materials like paper or wood.<br/>
看上去水汽和泥土是通过损坏的边缘进入了盒子。这种情况可能会破坏纸张或木材等材料。</p>
<p>What did survive was a five-cent coin from the year 1795, an 1800 Liberty Dollar, an 1818 25-cent coin, 10-cent, and 1-cent coins from 1827, and an 1828 50-cent coin. There was also a medal remembering the Erie Canal from 1826.<br/>
残留下来的是一枚1795年的5美分硬币、一枚1800年的自由银币、一枚1818年的25美分硬币、1827年的10美分硬币和1美分硬币各一枚，以及一枚1828年的50美分硬币。还有一枚纪念1826年伊利运河的奖章。</p>
<p>The discoveries seem to confirm school officials' theory that the box was put in place by military students in 1828 or 1829. The monument to Kosciuszko, which included a statue of him, was completed at about that time.<br/>
这些发现似乎证实了学校官员推测的盒子是1828年或1829年由军校学生安放的。科希丘什科纪念碑，包括他的雕像，大约是在那个时候造好的。</p>
<p>A group of five military students, or cadets, was involved in the ceremony dedicating the monument. One of them was U.S. Civil War general Robert E. Lee who graduated in 1829.<br/>
一个由五名军校学员组成的小组参与了纪念碑的落成仪式。其中一位是1829年毕业的美国内战将领罗伯特·E·李。</p>
<p>Kosciuszko had designed wartime fortifications for the Continental Army at West Point during the Revolutionary War. He died in 1817. The statue of Kosciuszko was added to the monument in 1913.<br/>
科希丘什科在独立战争期间为大陆军在西点军校设计了战时防御工事。他于1817年去世。科希丘什科的雕像于1913年被添加到纪念碑中。</p>
<p>The historical preservation and research of the time capsule will continue.<br/>
对时间胶囊的历史保存和分析将继续进行。</p>
<p>"I think there's more that we can learn from this," Hudson said.<br/>
哈德森说：“我认为我们可以从中学到更多东西。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Extends Protection for Migrants from Six Countries  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-extends-protection-for-migrants-from-six-countries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The administration of U.S. President Joe Biden recently announced it is extending temporary protection from <strong>deportation</strong> to migrants from six countries.</p>
<p>Nationals of Sudan, Ukraine, El Salvador, Honduras, Nepal and Nicaragua can remain in the United States under the extended policy.</p>
<p>The Temporary Protected Status (TPS) program permits migrants, whose home countries are considered unsafe, to live and work in the United States. They can do so under the program although they do not have normal legal permission to be in the country. However, they can only be in the U.S. for a set period of time, and they must meet U.S. government requirements.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Demonstrators participate in the March for TPS (Temporary Protected Status) Justice during a protest in support of permanent residency, outside the White House in Washington, Feb. 12, 2019. (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01460000-0aff-0242-4fb4-08da65d00dde_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Demonstrators participate in the March for TPS (Temporary Protected Status) Justice during a protest in support of permanent residency, outside the White House in Washington, Feb. 12, 2019. (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Daniel Costa is director of immigration law and policy research at the Economic Policy Institute, an organization based in Washington, D.C. Costa said current TPS holders have high employment rates and add billions of dollars to the U.S. economy every year.</p>
<p>"TPS raises <strong>wages</strong> through...work <strong>authorization</strong> for people who don't have it...Higher wages also mean more spending back in the economy, which creates more jobs," he said.</p>
<p>The United States first gave Honduras, Nicaragua and El Salvador Temporary Protected Status more than 20 years ago. When the Biden administration extended TPS for those countries in June, it was for people who were current TPS holders.</p>
<p>If the Biden administration again gives those countries temporary protected status, it would expand TPS for many people. It would permit any qualifying migrant who entered the U.S. during the last 20 years to receive TPS.</p>
<p>A <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.niskanencenter.org/the-value-of-temporary-protected-status-as-a-u-s-policy-tool/" target="_blank">report by the Niskanen Center</a>, a Washington-based policy research organization, said the "<strong>vast</strong> majority" of TPS holders are employed.</p>
<p>"More than 94 percent of TPS holders were in the labor force as of 2017," the report stated. It said that they worked in industries including sales and health care. The 2017 report warned that ending TPS for just El Salvador, Honduras, and Haiti would cause the U.S. economy to lose over $160 billion over 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Adding new countries</strong></p>
<p>Immigrant organizations have called for the U.S. to give new TPS <strong>designations</strong>. They hope the government will add Mauritania and the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) to the program.</p>
<p>Nils Kinuani is the immigration coordinator for the Congolese Community of Washington Metropolitan. He told VOA the group had conversations with U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) officials in April.</p>
<p>"We have been also working with congressional leaders to push for this designation," Kinuani said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State says the DRC is suffering a humanitarian crisis marked by over 20 years of civil war and conflict.</p>
<p>Leaders of Black Mauritanians say the U.S. had an earlier policy of not deporting Mauritanians because of the country's human-rights record. Haddy Gassama is with the organization UndocuBlack Network. She wrote that the abuses "include the practice of enslaving Black people" and keeping a system of apartheid.</p>
<p>Apartheid is a political system of racial separation.</p>
<p>In January, Democratic Senator Sherrod Brown and Republican Representative Mike Carey sent a letter to Biden and other government officials to support TPS for Mauritanians living in the U.S. without legal permission.</p>
<p>Congress established TPS in 1990. Currently, 16 countries are <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uscis.gov/humanitarian/temporary-protected-status" target="_blank">designated for the program</a>.</p>
<p>Current TPS holders who want to extend their protection must register again during the 60-day registration period for their country's designation. Re-registration opens soon for four countries, starting with El Salvador on September 10.</p>
<p>TPS designations are set for six, 12, or 18 months. About two months before a country's TPS ends, the DHS secretary has to decide if the U.S. will end or extend the TPS.</p>
<p>The TPS program does not lead to permanent U.S. <strong>residency</strong>. As of March, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/homesec/RS20844.pdf" target="_blank">about 610,000 foreign nationals</a> held temporary protected status.</p>
<p>TPS holders who leave the U.S. without first getting a travel authorization may lose their TPS status and may not reenter the country.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Aline Barros wrote this story for Voice of America. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>deportation </strong><em>–n.</em> the process of legally removing someone from a country who is not permitted by law to be in that country</p>
<p><strong>wages </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> money paid to a worker in exchange for the amount of time they worked</p>
<p><strong>authorization </strong><em>–n.</em> official permission to do, have or act as something</p>
<p><strong>vast </strong><em>–adj.</em> very large in size or extent</p>
<p><strong>designation </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of officially naming or choosing someone or something; the state of being named to a position or status under the law</p>
<p><strong>residency </strong><em>–n.</em> the status of legally being permitted to live in a place</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Maine’s Puffin Bird Population Is Recovering  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/scientists-maine-s-puffin-bird-population-is-recovering.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists studying the Atlantic puffin population off the coast of Maine say the birds are now recovering after suffering major losses in 2021.</p>
<p>Atlantic puffins look and walk similarly to penguins. Wildlife officials say reproductions for the animals on islands off the coast of Maine fell sharply in 2021. But last year, about two-thirds of puffins in the area produced young. While the numbers did not reach that same level this year, the birds still had a better year than in 2021.</p>
<p>The main reason for the decreasing numbers is a drop in the population of small fish puffins feed on, such as herring. Two years ago, puffin colonies suffered one of the lowest reproduction rates in many years because of a lack of those fish. Only about one-quarter of the birds were able to raise young in 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An Atlantic puffin brings a beak full of baitfish to feed its chick in a burrow under rocks on a small island off mid-coast Maine, Sunday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-352d-08dbaa2a9377_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An Atlantic puffin brings a beak full of baitfish to feed its chick in a burrow under rocks on a small island off mid-coast Maine, Sunday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)</span></div>
<p>Environmental groups have linked the lower fish populations in the area to warming ocean temperatures. The Gulf of Maine, which has puffin colonies on its islands, is warming faster than most of the world's oceans. Some recent years have been especially warm and local climate officials have said this summer appears to have been "still unusually warm."</p>
<p>Bill Sydeman is the president and chief scientist at the Farallon Institute, a <strong>conservation</strong> organization based in California. He told The Associated Press the reasons for the puffin population drop include deadly heat waves, loss of food, loss of islands to sea level rise and an inability to reproduce, or breed.</p>
<p>"The problem with climate change is these breeding failures and low breeding productivity years are now becoming <strong>chronic</strong>," Sydeman said. "There will be fewer young birds in the population that are able to <strong>recruit</strong> into the breeding population."</p>
<p>Maine's puffins are the only breeding Atlantic puffins in the United States. Worldwide, the species lives in the North Atlantic from Maine and Canada to Europe. Other countries with large puffin populations, such as Iceland, have also seen their bird populations drop.</p>
<p>The Maine puffin population once fell to only about 70 pairs in an area known as Matinicus Rock. Hunters who went after the birds for their meat and feathers had nearly destroyed them by the early 1900s. Stephen Kress is a scientist with the Audubon Society who has sought to grow puffin colonies since the 1970s. His attempts included moving young puffins from Canada to Eastern Egg Rock, another small island in the area.</p>
<p>Wildlife officials say adult birds in the colonies appear fairly strong, and it's "likely the population is stable, and it could still be growing," said Don Lyons. He is the director of conservation science at the National Audubon Society's Seabird Institute in Bremen, Maine.</p>
<p>The difficulties facing seabirds make successful breeding seasons especially important, said P. Dee Boersma. She is a University of Washington professor of biology and director of the university's Center for Ecosystem Sentinels.</p>
<p>"What that means is we should be more <strong>cautious</strong> and concerned about reproductive failures and things like that to make sure that in good years everyone that wants to has a chance to breed, and do well," Boersma said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>chronic </strong><em>– adj. </em>something that continues for a long time</p>
<p><strong>recruit </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to persuade someone to work for a company or to join an organization</p>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>– adj. </em>taking care to avoid risks or danger</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Whole Genome Testing Finds Diseases Better in Children  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/study-whole-genome-testing-finds-diseases-better-in-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Brynn Schulte nearly died two times when she was a baby. At one point she needed emergency <strong>surgery</strong> for bleeding in her brain.</p>
<p>No one knew what was wrong. Then, a test that looked at her full genetic details found a rare bleeding disorder. Catching the disorder early saved her life.</p>
<p>"You have this hopeless feeling when you don't really know what's going on," said her father, Mike Schulte. He noted that the test made a difference in finding the cause and "getting her the right care that she needed almost immediately."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Courtney Chase, a nurse at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, listens to 4-year-old Brynn Schulte's heart before the girl gets an infusion of medication to treat a rare genetic bleeding disorder, Aug. 3, 2023, in Cincinnati, Ohio. (AP Photo/Laura Ungar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/39dbaf16-ac54-4538-8791-dd63710aaa49_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Courtney Chase, a nurse at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, listens to 4-year-old Brynn Schulte's heart before the girl gets an infusion of medication to treat a rare genetic bleeding disorder, Aug. 3, 2023, in Cincinnati, Ohio. (AP Photo/Laura Ungar)</span></div>
<p>Brynn, now 4, got the genetic testing as part of a <strong>clinical </strong>trial. The results of which were published recently in <em>The Journal of the American Medical Association</em>.</p>
<p>Testing all of the details of a person's genes is called "whole genome" testing. Whole genome tests are much better than narrowly targeted tests when it comes to finding genetic differences, called abnormalities, that can cause disease.</p>
<p>The study found 49 percent of these abnormalities, compared to 27 percent with more commonly used tests targeting only some genetic diseases.</p>
<p>Whole genome tests could solve the problem of doing several narrowly targeted tests on babies, which still might not find the disorder. Experts warn there are some problems because labs vary in how they understand results. Also, whole genome tests are costlier and less likely to be covered by <strong>insurance</strong>.</p>
<p>But researchers hope that whole genome tests will at some point be used for millions of hospitalized babies with rare and difficult conditions. The U.S. National Human Genome Research Institute has found that around 350 million people around the world live with rare disorders. And it found that about 80 percent of the more than 7,000 conditions are genetic.</p>
<p>"I've been doing clinical trials of babies for over 40 years," said study writer Dr. Jon Davis, chief of newborn medicine at Tufts Medical Center in Boston. "It's not often that you can do something that you feel is going to really change the world and change clinical practice for everyone."</p>
<p><strong>No one was sure about Brynn's condition</strong></p>
<p>The night Brynn was born, she had difficulty breathing. There was also some bleeding in her brain. So, doctors gave her blood <strong>transfusions</strong> and tests for different bleeding problems. When Brynn was a month old, she had surgery after a huge brain bleed.</p>
<p>Her mother Lindsay Schulte said no one was sure about her condition. "I don't think we slept. I mean, watching your child nearly die in front of your eyes <strong>twice</strong> is a memory I'll never <strong>erase</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>Then the Schulte family learned about the clinical trial. Brynn and both parents got the whole genome testing. The results came in less than a week later: She had a rare bleeding disorder. It affects an estimated 1 in 2 million to 1 in 3 million live births. She also had another condition that caused a severe reaction to some drugs.</p>
<p>Doctors said the correct results would likely have taken more time or even missed with several narrow, targeted tests.</p>
<p>That is because targeted tests cover maybe 1,700 out of 20,000 genes. But whole genome testing "captures more things," said Dr. Paul Kruszka of GeneDx. It is a company that provides whole genome testing but was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>Dr. Jill Maron is a study writer and a chief of children's medicine at Women &amp; Infants Hospital in Rhode Island. She said full genome tests generally cost about three times more than narrow tests and are not covered by public insurance in most U.S. states.</p>
<p>Experts like her say that greater <strong>access</strong> to full genome tests is necessary if more children are going to be helped.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surgery </strong><em>– n.</em> medical treatment in which a doctor cuts into someone's body in order to repair or remove damaged or diseased parts</p>
<p><strong>clinical </strong><em>– adj.</em> relating to or based on work done with real patients: of or relating to the medical treatment that is given to patients in hospitals or clinics</p>
<p><strong>insurance</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> an agreement in which a person makes regular payments to a company and the company promises to pay money if the person is injured or dies, or to pay money equal to the value of something (such as a house or car) if it is damaged, lost, or stolen</p>
<p><strong>transfusion </strong><em>– n.</em> a medical treatment in which someone's blood is put into the body of another person</p>
<p><strong>twice </strong><em>– adv.</em> two times</p>
<p><strong>erase </strong><em>– v.</em> to remove any thought or memory of (something)</p>
<p><strong>access </strong><em>– n.</em> a way of being able to use or get something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>London Artist Paints Crushed Chewing Gum  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/london-artist-paints-crushed-chewing-gum.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Lying on London's famous Millennium Bridge, British artist Ben Wilson paints on a piece of dried <strong>gum</strong>. It has been crushed flat into the ground.</p>
<p>"The important thing is the gum is below the metal<strong> tread</strong>," said the 60-year-old Wilson. "The beauty of it is they're all different shapes and sizes...," he continued, describing pieces of gum.</p>
<p>Wilson sees possibility in things most people avoid looking at. The flattened gum is a chance to turn a piece of waste into something beautiful.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ben Wilson, artist, paints on the Millennium Bridge, London, Britain, August 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Anna Gordon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/331959f3-3b17-4880-b14c-138894efe4a5_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ben Wilson, artist, paints on the Millennium Bridge, London, Britain, August 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Anna Gordon)</span></div>
<p>The artwork also is a way to surprise walkers and get them to take a closer look at the path they are on.</p>
<p>"By painting a picture which is so small, those that see it then discover a hidden world beneath their feet," Wilson said.</p>
<p>Back in his north London art room, Wilson paints on the surface of a small <strong>mosaic tile</strong>. It will be part of a collection that he is creating on the walls of London's Underground train platforms. The images are more personal than the chewing gum works, Wilson says, and represent a kind of "visual <strong>diary</strong>."</p>
<p>"The pictures are a celebration of my life and those that I care dearly about," he said. "They are a process of visual inquiry - trying to make sense of the world," he added.</p>
<p>Wilson was born in London to artist parents. He remembers working with <strong>clay</strong> from the age of three. He had his first art show when he was around 10 or 11 years old.</p>
<p>He began making sculptures and large pieces for display in nature settings. Then his interest turned to waste, also called trash. He has been painting gum and other pieces of trash for 19 years.</p>
<p>The top surface of the dried gum is not subject to local or national laws. As a result, the dried gum surface creates a space where Wilson says he can paint without damaging public property.</p>
<p>"I found this little space where I could create a form of art where I could be <strong>spontaneous</strong> and do something which evolves out of the place in which it's created," Wilson said.</p>
<p>Government officials have removed much of the artist's public street art. But the hundreds of gum paintings on Millennium Bridge remain for all to see.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Lucy Marks reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gum</strong> –<em> n.</em> a type of soft candy that you chew on but do not swallow</p>
<p><strong>tread </strong><em>– n.</em> the raised surface that people walk on</p>
<p><strong>mosaic </strong><em>– n</em>. a decoration made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material that then hardens</p>
<p><strong>tile</strong><em> – n</em>. a usually flat piece of hard clay or other material that is used for covering walls or floors</p>
<p><strong>diary</strong> –<em> n.</em> a book in which you write down your personal experiences and thoughts each day</p>
<p><strong>clay</strong> <em>– n.</em> a heavy, sticky material from the earth that is made into different shapes and that becomes hard when it is baked or dried</p>
<p><strong>spontaneous</strong> <em>– adj.</em> created in a natural and often sudden way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US City Turns to Science to Help Reduce Gun Violence  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-city-turns-to-science-to-help-reduce-gun-violence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>"That's where I got shot," said Rashaad Woods, pointing toward a small store in the city of Knoxville in the state of Tennessee. Nearby are a <strong>nightclub</strong> where some people were shot and killed and a church with bullet holes in the walls.</p>
<p>"There was a point in time I wasn't <strong>comfortable</strong> standing here," said Kodi Mills. "But that time is passing."</p>
<p>The two men work for Turn Up Knox, a community-based organization that began operating in July of 2022. It mentors children and teenagers on how to prevent conflicts from becoming violent. The project is a central part of city efforts to use research-based methods to reduce gun violence.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Knoxville Deputy Police Chief Tony Willis talks with Terry Walker-Smith after a meeting of the Violence Reduction Leadership Committee on Thursday, Aug. 3, 2023, in Knoxville, Tenn. (AP Photo/George Walker IV)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1f84-08dba95232a9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Knoxville Deputy Police Chief Tony Willis talks with Terry Walker-Smith after a meeting of the Violence Reduction Leadership Committee on Thursday, Aug. 3, 2023, in Knoxville, Tenn. (AP Photo/George Walker IV)
</span></div>
<p>Turn Up Knox began operating after a sharp rise in shooting deaths in Knoxville. The larger city effort to reduce gun violence includes policy changes in policing and other action.</p>
<p>However, it does not depend on restrictions to gun ownership. That was important, since Tennessee has repeatedly moved to loosen gun restrictions.</p>
<p>In 2021, Tennessee started letting people carry handguns in the open or hidden, without a permit. This year, the minimum age for carrying handguns dropped to 18.</p>
<p><strong>Turning to research for answers</strong></p>
<p>Indya Kincannon is the city's mayor.</p>
<p>"I wanted to be able to fix it," she said of the rising gun violence.</p>
<p>As the gun violence goes up in the United States, so has research into how to stop it. Researchers estimate there were more than 48,000 gun deaths last year, with gun-related killings and suicide rates not seen since the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Gun-related incidents are now the leading cause of death among American children and teenagers.</p>
<p>Now, researchers say they know more about which public health strategies help reduce gun violence and which ones do not.</p>
<p>A report from the non-profit research group Rand Corporation points to policies that it found help reduce gun violence. These steps include laws that permit the charging of adults who let children have unsupervised <strong>access to</strong> guns. The researchers say strong background checks on gun purchasers also helps reduce gun violence. Another helpful measure involves banning guns from people with a legal record of family violence, Rand reported.</p>
<p>The RAND report also noted policies that do not help reduce gun violence. For example, it said <strong>concealed</strong> carry laws increase gun killings, as do gun buyback programs.</p>
<p><strong>East Knoxville and trusting police </strong></p>
<p>About 16 percent of Knoxville's population is Black and about 40 percent of that group is very poor. Many of them live in East Knoxville, where the firearm violence has greatly increased.</p>
<p>Like other American cities, violence increased in Knoxville during the COVID-19 pandemic. Before the pandemic, there were around 20 shooting deaths per year. The number rose to 38 in 2020 and grew again to 41 in 2021.</p>
<p>As shootings increased, Kincannon, the city's mayor, looked to ideas by Thomas Abt, a crime researcher at the University of Maryland. His plan includes having police and community organizations work closely together.</p>
<p>Abt's Center for the Study and Practice of Violence Reduction at the University of Maryland worked with an outside researcher to study Knoxville's violent crime.</p>
<p>The study contained a few surprises, said Knoxville Deputy Police Chief Tony Willis.</p>
<p>Just 12 percent of killings by gun were related to organized criminal groups alone. That suggests many of the shootings only involved personal disagreements.</p>
<p>The city's plan centered first on areas in East Knoxville with high rates of gun violence. The effort involves church leaders and community organizations. It also included a new police chief, an investigative division centered on homicides and shootings, and officers who work mostly in areas with many shootings.</p>
<p>A goal is to increase public trust in law enforcement, which had been low.</p>
<p>"We would have someone get killed in broad daylight, with a lot of witnesses, but no one wanted to talk," Kincannon said. "That means we need more partnership in the community, to build trust."</p>
<p>That is where Turn Up Knox is expected to help. It involves ex-offenders, victims and other community members assisting. They help identify those most likely to be shot or to become shooters. They also mentor teenagers and operate a <strong>lawn</strong> service that gives jobs to kids. And, they teach families how to settle conflicts and deal with shooting events.</p>
<p>Sometimes, when someone is in danger of becoming the victim of a<strong> revenge</strong> shooting, Turn Up Knox gives the person a bus ticket to leave town for a few days.</p>
<p>However, some experts say programs built around Thomas Abt's ideas do not deal with enough of the problem. They note that the programs do not deal with suicide by gun nor the issue of poverty as a risk for gun violence.</p>
<p>Charlene Roberts' 25-year-old daughter, Jessie, was shot and killed in 2019 while sitting in a car. Her son Kevin, 33, was killed in 2021 in gunfire at a birthday party.</p>
<p>She is now raising Jessie's son, Princeton. She says he is strong but that he has also changed.</p>
<p>"He always had the biggest smile, just like his mother," she said. "It breaks my heart. He <strong>fakes</strong> a smile now. He don't have that smile anymore."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Mike Stobbe reported this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nightclub </strong><em>-n. </em>an indoor social gathering place with music and dancing or other entertainment</p>
<p><strong>comfortable </strong><em>-adj. </em>feeling relaxed and at ease</p>
<p><strong>access </strong><em>-v. </em>to reach or get something or be someplace</p>
<p><strong>conceal </strong><em>-v. </em>to hide something</p>
<p><strong>lawn </strong><em>-n. </em>an area of cut grass, typically in the yard's of people's homes</p>
<p><strong>revenge </strong><em>-n. </em>an action in retaliation against a perceived ethically wrong action done against oneself or others</p>
<p><strong>fake </strong><em>-v. </em>to pretend to do something but not really do it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Super, Blue and Blood: A Guide to Different Full Moons  (2023/9/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/super-blue-and-blood-a-guide-to-different-full-moons.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Sky watchers around the world were <strong>treated</strong> this month to two full moons, a supermoon and a blue moon.</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/news/922/what-is-a-supermoon/">explains</a> a supermoon happens when the moon's orbit brings it closer than usual to Earth at the same time that the moon appears full from Earth. The first supermoon of 2023 was in July. The fourth and last one will be in September.</p>
<p>The last time two supermoons appeared in the sky in the same month was in 2018, The Associated Press reports. The next time a blue supermoon is set to arrive is 2037.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The supermoon rises behind the ancient temple of Poseidon at Cape Sounion, about 70 kilometers (45 miles) south of Athens, Greece, Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d34a-08dbaa956c6f_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The supermoon rises behind the ancient temple of Poseidon at Cape Sounion, about 70 kilometers (45 miles) south of Athens, Greece, Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Thanassis Stavrakis)</span></div>
<p>The first supermoon arrived on the first day of August, while the blue moon was seen beginning August 30. NASA noted that when the blue moon arrived, the planet Saturn was just a few days from its closest and brightest appearance of the year from Earth. Saturn appeared as a bright "star" to the upper right of the blue moon.</p>
<p>Italian astronomer Gianluca Masi, creator of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.virtualtelescope.eu/">Virtual Telescope Project</a>, held an online watch event as the blue supermoon was setting below the skyline of Rome. But he advised that, as long as the weather was good, world observers looking to the sky would not need any special equipment to see the moons.</p>
<p>"Warm summer nights are the ideal time to watch the full moon rise in the eastern sky within minutes of sunset," said retired NASA astrophysicist and moon expert Fred Espenak.</p>
<p>Full moons happen at the exact moment when the moon is opposite the sun, NASA says. Astronomers say a supermoon can appear about 14 percent larger and a bit brighter than other moons.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.almanac.com/">Old Farmer's Almanac</a> notes that the August full moon is known as the sturgeon moon. This is because of a traditionally large increase in fish in the American Great Lakes area during the month of August.</p>
<p>Although it is called a blue moon, it does not appear blue in color. Instead, the name means it is the second full moon to happen within one month or the fourth to take place in a season.</p>
<p>NASA says the moon takes 27.3 days to orbit Earth, but it takes 29.5 days to complete a full moon cycle. This is what makes it possible to see one full moon at the start of the month and another one right at the end.</p>
<p>Astronomers say, however, that the moon can look blue under the right conditions. For example, this can happen as a result of smoke or dust particles in the atmosphere.</p>
<p>While the blue supermoon brings the possibility for watching and taking beautiful pictures, its stronger gravitational pull also can influence higher tides. Weather experts advise people living in areas near shorelines to be aware of this, especially during storm activity.</p>
<p>There are other kinds of moons that appear at different times.</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://spaceplace.nasa.gov/full-moons/en/">says</a> a blood moon happens during a total lunar <strong>eclipse</strong>. This event is when Earth lines up between the moon and the sun, hiding the moon from sunlight. In addition, the term blood moon can also be used to describe a moon that appears reddish because of dust, smoke or <strong>haze</strong> particles in the sky.</p>
<p>A harvest moon is a full, bright moon that appears "closest to the start of autumn," NASA explains. This name dates from the time before electricity, when farmers depended on the moon's light to harvest their crops late into the night. The moon's light was especially important during fall when harvests are the largest.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse and NASA.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>treat to </strong><em>–v. (phrasal) </em>to give a person something that is pleasant, interesting or fun</p>
<p><strong>eclipse </strong><em>– n. </em>an event in which the sun is blocked by the moon, or when the moon passes through the Earth's shadow</p>
<p><strong>haze </strong><em>– n. </em>the appearance of air when it is not very clear because of the presence of heat, dust or smoke</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Unwanted Kiss Prompts Spain to Change Soccer Culture  (2023/9/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/unwanted-kiss-prompts-spain-to-change-soccer-culture.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Spain has spoken loudly through its government, politicians, soccer teams and ordinary citizens to condemn the leader of its soccer federation for kissing a player.</p>
<p>Luis Rubiales kissed soccer player Jenni Hermoso on the mouth just after Spain defeated England to win the women's soccer World Cup in August.</p>
<p>The 46-year-old Rubiales took the action during the awards ceremony following the game. Hermoso is one of the star players on Spain's team. The 33-year-old said she did not want or like the kiss.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Spain's Jennifer Hermoso celebrates with President of the Royal Spanish Football Federation Luis Rubiales after the match, August 20, 2023. (REUTERS/Hannah Mckay)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9bdb-08dba391259e_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Spain's Jennifer Hermoso celebrates with President of the Royal Spanish Football Federation Luis Rubiales after the match, August 20, 2023. (REUTERS/Hannah Mckay)</span></div>
<p>FIFA, the world soccer governing body, later suspended Rubiales for 90 days. The Spanish government is considering whether to push for his permanent removal from the job.</p>
<p>Some Spanish women who grew up playing soccer said kisses and unwanted touches from male leaders were common. They want the behavior to change.</p>
<p>Patricia Otero is 30. She is a high school teacher but still plays soccer in her free time. She said "we have seen that all our lives," when asked about Rubiales' actions.</p>
<p>She said male <strong>coaches</strong> would often touch her and say "you are like a daughter to me." Otero said she was too young to know it was wrong. "You think it is normal," she said.</p>
<p>People in Spain now say it is time to end sexism in soccer. They point to policies and actions that favor boys and men over women and girls in the sport. For example, Otero said she and her teammates had to raise money for their team and clean their own <strong>locker rooms</strong>. The boys did not have to do that.</p>
<p>The <em>Associated Press</em> recently <strong>interviewed</strong> Spanish women working in soccer and other professions. Many said that Rubiales' behavior would have been ignored if the act had taken place 10 years earlier.</p>
<p>Maria Soleto is president of Spain's Women's Foundation. She said Spanish society has undergone a <strong>seismic</strong> shift.</p>
<p>At recent men's games in Spain's famous "La Liga," the country's top<strong> league</strong>, fans shouted repeatedly against Rubiales. They said he must leave his position. In Madrid, hundreds of people gathered in support of Hermoso.</p>
<p>The campaign of support is being called "Se Acabo" in Spain. It means "this is over." The male players on Sevilla's La Liga team wore the term on their soccer shirts.</p>
<p>The kiss may serve as a lesson for male leaders throughout the world. Lisa Banks is a civil rights and employment lawyer in Washington, D.C. She said men in sports now know "that an <strong>assault</strong> is an assault, even if it happens in a moment of <strong>jubilation</strong>."</p>
<p>Although the early reactions in Spain seemed to support Rubiales, the general opinion is now against him. The women's soccer team said it will not play any other games if he keeps his job. Government lawyers are deciding whether to open a case against Rubiales for sexual aggression. Some Spanish soccer federation officials are calling for his resignation.</p>
<p>Hermoso called the kiss "the <strong>final straw</strong>." She said the actions during the championship celebration "have been a part of our team's daily life for years."</p>
<p>Even before the kiss, the players had protested their treatment by soccer officials. Almost a year ago, 15 Spanish players said they would no longer play for <strong>coach</strong> Jorge Vilda if things did not get better. Spain's soccer federation sided with Vilda and replaced most of the players.</p>
<p>Other observers of women's sports hope the outcry over the kiss improves the financial conditions for women players. Some mid-level male soccer players earn close to $200,000 per year while the women only earn about $17,000.</p>
<p>Pilar Calvo of Spain's Association of Women in Professional Sports said she has seen five times the number of protests over inequality in recent days.</p>
<p>She said people have talked about inequality in prize money, poor training centers and a lack of financial support.</p>
<p>Others, including Tona Is, a former player and coach, say they feel <strong>vindicated</strong>. She was a top player on Spain's under-17 team in 2018 and an assistant to Vilda until she was dismissed in 2020.</p>
<p>She said she lost her job because she protested about bad behavior by male leaders.</p>
<p>"Time has finally shown that we were right, that there have been <strong>inappropriate</strong> <strong>episodes</strong> inside the federation for years," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>coach </strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who runs a sports team and helps players learn the game</p>
<p><strong>locker room </strong>–<em>n</em>. the place where a sports team dresses and keeps their regular clothing</p>
<p><strong>interview </strong>–<em>n</em>. a conversation between two people where one seeks information</p>
<p><strong>seismic </strong>–<em>adj</em>. having to do with the energy created when two parts of the earth move against each other, such as in an earthquake</p>
<p><strong>league </strong>–<em>n</em>. an organization, usually of sports teams, that creates games and a schedule and awards a winner or championship</p>
<p><strong>assault </strong>–<em>n</em>. a form of violence where one person attacks another</p>
<p><strong>jubilation </strong>–<em>adj</em>. a large amount of excitement</p>
<p><strong>final straw </strong>–<em>expression</em> – the last in a series of bad things to make someone very upset and unwilling to accept any more bad things</p>
<p><strong>inappropriate episode </strong>–<em>n.</em> an event or happening or action that is not socially permitted</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: Hundreds of Thousands in Southeast Asia Tricked into Online Crime  (2023/9/4) | 联合国称东南亚数十万人身陷网络诈骗</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/un-hundreds-of-thousands-in-southeast-asia-tricked-into-online-crime.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The United Nations human rights office says criminal groups have forced hundreds of thousands of people in Southeast Asia into unlawful online scam operations.<br/>
联合国人权办公室表示，犯罪集团已迫使东南亚数十万人从事非法网络诈骗活动。</p>
<p>A scam is a dishonest way to make money by tricking people.<br/>
诈骗是指通过欺骗人们来赚钱的一种不正当手段。</p>
<p>The Office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights released a new report on the issue on Tuesday. It said that at least 120,000 people in Myanmar and about 100,000 in Cambodia "may be held in situations where they are forced to carry out online scams."<br/>
联合国人权事务高级专员办事处周二就此问题发布了最新报告。报告称，缅甸至少有12万人，柬埔寨约有10万人“可能身处被迫实施网络诈骗的境地”。</p>
<p>Cybercrime scams have become a major problem in several Asian countries. Many workers are forced to join in scams targeting people over the internet. Criminal groups have increasingly targeted migrants. They offer false promises of real employment to the victims.<br/>
网络犯罪诈骗已成为几个亚洲国家的一个主要问题。许多工人被迫加入针对互联网用户的诈骗活动。犯罪集团越来越多地以移民为目标。他们向受害者提供真实就业的虚假承诺。</p>
<p>The U.N. rights office said it is hard to estimate how many people are caught up in such operations. It is also difficult to know how much money the criminal groups make through their scam operations. But it is believed to be in the billions of U.S. dollars every year.<br/>
联合国人权办公室表示，很难估计有多少人被卷入此类行动。也很难知道犯罪集团通过诈骗活动赚了多少钱。但据信每年都有数十亿美元。</p>
<p>Some victims have been subjected to torture, cruel punishments, sexual violence and other crimes, the rights office said.<br/>
人权办公室表示，一些受害者遭受了酷刑、残忍的惩罚、性暴力和其他罪行。</p>
<p>Pia Oberoi is a senior advisor on migration and human rights for the Asia-Pacific area at the U.N. human rights office. She described two kinds of victims: people who have lost large amounts of money and people trafficked into working for the scammers.<br/>
皮娅·欧贝罗伊是联合国人权办公室亚太地区移民和人权问题高级顾问。她描述了两种受害者：损失大量金钱的人士和被贩卖为骗子工作的人士。</p>
<p>Oberoi told reporters in Switzerland that many of the scams started during the COVID-19 pandemic. Lockdowns shut down casinos that were an important part of the economy along boarder areas and in Cambodia. The closures caused "economic distress" that left "middle class, educated...young people" out of work. Many of them got talked into working for the schemes.<br/>
欧贝罗伊在瑞士告诉记者，许多骗局始于新冠肺炎大流行期间。疫情封锁导致赌场关闭，这些赌场是边境地区和柬埔寨经济的重要组成部分。关闭造成了“经济困境”，导致“中产阶级、受过教育的年轻人”失业。他们中的许多人被说服为这些骗局效力。</p>
<p>In May, leaders from the Association of Southeast Asian Nations agreed in a meeting in Indonesia to increase border controls and law enforcement. And they agreed on increasing public education to fight criminal groups that traffic workers to other nations, where they join in the online scams.<br/>
5月，东南亚国家联盟领导人在印度尼西亚举行的一次会议上同意加强边境管制和执法。他们还同意加强公共教育，以打击将工人送往其他国家参与网络诈骗的犯罪集团。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New COVID-19 Variant Expands Internationally  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/new-covid-19-variant-expands-internationally.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>International health officials are closely following a new version of COVID-19 as it spreads to more countries.</p>
<p>The version, or variant, is called BA.2.86. Officials from the World Health Organization (WHO) say it has already been identified in several countries, including the United States, Switzerland, South Africa, Israel, Denmark and Britain.</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus recently spoke to reporters about the latest COVID-19 developments. He said the new COVID-19 variants show that the virus remains a health threat around the world.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, a student at the University of Pennsylvania's Perelman School of Medicine in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania demonstrates a viral RNA extraction on December 16, 2021. (REUTERS/Hannah Beier)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a292-08dba9a08485_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, a student at the University of Pennsylvania's Perelman School of Medicine in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania demonstrates a viral RNA extraction on December 16, 2021. (REUTERS/Hannah Beier)</span></div>
<p>Tedros noted the latest data show that COVID-19 infections and hospitalizations are decreasing. But he added that the agency had seen "increasing reports of hospitalizations, ICU admissions and deaths in some countries." ICU is a short form for the term intensive care unit, part of a hospital that cares for very sick patients.</p>
<p>Maria Van Kerkhove is with the WHO's Health Emergencies Program. She said that, as of last week, only about 10 cases of the BA.2.86 variant had been found worldwide. But Van Kerkhove added that health officials are worried because the variant appears to have more than 30 genetic <strong>mutations</strong>.</p>
<p>She said the WHO is currently trying to closely follow the movements of the latest virus variants. The efforts include taking wastewater <strong>samples</strong> from different cities to follow where COVID-19 is spreading. In addition, such methods can help officials learn how fast current variants are spreading and how severe they are. "Governments cannot <strong>drop the ball</strong>," Van Kerkhove said.</p>
<p>Health officials say BA.2.86 broke off from the Omicron variant, which has been spreading in the U.S. at least since last year. It was first discovered in Denmark on July 24.</p>
<p>Some international scientists have said that while it is important to keep following BA.2.86, the variant was unlikely to cause a new, harmful wave of infections. This is because much of the population has built up defenses against COVID-19 because of vaccinations or previous infection.</p>
<p><strong>Testing new vaccines</strong></p>
<p>Scientists are currently testing how effective newly created COVID-19 vaccines will work against BA.2.86. Van Kerkhove noted that in the past, vaccines have been better at preventing severe sickness and death than blocking re-infections. U.S. health officials said earlier this month the latest COVID-19 vaccines are set to be released sometime in September.</p>
<p>The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) completed a risk report on the new variant last week. The report said BA.2.86 may be capable of causing infection in vaccinated people and those who had COVID-19 before. But officials noted there is so far no evidence that the new variant is causing more severe sickness than earlier ones.</p>
<p>The WHO said COVID-19 testing has dropped by 90 percent worldwide from the highest point of the pandemic. Testing rates have also fallen sharply in the U.S., and genetic <strong>sequencing</strong> is down by around 90 percent, said Dr. Ashish Jha. He served as the White House COVID-19 Response Coordinator until June 2023.</p>
<p>Jha said data from hospital stays, emergency room visits, deaths, wastewater testing and sequencing efforts had given health officials improved information about current virus spread.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and the Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mutate </strong><em>– v. </em>to cause a gene to change and create an unusual characteristic in a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>drop the ball </strong><em>– idiom</em> to make a mistake, especially by not taking action or dealing with something that should have planned for</p>
<p><strong>sequence </strong><em>– v. </em>to combine things in a particular order, or discover the order in which they are expressed</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>West Virginia University to Cut Languages, Creative Programs  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/west-virginia-university-to-cut-languages-creative-programs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>School leaders at West Virginia University recently proposed cutting almost 10 percent of the university's study programs and over 100 educators because of a $45 million budget deficit.</p>
<p>Included in the cuts were study programs, known as majors, in world languages, art history, jazz performance, creative writing, and degrees in math and education.</p>
<p>The languages include Chinese, French, German, Russian and Spanish. In addition, professors leading programs in <strong>linguistics </strong>and TESOL could be cut.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="West Virginia University students lead a protest against cuts to programs in world languages, creative writing and more amid a $45 million budget deficit outside Stewart Hall in Morgantown, W.Va., on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Leah Willingham)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c8e5aca3-3485-4dcf-bdb7-8abf9ca4cd6c_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">West Virginia University students lead a protest against cuts to programs in world languages, creative writing and more amid a $45 million budget deficit outside Stewart Hall in Morgantown, W.Va., on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Leah Willingham)</span></div>
<p><strong>‘Emotions are high'</strong></p>
<p>The university's Office of the Provost considered "several key <strong>metrics</strong>" to reduce or eliminate majors. The metrics included: the number of students interested in the majors, the <strong>ratio</strong> of students to professors in the program, the amount of money the programs bring to the school, and the future research plans each program had.</p>
<p>WVU released its plan in early August. The school permitted the affected programs to appeal the university's decision. The cuts resulted in a large protest on August 21.</p>
<p>The provost, one of the university's top leaders, is Maryanne Reed. At a meeting during the protests, she called the time "incredibly <strong>stressful</strong>," and noted, "emotions are very high right now."</p>
<p>The university's final plan will be announced in the middle of September.</p>
<p><strong>Appeal results</strong></p>
<p>The World Languages department appealed WVU's proposal on August 25, asking the university to reconsider part of its plan.</p>
<p>Lisa Di Bartolomeo is one of the professors in the department. She also attended the university as a student.</p>
<p>Before the appeal, she told VOA that cutting foreign language instruction would hurt students from West Virginia when they look for jobs. She said it would hurt their career earnings and hurt elementary and high school-aged children in West Virginia who depend on language teachers trained at WVU.</p>
<p>"The best and the brightest students don't see a future for themselves in West Virginia."</p>
<p>On August 29, WVU said it planned to follow through with much of its proposal. It is likely to cut all language majors but continue some teaching in both Spanish and Chinese. The university said it is important to continue with those languages because Spanish is in "high demand" and Chinese is a "critical need."</p>
<p>Reed said the university will remove a foreign language study requirement for students seeking Bachelor of Arts degrees. The university said it will work to support students who are interested in "<strong>immersive</strong> (language) experiences" through study abroad programs.</p>
<p><strong>Poor planning?</strong></p>
<p>Those who run the school are concerned about the state's decreasing population and the decreasing number of college-aged students. West Virginia is the only state in the U.S. with a population that is lower today than it was in 1950.</p>
<p>WVU has about 27,000 students. About 25,000 are at its main campus in Morgantown. That number is 10 percent lower than it was in 2015. That means the school takes in less money from students and taxpayers.</p>
<p>The population loss is one reason for the university's financial problems. New student housing and new academic buildings meant for a growing number of students are empty today.</p>
<p>E. Gordon Gee, the university president, said the cuts are needed so WVU can be "a competitive university on the national stage." He said the school is not taking its reduction proposal lightly. University leaders say study programs and professors are not all that are being cut.</p>
<p><strong>International students affected</strong></p>
<p>Among the 27,000 students at WVU, there are about 1,000 international students. Some of them are studying in the programs that might be <strong>eliminated</strong>. All of them will be permitted to finish their degrees. But no new students will come into the eliminated programs. That process is called a "teach out."</p>
<p>VOA Learning English spoke with two international students who are worried about their study programs: Jose Ramirez is a music and higher education graduate student from Colombia. Winda Melati is a higher education <strong>graduate</strong> student from Indonesia.</p>
<p>Ramirez also is a graduate of WVU's world languages program: he studied German.</p>
<p>He said the plan to take away most language teaching is "sad," and he wondered if the university no longer sees language learning as important.</p>
<p>Ramirez said:</p>
<p>"And it's also showing... like kind of the mentality of a lot of English speakers is that they don't need to learn another language because everybody (else) will learn English."</p>
<p>Melati said she is concerned for herself and other students who are in the U.S. on F-1, or student visas. Some, she noted, planned to stay at WVU to continue teaching or studying after completing their degrees. Now they may have to change their plans because of the cuts.</p>
<p>Melati and Ramirez both expressed concern about the programs and the value of their degrees if they are cut. Melati asked: "How can I be proud of (my work) if I graduate from a program that is no longer there?"</p>
<p>Ramirez said he feels lucky that he was able to study at WVU, but he feels sad that future students will not get the same instruction he did. They worry international students will not come to WVU after learning of the cuts.</p>
<p>But, Henry Oliver of the university's global affairs office believes the university will still appeal to international students.</p>
<p>"WVU has a really long-standing history and appeal for international students. And to be honest, I don't expect that to change."</p>
<p>He noted that popular WVU programs are safe. He listed most science, technology, engineering, math and business study programs. "These programs are still things that remain very strong at WVU and will continue to be strong," Oliver said.</p>
<p><strong>A compromise ahead?</strong></p>
<p>Many who are protesting the reductions say they would have liked to see the university do more to talk with professors, students, employees and West Virginians before announcing the cuts.</p>
<p>Both Di Bartolomeo and Ramirez are afraid there was not enough input from students, parents and graduates.</p>
<p>And Ramirez said, even with the appeal process, he believes most decisions have already been made.</p>
<p>"I would like to be wrong, but I think that everything is ... they are just seeing the numbers and the numbers are not making it."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell reported this story for Learning English with additional reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>linguistics </strong><em>–n.</em> the study of how languages work</p>
<p><strong>metric </strong><em>–n.</em> a tool for measuring something, especially something's value<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>ratio </strong><em>–n.</em> the relationship that exists between two values which can be expressed as two numbers</p>
<p><strong>stressful </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing worry or fear</p>
<p><strong>immersive </strong><em>–adj.</em> a method involving being completely surrounded by a language in an effort to learn it</p>
<p><strong>eliminated</strong><em>—adj.</em> having been removed or ended</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong><em>–adj</em>. having already graduated from undergraduate schooling</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Explore from Your 'Armchair'  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/explore-from-your-armchair.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a piece of <strong>furniture</strong> used for sitting. As the name suggests, an armchair has extensions for resting your arms. So, armchairs are more <strong>comfortable</strong> than other chairs. In fact, they are so comfortable that people sit in them for hours.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pictured here is an traditional style armchair in front of some bookshelves." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-936e-08dbaa5c816c_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pictured here is an traditional style armchair in front of some bookshelves.</span></div>
<p>Besides being a kind of furniture, Americans use the word "armchair" in front of other words. They do this to describe different sorts of people and the experiences they might or might not have.</p>
<p>For example, some experiences can be called <strong>vicarious</strong>. If you live vicariously, you experience things through other people. You do not actually do the thing you are interested in yourself. Rather, you enjoy the activity by watching or reading about what others do.</p>
<p><u>Armchair detectives</u> are not real detectives investigating crimes. An armchair detective enjoys reading detective novels or watching true crime shows. Armchair detectives may even try to solve a crime. But all their efforts are done from the safety and comfort<strong> </strong>of their homes.</p>
<p>Living vicariously through others can be a wonderful chance to escape. Let's say you do not have the time or money to travel. But you still want to experience the pleasure of traveling. You can read about places that you would like to visit. You can watch travel <strong>documentaries</strong> about them too. And you can do these things from the comfort<strong> </strong>of your own home. So, you could call yourself an <u>armchair traveler. </u></p>
<p>If you enjoy watching and reading about people who do dangerous activities -- such as climbing Mount Everest or free diving into the depths of the ocean -- you might be an <u>armchair adventurer</u>.</p>
<p>However, we also use "armchair" to describe another sort of person. If someone does not have responsibility for a job but talks about it from a distance, we can use the word "armchair" to describe them. Also, if someone is not an expert in a subject, but gives advice anyway, we could use the word "armchair."</p>
<p>For example, an armchair <u><strong>strategist</strong></u> gives strategies that are more <strong>theoretical</strong> than <strong>practical</strong>. This means they are talking about a problem but are not actually involved in solving it.</p>
<p>In the same way, an <u>armchair general</u> gives advice on going into battle ... from a safe distance. Armchair generals are not involved in a real battle.</p>
<p>In the U.S., a favorite term comes from American football. <u>Armchair quarterbacks</u> comment on a football game from the comfort of their own chair. They criticize and insult the players who actually play the game while they themselves have never played it.</p>
<p>But the use of the term "armchair quarterback" goes far beyond the world of sports. So, you could hear the term used to describe anyone who does not do an activity or have responsibility but still makes sharp comments or criticizes others who work at the job every day.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>furniture </strong>–n. things found in the room of a home or business such as chairs, tables, sofas, and shelves</p>
<p><strong>comfortable </strong>–adj. causing a feeling of ease and enjoyment and not pain</p>
<p><strong>vicarious </strong>–adj. something that is not felt by oneself but through others</p>
<p><strong>documentary </strong>–n. a kind of movie that tells a real story and that does not use actors but real people</p>
<p><strong>strategist </strong>–n. a person who is skilled at making detailed plans to reach goals that extend over a long period of time</p>
<p><strong>theoretical </strong>–adj. having to do with the theory of how something should work rather than how people know something works</p>
<p><strong>practical </strong>–adj. having to do with reality rather than what is possible in the future or imaginary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Woodrow Wilson: Idealist  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-president-woodrow-wilson.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Woodrow Wilson. He served two terms, from 1913 to 1921, and led the United States through the first World War.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Woodrow Wilson" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/92cf1972-5ba1-4b76-a2d3-807f2f365994_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Woodrow Wilson</span></div>
<p>Wilson might have seemed an unlikely war president. He was a university professor before he entered politics.</p>
<p>And, when the conflict began in Europe in 1914, Wilson strongly rejected the idea of the U.S. getting involved. He even campaigned for his second term on the slogan "He kept us out of the war."</p>
<p>But Wilson's idealism eventually made him believe the U.S. must enter the conflict. He famously said, "The world must be safe for democracy."</p>
<p>He spent the last months of his presidency fighting to create a league of nations that would prevent future wars.</p>
<p>Wilson did not succeed in that effort. But the effects of his presidency are still seen today in both the domestic and foreign affairs of the United States.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Woodrow Wilson was born in the state of Virginia in 1856 and grew up in the South.</p>
<p>Wilson's father was a Protestant Christian minister who supported the views of the Confederacy during the Civil War.</p>
<p>Wilson's mother had been born in England but raised in the United States. She was reportedly warm and loving, especially to her husband and four children.</p>
<p>Wilson's early life was marked by poor health and a passion for learning. His education included tutoring by Confederate soldiers, classes with his father, a year at Davidson College, a bachelor's degree from the school now called Princeton, one year of law school, and a doctoral degree in history and political science from the University of Johns Hopkins.</p>
<p>He remains, so far, the only president with a Ph.D.</p>
<p>Wilson's academic interests were in government, and how it could be most effective. Even as a young man, he supported the idea of a strong executive, either a prime minister or a president.</p>
<p>He wrote a number of books, including a biography of George Washington, and a history of the United States. He also taught popular classes at several colleges, including Bryn Mawr in Pennsylvania, Wesleyan in Connecticut, and Princeton in New Jersey.</p>
<p>In time, Wilson became the president of Princeton. He made major reforms to the school until some faculty and alumni resisted his efforts.</p>
<p>Wilson had always been interested in political power. The Democratic Party in New Jersey became interested in Wilson when they were looking for a candidate with an honest public image.</p>
<p>In truth, party officials believed he would be a weak leader whom they could influence. Wilson surprised them by winning the seat as New Jersey governor easily, and then rejecting their efforts to control him.</p>
<p>He went on to pass major reform legislation in New Jersey that reduced corruption and protected the rights of workers. His actions drew the attention of Democratic Party leaders seeking a candidate for president in 1912.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: first term</strong></p>
<p>Voters did not overwhelmingly choose Wilson in 1912. Although he did well in the Electoral College, he earned only a little more than 40 percent of the popular vote. Other votes were mostly divided between two former presidents, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-theodore-roosevelt/3986653.html" target="_blank">Theodore Roosevelt</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americans-presidents-william-taft/3997949.html" target="_blank">William Taft</a>.</p>
<p>Yet Wilson quickly <strong>asserted</strong> authority over Congress and pushed through a number of laws aimed at dramatic reform.</p>
<p>Historian Kendrick Clements at the University of South Carolina <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/wilson/domestic-affairs">says</a> Wilson had a strongly progressive vision.</p>
<p>He was interested in "expanding economic <strong>opportunity</strong> for people at the bottom of society and <strong>eliminating</strong> special <strong>privileges</strong> enjoyed by the richest and most powerful members of society."</p>
<p>One of Wilson's most important acts was to create a new federal agency called the Federal Reserve Board. It still <strong>regulates</strong> American banks, credit, and money supply. He also created the Federal Trade Commission to ensure fair business practices, and the Department of Labor to protect workers' rights.</p>
<p>And he supported laws to reduce working hours for railroad employees, bar child labor, and offer government loans to farmers.</p>
<p>But even during Wilson's busy lawmaking, the threat of world war demanded his attention. Wilson had declared that the U.S. would remain neutral in the growing conflict between the Allied and Central Powers.</p>
<p>One of his reasons was that people in the U.S. were immigrants from the countries that were at war. Wilson did not want the conflict to divide Americans.</p>
<p>However, he permitted international trade, including with Britain and France. As a result, many believed the U.S. was favoring those countries.</p>
<p>In 1915, a German submarine sank a British ship called the Lusitania and killed more than 100 Americans on board.</p>
<p>Wilson protested several times to Germany about the sinking. He warned that the U.S. would not accept another such aggression. But two years later, Germany attacked U.S. <strong>commercial</strong> ships. It also invited Mexico to enter into an alliance against the United States.</p>
<p>At the beginning of Wilson's second term in office, he asked Congress to declare war on Germany.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: second term</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. entered World War I on the side of the Allied Powers. The additional support came at an important time. American soldiers were able to help resist German troops in France.</p>
<p>In time, Germany asked for an <strong>armistice </strong>– an agreement to stop fighting.</p>
<p>Following the war, Wilson had a grand vision for how to gain lasting peace in Europe. In a speech known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/wilson-outlines-the-fourteen-points">Fourteen Points</a>," he proposed that the countries that had won the war not punish Germany.</p>
<p>Wilson also wanted European colonies to rule themselves, and other areas be given immediate independence.</p>
<p>Most importantly, Wilson suggested a League of Nations that would guarantee the member countries' independence and safety.</p>
<p>But few world leaders agreed with his plan completely.</p>
<p>Even in the U.S., many Republican lawmakers in Congress resisted Wilson's idea for a League of Nations. Some strongly objected to any treaty that would limit the country's independence. Others did not want the country to be involved in world issues at all.So Wilson began a trip across the U.S. to raise public support for the League of Nations. He traveled more than 15,000 kilometers in 22 days and gave 29 speeches.</p>
<p>Wilson's doctors warned him that the trip was hard on his health. But Wilson was firm about pressuring Senate Republicans to adopt the agreement.</p>
<p>Finally, he collapsed from <strong>exhaustion</strong>. Shortly after, he suffered a major stroke. Although he recovered somewhat, he remained partly <strong>paralyzed</strong>. He rarely appeared in public again.Instead, Wilson communicated to Congress through his wife. When Republicans changed the treaty to deal with their concerns, Wilson told his supporters to reject it.</p>
<p>In the end, the U.S. never did join the League of Nations.</p>
<p>When a new president, Warren Harding, was sworn-in in 1921, Edith and Woodrow Wilson retired to a house in Washington, D.C. Three years later, the former president died quietly there, finally at peace.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Caty Weaver was the editor. </em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>assert </strong>— <em>v. </em>to demand that other people accept or respect (something)</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>— <em>n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>eliminate</strong> — <em>v. </em>to remove; to get rid of</p>
<p><strong>privilege</strong> - <em>n. </em>a right or benefit that is given to some people and not to others</p>
<p><strong>regulate</strong> -<em> v. </em>to make rules or laws that control (something)</p>
<p><strong>commercial</strong> - <em>adj. </em>related to or used in the buying and selling of goods and services</p>
<p><strong>armistice</strong> -<em> n. </em>an agreement to stop fighting a war</p>
<p><strong>exhaustion</strong> -<em> n.</em> the state of being extremely tired</p>
<p><strong>paralyzed</strong> - <em>adj. </em>unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Abandoned Village Is a Reminder of Fast-changing UAE  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/abandoned-village-is-a-reminder-of-fast-changing-uae.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>About an hour's drive from the tall buildings of Dubai is an empty village in the sands of the United Arab Emirates. It stands as a <strong>reminder</strong> of how fast the Middle Eastern country is changing.</p>
<p>Built in the 1970s, the village of al-Ghuraifa was left empty twenty years later. Oil wealth has turned the UAE, home to the cities of Dubai and Abu Dhabi, into an international center of commerce and <strong>tourism</strong>.</p>
<p>In recent years, the empty village near the town of al-Madam in the Sharjah emirate has become more popular with visitors.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A house's entrance gate is buried under the sand at the Bedouin village of al-Ghuraifabout 100 km, 62 miles, southeast of Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/31efa6d1-767b-4fb3-9828-2e3bf75bda2c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A house's entrance gate is buried under the sand at the Bedouin village of al-Ghuraifabout 100 km, 62 miles, southeast of Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)</span></div>
<p>The village, made up of two rows of homes and a religious center, "can teach us a lot of the modern history of the UAE," said Ahmad Sukkar of the University of Sharjah. Sukkar is part of a team studying the area.</p>
<p>Al-Ghuraifa was built as part of a public housing project after the 1971 establishment of the United Arab Emirates, a group of seven sheikhdoms. The discovery of oil 13 years earlier was just starting to reshape the country.</p>
<p>The village housed around 100 members of the al-Ketbi tribe, Sukkar said. They were one of several Bedouin groups that until then had led a semi-<strong>nomadic</strong> existence. They raised animals, traveled among the desert <strong>oases</strong> and visited Dubai and Abu Dhabi when they were small towns.</p>
<p>The modern cement houses were built with local details to ease the change to settled life. The inside walls were brightly colored, and some had <strong>mosaics</strong>. The homes also had spaces where village leaders could gather locals for meetings. One house had special paper known as wallpaper showing a land with green plants and trees - a big difference from the sandy environment outside.</p>
<p>It is unclear what exactly caused people to leave just twenty years after the homes were built. Some say that they were driven away by evil spirits. But Sukkar says it is more likely that people left to seek a better life in the UAE's fast-growing cities.</p>
<p>The village had limited electricity and water, and was often hit by sandstorms. Families would have also had to deal with long traveling times across the desert to reach government jobs and schools in Dubai.</p>
<p>Now, the desert is slowly taking back the village. Sand has blown into the homes. Only the religious center, or mosque, remains as it was, thanks to regular cleaning by workers from nearby al-Madam.</p>
<p>Some <strong>descendants</strong> of the camel-mounted Bedouin who once traveled the desert sands still live in the Emirates' rural areas. However, many now live in cities with tall buildings, large shopping centers, and modern roads.</p>
<p>Foreign nationals make up the majority of the UAE's population, and some have taken an interest in its history. It is also a place for them to record music videos and social media posts. On a recent day, groups of visitors walked through the abandoned village.</p>
<p>"I wonder why they left," said Nitin Panchal, an Indian living in the UAE. "Could it be a <strong>genie</strong>," could it be "black magic?" Panchal asked. "We'll never know."</p>
<p>The local government recently installed fencing along with a security gate, waste containers and a parking lot. Officials made the changes because past visitors had caused damage to the village.</p>
<p>The new measures have taken some of the mystery from the village.</p>
<p>Danny Booth is from the Isle of Man, a British Crown Dependency in the Irish Sea. He said he had decided to "come and have a look before things start to change here."</p>
<p>"Sometimes these places are better left<strong> undisturbed</strong>, as they lose their <strong>charm</strong> when they become crowded," he said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Nick El Hajj reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>reminder</strong><em> -- n. </em>something that causes you to remember or to think about something</p>
<p><strong>tourism </strong><em>-- n. </em>the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>nomadic </strong>– adj. describes a member of a group of people who move from place to place</p>
<p><strong>oasis</strong> – n. an area in a desert where there is water and plants</p>
<p><strong>mosaic </strong>– n. a decoration on a surface made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material that then hardens to make pictures or patterns</p>
<p><strong>descendant </strong>– n. someone who is related to a person or group of people who lived in the past</p>
<p><strong>genie</strong> – n. a magic spirit that looks like a person and often lives in a lamp or bottle</p>
<p><strong>undisturbed </strong><em>-- adj. </em>not changed or touched by anyone or anything</p>
<p><strong>charm </strong><em>-- n. </em>an attractive quality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Cities Answer Some Emergency Calls with Mental Health Teams  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-cities-use-mental-health-teams-for-emergency-calls.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Clear Creek County in Colorado is one of the latest places to begin using mental health teams to answer some emergency 911 calls.<br/>
<br/>
Mental health response teams are not new. Many large cities put such teams in place after the killing of George Floyd during his arrest by police in Minneapolis in 2020.<br/>
</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - WellPower clinician Jane Lemaux loads supplies into a STAR van in Denver on Oct. 20, 2022. The STAR program uses clinicians and EMTs or paramedics to respond to nonviolent mental health crises, instead of police. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-eff8-08dba98a290d_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - WellPower clinician Jane Lemaux loads supplies into a STAR van in Denver on Oct. 20, 2022. The STAR program uses clinicians and EMTs or paramedics to respond to nonviolent mental health crises, instead of police. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)</span></div>
Some people believe mental health response teams might be more successful in answering some emergency 911 calls than police. The job of a mental health worker is to help people who have emotional problems or mental sickness. The job of the police is to enforce laws. They are not trained to treat mental health conditions.<br/>
<br/>
In Clear Creek County, the case of Christian Glass received a lot of attention. News reports said Glass called the 911 emergency phone number when his car got <strong>stuck</strong> on the roadside. Police answered the call, but Glass refused to get out of his car.<br/>
<br/>
Later, the police broke the car window. Glass threatened them with a small knife. He was then shot and killed by police. The lawyer for Glass's parents said he was having a mental health crisis. He believed that <strong>supernatural</strong> beings meant to harm him.<br/>
<br/>
After legal action, Clear Creak County agreed to pay $19 million as a result of the case and two officers face criminal charges.<p></p>
<p>New York City officials said mental health response teams resolve half of their calls by talking to people or taking them to social services or community health centers. However, the Associated Press (AP) reported that workers for the city's mental health crisis program, called B-HEARD, have had difficulty dealing with the number of calls and cases. The program answered about two percent of the 171,000 calls throughout the city in 2022.<br/>
<br/>
Carleigh Sailon was a mental health response team supervisor who used to work in a program in Denver, Colorado. She said mental health teams aim to meet the needs of the community and send the right experts to solve the problems.<br/>
<br/>
Mental health teams may also have more time to spend in response to an emergency call than police. That could be a reason that mental health response teams might be more successful than police in answering some 911 calls.<br/>
<br/>
For example, a mental health team responded to a 911 call about a homeless man in Denver, Colorado. The team spent three hours helping the man get a form of identification, food, and medications. They also took him to a shelter designed to house homeless people. Police might spend 10 to 90 minutes on a call.<br/>
<br/>
This would not be long enough to help a homeless person.<br/>
<br/>
At least 14 of America's 20 biggest cities are using mental health teams to answer some emergency 911 calls. New York City, Los Angeles; Houston, Texas; and Columbus, Ohio, spent almost $125 million on their programs. Smaller cities are also starting to use the teams.<br/>
<br/>
The AP reports that federal government information is incomplete on how effective mental health response teams are. But a recent study of a mental health response program in Denver from Stanford University suggested they have good results. The 2022 study found that, in some Denver neighborhoods where the programs were in place, few small crimes were reported while violent crimes remained unchanged.<br/>
<br/>
At a conference discussing mental health teams in Washington, D.C. this spring, officials from several cities discussed using mental health response teams. They said they faced difficulties in finding enough trained mental health workers, training workers at 911 call centers and sending unarmed civilians into situations that could be dangerous.<br/>
<br/>
However, an official for New York's B-HEARD program believes the effort is important.<br/>
<br/>
Laquisha Grant is with the New York Mayor's Office of Community Mental Health. She said, "We really think that every single B-HEARD response is just a better way that we, the city, are providing care to people."<br/>
<br/>
I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
<br/>
<em>Gena Bennett adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English with the addition of other sources.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stuck</strong> –adj. unable to move; trapped in a spot or place</p>
<p><strong>supernatural</strong> –n. unable to be explained by science or laws; seeming to come from something beyond this world</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cheer vs. Applause  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/cheer-vs-applause.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "cheers" and "applause."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA Learning English,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6e7a-08dba9a1a624_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am Sina from Iran. I have been learning English with your app for two years. I have a question:</p>
<p>What is the difference between "cheers" and "applause?"</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for writing to us, Sina.</p>
<p>These two words can mean to express approval or excitement, but the way that these feelings are expressed is a little different.</p>
<p>Cheering uses your voice, and applauding uses your hands to clap and make a sound. But let's look a little closer at each.</p>
<p><em>"I live for the applause-plause, live for the applause-plause, live for the-</em></p>
<p><em>Way that you cheer and<strong> scream</strong> for me</em></p>
<p><em>The applause, applause, applause..." </em></p>
<p>"Applause" is a noun that has two meanings. The first meaning is the approval or excitement marked by clapping hands together. The second meaning is the show of approval through<strong> praise</strong> or vocalizing.</p>
<p>Lady Gaga sang that she lives for the applause of her fans.</p>
<p>"Applaud" is the verb form and also has two meanings. When you applaud something, you are showing your approval or excitement by clapping your hands together. The verb can either take a direct object or not.</p>
<p><em>The crowd applauded the dancers during the show.</em></p>
<p><em>The <strong>audience</strong> applauded after the musical performance.</em></p>
<p>The second meaning of "applaud" is to praise or say that you like or agree with something that a person has done.</p>
<p><em>My professor applauded my work this year.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "cheer."</p>
<p>Much like "applaud," "cheer" as a verb means to show approval or excitement by vocalizing or shouting.</p>
<p><em>Parents cheered on their children at the soccer game.</em></p>
<p>To "cheer" also means to perform the act of cheerleading. Cheerleaders are people who lead the crowds at sporting events through cheering and applauding the teams. They encourage their team to win.</p>
<p><em>Kirstin cheered in school for the basketball team.</em></p>
<p>As a verb, "cheer" also means to be cheerful or to make glad or happy. We often use this verb with the preposition "up" in the command, "Cheer up!"</p>
<p><em>You look so unhappy, cheer up!</em></p>
<p><em>He cheered his girlfriend up with flowers.</em></p>
<p>Cheer is also a noun, and its meanings are closely related to the verb form.</p>
<p>"Cheer" is a shout of approval or excitement.</p>
<p><em>The cheers of the crowd grew louder as the football team started winning.</em></p>
<p>"Cheer" is the sport or activity of cheerleading.</p>
<p><em>There are different kinds of shoes needed in cheer depending on what position you are in.</em></p>
<p>"Cheer" also has other meanings as a noun, such as a mood or feeling, gladness or joy, or encouragement.</p>
<p><em>Holidays are a time for good cheer and making memories with family.</em></p>
<p>And we often say "cheers" before eating or drinking at a party or social gathering.</p>
<p><em>Cheers to the happy couple on their wedding day.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Sina.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scream </strong><em>– v.</em> to shout or cry out</p>
<p><strong>praise </strong><em>– n. </em>spoken or written words about the good qualities of someone or something: an expression of approval for someone or something</p>
<p><strong>audience </strong>– <em>n</em>. people who gather to watch a performance</p>
<p><em>Do you have a question for the teacher? We want to hear from you. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Activists Campaign against Rich Lifestyles  (2023/9/1) | 环保人士抨击富豪生活方式</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/climate-activists-campaign-against-rich-lifestyles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Climate activists have spray painted a boat, blocked private planes from taking off and covered holes in golf courses over the summer.<br/>
今年夏天，气候活动人士向一艘船泼油漆，阻止私人飞机起飞，并填平了高尔夫球场的球洞。</p>
<p>These actions are part of a campaign against the lifestyles of very rich people who, the activists say, release a lot of carbon pollution into the atmosphere.<br/>
这些行动是反对超级富豪生活方式运动的一部分，活动人士称这些人向大气中释放了大量碳污染。</p>
<p>As flooding, storms, and wildfires take place around the world, climate activists have also turned to new measures to call attention to these bad weather events. Some activists glued themselves to a road in Germany. Others threw soup on a Vincent van Gogh painting in Britain. They caused delays in sporting events including a Formula One Grand Prix racecar competition and the Tour de France bicycle race.<br/>
随着洪水、风暴和野火在世界各地发生，气候活动家也转向了新的措施，以引起人们对这些恶劣天气事件的关注。一些激进分子把自己粘在德国的一条路上。有人在英国向文森特·梵高的画作泼汤。他们导致了包括一级方程式大奖赛和环法自行车赛在内的体育赛事延误。</p>
<p>Now, they are turning their attention to rich people after targeting oil and gas companies and businesses that invest in fossil fuels.<br/>
他们在瞄准石油和天然气公司以及投资化石燃料的企业后，现在又将注意力转向了富豪。</p>
<p>"We do not point the finger at the people but at their lifestyle, the injustice it represents," said Karen Killeen. She was protesting in Ibiza, Spain, a popular summer place for the wealthy.<br/>
克伦·基利恩说：“我们不是把矛头指向这些人，而是指向他们的生活方式以及它所代表的不公正。”她在西班牙的伊维萨岛抗议，那里是富人的避暑胜地。</p>
<p>Killeen and other climate activists spray painted a $300 million boat while holding up a sign that read, "You consume, others suffer." She said she was protesting unnecessary carbon releases such as superrich individuals picking up food by boat. "In a climate emergency, it's an atrocity," she said.<br/>
基利恩和其他气候活动家向一艘价值3亿美元的船泼油漆，同时举着一块牌子，上面写着：“你享受，他人遭罪。”她说她在抗议不必要的碳排放，比如超级富豪乘船吃大餐。她说，“这在气候危机下是一种暴行。”</p>
<p>In Switzerland, about 100 activists chained themselves to aircraft stairs and to an entrance at Europe's biggest private jet sales gathering in Geneva. Another group of activists spray painted a private jet on the island of Sylt in the North Sea. In Spain, activists plugged holes in golf courses to protest the sport's heavy water needs during hot, dry weather.<br/>
在瑞士，大约100名活动人士将自己锁在飞机舷梯上，以及在日内瓦举行的欧洲最大私人飞机展销会的入口处。另一群活动人士在北海的西尔特岛上向一架私人飞机泼油漆。在西班牙，活动人士堵住高尔夫球场的球洞，以抗议这项运动在炎热干燥的天气下对水的大量需求。</p>
<p>In the United States, Abigail Disney of the Disney family was arrested at East Hampton Town Airport in New York, in July along with 13 other protesters. They blocked cars from entering or leaving a parking area. The group also protested at a golf course, a museum event, and outside private homes.<br/>
在美国，迪士尼家族的阿比盖尔·迪士尼与其他13名抗议者于7月在纽约东汉普顿镇机场被捕。他们阻止汽车进出停车场。该组织还在高尔夫球场、博物馆活动和私人住宅外举行抗议。</p>
<p>"Luxury practices are disproportionately contributing to the climate crisis at this point," said American University social scientist Dana Fisher.<br/>
美国大学社会科学家戴纳·费舍尔表示：“目前，奢侈行为对气候危机的影响尤为严重。”。</p>
<p>In a 2021 report, the nonprofit organization Oxfam said the richest one percent of people would be responsible for around 16 percent of emissions by 2030.<br/>
非营利组织乐施会在2021年的一份报告中表示，到2030年，人类最富有1%要对约16%的排放负责。</p>
<p>Richard Wilk is an economic anthropologist at Indiana University. He criticized superyachts: large boats that come with a crew, a helicopter, submarines and swimming pools. Wilk said superyachts release about 6,400 metric tons of carbon dioxide a year. That is over 1,500 times more than a family car, he said.<br/>
里查德·维尔克是印第安纳大学的经济人类学家。他批评了超级游艇这种配备船员、直升机、潜艇和游泳池的大型游艇。威尔克说，超级游艇每年释放约6400公吨二氧化碳。他说，这是家用汽车的1500多倍。</p>
<p>The environmental group Greenpeace estimated that private aircraft caused about 3 million metric tons of carbon pollution in Europe alone. That is the same as the average yearly CO2 emissions of over half a million people in the European Union.<br/>
绿色和平环保组织估计，私人飞机仅在欧洲就造成了约300万公吨的碳污染。这与欧盟50多万人的年均二氧化碳排放量相同。</p>
<p>But University of Pennsylvania climate scientist Michael Mann warned not to take attention away from fossil fuel companies. "The solution is to get everyone to use less carbon-based energy," whether wealthy or lower-income people, he said.<br/>
但宾夕法尼亚大学气候科学家迈克尔·曼警告说，不要把注意力从化石燃料公司身上转移开。他说，“解决方案是让每个人都减少使用碳基能源”，无论是富人还是低收入人群。</p>
<p>David Gitman is president of Monarch Air Group, a private airline in Florida. He urged activists to think about whether their actions would bring real change "like sustainable aviation fuel, like carbon offsets."<br/>
大卫·吉特曼是佛罗里达州私人航空公司君主航空集团的总裁。他敦促活动人士思考他们的行动是否会带来真正的改变，“比如可持续的航空燃料，比如碳抵消。”</p>
<p>Gitman added, "Now, if they go out and they spray-paint a private jet in an airport in Europe, is that going to get those results? In my opinion, no."<br/>
吉特曼补充道，“现在，如果他们去欧洲的一个机场向一架私人飞机泼油漆，会得到这种结果吗？在我看来，不会。”</p>
<p>But as protests increase, Wilk said they could still bring changes in behavior.<br/>
但威尔克表示，随着抗议活动的增加，他们仍有可能带来行为的改变。</p>
<p>"Public shaming is one of the most powerful ways of controlling people," Wilk said. "It acts in a lot of different ways to embarrass people, to make them more conscious of the consequences of their actions."<br/>
威尔克说：“公开羞辱是控制人们最有力的方式之一，它以多种不同的方式让人们感到尴尬，让他们更加意识到自己行为的后果。”</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Don’t Ask Voice Assistants for Lifesaving Measure  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-don-t-ask-voice-assistants-for-lifesaving-measure.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Voice assistants like Amazon's Alexa or Apple's Siri can be helpful when asking about something like the weather. But if you want to save someone's life? Call emergency services for that.</p>
<p>Voice assistants often are not helpful when asked how to perform CPR, a study published Monday found. Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation, or CPR, is an emergency lifesaving process performed when the heart stops beating.</p>
<p>Researchers asked voice assistants eight questions that someone who may need to perform CPR might ask. In answer, the voice assistants said:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man holds an iPhone next to an Amazon Echo, center, and a Google Home, right, in New York on June 14, 2018. (AP Photo/Mark Lennihan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c632eb65-7ee8-4f41-a528-c4ea4234a655_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man holds an iPhone next to an Amazon Echo, center, and a Google Home, right, in New York on June 14, 2018. (AP Photo/Mark Lennihan)</span></div>
<p>— "Hmm, I don't know that one."</p>
<p>— "Sorry, I don't understand."</p>
<p>— "Words fail me."</p>
<p>— "Here's an answer ... that I <strong>translated</strong>: The Indian Penal Code."</p>
<p>Only nine of 32 answers suggested calling emergency services for help – an important step suggested by the American Heart Association. The American Heart Association is a nonprofit organization that supports heart medical research.</p>
<p>Some voice assistants sent users to web pages that explained CPR, but only 12 percent of the 32 answers included voiced <strong>instructions</strong>.</p>
<p>Voiced instructions are important because immediate action can save a life, said study co-writer Dr. Adam Landman. He is chief information officer at Mass General Brigham in Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p><strong>Chest</strong> compressions – pushing down hard and fast on the victim's chest – work best with two hands.</p>
<p>"You can't really be <strong>glued</strong> to a phone if you're trying to provide CPR," Landman said.</p>
<p>The study was published in <em>JAMA Network Open</em>. Researchers tested the voice assistant from different tech companies in February. They included Amazon's Alexa, Apple's Siri, Google's Assistant, and Microsoft's Cortana. They asked questions such as "How do I perform CPR?" and "What do you do if someone does not have a <strong>pulse</strong>?"</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, better questions meant better answers. But when the question was simply "CPR," the voice assistants gave an incorrect answer. One played news from a public radio station. Another gave information about a movie called "CPR." A third gave the address of a local CPR training business.</p>
<p>ChatGPT from OpenAI, a free web-based <strong>chatbot</strong>, performed better on the test. It provided more helpful information. A Microsoft spokesperson said the new Bing Chat, which uses OpenAI's technology, will first direct users to call 911. It will then give simple steps when asked how to perform CPR.</p>
<p><strong>Standard</strong> CPR instructions are needed across all voice assistant devices, Landman said. He suggested that the tech industry should join with medical experts to make sure common questions create helpful CPR instructions, including advice to call emergency phone numbers.</p>
<p>A Google spokesperson said the company recognizes the importance of working with the medical community and is "always working to get better." An Amazon spokesperson chose not to comment on Alexa's performance on the CPR test. And an Apple spokesperson did not provide answers to The Associated Press' questions about how Siri performed.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>translate </strong><em>– v.</em> to change words from one language into another language</p>
<p><strong>instructions </strong><em>– n.</em> a statement that describes how to do something</p>
<p><strong>chest </strong><em>– n.</em> the front part of the body between the neck and the stomach</p>
<p><strong>glue</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to stay in one place because of interest, shock, or excitement</p>
<p><strong>pulse </strong><em>– n.</em> the regular movement of blood through your body that is caused by the beating of your heart and that can be felt by touching certain parts of your body</p>
<p><strong>chatbot </strong><em>– n.</em> a computer program designed to create conversation with human users, especially over the internet</p>
<p><strong>standard</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>adj.</em> regularly and widely used, seen, or accepted</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Support Grows for Bioeconomy in Amazon  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/support-grows-for-bioeconomy-in-amazon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Brazil's Amazon rainforest has long been home to small and mid-sized <strong>sustainable</strong> businesses. These companies use the area's nuts, fruits and other materials.</p>
<p>Now there is a push to increase the number of those businesses. And a new term has come about to describe these kinds of businesses: "bioeconomy."</p>
<p>Marcelo Salazar has a drink company called Mazo Mana Forest Food. The business partners with communities that live from the forest and gather the nuts, cocoa beans, acai, mushrooms, fruits and other ingredients that go into the drinks. They have received financial support from an investment group in Manaus, Brazil. The hope is that the bioeconomy counters an economy based on forestry and ranching.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="ARCHIVE - View of the forest on Combu Island on the banks of the Guam&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225; River, near Bel&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;233;m, Par&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;, Brazil, August 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, Archive)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fde4-08dba8a2b8cd_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">ARCHIVE - View of the forest on Combu Island on the banks of the Guam<i>&amp;#</i>225; River, near Bel<i>&amp;#</i>233;m, Par<i>&amp;#</i>225;, Brazil, August 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, Archive)</span></div>
<p>Leaders from Amazon countries used and heard the term repeatedly at an August meeting in Belem. The officials expressed interest for policies to protect the rainforest and provide paying work for tens of millions who live in it.</p>
<p>However, beyond general support for the idea, there was little agreement about what exactly a bioeconomy should look like. Salazar was on a team chosen by Brazil's environment ministry to speak about the subject.</p>
<p>The idea is not new. It is the latest term for sustainable development, also called the green economy.</p>
<p>Besides the Brazil nuts and acai harvesters, people are making chocolate from native cocoa. There is a sustainable fishery for one of the world's largest freshwater fish. A community of rubber gatherers is helping produce shoes.</p>
<p>"The challenge is <strong>scale</strong>," Para state Governor Helder Barbalho said. His state is believed to be the only in Brazil that has a complete bioeconomy plan. Para is Brazil's top producer of acai, yet its economy is far more dependent on iron ore exports to China. A large amount of land in Para is used by an estimated 27 million farm cows. The state emits more <strong>greenhouse gases</strong> than any Amazon country besides Brazil.</p>
<p>But when it comes to larger sustainable companies, there are few success stories. The best example has been skin product company Natura. Twenty years ago it started a product line using ingredients from traditional Amazon communities and family farms.</p>
<p>When the company started, local people were using ucuuba trees to make <strong>brooms</strong>. They greatly increased their earnings by leaving the trees standing and selling the seeds to Natura. The change helped conserve more than 2 million hectares of forest.</p>
<p>Natura bought goods from 41 communities – home to 9,120 families – who in 2022 received about $9 million.</p>
<p>Para State's plan for the bioeconomy names 43 forest products that could be exported, including acai, cocoa, cassava, pepper, fish species and essential oils for skin products.</p>
<p>And the neighboring Amazonas state is creating a bioeconomy plan with financial support from the U.S. Agency for International Development.</p>
<p>But some earlier efforts reveal problems.</p>
<p>A state <strong>condom</strong> factory in the Amazon city of Xapuri opened in 2008. It was supposed to provide a market for hundreds of rubber-gathering families. But the factory closed 10 years later, after federal funding came to an end. Locals resorted to cattle ranching and today the area ranks high for deforestation.</p>
<p>Cocoa beans have also caused problems. The trees can be a way to let forest grow back where it has been cut down. But its appeal in places like the Ivory Coast and Ghana has meant massive deforestation to make way for the trees that earn more money.</p>
<p>Salazar, head of Mazo Mana, views his company as both social-minded and good for the economy. It keeps nearly 10 percent of its money for its partner community associations.</p>
<p>Salazar thinks the sustainable companies that succeed and grow big will be those with a mission to solve the Amazon's problems. He says those companies will drive an economy that sees the value of the forest.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be used without being completely used up or destroyed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scale </strong><em>— n. </em>the size or level of something especially in comparison to something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>greenhouse gas </strong><em>— n. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>broom </strong><em>— n. </em>a brush that has a long handle and that is used for sweeping floors</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>condom </strong><em>— n. </em>a thin rubber covering that a man wears on his penis during sex in order to prevent a woman from becoming pregnant or to prevent the spread of diseases</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More Tenses in 'We Didn’t Start the Fire'  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/more-tenses-in-we-didn-t-start-the-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
In today's Everyday Grammar, we finish our discussion of Fallout Boy's remake of the song We Didn't Start the Fire, which was written and performed by Billy Joel.

The new version of the song lists historical events from 1989 to the present, but the chorus is the same as Billy Joel's 1989 version. Today, we will look at verbal tenses in that part of the song.

Lyrics and the meaning

Everyday Grammar: More Tenses in "We Didn't Start the Fire"
Everyday Grammar: More Tenses in "We Didn't Start the Fire"
We didn't start the fire

It was always burning since the world's been turning

We didn't start the fire

No, we didn't light it but we're trying to fight it

The "fire" can be understood as bad things happening in the world. The song is talking about how bad things have existed throughout history and that one generation is not responsible for all of them. Joel was saying that his generation was doing its best to help by trying to fight "the fire."

Let's move on to verbal tenses in the chorus.

Verbal tenses in the chorus

In the chorus, the simple past tense in the negative is used in the 1st person plural or "we" form.

To form the negative simple past, we use:

Subject + did + not + base verb + the rest of the sentence.

In the song, the contraction of "did not" is used, "didn't."

We didn't start the fire.

No, we didn't light it...

Next, we see the past continuous tense in the 3rd person singular form. The past continuous is used to talk about ongoing things that happened in the past.

It was always burning...

To form the past continuous, we use:

Subject + past tense form of be (was or were) + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) + the rest of the sentence

It was always burning since the world's been turning.

In the second half of that sentence, we have a clause starting with "since" in the present perfect continuous. The present perfect continuous is used to talk about things that started in the past and are continuing today.

To form the present perfect continuous, we use:

Subject + has been or have been + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) + the rest of the sentence or clause

...since the world has been turning...

The contraction form is used in the song. In everyday English "has" sometimes appears as apostrophe "s" (‘s).

...since the world's been turning...

And lastly, we see the present continuous tense used in the second half of the last line of the chorus. It is in the first person plural using "we" in a contraction with "are."

No, we didn't light it, but we're trying to fight it

The present continuous tense is used to talk about actions that are happening now, occurring often and may continue into the future.

To form the present continuous, we use:

Subject + be (am, is, are) + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) +the rest of the sentence.

In the final chorus of the song, there is a conditional statement:

But when we are gone,

It will still go on...

This is a type one or first conditional. This type of conditional is used to talk about future situations that are possible or real.

The structure of type one conditionals is:

If or when + present simple tense verb, will + infinitive verb.

The word "gone" is a past participle adjective. This sentence means that the world will continue when this generation is no more.

Final thoughts

In today's Everyday Grammar, we closely examined other verbal tenses in the chorus of the song We Didn't Start the Fire. There were the past and present continuous tenses, the present perfect continuous and the simple past tense. We even talked about first conditional statements. Next time you are listening to a song, try to see which tenses are used or if there are any conditional statements.

I'm Faith Pirlo.

Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.

_____________________________________________

Words in This Story
chorus – n. part of a song that is repeated

tense – n. grammar: a form of a verb that is used to show when an action happened

contraction – n. grammar: a shortened form of a word

conditional – n. grammar: showing or used to show that something is true or happens only if something else is true or happens

infinitive verb – n. grammar: the basic form of a verb with the word "to"</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google Launches Watermark Tool to Identify AI-created Images  (2023/8/31) | 谷歌发布数字水印工具识别人工智能生成图像</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/google-launches-watermark-tool-to-identify-ai-created-images.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Google has launched a tool designed to mark identity on images created by artificial intelligence (AI) technology.<br/>
谷歌推出了一款工具，旨在给人工智能生成的图像标记身份。</p>
<p>The American-based search engine and online advertising company announced the new tool in a statement Tuesday. Google has already made the system available to a limited number of beta testers. Google plans to expand its use in the future.<br/>
这家总部位于美国的搜索引擎和网络广告公司周二在一份声明中宣布了这一新工具。谷歌已经向数量有限的测试人员提供了该系统。谷歌计划在未来扩大其使用范围。</p>
<p>A team at Google Deep Mind developed the tool, called SynthID, in partnership with Google Research. SynthID is designed to work with Google's AI image creator Imagen. That system creates full film-quality images from simple text commands. For now, only Imagen users will be able to use the AI identifying tool.<br/>
谷歌Deep Mind的一个团队与谷歌研究院合作开发了这款名为SynthID的工具。SynthID旨在与谷歌旗下的人工智能图像生成器Imagen搭配使用。该系统可以通过简单的文本命令生成全胶片质量的图像。目前，只有Imagen用户才能使用这款人工智能识别工具。</p>
<p>SynthID works by creating a hidden, digital "watermark" on images. Watermarks have long been used with paper documents and money as a way to mark them as being real, or authentic. With this method, paper can be held up to a light to see if a watermark exists and the document is authentic.<br/>
SynthID的工作原理是在图像上创建一个隐藏的数字水印。水印长期以来一直被用于纸质文件和货币，作为将其标记为真实的一种方式。使用这种方法，可以将纸张举到灯光下，查看水印是否存在以及文档是否真实。</p>
<p>A digital watermark serves the same purpose. But it uses technology to digitally embed hidden markers in images. These watermarks are hard to see by just looking at an image. Instead, special tools are needed to identify the watermark.<br/>
数字水印也有同样的作用。但它是使用技术在图像中数字化嵌入隐藏的标记。肉眼很难看到这些水印。相反，识别这种水印需要特殊的工具。</p>
<p>Google says the digital watermark is designed to help individuals and companies identify whether an image has been created by AI tools or not. This could help people recognize inauthentic pictures published online and also protect copyright-protected images.<br/>
谷歌表示，数字水印旨在帮助个人和公司识别图像是否由人工智能工具生成。这可以帮助人们识别网上发布的不真实图片，也可以保护受版权保护的图片。</p>
<p>Technology experts have identified these issues as two of the biggest problems with AI creation tools – they can increase the amount of misinformation online and they can violate copyrights.<br/>
技术专家认为这是人工智能创作工具的两个最大问题——它们可能会增加网上错误信息的数量，也可能侵犯版权。</p>
<p>Last month, Google's parent Alphabet joined other major technology companies in agreeing to establish watermark tools to help make AI technology safer.<br/>
上个月，谷歌母公司Alphabet与其他大型科技公司一道，同意创建水印工具，以帮助提高人工智能技术的安全性。</p>
<p>The companies – including Facebook parent Meta, Microsoft-backed AI developer OpenAI and online seller Amazon – made the agreement during a meeting with U.S. President Joe Biden at the White House. They promised to fully develop and test watermarking tools for content including text, audio and video.<br/>
包括脸书母公司Meta、微软支持的人工智能开发商OpenAI以及网上卖家亚马逊在内的这些公司在白宫与美国总统乔·拜登会面时达成了协议。他们承诺将全面开发和测试文本、音频和视频等内容的水印工具。</p>
<p>Google said its system embeds a digital watermark directly into the details of an image. The tool can be used for "connecting people with high-quality information and upholding trust between creators and users across society."<br/>
谷歌表示，其系统将数字水印直接嵌入图像的细节中。该工具可用于“将人们与高质量的信息联系起来，维护全社会创作者和用户之间的信任”。</p>
<p>Developers of the SynthID system said it is built to keep the watermark in place even if the image itself is changed by creative tools designed to resize pictures or add additional light or color.<br/>
SynthID系统的开发人员表示，即使图像本身被设计用于调整图片大小或添加额外光线或颜色的创造性工具更改，它也能保持水印不消失。</p>
<p>The tool can add a hidden watermark to AI-produced images created by Imagen. SynthID can also examine an image to find a digital watermark that was embedded with the Imagen system.<br/>
该工具可以为Imagen生成的人工智能图像添加隐藏水印。SynthID还可以检查图像，找出Imagen系统所嵌入的数字水印。</p>
<p>Google says it will continue to test the watermarking tool and hopes to collect many user experiences from the current beta testers. And the company looks forward to adding the system to other Google products and making it available to more individuals and organizations.<br/>
谷歌表示，它将继续测试这款水印工具，并希望从目前的测试人员那里收集到许多用户体验。该公司期待着将该系统添加到谷歌的其他产品中，并将其提供给更多的个人和组织。</p>
<p>In addition to SynthID, Google also announced Tuesday the launch of additional AI tools designed for businesses and structural improvements to its computing systems. Those systems are used to produce AI tools, also known as large language models.<br/>
除了SynthID，谷歌周二还宣布推出更多为企业设计的人工智能工具，并对其计算系统进行结构改进。这些系统用于生成也称为大型语言模型的人工智能工具。</p>
<p>Google made public a new version of its self-designed AI computing chips. The company says the new chip, called TPU v5e, was built to train large computer models, but also more effectively serve those models. Google also released new versions of software and security tools designed to work with AI systems.<br/>
谷歌公开了其自行设计的新版人工智能计算芯片。该公司表示，这款名为TPU v5e的新芯片旨在训练大型计算机模型，但也能更有效地为这些模型服务。谷歌还发布了新版本的软件和安全工具，旨在与人工智能系统配合使用。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Change Has Sweden Growing its Wine Industry  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/climate-change-has-sweden-growing-its-wine-industry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Most people would not connect the country of Sweden with the tradition of fine <strong>wine</strong> making. It is far north of the famous wine-growing areas in France, Italy or Spain, where the tradition is ancient.</p>
<p>However, climate change is making for warmer and longer growing seasons in Sweden. There are also new kinds of <strong>grapes</strong> created especially for the country's environment.</p>
<p>As a result, winemaking is a growing industry.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A tractor works at Kullabergs Ving&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;229;rd, in Nyhamnsl&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;228;ge, Sweden, Tuesday, July 25, 2023.
(AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b06ed163-14a3-4d18-a875-832a0cdc2d3d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A tractor works at Kullabergs Ving<i>&amp;#</i>229;rd, in Nyhamnsl<i>&amp;#</i>228;ge, Sweden, Tuesday, July 25, 2023.
(AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin)</span></div>
<p>Its growth comes as drought, rising heat and other extreme weather are forcing traditional winemaking areas to re-think their growing methods.</p>
<p>The Swedish Meteorological and Hydrological Institute reports temperatures in the country's south have increased by about 2 degrees Celsius over the past 30 years compared to the 30 years earlier. The experts also say Sweden's growing season has lengthened by about 20 days.</p>
<p>Felix <i></i>197;hrberg is the chief oenologist, or expert winemaker, at the 14-hectare Kullabergs Vingard, near the North Sea.</p>
<p>He noted that the rising temperatures are hurting vineyards in traditional winemaking countries. At the same time, "we are gaining <strong>momentum</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Kullabergs produces about 30,000 bottles of wine yearly. Some of their wines have won prizes in different competitions. Costly restaurants from Hong Kong to Europe sell the wine.</p>
<p>Even some oenologists from France are settling in Sweden to grow grapes and careers.</p>
<p>"It is the new <strong>frontier</strong> of wine making and grapes grow best on their coolest frontier," <i></i>197;hrberg said.</p>
<p>Emma Berto is one such winemaker from France who now works at Thora Vingard, about 20 kilometers from <i></i>197;hrberg's land.</p>
<p>She and her partner, Romain Chichery, moved to Sweden for the chance to lead a vineyard just after completing their education. They say Sweden's climate is more predictable than France's. There, the early spring weather can be too warm and the grapes begin to develop before they should.</p>
<p>In addition, Berto and Chichery said they want to use more <strong>sustainable</strong> grape-growing methods, including limits on insect poisoning.</p>
<p>Chichery said France has been making wine for so long, there are many rules winemakers must follow. In Sweden, it is a newer business so there is more freedom.</p>
<p>However, there is still a lot to learn about growing grapes in Sweden. The main grape grown in the country is Solaris, which began in Germany, and grows well in Northern Europe.</p>
<p>The winemakers treat the vines differently, too. In Sweden, the leaves are removed from the vines so the grapes can receive more sunlight. In France and Spain, sometimes winemakers are worried the grapes will get too much.</p>
<p>The Thora owners who hired the French winemakers are Johan and Heather Oberg. They depend on wine experts from the traditional winemaking countries because Swedish universities do not have study programs in the science and <strong>practice</strong> of winemaking.</p>
<p>Maarten van Aalst is a climate professor at the University of Twente in the Netherlands. He said businesses are often first to identify and react<strong> </strong>to climate change. He said it is good that "climate change is partly something we can <strong>adapt</strong> to."</p>
<p>But, he warned, it is not all good weather in Sweden. He pointed to recent heavy rains that caused flooding, resulting in $150 million in damage. He said bad weather is becoming more common because of human-caused climate change.</p>
<p>In Sweden, vineyards account for about 150 hectares of land. The number is one million in Spain and about 800,000 in France.</p>
<p>Swedish winemakers hope that as the industry grows, the government will make rules that help them expand their businesses. For example, right now in Sweden, wine makers cannot sell their own wine. People who want a bottle must purchase from a government-run store.</p>
<p>Mikael Molstad writes about wine. He said the Swedish government is not in favor of making it easier to buy alcohol.</p>
<p>"Politicians," he said, "still see alcohol as a social problem."</p>
<p>Goran Amneg<i></i>229;rd is a prize-winning winemaker who started 20 years ago. He is pleased to see more wineries opening in Sweden.</p>
<p>He thinks more people will come to take advantage of the warmer temperatures and longer growing time.</p>
<p>"I can see things growing here that were unthinkable 30 or 40 years ago," Amneg<i></i>229;rd said as he looked out over his small vineyard.</p>
<p>"We're seeing fruit trees like peaches and apricots. I'm getting beautiful peaches in August."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>wine</strong> <em>–n. </em>an alcoholic beverage made from fermented grapes<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>grape</strong> <em>–n. </em>a fruit that grows on a vine that is used to make wine or juice<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>momentum</strong> <em>–n. </em>forward movement or progress toward a goal<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>frontier</strong> <em>–n. </em>an unexplored area, or a place far away from a developed part of the world<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>sustainable</strong> <em>–n. </em>something that can be done often and in a repeatable way<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>practice</strong> <em>–n. </em>the way of doing something</p>
<p><strong>adapt</strong> <em>–v. </em>to change and adjust to outside forces or pressure<em> </em></p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you interested in trying wine from Sweden?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gabon Military Seizes Power In Oil-rich Country  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/gabon-military-seizes-power-in-oil-rich-country.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Military officers in oil-producing Gabon said they had seized power on Wednesday and had put President Ali Bongo under house arrest. The military seized control minutes after the Central African state's election body announced he had won a third term.</p>
<p>The officers said they represented the armed forces. They said on television that the election results were canceled. They also said the borders were closed and state <strong>institutions</strong> had broken up. The military takeover took place after a vote that was set to extend the Bongo family's 50-plus years in power.</p>
<p>The Gabon officers call themselves The Committee of Transition and the Restoration of Institutions. They said the country faced "a severe institutional, political, economic, and social crisis." They said the August 26 vote was not <strong>credible</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This video grab shows soldiers speaking on state television as they announce that they had seized power in Libreville, Wednesday Aug. 30, 2023. (GABON 24 via AP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8123-08dba968095b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This video grab shows soldiers speaking on state television as they announce that they had seized power in Libreville, Wednesday Aug. 30, 2023. (GABON 24 via AP)
</span></div>
<p>One of the officers is Brice Oligui Nguema. In a video he appeared to be the military's leader. He told French newspaper <em>Le Monde</em> that he and other generals would meet on Wednesday to select someone to head the <strong>transitional</strong> government.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people celebrated the military's intervention on the streets of Libreville, the Gabonese capital.</p>
<p>The officers said they had detained Bongo, who took over in 2009. Before that, his father Omar, had ruled Gabon since 1967. The officer also said they had arrested the president's son and others for corruption and treason.</p>
<p>Opponents say the family has done little to share the state's oil and mining wealth with its 2.3 million people. Violent unrest broke out after Bongo's disputed 2016 election win. There was a failed <strong>coup</strong> attempt in 2019.</p>
<p>The 64-year-old Bongo was last seen in public voting on Saturday.</p>
<p><strong>French Condemnation</strong></p>
<p>France, Gabon's former colonial ruler, condemned the takeover. France has troops in the country.</p>
<p>"We condemn the military coup and recall our commitment to free and <strong>transparent</strong> elections," French government spokesman Olivier Veran said.</p>
<p>The coup creates more uncertainty for France's presence in the area. France has about 350 troops in Gabon. Its forces have been kicked out of Mali and Burkina Faso after coups there in the last two years.</p>
<p>The African Union's Peace and Security Council chair called for a meeting on the situation with Burundi, Senegal and Cameroon. China called for a peaceful resolution and Russia said it hoped for a quick return to <strong>stability</strong>.</p>
<p>Rukmini Sanya is an expert at the Economist Intelligence Unit. He said, "Mr. Bongo is not expected to be able to suppress the uprising." He said there was "widespread public discontent" against Bongo, his family and his ruling party.</p>
<p>Gabon produces about 200,000 barrels of oil a day. International companies include France's TotalEnergies and Anglo-French producer Perenco. French miner Eramet said it had halted operations in Gabon.</p>
<p>There were concerns about <strong>transparency</strong> regarding Saturday's vote. During the election, there was a lack of international observers and some foreign broadcasts were suspended. The government also cut internet service and put in place a nighttime curfew. On Wednesday, internet access appeared to be in place for the first time since the election.</p>
<p>Shortly before the coup, the election body had declared Bongo the election winner with 64.3 percent of the vote. His main opponent, Albert Ondo Ossa, received 30.8 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>institution </strong><em>— n. </em> an established organization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transition </strong><em>— n. </em>a change from one state or condition to another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>credible </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be believed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coup </strong><em>— adj. </em> a sudden attempt by a small group of people to take over the government usually through violence</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transparent </strong><em>— adj. </em>honest and open</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stability </strong><em>— n. </em>the quality or state of something that is not easily changed or likely to change</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hurricane Idalia Hits Florida with High Winds, Flooding  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/hurricane-idalia-hits-florida-with-high-winds-flooding.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hurricane Idalia made <strong>landfall</strong> on the west coast of the American state of Florida on Wednesday. Officials said the dangerous storm brought life-threatening <strong>storm surges</strong> and flooding to the area.</p>
<p>By early Wednesday morning, more than 200,000 people reportedly were without electricity as strong winds brought down trees and power lines. Along the coast, some homes were underwater, and structures were crushed in the storm surge.</p>
<p>"We have multiple trees down, <strong>debris</strong> in the roads, do not come," emergency officials in Cedar Key said. They said most of the streets around the downtown area were underwater.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Members of the Tampa Fire Rescue Dept., remove a street pole brought down during Hurricane Idalia Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023, in Tampa, Florida. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b673-08dba97f9a2f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Members of the Tampa Fire Rescue Dept., remove a street pole brought down during Hurricane Idalia Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023, in Tampa, Florida. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara)</span></div>
<p>Idalia landed in a lightly populated area near Keaton Beach at 11:45 UTC. The Category 3 hurricane came with <strong>sustained</strong> wind speeds as high as 205 kilometers per hour. The National Weather Service places hurricanes into five groups depending on wind speed. The strongest level, a Category 5 hurricane, can reach sustained wind speeds of 252 kilometers an hour or higher.</p>
<p>People who live along Florida's northwest coast had been ordered to leave the area before Idalia's arrival. On Wednesday morning, Governor Ron DeSantis told those who have not left to stay inside until the storm passes. He said, "Don't put your life at risk."</p>
<p><strong>A full moon could raise tides higher</strong></p>
<p>As the hurricane continues, a rare full moon, called a supermoon, could cause <strong>tides</strong> to rise higher than normal along Florida's coast.</p>
<p>When the moon is full, the sun and the moon are pulling in the same direction. This has the effect of increasing tides above normal, said Kerry Emanuel. He is an atmospheric scientist at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</p>
<p>The moon's gravitational pull is stronger when it is closer to the Earth, so the tides could be higher. Wednesday's supermoon is the closest to the Earth this year.</p>
<p>Brian Haines is head of the National Weather Service office in Charleston, South Carolina. He said, "I would say the timing is pretty bad for this one."</p>
<p>The storm surge is often the most dangerous event when a hurricane strikes. The National Hurricane Center estimated on Tuesday that ocean water levels could increase by 4.6 meters along parts of Florida's west coast. Farther south, a storm surge of up to 2.1 meters is expected in the Tampa Bay area.</p>
<p>Hurricanes get their energy from warm water. Idalia is feeding from warm water around Florida.</p>
<p>Colorado State University hurricane researcher Phil Klotzbach called the water temperature of 31-32 degrees "rocket fuel for the storm." He added, "It's basically all systems go for the storm to intensify."</p>
<p>The National Weather Service in Tallahassee called Idalia "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> event" since no major hurricanes on record have ever passed through the area around Big Bend. The state of Florida, however, is still dealing with damage from Ian, a Category 5 hurricane, last year. Ian was responsible for almost 150 deaths and damaged 52,000 structures.</p>
<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration recently said the 2023 hurricane season would be far more active because of extremely warm ocean temperatures. The season runs through November, with most storms taking place in August and September.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>landfall</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>the act of reaching land after a long trip at sea</p>
<p><strong>storm surge</strong> <em>–n.</em> an event in which high winds force water from the sea onto the land</p>
<p><strong>debris </strong><em>–n.</em> wreckage and broken pieces of things</p>
<p><strong>sustained </strong><em>–adj.</em> continuing for a period of time</p>
<p><strong>tide </strong><em>–n.</em> the regular upward and downward movement of sea levels in places caused by the moon and other influences</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>–adj.</em> describing something that has never happened before</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Air Pollution Now Considered Major Risk to Life Expectancy in South Asia  (2023/8/30) | 南亚空气污染被视为预期寿命的重大风险</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/air-pollution-now-considered-major-risk-to-life-expectancy-in-south-asia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A new environmental report says rising air pollution across South Asia can cut life expectancy rates by up to five years.<br/>
一份新的环境报告称，南亚各地日益严重的空气污染可能会使预期寿命缩短五年。</p>
<p>South Asia includes the world's most polluted countries, including India, Bangladesh, Nepal and Pakistan. The area accounts for more than half of the total lives lost worldwide to pollution, the Energy Policy Institute said in its latest Air Quality Life Index. The institute is part of the University of Chicago.<br/>
南亚囊括了全球污染最严重的国家：印度、孟加拉国、尼泊尔和巴基斯坦。美国能源政策研究所在最新的空气质量生命指数中表示，该地区占全球因污染致死总人数的一半以上。该研究所隶属于芝加哥大学。</p>
<p>The report blames the air pollution dangers on fast industrialization and population growth across South Asia. Researchers estimate the area currently has particle pollution rates that are 50 percent higher than at the start of the century.<br/>
该报告将这种空气污染威胁归咎于南亚的快速工业化和人口增长。研究人员估计，该地区目前的颗粒物污染率比本世纪初高出50%。</p>
<p>Individuals living in Bangladesh, the world's most polluted country, stand to lose 6.8 years of life on average per person, the report found. This compares to 3.6 months in the United States. The information is based on satellite data used to estimate the effects of increased airborne fine particles on life expectancy.<br/>
报告发现，生活在孟加拉国这个全球污染最严重国家的个人平均每人将减寿6.8年。相比之下，美国为3.6个月。这些信息是基于用于估算空气中细颗粒物增加对预期寿命影响的卫星数据。</p>
<p>The report said India has been responsible for about 59 percent of the world's increase in pollution since 2013. In densely populated New Delhi, the world's most polluted large city, the average life expectancy had dropped by more than 10 years.<br/>
报告称，自2013年以来，印度占到了全球污染增长的59%左右。人口稠密的新德里作为全球污染最严重的大城市，平均预期寿命下降了10年以上。</p>
<p>The report called for cuts in worldwide levels of lung-harming airborne particles to levels sought by the World Health Organization (WHO). If these cuts were reached, it could raise average life expectancy rates by 2.3 years.<br/>
该报告呼吁将全球危害肺部的空气颗粒物水平降至世界卫生组织要求的水平。如果实现这些削减，平均预期寿命可能会提高2.3年。</p>
<p>A person living in Pakistan would gain 3.9 years from meeting WHO pollution guidelines, the report added. And in Nepal, a person would live 4.6 years longer if the guidelines were met.<br/>
报告补充道，如果达到世卫组织污染指导方针的标准，巴基斯坦人民的寿命将因此延长3.9年。如果尼泊尔符合该指导方针，个人寿命将延长4.6年。</p>
<p>The report noted that China has worked to reduce pollution by 42.3 percent between 2013 and 2021. The researchers said this shows the need for governments to produce and share air quality data to help reduce inequalities in getting tools to fight pollution.<br/>
报告指出，中国在2013年至2021年间努力将污染降低了42.3%。研究人员表示，这表明政府有必要编制和发布空气质量数据，以帮助减少在获得对抗污染工具方面的不平等。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Lack of Ice Threatens Young Penguins  (2023/8/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-lack-of-ice-threatens-young-penguins.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers, using information gathered by satellites, say the loss of ice in Antarctica hurts the survival chances of rare seabirds.</p>
<p>The large flightless birds are called emperor penguins. They raise their young in groups, or colonies, on ice that forms around the continent. The ice partly melts during the summer months.</p>
<p>The British and French researchers studied satellite images to look at five breeding colonies of the birds in the area of the Bellingshausen Sea in 2022.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Emperor penguin chicks in Antarctica on Dec. 21, 2005. The loss of ice in Antarctica likely resulted in none of the emperor penguin chicks surviving in four colonies in that area. (Zhang Zongtang/Xinhua via AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/923936d3-6bf1-44c0-bf7a-b93cf3c469e8_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Emperor penguin chicks in Antarctica on Dec. 21, 2005. The loss of ice in Antarctica likely resulted in none of the emperor penguin chicks surviving in four colonies in that area. (Zhang Zongtang/Xinhua via AP, File)</span></div>
<p>They said the images showed no sea ice was left in December during the Southern Hemisphere's summer. This also happened in 2021, the researchers noted.</p>
<p>The scientists said four of the five colonies they studied had been affected by early sea ice loss.</p>
<p>Emperor penguin <strong>chicks </strong>are born on the ice in Antarctica that forms during the winter there. The ice is important because penguin chicks do not develop waterproof feathers for one to two months after they are born.</p>
<p>Peter Fretwell is a researcher with the British Antarctic Survey who helped write the study. He said, "If the sea ice breaks up under them, the young chicks will drown."</p>
<p>The scientists published their research in the<strong> journal </strong><em>Communications Earth &amp; Environmen</em>t.</p>
<p>Fretwell's team also started a study of places where the penguins make their nests across Antarctica. They were able to identify the nesting places in satellite images because the birds' waste is darker than the surrounding snow. The scientists estimate that there are 300,000 <strong>breeding pairs </strong>of emperor penguins in Antarctica. The birds are the world's largest penguin.</p>
<p>Fretwell told the Associated Press that 30 percent of the 62 known penguin colonies were hurt by low levels of sea ice. He said 13 colonies likely failed.</p>
<p>Daniel Zitterbart studies Antarctica at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in the state of Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study. But Zitterbart said he was not surprised by the results of the penguin study.</p>
<p>He said that, if penguins are not successful breeding in one place, they might look for another place next year. The population could recover.</p>
<p>But Zitterbart noted, "If you look further out <strong>down the line</strong>, how many <strong>suitable</strong> places will be left?"</p>
<p>I'm Dr. Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>chick</strong> <em>–n.</em> a baby bird</p>
<p><strong>journal</strong> <em>–v.</em> a publication that reports on special interest subjects, especially ones linked to university learning</p>
<p><strong>breeding pair<em> </em></strong><em>–n.</em> two animals that are ready to reproduce and raise young</p>
<p><strong>down the line</strong> <em>–idiom</em> at a later time</p>
<p><strong>suitable </strong><em>–adj.</em> having the qualities that are needed or required</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
