<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Australians Claim to Create Most Complete Map of Universe’s History  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/australians-claim-to-create-most-complete-map-of-universe-s-history.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Australian researchers say they have produced the most complete history of the universe to date. An Australian National University team says the study offers new ideas about how the universe might have started.</p>
<p>The research team says the study's aim was to understand the beginnings of all the objects in the universe.</p>
<p>The American space agency, NASA, says the universe "includes all of space, and all the matter and energy that space contains. It even includes time itself and, of course, it includes you."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A picture taken in Fontainebleau, southern Paris on August 13, 2023 shows shooting stars streaking across the Milky Way during the Nuits des &lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;233;toiles (Starry Night), a major annual celebration for astronomy enthusiasts. (Photo by Miguel MEDINA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5d8f-08db9ceb5d34_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A picture taken in Fontainebleau, southern Paris on August 13, 2023 shows shooting stars streaking across the Milky Way during the "Nuits des <i>&amp;#</i>233;toiles" (Starry Night), a major annual celebration for astronomy enthusiasts. (Photo by Miguel MEDINA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>NASA adds that "the Milky Way is but one of billions of <strong>galaxies</strong> in the observable universe -- all of them, including our own, are thought to have supermassive black holes at their centers."</p>
<p>A black hole is an area in space with gravity so strong that even light cannot escape it.</p>
<p>The Australian team says it has created the most complete <strong>maps</strong> showing the history of the universe.</p>
<p>The lead writer is honorary professor Charley Lineweaver. He said that when the universe began 13.8 billion years ago in a hot big bang, there were no objects, such as atoms, people, planets, stars, or galaxies.</p>
<p>The writers say the mapping provides new ideas about how the universe came into being.</p>
<p>The Australian National University (ANU) study is published in the most recent publication of <em>The American Journal of Physics. </em></p>
<p>The first map shows temperature and density of the universe as it expanded and cooled. The second map shows the mass and size of all objects in the universe.</p>
<p>The ANU researchers say the study suggests the universe may have started as what is known as an instanton not a singularity. An instanton has a defined size and mass. A singularity is defined as a point of <strong>infinite</strong> density and temperature.</p>
<p>Put simply, this would mean that the beginning of the universe was not infinite in size. That is important because researchers say that what lies beyond the limits of the universe is "also a major mystery."</p>
<p>Lineweaver told VOA that mapping the universe will increase our understanding of it.</p>
<p>"When you <strong>extrapolate</strong> in so many different ways it gives you just a lay of the land that I just think is a beautiful way of understanding the universe," he said. "If there is one way to understand the Big Bang, it started out hot and dense and it got cooler and less dense, and as it did that, particles and objects of all kinds <strong>condensed</strong> out of this hot, dense background."</p>
<p>He said that understanding that is something that we should all make an attempt to do because that is probably the most important understanding underlying the history of the universe.</p>
<p>Lineweaver says he believes that research into the beginning of the universe could help to answer some basic scientific questions about life beyond Earth.</p>
<p>"The basic idea is, well, if we can figure out how we got here, maybe we can make better guesses about whether other life forms have <strong>evolved</strong> elsewhere."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Phil Mercer reported this story for Voice of America. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>galaxy </strong>– <em>n</em>. any one of the very large groups of stars that make up the universe</p>
<p><strong>bang </strong><em>– n.</em> an implosion or explosion</p>
<p><strong>infinite </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having no limits</p>
<p><strong>extrapolate </strong><em>– v.</em> to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts</p>
<p><strong>condense </strong><em>– v.</em> to change from a gas into a liquid</p>
<p><strong>evolve</strong> <em>– v. </em>to develop from something else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New York Mayor Makes Robocalls in Different Languages Using AI  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/new-york-mayor-makes-robocalls-in-different-languages-using-ai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>New York Mayor Eric Adams has been using artificial intelligence (AI) to make robot phone calls in several languages.</p>
<p>The technology changes Adam's voice into languages that he does not speak. And it raises new ethical questions about the government's use of AI.</p>
<p>Adams told reporters about the phone calls, called robocalls, recently. He said they have gone out in languages like Mandarin and Yiddish for city events. They have not included any information that he only speaks English or that the calls were created using AI.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - New York City Mayor Eric Adams speaks in New York's Times Square during a news conference, Dec. 30, 2022. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fdee-08dbd0afeb39_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - New York City Mayor Eric Adams speaks in New York's Times Square during a news conference, Dec. 30, 2022. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey, File)</span></div>
<p>"People stop me on the street all the time and say, ‘I didn't know you speak Mandarin,'" Adams said. "The robocalls that we're using, we're using different languages to speak directly to the <strong>diversity</strong> of New Yorkers."</p>
<p>The calls come as questions arise over how best to use AI ethically and legally. <strong>Deepfake</strong> videos or audio can make it appear that anyone anywhere is doing anything a person on the other side of a computer screen wants them to do.</p>
<p>The Surveillance Technology Oversight Project called Adams' robocalls an unethical use of AI that is misleading to the people of New York.</p>
<p>Albert Fox Cahn is executive director of the organization. He said the calls are very unethical, especially because they are paid for with public money. "Yes, we need announcements in all of New Yorkers' native languages, but the deepfakes are just a <strong>creepy</strong> <strong>vanity</strong> project."</p>
<p>There is a growing use of artificial intelligence and deepfakes, especially in politics and election misinformation. It has led to calls for more rules and policing from the government and major media companies.</p>
<p>Google was the first big technology company to say it would identify political advertisements that use AI to fake a candidate's voice or actions. Meta does not have a rule specific to the use of AI in political ads. But the company has a policy restricting fake or <strong>manipulated</strong> audio and imagery used for misinformation.</p>
<p>A bipartisan bill in the U.S. Senate would ban "materially <strong>deceptive</strong>" deepfakes relating to federal candidates, with exceptions for <strong>parody</strong>. This month, two Democratic members of Congress sent a letter to the heads of Meta and X, formerly known as Twitter. The letter shared concerns about AI-created political ads on social media platforms.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, a number of technology companies have shown off AI tools that can take a person's speech and make it sound as if that person is speaking a different language.</p>
<p>In September, the music streaming service Spotify introduced an AI feature to translate a recording, or podcast, into several languages in the speaker's voice. More recently, the startup ElevenLabs in October introduced a voice translation tool. The tool can change spoken words to another language while keeping the voice of the speaker.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Adams' office said they used the ElevenLabs tool for their robocalls. Native speakers listened to the recordings before they went out to make sure the translations were accurate. Calls have been made in Spanish, Yiddish, Mandarin, Cantonese and Haitian Creole.</p>
<p>Adams defended himself against ethical questions about his use of artificial intelligence, saying his office is trying to reach New Yorkers through the languages they speak.</p>
<p>"I got one thing: I've got to run the city, and I have to be able to speak to people in the languages that they understand, and I'm happy to do so," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mayor </strong><em>— n. </em>an official who is elected to be the head of the government of a city or town</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diversity </strong><em>— n. </em> the quality or state of having many different forms, types, ideas, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>deepfake </strong><em>— n. </em>a real-looking, but untrue, video.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>creepy </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing people to feel nervous and afraid</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vanity </strong><em>— n. </em>the quality of people who have too much pride in their own appearance, abilities, achievements, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>manipulate </strong><em>— v. </em>to move or control with your hands or by using a machine</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>deceptive </strong><em>— adj. </em>intended to make someone believe something that is not true</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>parody </strong><em>— n. </em>a piece of writing, music, etc., that imitates the style of someone or something else in an amusing way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'When' with Past Tense  (2023/10/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/when-with-past-tense.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about using "when" with past simple or past continuous tenses.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3e4a-08dbd0147fdb_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Hi,</p>
<p>I'm a learner from China. Could you please help me with the following question?</p>
<p>Is the sentence <em>The good news came when we weren't expecting it </em>grammatically correct?</p>
<p>If it is correct, how can we understand the following rule:</p>
<p>"As a general rule, you should use "while" in a clause with a continuous action, using a verb in a continuous tense. Use "when" in a clause with a single action, using a simple past or present tense."</p>
<p>Many thanks,</p>
<p>Jinye</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Jinye. Keep up the good work learning English with us!</p>
<p>The sentence "The good news came when we weren't expecting it" is grammatically acceptable.</p>
<p><strong>When and while </strong></p>
<p>As for "when" and "while" we answered a question about <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/how-to-use-when-and-while-/5888101.html" target="_blank">How to Use ‘When' and ‘While'</a> in an earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em> program.</p>
<p>We explained that some experts call both words "subordinating conjunctions" in some cases. This means they signal how pieces of information are related to one another. And we shared that general rule to give an idea of how they are used in English.</p>
<p>Let's look at these two examples:</p>
<p><em>When the phone rang, I was making dinner.</em></p>
<p><em>While I was making dinner, the phone rang.</em></p>
<p>"While" and "when" both relate to time although "while" usually signals that two events are happening at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>Using English in real life</strong></p>
<p>Another issue to consider is how people use language in real life. Sometimes, the real-life use of language does not seem to equal textbook rules.</p>
<p>For example, many native users of English use "when" with continuous action. In fact, "when" is used with past progressive more often than "while" in the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/use-a-language-corpus-to-improve-your-vocabulary/7189316.html" target="_blank">Corpus of Contemporary American English</a>. Here are some example sentences from the corpus.</p>
<p><em>When I was growing up, I wanted to be a cowboy.</em></p>
<p><em>I was thinking about her when we were talking.</em></p>
<p><em>When he was running for President, Obama gave electrifying speeches.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Jinye.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Try Listening to Learn about Wildlife  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-try-listening-to-learn-about-wildlife.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A team of scientists is studying the sound of the forest in Ecuador to learn how artificial intelligence (AI) could follow animal life in recovering environments.</p>
<p>When scientists want to measure new forest growth, they can study large areas of land with tools like satellites and <strong>lidar</strong>.</p>
<p>But understanding how fast and in what amount wildlife is returning to an area is more difficult. Sometimes it requires an expert to listen through sound recordings and pick out animal calls.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - View of the forest in Combu Island on the banks of the Guama River, near the city of Belem, Para state, Brazil, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5ef1-08dba4b4c311_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - View of the forest in Combu Island on the banks of the Guama River, near the city of Belem, Para state, Brazil, Aug. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)</span></div>
<p>Jorg Muller is a field expert on birds at the University of Wurzburg Biocenter in Germany. He wondered if there was a different way.</p>
<p>Muller told the French news agency AFP: "I saw the <strong>gap</strong> that we need, particularly in the tropics, better methods to <strong>quantify</strong> the huge <strong>diversity</strong>... to improve <strong>conservation</strong> actions."</p>
<p>So, he turned to bioacoustics, which uses sound to learn more about animal life and the environments in which they live.</p>
<p>The tool has been used by scientists for some time. But more recently, researchers are using it with computer learning to study large amounts of data more quickly.</p>
<p>Muller and his team recorded wildlife sounds at sites in Ecuador's Choco area. The environments they recorded included areas that were once used for agriculture and raising livestock to old-growth forests.</p>
<p>They first had experts listen to the recordings and index the sounds of different animals. Then, they examine the sound quality to measure the environment.</p>
<p>Finally, they ran two weeks of recordings through an AI computer program trained to understand 75 different bird calls.</p>
<p><strong>More recordings needed</strong></p>
<p>The program was able to pick out the calls on which it was trained. However, scientists wondered if the program could correctly identify the number of different kinds of plants and animals in each environment.</p>
<p>To see if the program could do that, the team used two different controls. One was from the experts who listened to the audio recordings, and the second was based on examples from each environment, which can be used to understand<strong> </strong>biodiversity.</p>
<p>Since the amount of available sounds used to train is limited, the AI program could only identify one-fourth of the bird calls that experts could. But it was still able to correctly measure biodiversity levels in each environment, the study said.</p>
<p>The research was published recently in <em>Nature Communications</em>. The study said the scientists' results show that the AI program is a powerful tool to measure the recovery of animal communities in <strong>tropical</strong> forests.</p>
<p>The research noted that biodiversity found from recordings can be quantified in a cost-effective and complete way. And it said that it can measure environments, "... from active agriculture to recovering and old-growth forests."</p>
<p>There are still areas for improvement, including the lack of animal sounds on which to train AI models. And the method can only capture animals that use sound to communicate.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Agence France-Presse reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lidar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a remote sensing method that uses light in the form of a pulsed laser to measure ranges (variable distances) to the Earth</p>
<p><strong>gap </strong>– <em>n</em>. a missing part</p>
<p><strong>quantify </strong>– <em>v</em>. to find or calculate the quantity or amount of (something)</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong>– <em>n</em>. the quality or state of having many different forms, types, or ideas</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong>– <em>n</em>. the protection of animals, plants, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>tropics </strong>– <em>n</em>. the part of the world that is near the equator where the weather is very warm</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Water Levels Low in North Brazil, Near Amazon River  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/water-levels-low-in-north-brazil-near-amazon-river.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>People, animals and fish who depend on the waterways connected to the Amazon River close to the Brazilian city of Manaus are facing a long period of dry weather.</p>
<p>The city's port is an important economic area for northern Brazil. But recently, the water level of the area where the Amazon and Rio Negro rivers meet reached a very low level.</p>
<p>The civil defense agency in Amazonas state said the drought is hurting over 400,000 people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="View of a stranded ferry boat at the Marina do Davi, a docking area of the Negro river, city of Manaus, Amazonas State, northern Brazil, on October 16, 2023. (Photo by MICHAEL DANTAS / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6dd3975d-c5bd-4886-9a92-a533a1227a23_cx5_cy10_cw91_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">View of a stranded ferry boat at the Marina do Davi, a docking area of the Negro river, city of Manaus, Amazonas State, northern Brazil, on October 16, 2023. (Photo by MICHAEL DANTAS / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Those who have floating homes or use boats to move around on the river for work cannot travel. They cannot get fuel, food or fresh water.</p>
<p>Animals and fish along the river are dying. Thousands of dead fish float on the water's surface. A number of river dolphins died when they washed up on land. Dolphins are rare water mammals that live in Brazil's biggest rivers.</p>
<p>The organization that runs the port said the water level is only about 14 meters, the lowest since measurements started in 1902.</p>
<p>The <strong>previous</strong> all-time low came in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Without water, ‘there is no life'</strong></p>
<p>Brazil's <strong>monitoring</strong> and disaster alert center, Cemaden, said the rainfall in the Amazon area is the lowest it has been since July to September 1980.</p>
<p>The nation's science ministry said the weather pattern known as El Ni<i></i>241;o is to blame for the <strong>drought</strong> and low rainfall.</p>
<p>Reporters in the area are describing the situation as "<strong>grim</strong>."</p>
<p>Raimundo Silva do Carmo is a fisherman. But he cannot fish at this time. It takes him much of the day just to get water. One recent morning he was making his fourth visit of the day to a well east of Manaus.</p>
<p>He called carrying a water container back and forth "dreadful work" made harder because of the hot sun. "Without water," he said, "there is no life."</p>
<p>Another man, Joaquim Mendes da Silva is 73. For 43 years, he repaired ships on a large lake. The water is the lowest he has ever seen.</p>
<p>Children in the area stopped going to school one month ago because they could no longer travel by boat to the schoolhouse.</p>
<p>Along with Amazonas state, Cemaden said seven other states recorded their lowest rainfall in 40 years for the period from July to September.</p>
<p>The drought is hurting all of the waterways that connect to the Amazon River, an area that contains 20 percent of the world's fresh water. By last week, 42 of the 62 cities and towns in the area declared a state of emergency.</p>
<p>In one area, about 600 kilometers east of the lake, about 300 families are having trouble getting food and supplies in the Auati-Paraná reserve. They can only use small boats to get to the closest city. As a result, their travel time is 14 hours instead of the usual nine.</p>
<p>Along the river, people fish for a large fish called a pirarucu. The fish weigh as much as 200 kilograms. People catch the fish and then take them to local markets. They usually bring their catch to market by boat. But they can no longer sell the fish because they cannot reach the market.</p>
<p>Edvaldo de Lira is a local business leader. He said the fishermen "run the risk of catching fish in the lake, and it arrives <strong>spoiled</strong>. So, there is no way for us to fish," de Lira said.</p>
<p>Rain does not fall all year in the Amazon area. Rainfall is light from May to October, but the El Ni<i></i>241;o weather event is reducing the rain more than usual, said Ana Paula Cunha of Cemaden.</p>
<p>Climate scientists say the effects of El Ni<i></i>241;o this year are stronger because of global warming. Warming temperatures, they say, are because of carbon gases from years of burning coal, oil and gas.</p>
<p>One of the important rivers in the Amazon area is the Madeira. It travels over 3,500 kilometers from Bolivia to Brazil. Four of its five lowest water levels were recorded in the last four years, the Brazilian Geological Survey said.</p>
<p>In the port city of Porto Velho, the river's level is the lowest since measurements started in 1967. Brazil's fourth-largest hydroelectric dam, which produces power from water, is in nearby Santo Antonio. It stopped producing power last week for the first time since it opened in 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Unprecedented difficulties</strong></p>
<p>For now, the Brazilian government of President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva is sending food and water to the far away communities in the northern part of the country. Engineers will start digging paths along dry rivers for boat travel. Payments will soon go to families who cannot work.</p>
<p>But the problems will continue, experts say.</p>
<p>Photographs of dead dolphins appeared in newspapers and on television programs. Ayan Fleischmann is a hydrologist, or a scientist who studies water, at the Mamiraua Sustainable Development Institute. It describes itself as a social organization supervised by the Ministry of Science, Technology and Innovation. He said the photos were a "shock for everyone." He said the extreme heat may have hurt the organs of the dolphins or contributed to the growth of harmful bacteria.</p>
<p>"It was an unprecedented tragedy," he said. Unprecedented means never seen before.</p>
<p>Experts in Brazil from the National Institute for Space Research say the drought will likely continue until the end of 2023.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this report for VOA Learning English based on reporting from the Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>previous</strong> –adj. taking place at an earlier time</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong>–v. to watch or observe over time for a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> a period with very little rain or with an abnormally low amount of rainfall</p>
<p><strong>grim </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing feelings of sadness or worry</p>
<p><strong>spoiled </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>ruined; no longer usable or edible</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists to Study Fish after Fukushima Water Release  (2023/10/20) | 科学家研究日本核污水排海后的鱼类情况</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-to-study-fish-after-fukushima-water-release.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A team of international scientists collected fish samples from an area near Japan's Fukushima nuclear plant Thursday. They are examining the effects of the recent release of treated radioactive water from the plant into the sea.<br/>
一个国际科学家小组星期四从日本福岛核电站附近地区采集了鱼类样本。他们正在研究最近处理过的放射性水从核电站排入大海的影响。</p>
<p>The study by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is the first since the water release began in August. Local fishermen criticized the release. It also led China to ban all seafood products from Japan over food safety fears.<br/>
国际原子能机构的这项研究是自8月份开始排海以来的首次。当地渔民批评这次排海。这也导致中国出于对食品安全的担忧，禁止所有来自日本的海鲜产品。</p>
<p>Scientists from China, South Korea and Canada observed the collection of fish samples at Hisanohama Port, about 50 kilometers south of Fukushima.<br/>
来自中国、韩国和加拿大的科学家在福岛以南约50公里的久滨港观察了鱼类样本的采集情况。</p>
<p>The samples will be sent to laboratories in each country for independent testing, the U.N. nuclear agency said.<br/>
这家联合国下属的核机构表示，这些样本将被送往每个国家的实验室进行独立检验。</p>
<p>Paul McGinnity is a research scientist with the IAEA overseeing the study. He said, "The Japanese government has requested that we do this and one of the reasons they want us to do this is to try and strengthen confidence in the data that Japan is producing."<br/>
保罗·麦金尼提是国际原子能机构的一名研究科学家，他负责监督这项研究。他说：“日本政府请求我们这样做，他们希望我们这样做的原因之一是试图加强对日本正在产生的数据的信心。”</p>
<p>More than a million metric tons of water was contaminated by contact with fuel at the nuclear reactor following the 2011 earthquake and tsunami disaster.<br/>
2011年地震和海啸灾难后，超过100万公吨的水因接触核反应堆的燃料而受到污染。</p>
<p>Before being released, the water is filtered to remove isotopes, leaving only tritium, which is difficult to separate. Plant operator Tepco said the levels of tritium in the water are weakened to below official limits.<br/>
在排海之前，这些水被过滤以去除同位素，只留下难以分离的氚。核电站运营商东电表示，水中的氚含量已降至官方限值以下。</p>
<p>The IAEA says that tritium is "a naturally occurring radioactive form of hydrogen that is produced in the atmosphere when cosmic rays collide with air molecules."<br/>
国际原子能机构表示，氚是“宇宙射线与空气分子碰撞时在大气中产生的一种天然放射性氢。”</p>
<p>The agency says tritium cannot enter the body through human skin. It is only harmful if ingested in a very large amount.<br/>
该机构表示，氚不能通过人体皮肤进入人体。只有大量摄入才有害。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Disagreements  (2023/10/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/grammar-and-disagreements.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Consider almost any social or political issue. It could be local or international.</p>
<p>Some people have one idea about the issue, and other people have other ideas about the issue. In other words, people disagree with each other.</p>
<p>In this week's<em> Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore disagreements. We will learn about the verb, disagree, and the noun form, disagreement. We will learn some important ideas about how to use the terms.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1795-08dbcffb2b0f_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start with some history.</p>
<p><strong>History </strong></p>
<p>When we explore individual words, we often look at their histories. Words – like people – grow and change over time. By learning a little about these changes, we can make words more memorable and meaningful to us.</p>
<p>So, let's take a look at the verb "disagree."</p>
<p>Disagree first appeared in English over 500 years ago. The <em>Online Etymology Dictionary</em> tell us that disagree first meant "refuse <strong>assent</strong> to." It came from an Old French word desagreer, a word that we can break into two parts. Des- meant "not, opposite of" and agreer meant "to please; satisfy." In English, you might think of these two parts as dis- and agree.</p>
<p>With time, disagree took on new meanings. About 450 years ago, it took on the meaning of differing in opinion, or expressing differing views, the <em>Online Etymology Dictionary</em> tells us.</p>
<p>Some time later, we have the birth of the noun form disagreement.</p>
<p><strong>Usage </strong></p>
<p>We have followed disagree from its beginning. But how do we explain its modern usage?</p>
<p>One important idea is that we generally use disagree without an object. So, for example, you might say a simple, complete sentence such as this:</p>
<p><em>I disagree.</em></p>
<p>Or you might say this:</p>
<p><em>The two sides disagree.</em></p>
<p>But what about more complex sentences, you might ask? Internet data sources can give us some important information about how to do that.</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer contains data from many written materials. We can do a careful study of exact words.</p>
<p>What <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=disagree+*&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-fiction-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">Google's Ngram Viewer</a> tells us is that by far the most commonly used word after the verb disagree is the word "with." After the word "with," we generally have a pronoun, noun, or noun phrase.</p>
<p>So, for example, you might hear or read a sentence that involves a pronoun after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>I disagree with you.</em></p>
<p>You might hear or read a sentence that has a noun after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>He disagrees with Tom.</em></p>
<p>Or you might hear or read a sentence that has a noun phrase after "with," as in:</p>
<p><em>They disagree with these ideas.</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>We disagree with the prime minister's policies.</em></p>
<p>What about the noun disagreement, you might ask?</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=disagreement+*+&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">tells us </a>that once again, the word "with" is commonly used after the noun disagreement. So, you might hear or read the following:</p>
<p><em>He had a disagreement with his friend.</em></p>
<p>And what words might we use before the noun disagreement? <a class="wsw__a" href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=*+disagreement&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2019&amp;corpus=en-fiction-2019&amp;smoothing=3" target="_blank">Google's Ngram Viewer tells us</a> we are more likely to hear or read the short word "a," as in "a disagreement," So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>They had a disagreement.</em></p>
<p><strong>Quiz </strong></p>
<p>You may have noticed a difference between how we explored disagree and disagreement. We explored words that commonly come before and after disagreement, but we only explored a word that comes after the verb disagree. We did not explore the most common word that comes before disagree. Aside from pronouns, can you guess what the most common word is before the verb disagree?</p>
<p>Here is a hint: think about one short word that we often use before a verb in English.</p>
<p>Write us your answer in the comments section on our website or in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>assent </strong><em>– n. </em>to agree to or approve of something (such as an idea or suggestion)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Google's Antitrust Trial Could Change the Internet Search Market  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-google-s-antitrust-trial-could-change-the-internet-search-market.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A court in the United States is hearing evidence in a case against search engine provider Google. The government accuses the company of using illegal methods to crush business competitors.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Justice is leading the case against Google in a court in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>The trial could change the way Google is permitted to do business in the future. The case is one of the biggest antitrust trials in American history. Antitrust is a term relating to laws designed to prevent illegal competition.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Google sign is shown over an entrance to the company's new building in New York on Wednesday, Sept. 6, 2023." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4c21-08dbb2f1897a_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Google sign is shown over an entrance to the company's new building in New York on Wednesday, Sept. 6, 2023.</span></div>
<p>If the trial judge rules in favor of the government, the resulting punishment could lead to new online search possibilities for individual users and businesses.</p>
<p>Google's search engine earned a huge market share by helping people quickly connect to the wealth of information available on the internet. Google co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin developed the search technology in the late 1990s.</p>
<p>The Justice Department argues that Google has an unfair advantage in the market because its search engine is the <strong>default</strong> choice on the world's most popular smartphones and web browsers.</p>
<p>Witnesses from device makers, service providers and Google recently <strong>testified</strong> about one way the company's search engine is able to remain the default choice. They said the company pays an estimated $10 billion yearly to phone makers and other businesses in exchange for the default position.</p>
<p>In opening arguments, Justice Department lawyer Kenneth Dintzer said, "This case is about the future of the internet and whether Google will ever face meaningful competition in search."</p>
<p>Google has denied accusations that it uses unlawful methods to keep its huge market share. It says its search engine is wildly popular across the world because it offers users a high level of quality. Google lawyers have also argued that any users not happy with its search services can easily change to competitors.</p>
<p>But industry experts point out that many users choose to keep Google as the default so they do not have to take additional steps to change it. Research has shown that because of this ease, very few people change the default setting of Google.</p>
<p>The chief executives from two privacy-centered search engines, DuckDuckGo and Neeva, have argued that the default system favors Google and hurts their businesses. Neeva closed its operations earlier this year.</p>
<p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella also testified that Google has established a strong hold over users over the years. "You get up in the morning, you brush your teeth and you search on Google," Nadella said. He added that the only way to break this dependence is to remove Google as the default choice.</p>
<p>To solve this problem, industry experts say the judge may order a requirement for smartphones and web browsers to present a series of search engines to users during the setup process. This is already being done in Europe. But research shows that so far, most European users are still choosing to go with Google.</p>
<p>Florian Schaub is a professor of information at the University of Michigan who has studied people's online behavior. He says the fairest result in the trial would be a total ban on default agreements between technology companies.</p>
<p>Schaub spoke to the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>He said the current search environment is being shaped "by the big companies that control the space." He added, "What the government can do is inject some neutralism into this and give <strong>consumers</strong> some actual choices."</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a Justice Department lawyer accused Google in court of using unfair methods to push up internet advertising prices. The government <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-google-monopolizing-digital-advertising-technologies">argues</a> that "Google now controls the digital tool that nearly every major website publisher uses to sell ads on their websites."</p>
<p>The Justice Department accuses Google of using unfair methods to control online <strong>auctions</strong> that connect buyers and sellers of online advertising. By making small changes to the auction system, Google can drive ad prices up to make more money, government lawyers say.</p>
<p>Advertisers and website publishers have long criticized Google's ad business as being too complex and secretive.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>default </strong><em>– n. </em>what exists or happens if no changes are made</p>
<p><strong>testify </strong><em>– v. </em>to make a declaration under oath for the purpose of establishing a fact (as in a court)</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>– n.</em> someone who buys goods or services</p>
<p><strong>auction </strong><em>– n. </em>a sale in which things are sold to the person offering the most money</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Chemical Used in Air Coolers Needs Replacing  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-chemical-used-in-air-coolers-needs-replacing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Jennifer Byrne owns a heating and air conditioning repair company in the American city of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>Air conditioning, or AC equipment, cools the air in a home. To do this, the equipment uses a gas called a refrigerant.</p>
<p>While working on AC equipment in a house, Byrne puts gas from the equipment into a special container.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Operators move a used refrigerant cylinder at the A-Gas Rapid Recovery DFW facility on Monday, Oct. 9, 2023, in Arlington, Texas. (AP Photo/Sam Hodde)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a17b-08dbcf3bd83d_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Operators move a used refrigerant cylinder at the A-Gas Rapid Recovery DFW facility on Monday, Oct. 9, 2023, in Arlington, Texas. (AP Photo/Sam Hodde)</span></div>
<p>The gas is known by an industrial name: R-410A. Scientists say it traps 2,088 times more heat in the atmosphere than carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Because chemical refrigerants capture heat, some people say they need to be replaced with something else. Some scientists are worried that the release of methane, carbon dioxide, and other gases is making the atmosphere warmer.</p>
<p>The Clean Air Act bars businesses from releasing refrigerants into the air on purpose. Some companies are trying to find replacement gases that trap less heat, which might work almost as well.</p>
<p>Leaking AC equipment in homes is one way the gases get into the atmosphere. Cars are another <strong>source</strong> of these pollutants, said Eckhard Groll. He is an expert in refrigeration and head of mechanical engineering at Purdue University in the state of Indiana.</p>
<p>He said AC units in cars can leak. He said that, on average, about 25 percent of refrigerant from all cars leak out every year. There are more than 200 million gasoline cars in the U.S. alone, Groll said. Using those numbers, Groll said he estimates about 45 million kilograms of refrigerant is leaking into the atmosphere each year.</p>
<p>Supermarkets are the second-largest source of leaks. Long pipes carry refrigerant to coolers that store food. Danielle Wright is head of the North American Sustainable Refrigeration Council, a nonprofit group based in Mill Valley, California. It supports cleaner methods of cooling.</p>
<p>Wright said the average supermarket leaks about 25 percent of its refrigerant each year. That number is based on a U.S. Environmental Protection Agency report from 2005.</p>
<p>She criticized supermarkets, saying "...it's <strong>cheaper</strong> to leak the refrigerant than to build a leak-proof system."</p>
<p>Limiting leaks is important because the refrigerant can be reused. Many businesses <strong>recycle</strong> refrigerant gas. One such company, A-Gas, was founded in Britain in 1993. The company has several centers in the U.S.</p>
<p>Refrigerants can be used many times over and can last for 30 years, said Mike Armstrong, President of A-Gas in the Americas. The company takes in refrigerants and containers from around the U.S. and other countries. It processes the gas to be sold and used again. He said his business is doing well.</p>
<p>"This industry is probably going to increase four to five times in the next couple years," Armstrong said.</p>
<p>The chemical industry is also looking for a chemical to replace R-410A. Some researchers have suggested carbon dioxide itself as a possibility. But Groll of Purdue University said that carbon dioxide has to be under high pressure to work as a refrigerant. Completely different equipment would be necessary.</p>
<p>Christopher Cappa teaches environmental engineering at the University of California, Davis. He said carbon dioxide would be useful "if we're pulling it out of the atmosphere." But he added, "if we're producing it just as a refrigerant, that wouldn't be necessarily nearly as good."</p>
<p><strong>Refrigeration easier to clean than air conditioning</strong></p>
<p>Wright of the Sustainable Refrigeration Council supports the use of carbon dioxide. "This is kind of a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/low-hanging-fruit/7025641.html">low-hanging fruit</a>, it's a known technology and it's market ready," she said.</p>
<p>However, she said that reducing leaks from air conditioners is more difficult. She said chemical and equipment manufacturers and existing building rules have slowed the growth of new refrigerants in the U.S.</p>
<p>But one manufacturer, Trane Technologies, said it has been working hard on different choices. Trane says it has a refrigerant that is 78 percent less damaging to the environment than the current one. The company says it will start using it in its equipment beginning in 2024.</p>
<p>And at Harvard University, researchers are working to develop a solid refrigerant instead of a gas. Jarad Mason, an assistant professor of chemistry and chemical biology at Harvard University, is working on the project.</p>
<p>He said he is hopeful about using solid materials because they could be used in both large buildings and normal homes.</p>
<p>"Demands for heating and cooling are only going to increase," he said. He added that researchers must find ways of cooling that do not harm the environment and are not costly.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Isabella O'Malley wrote this story for the Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>source </strong>–n. where something comes from</p>
<p><strong>cheaper </strong>–comp. adj. less costly than something else</p>
<p><strong>recycle </strong>–v. to take something that has been used before, reprocess it, then use it again as if it were new</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Old Ways of Making Wine Gain New Fans  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/old-ways-of-making-wine-gain-new-fans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Wine made by ancient methods is gaining new fans.</p>
<p>Wine is an alcoholic drink made from fruit like grapes.</p>
<p>Natural wine uses methods that reduce processing and harmful effects on the Earth. Research company IWSR Drinks Market Analysis found that people in the U.S. are seeking natural wine in increasing numbers. At the same time, the number of wine buyers has been dropping since 2015.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Interns at Pax Wines in Sebastopol, Calif., stomp organic grapes with their bare feet in large vats, pulling out the juice to start the fermentation process on Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Haven Daley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/eff3d4fe-ea45-49c3-a3c7-75322d559b2e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Interns at Pax Wines in Sebastopol, Calif., stomp organic grapes with their bare feet in large vats, pulling out the juice to start the fermentation process on Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Haven Daley)</span></div>
<p>Natural and other Earth-friendly wines made up less than one percent of sales in 2021. But demand for those wines was rising faster than other kinds on the whole, reported Drizly, an online site for ordering and shipping wine and other alcohol.</p>
<p>Most natural wines are made with organic grapes collected by hand. Organic growers do not use poisonous chemicals to stop or control insects or<strong> </strong>unwanted plant growth.</p>
<p>To make wine, the grapes need to be crushed. Some wine producers crush grapes by foot like people of ancient times. Afterwards, the crushed grapes <strong>ferment</strong> naturally. Manufacturers do not add water, yeast or other substances.</p>
<p>There are exceptions. Some natural winemakers add sulfites, a chemical produced naturally in grapes. Extra sulfites can help preserve, or keep, the wine. And some winemakers clear the final liquid of any small pieces that could make it look cloudy.</p>
<p>The result is wines that are earthy and less predictable than many of the wines created by bigger producers.</p>
<p>"The first time you taste it, you can tell it's alive," said John Keller. He is the owner and winemaker at Neu Cellars in Northern Michigan.</p>
<p>But selling natural wine processes can be difficult. Natural wine has no set definition in the U.S. It is not easy to find, since most natural wines do not identify as such on their <strong>labels</strong>.</p>
<p>"Natural just sounds good, but <strong>conventional</strong> wine is pretty natural too," said Anita Oberholster. She is a professor in the Department of Viticulture and Enology at the University of California, Davis. "If the idea of natural wine is going to grow, we should do research on it and define it."</p>
<p>Keller of Neu Cellars has a degree in biochemistry. He started out working for a big winemaker in California. But he left because he was not happy about all the chemical mixes it used. These include gelatin, oak dust, and eggs.</p>
<p>However, some say the line between natural and conventional wines is very narrow.</p>
<p>Many products added to wine, like yeast, are natural products, Oberholster said. And many conventional wines are made without adding anything.</p>
<p>Some in the industry would like to establish rules<strong> </strong>for producing natural wine. France's wine industry took such action in 2020, enacting requirements that winemakers must meet to identify their wines as natural.</p>
<p>Some manufacturers argue that rules can make wine making more costly. Keller uses organic grapes but he says he cannot support the cost of repeated inspections for approval as an organic wine.</p>
<p>Anthony Zhang is the co-founder and CEO of Vinovest, a wine investment company. He sees another problem.</p>
<p>Vinovest says some wine companies are profiting from the lack of rules. They use labeling content like imagery that suggests their wine making is natural when they are not, he argues.</p>
<p>That can mislead buyers who often will pay higher prices for wines made by smaller producers that use natural methods.</p>
<p>However, buyers may have more information on wine bottles soon. Starting in December, wines sold in the European Union will have to identify on their labeling all the substances each product contains.</p>
<p>Oberholster expects the U.S. to pass similar measures as well in the next few years.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dee-Ann Durbin and Haven Daley reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ferment </strong>– <em>v</em>. to go through a chemical change that results in the production of alcohol</p>
<p><strong>conventional </strong>– <em>adj</em>. common and ordinary</p>
<p><strong>label </strong>– <em>adj</em>. a piece of paper or cloth that is attached to something to identify or describe that thing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gaza Hospital Explosion Limits Biden Visit to Israel, Middle East  (2023/10/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gaza-hospital-explosion-limits-biden-visit-to-israel-middle-east.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden visited Israel on Wednesday after the October 7 attack by the militant group Hamas that killed more than 1,400 people.</p>
<p>In addition to talks with Israeli leaders, Biden had planned to visit Jordan. But, that part of his plan was canceled after an explosion killed hundreds of people at a hospital in Gaza.</p>
<p>Since the attack by Hamas on civilians earlier this month, Israel has answered with air strikes and other attacks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (L) greets US President Joe Biden upon his arrival at Tel Aviv's Ben Gurion airport on October 18, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Brendan SMIALOWSKI / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fb1386b2-cdd4-4f7e-91cf-96d29f8d2ffd_cx7_cy0_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (L) greets US President Joe Biden upon his arrival at Tel Aviv's Ben Gurion airport on October 18, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Brendan SMIALOWSKI / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Hamas fighters said Israel was to blame for the blast that they said killed about 500 people. Israel's defense force responded, saying the explosion came from an off-target rocket fired by the Islamic Jihad militant group.</p>
<p>Before the explosion, Biden was supposed to speak with King Abdullah II of Jordan, President Abdel Fattah el-Sisi of Egypt and Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas to discuss humanitarian aid for Gazans.</p>
<p>Israel has promised a full ground invasion of Gaza and asked that Palestinians living in the northern part of the territory <strong>evacuate</strong> to the south. About 600,000 people so far have followed the order.</p>
<p>About 3,000 Palestinians have died during Israel's operations, the Gaza Health Ministry said.</p>
<p>Biden said he was given information from U.S. military experts that made him believe the hospital explosion was not from an Israeli weapon. While in Israel, he said he was sad to see what happened to the hospital, but "it appears it was done by the other team, not you."</p>
<p>Islamic Jihad says it was not responsible for the explosion.</p>
<p>Biden said he understands that many people watching the conflict from afar might not believe him.</p>
<p>He told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu that "Americans are <strong>grieving</strong>," and "worried" about how difficult it will be for Israel to respond to the attack.</p>
<p>The Biden administration said Wednesday that Biden spoke with King Abdullah II and chose to postpone his travel to Jordan.</p>
<p>As Biden was in Israel, the United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres called for a humanitarian cease-fire that would permit Hamas to release Israeli hostages. In addition, the U.N. would like Israel to re-open its borders with Gaza to permit food and water to enter.</p>
<p>The U.S. president said he was concerned that food and other aid would not reach the Palestinian people who need it the most.</p>
<p>"If Hamas <strong>diverts</strong> or steals the assistance, they will have demonstrated once again that they have no concern for the welfare of the Palestinian people," Biden said.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. approved $100 million in aid if it could be delivered to the neediest people.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said Biden's visit was "deeply moving." Biden said the U.S. would continue to support Israel but also work "to prevent more tragedy to innocent civilians."</p>
<p><strong>UN Concerns</strong></p>
<p>The Palestinian ambassador to the United Nations is Riyad Mansour. He said the meeting with Jordan, Egypt and the Palestinian leaders would only happen if Biden were to negotiate a cease-fire.</p>
<p>Israel is being criticized for cutting off electricity and restricting entry to Gaza. European Council President Charles Michel called Israel's tactic "not in line with international law."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by VOA's Patsy Widakuswara and wire services.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>evacuate </strong>–v. to leave or be moved from an area because of a threat or because it is unsafe</p>
<p><strong>grieve </strong>–v. the show great sadness because of an event especially in public</p>
<p><strong>divert </strong>–v. to take in a different direction that planned</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Climate, Land Use Changes Sharply Reduce Pollinating Insects  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-climate-land-use-changes-sharply-reduce-pollinating-insects.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests changes in world climate and land use are sharply reducing the number of insects needed for <strong>pollinating</strong> crops.</p>
<p>The study looked at thousands of species and areas around the world. It found that the number of pollinating insects dropped by 61 percent during periods of abnormally high temperatures and reduced supply of flowering plants.</p>
<p>Leaders of the study noted that bees, flies, moths and other pollinators are more affected than the general insect population. Results of the research recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adh0756">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Science Advances</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Bees and other insects gather on a sunflower at the Agro Brasilia, an agricultural exhibition on the outskirts of Brasilia, Brazil, May 18, 2012. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-55cc-08dbcf1b8f89_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Bees and other insects gather on a sunflower at the Agro Brasilia, an agricultural exhibition on the outskirts of Brasilia, Brazil, May 18, 2012. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, File)</span></div>
<p>"We're seeing the climate change is already having this really strong <strong>impact</strong> on pollinators," study co-writer Tim Newbold told The Associated Press. He is an ecologist at the University College of London.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture estimates about 35 percent of world food crops and 75 percent of flowering plants depend on insects and other animal pollinators to reproduce.</p>
<p>The study found the biggest problems with pollinator loss are in the tropics – areas that sit close to Earth's equator. The countries most at risk of crop loss from reduced pollinators include China, India, Indonesia and Brazil. Sub-Saharan Africa is also in danger, especially its cocoa and mango crops, the study found.</p>
<p>Given the current situation, the researchers said some important tropical crops – especially coffee and cocoa – could be badly hurt. Those plants depend heavily on bees and flies to help them reproduce.</p>
<p>Past studies have shown insect populations are decreasing for several reasons, including climate change and loss of <strong>habitat</strong>.<strong> </strong>Other studies have shown shrinking numbers of pollinators, with coffee and cocoa plants especially harmed by the absence.</p>
<p>Newbold, from the University College of London, said he sees a "double hit of climate change" affecting the coffee plants themselves, as well as the pollinators they depend on.</p>
<p>This does not mean, however, that there will be no coffee or chocolate available, said the study's lead writer, Joe Millard. It will just mean buyers will have to pay more for them. Millard is a computational ecologist at the Natural History Museum in London.</p>
<p>University of Delaware insect expert Douglas Tallamy – who was not part of the research – said this study is unusual because it centered on the tropics, which other research has not. "We're not paying enough attention to the tropics," Tallamy said. "They are important."</p>
<p>Newbold noted that pollinating insects in the tropics are likely hit harder than other places because they are already near their temperature limits that place them at risk. "Massive warming in the tropics is pushing those species over the edge," Newbold said.</p>
<p>Habitat loss is the main driver for the shrinking number of pollinators because it leaves less food for them, Millard said. Climate change, <strong>parasites</strong>, disease, and chemicals in the environment add to that difficulty.</p>
<p>Newbold said scientists are still trying to find out why pollinators seem to be suffering worse effects from warming temperatures than other insects. It could be because they have hairier legs and bodies that help them carry <strong>pollen</strong>, the researchers said.</p>
<p>It is like "being forced to have a big furry coat and it's getting hot," Newbold said.</p>
<p>But the University of Delaware's Tallamy is not so sure. He said that the study's data is solid, but its explanation as to cause of impact is more of a <strong>guess</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pollinate </strong><em>– v. </em>to carry pollen from a male part of a flower to the female part of another flower of the same type</p>
<p><strong>habitat </strong><em>– n. </em>the natural environment of a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>– n.</em> the affect a person, event or situation has on someone or something</p>
<p><strong>parasite </strong><em>– n.</em> a plant or animal that lives on or inside another plant or animal in order to get food</p>
<p><strong>pollen </strong><em>– n.</em> a powdery substance produced by flowers that is carried by insects or wind and makes other flowers produce seeds</p>
<p><strong>guess </strong><em>– adj. </em>to form an opinion of from little or no evidence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some Mexican Students Will Pay Less to Attend California Community Colleges  (2023/10/18) | 部分墨西哥学生就读加州社区大学将能享受低学费</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/some-mexican-students-will-pay-less-to-attend-california-community-colleges.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>
California Governor Gavin Newsom signed a law last week permitting low-income Mexican students to pay the same cost as Californians to attend some community colleges.<br/>
加州州长加文·纽瑟姆上周签署了一项法律，允许低收入的墨西哥学生支付与加州人相同的费用进入一些社区大学。</p>
<p>The law starts next year and will run as a pilot, or test program, for five years. The program is open to Mexican students who live within 72 kilometers of the U.S. border in California.<br/>
该法律将于明年开始实施，并将作为试点或测试项目运行五年。该项目对居住在美国加州州界72公里以内的墨西哥学生开放。</p>
<p>In California, the Education Data Initiative says the average yearly cost of tuition at community colleges for Californians is $1,500. For out-of-state students, the yearly cost is nearly $10,000. It means a possible saving of more than $8,000 for some Mexican students under the program.<br/>
在加州，教育数据倡议组织表示，加州人在社区大学的平均年学费为1500美元。对于州外的学生来说，每年的费用将近1万美元。这意味着该项目可能为一些墨西哥学生节省8000多美元。</p>
<p>David Alvarez is a California state lawmaker who worked on the law. He said many Mexicans travel between the two countries to work or visit family. And the law will help make education readily available to prepare them for jobs.<br/>
大卫·阿尔瓦雷斯是加州的一名州议员，他曾参与这项法律的制定。他说，许多墨西哥人往返于两国之间工作或探亲。这项法律将有助于他们随时接受教育，为就业做好准备。</p>
<p>Alvarez said in a statement that the program would help "prepare a more diverse population among our workforce."<br/>
阿尔瓦雷斯在一份声明中表示，该计划将有助于“在我们的劳动力中培养更多样化的人群”。</p>
<p>Southwestern College in Chula Vista, California, is just 11 kilometers from the U.S. border with Mexico. The college's president Mark Sanchez said many students at the school split their time between the two countries.<br/>
位于加州丘拉维斯塔的西南学院距离美国与墨西哥的边境只有11公里。该学院院长马克·桑切斯表示，该校许多学生穿梭于两国之间。</p>
<p>"Without this pilot, we risk everything in terms of loss of talent," he told lawmakers at a hearing last June.<br/>
他在去年6月的一次听证会上对议员表示：“如果没有这个试点，我们将面临人才流失的风险。”</p>
<p>Students from Mexico who decide to go to Southwestern College will save about $7,000 based on the lower cost for Californians.<br/>
来自墨西哥的学生如果决定去西南学院，将在享受加州人低廉学费的基础上节省约7000美元。</p>
<p>The law requires community colleges to report by 2028 on the attendance and the number of students receiving in-state tuition under the program.<br/>
该法律要求社区大学在2028年前报告入学率和根据该计划享受州内学费的学生人数。</p>
<p>In 2015, California passed a similar law that permitted students who lived close to its border with Nevada to attend Lake Tahoe Community College at in-state tuition.<br/>
2015年，加州通过了一项类似的法律，允许居住在加州与内华达州边境附近的学生以州内学费进入太浩湖社区学院。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·菲利德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN Report: Education Technology Should Be Used Carefully  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/un-report-education-technology-should-be-used-carefully.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic showed how useful digital technology could be for schools. But it also showed the limitations of technology in the educational setting. Millions of students were able to attend classes online to avoid spreading the virus. But many students failed to learn by such methods. Their educational progress slowed and in some cases went backwards.</p>
<p>Digital tools and the internet have made it easier for students to <strong>access</strong> educational resources. However, a large number of schools around the world remain unconnected to the internet. Additionally, digital tools have entered markets that have no official supervision. Such educational products do not require any testing or proof as to their value to schools and learners.</p>
<p>The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) argues against unsupervised wide use of digital tools and AI in education. A recent UNESCO report says there is little evidence that wide technology use improves learning. The organization says digital educational tools can never replace the human connection of teacher and student.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Michael Burton-Straub, left, and Declan Lewis attempt to Find the Bot in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0840-08db135b1232_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Michael Burton-Straub, left, and Declan Lewis attempt to "Find the Bot" in Donnie Piercey's class at Stonewall Elementary in Lexington, Ky., Monday, Feb. 6, 2023.<i>&amp;#</i>160; (AP Photo/Timothy D. Easley)</span></div>
<p>Audrey Azoulay is UNESCO's Director General. She says there is a very large divide, or gap, between rich and poor countries when it comes to digital resources. Just 40 percent of primary schools worldwide have access to the internet, she said. Many schools also lack electricity, especially in Africa and Central and Southern Asia. In sub-Saharan Africa, just 32 percent of schools have electricity.</p>
<p>And, internationally, about one-third of students were unable to attend online classes during the pandemic.</p>
<p>"Even if connectivity was universal, it would still be necessary to demonstrate ...that digital technology offers real added value in terms of effective learning," the report says.</p>
<p>Often, technology changes faster than it is possible to study it, the report says. Educational technology products change every three years on average. In Britain, for example, just seven percent of educational technology companies had done studies to judge the effectiveness of their products.</p>
<p>UNESCO also reported that many companies pay for studies on the effectiveness of their own product. These studies are not independent examinations.</p>
<p>Pearson, an education technology company, has a tool called Successmaker for teaching math and reading. Independent studies show the tool has little or <strong>negative</strong> effectiveness in learning. But the company stands by the results of the private study it paid for. That study found the product very helpful to learning.</p>
<p>UNESCO says such companies need to be better regulated. Azoulay said just 14 percent of countries require data protection in education.</p>
<p>"Student data should not be used either by education technology or advertising technology companies for marketing purposes," the report says. Yet a study of 163 products found that 89 percent of them gathered student data and sent them to third-party companies, often for advertising purposes. This usually happened without the student or parent knowing, the study said.</p>
<p>UNESCO argues that technology holds great possibilities for education. But studies have shown that educational technologies are most effective when a teacher is involved in the <strong>instructional</strong> process.</p>
<p>"We must never forget the social and emotional <strong>dimensions</strong> of teaching and learning," Azoulay said, adding, "no screen will ever replace a teacher."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>negative </strong><em>— adj. </em>harmful or bad</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>regulation </strong><em>— n. </em>an official rule or law that says how something should be done</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>instruction </strong><em>— n. </em>the action or process of teaching</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dimension </strong><em>— n. </em>the amount or number of things that something affects or influences</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pepper X Sets Guinness Record for Hottest Pepper  (2023/10/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/pepper-x-sets-guinness-record-for-hottest-pepper.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ed Currie is the pepper expert who grew the Carolina Reaper, which has been considered the hottest pepper in the world since 2013. Ten years later, Currie broke his record with one that is three times hotter: Pepper X.</p>
<p>The Guinness Book of World Records named Currie’s latest creation the world’s <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/news/2023/10/pepper-x-dethrones-carolina-reaper-as-worlds-hottest-chilli-pepper-759706">“hottest chili pepper”</a> this month.</p>
<p>Guinness uses what are called Scoville Heat Units (SHU) to measure heat in a chili pepper. A normal jalapeno pepper registers about 5,000 units. A habanero, the record-holder about 25 years ago, reaches 100,000 SHU.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Pepper X pepper is shown on Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023, in Fort Mill, S.C. The pepper variety is now the hottest pepper in the world according to the Guinness Book of World Records (AP Photo/Jeffrey Collins)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/sp/01000000-0aff-0242-0f71-08dbcf20c95f_cx0_cy11_cw84_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">A Pepper X pepper is shown on Tuesday, Oct. 10, 2023, in Fort Mill, S.C. The pepper variety is now the hottest pepper in the world according to the Guinness Book of World Records (AP Photo/Jeffrey Collins)</span></div>
<p>The Carolina Reaper held the record since 2013 with 1.64 million SHU. And Pepper X is the new record holder with an average of 2.69 million units. By comparison, pepper spray commonly carried by police is around 1.6 million units. And bear spray, a product to keep bears away, is advertised to have 2.2 million units.</p>
<p>Currie said when he first tried Pepper X, “I was feeling the heat for three-and-a-half hours.” Currie, one of only five people so far to eat an entire Pepper X added, “Then the <strong>cramps</strong> came.” The cramps, he said, left him lying in pain for another hour.</p>
<p>Currie started working on Pepper X after he set the record in 2013 with the Carolina Reaper. He <strong>crossbred</strong> 100 different kinds of peppers every year for 10 years. Currie hoped that just one or two would make it through the development process. His goal was to offer an extremely hot pepper flavored with a little sweetness.</p>
<p>Pepper X is greenish yellow. It is a crossbreed of a Carolina Reaper and, what Currie mysteriously called, a “pepper that a friend of mine sent me from Michigan that was brutally hot.”</p>
<p>The chemical in peppers that causes the burn is called capsaicin. The chemical causes a burning sensation when it touches human tissue. The burning sensation is also said to release chemicals into the body called endorphins and dopamine.</p>
<p>Currie started growing peppers after ending drug and alcohol <strong>addictions</strong>. He considers that sensation a natural “high.” He shares his peppers with medical researchers, hoping they can use them to treat disease and help people who suffer <strong>chronic</strong> pain or discomfort.</p>
<p>Currie is trying to build a business with his new creation. In the past, Currie permitted people to grow his peppers without protecting his ideas. His lawyers say they have counted more than 10,000 products that use the Carolina Reaper name, or other <strong>intellectual property</strong>, without permission.</p>
<p>For Pepper X, he said no seeds will be released without his permission. “Everybody else made their money off the Reaper. It’s time for us to reap the <strong>benefits</strong> of the hard work I do,” Currie said.</p>
<p>Currie wants people to eat peppers and thinks they can gain from the experience that comes after the burn. He warns people from reaching too quickly for a Carolina Reaper or Pepper X.</p>
<p>When asked if Pepper X is the “pinnacle” or the hottest a pepper can be, Currie said with a smile, “No, it’s not the pinnacle.”</p>
<p>I’m Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from the Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cramps</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. (usually pl) </em>a feeling of pain and tightening often near the stomach or abdomen or in the muscles</p>
<p><strong>crossbred</strong> <em>–v.</em> to purposely breed different versions of similar plants so that the offspring will have certain qualities</p>
<p><strong>addiction </strong><em>–n.</em> a strong and harmful need to regularly have something, often a drug, or to do something like gambling</p>
<p><strong>chronic </strong><em>–adj. (medical)</em> continuing for a long time or repeatedly</p>
<p><strong>intellectual property </strong>–n. the inventions of a person that are recognized as that person’s property and which cannot legally be copied</p>
<p><strong>benefits </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> the good results of work</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Groups Demand Urgent Rules to Protect Whales from Ships  (2023/10/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/groups-demand-urgent-rules-to-protect-whales-from-ships.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An alliance of environmental groups is calling for new federal rules to protect an endangered whale from crashes with ships.</p>
<p>The groups presented their demands in a document, called a petition, provided to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) on September 28.</p>
<p>The action aims to protect the North Atlantic right whale, which has long been considered endangered. The population of these extremely large sea animals has decreased sharply in recent years. Just 340 are believed to be alive today.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A North Atlantic right whale is seen feeding on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-97ad-08dbcb2ccb79_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A North Atlantic right whale is seen feeding on the surface of Cape Cod bay off the coast of Plymouth, Mass., March 28, 2018. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)</span></div>
<p>Officials at NOAA have said ship collisions are among the most serious threats to the survival of the whale. One rule the environmental groups are calling for would seek to prevent ship strikes by making more ships slow down for whales. NOAA has yet to release a final updated speed rule although it proposed new rules more than a year ago, the groups said.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have appealed for urgency in enacting the measure. They say it is important to approve new rules before the upcoming birthing season. At that time of year, the whales migrate hundreds of miles from waters off New England and Canada to areas off the coasts of Florida and Georgia.</p>
<p>"Even one ship strike would bring these whales closer to <strong>extinction</strong>, but speed limits can help prevent that," said Kristen Monsell. She is a legal director at the Center for Biological Diversity, one of the groups that prepared the petition to NOAA. "Federal officials can't sit back and do nothing while right whales are in danger," Monsell told The Associated Press.</p>
<p>Katie Wagner is a spokesperson for NOAA. She said she expects the agency to announce its final action on the proposed rule sometime this year. That means the rule could be publicized during the middle of <strong>calving</strong> season and may not be put into effect until even later.</p>
<p>Wagner said NOAA knows about the petition but has a policy not to comment on legal matters. The agency is considering expanding "slow zones" off the U.S. East Coast, and also requiring more ships to obey those rules.</p>
<p>NOAA denied a request from environmentalists last year to immediately put new rules in place. At the time, the agency said in public documents that it was considering "long-term, <strong>substantive</strong>" measures to reduce whale strikes by ships. Wagner said NOAA received more than 90,000 comments on the proposed rule and would use those to decide on its final action.</p>
<p>Right whales were once common off the U.S. East Coast. But the animals fell in numbers after years of heavy hunting activities. The whales have long been protected under the Endangered Species Act.</p>
<p>Right whales are also at risk of becoming accidentally <strong>entangled</strong> in fishing equipment. Proposed restrictions to prevent such entanglements have been the subject of a legal case between the federal government and fishermen.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinct </strong><em>– adj. </em>no longer existing; when a living thing disappears from the Earth forever</p>
<p><strong>calving </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for when certain animals give birth</p>
<p><strong>substantive </strong><em>– adj.</em> important or serious</p>
<p><strong>entangle </strong><em>– v.</em> to cause something to become caught in something such as a net or ropes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gates Foundation Helps mRNA Vaccine Development in Africa  (2023/10/17) | 盖茨基金会帮助非洲开发mRNA疫苗</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gates-foundation-helps-mrna-vaccine-development-in-africa.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation announced last week that it will invest $40 million in African drug makers. The money will help produce new messenger RNA vaccines in Africa. The continent's people were the last to receive vaccinations against COVID-19 during the pandemic.<br/>
比尔和梅琳达·盖茨基金会上周宣布，将向非洲制药商投资4000万美元。这笔钱将帮助在非洲生产新的信使核糖核酸疫苗。在大流行期间，非洲大陆的人民是最后一批接种新冠肺炎疫苗的人。</p>
<p>The foundation said that its investment marks an important step forward in improving vaccine equity. It said making vaccines and getting them approved for use could take at least three more years.<br/>
该基金会表示，其投资标志着在提高疫苗公平性方面迈出了重要一步。它表示，生产疫苗并获批使用可能至少还需要三年时间。</p>
<p>"Whether it's for local diseases in Africa like Rift Valley (fever) or for global diseases like TB (tuberculosis), mRNA looks like a very promising approach," Bill Gates told the Associated Press.<br/>
比尔·盖茨告诉美联社：“无论是针对非洲的局部疾病，如裂谷热，还是针对结核病，信使核糖核酸看起来都是一种非常有前景的方法。”</p>
<p>The Microsoft founder added, during a visit to the Institut Pasteur in Dakar, Senegal, "And so it allows us to bring in lots of African capabilities to work on these vaccines, and then this can be scaled up."<br/>
这位微软创始人在访问位于塞内加尔达喀尔市的巴斯德研究所时补充道，“因此，这使我们能够引入大量非洲能力来研究这些疫苗，然后可以扩大规模。”</p>
<p>The announcement came as the foundation opened its yearly three-day Grand Challenges event. The gathering brought together scientists and public health researchers from around the world.<br/>
值此消息宣布之际，该基金会一年一度的为期三天的“大挑战”活动拉开了帷幕。这次活动汇集了来自世界各地的科学家和公共卫生研究人员。</p>
<p>Institut Pasteur, along with South Africa-based company Biovac, will be using an mRNA research and manufacturing process developed by Quantoom Biosciences in Belgium.<br/>
巴斯德研究所和南非Biovac公司将使用比利时Quantoom生物科学公司开发的信使核糖核酸研发和制造工艺。</p>
<p>The foundation is giving five million dollars to each vaccine manufacturer. It will award another $10 million to other companies not yet identified. The remaining $20 million is going to Quantoom "to further advance the technology and lower costs."<br/>
该基金会向每家疫苗制造商捐赠500万美元。它将向其他尚未确定的其它公司再奖励1000万美元。剩下的2000万美元将用于Quantoom公司“进一步推进技术和降低成本”。</p>
<p>Pfizer and its partner BioNTech along with Moderna used the mRNA technology to develop COVID-19 vaccines in record time. The medicine supplies genetic direction to human cells leading to antibody production to fight COVID-19.<br/>
辉瑞公司及其合作伙伴BioNTech，连同莫德纳公司在打破记录的时间内使用mRNA技术开发了新冠肺炎疫苗。该药物为人类细胞提供基因方向，从而产生抗体来对抗新冠肺炎。</p>
<p>Those COVID-19 mRNA vaccines were quickly pushed through approval processes and received emergency use permission during the pandemic. The new vaccines under development in Africa will take longer anywhere from three to seven years.<br/>
这些新冠肺炎mRNA疫苗很快通过了审批程序，并在大流行期间获得了紧急使用许可。非洲正在研发的新疫苗需要三到七年的时间。</p>
<p>Dr. Amadou Sall is chief executive officer at Institut Pasteur. He said the deal will help build vaccine self-reliance in Africa. The organization has been producing yellow fever shots since the 1930s. It now hopes mRNA technology can be used to produce vaccines for other diseases in Africa including Lassa fever, Rift Valley fever, and Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever.<br/>
阿马杜·萨尔博士是巴斯德研究所的首席执行官。他说，该协议将有助于非洲建立疫苗自力更生的能力。自20世纪30年代以来，该组织一直在生产黄热病疫苗。它现在希望信使核糖核酸技术可以用于生产非洲其他疾病的疫苗，包括拉萨热、裂谷热和克里米亚-刚果出血热。</p>
<p>"What we want is next time there is a pandemic — we hope it won't happen soon — Africa would be able to make its own vaccine, to contribute to the development, and make sure that we protect the population," Sall said. "What happened with COVID should never happen again in the sense that Africans should get vaccinated as a matter of equity."<br/>
萨尔说：“我们希望下次疫情爆发时非洲将能够制造自己的疫苗，为发展做出贡献，并确保我们保护人民。当然我们希望下次疫情不会来得那么快。从非洲人应该公平接种疫苗的意义上讲，新冠肺炎的情况不应该再次发生。”</p>
<p>Jose Castillo is the leader of Quantoom Biosciences. He said the mRNA technologies permit low- and middle-income countries "to become autonomous in terms of research and development."<br/>
何塞·卡斯蒂略是Quantoom生物科学公司的负责人。他说，信使核糖核酸技术能够让中低收入国家“在研发方面实现自主”。</p>
<p>With $8.3 billion to give away in 2023, the Gates Foundation is the world's largest private philanthropic donor. The organization has spent billions of dollars to vaccinate against polio, treat and prevent malaria and HIV and, more recently, to develop vaccines for diseases like cholera.<br/>
盖茨基金会是世界上最大的私人慈善捐赠机构，它将在2023年捐出83亿美元。该组织已花费数十亿美元接种脊髓灰质炎疫苗，治疗和预防疟疾和艾滋病毒，最近还开发了霍乱等疾病的疫苗。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gaza Aid Halted in Egypt as Israeli Air Strikes Continue  (2023/10/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/gaza-aid-halted-in-egypt-as-israeli-air-strikes-continue.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Emergency aid for Gaza was being held up at a border crossing in Egypt Monday as Israel continued to launch air strikes into the Palestinian-ruled territory.</p>
<p>Egyptian officials said Israel has not cooperated in recent days with efforts to get large aid shipments into Gaza from a crossing in Rafah, Egypt.</p>
<p>On Friday, Israel began ordering Palestinians to leave Gaza City and surrounding areas in the north, telling them to head to the south. Israeli officials say the order was issued ahead of a planned military ground campaign against forces of Palestinian ruler Hamas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Palestinians carry a person wounded in Israeli airstrikes in Khan Younis, Gaza Strip, Monday, October 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Fatima Shbair)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7908-08dbce7360b4_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Palestinians carry a person wounded in Israeli airstrikes in Khan Younis, Gaza Strip, Monday, October 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Fatima Shbair)</span></div>
<p>Hamas militants have built major military bases in the north. Israel's expected ground offensive there is expected to center on killing Hamas leaders, recovering captives, and destroying the group's military equipment, The Associated Press (AP) reported.</p>
<p>More than a million people had already fled their homes in northern Gaza in preparation for a ground invasion.</p>
<p>Israel has continued to attack positions in Gaza after Hamas launched a major military operation into southern Israel on October 7. Israeli airstrikes have destroyed whole neighborhoods as Palestinian militants continued firing rockets into Israel.</p>
<p>Israeli officials say more than 1,400 Israelis – including many civilians – have died in the conflict. Health ministry officials in Gaza say at least 2,750 Palestinians have been killed and 9,700 injured since the Hamas attacks began.</p>
<p>Israel controls the other two crossing points into Gaza. But it has declared a "complete <strong>siege</strong>" of the coastal Palestinian territory. This means Israel has cut off food, water, fuel and electricity supplies to the area.</p>
<p>Gaza has been under a joint Israeli-Egyptian blockade ever since Hamas seized control of the territory in 2007. The blockade closely controls movements of goods and people into Gaza.</p>
<p><strong>Mediators</strong> have pressed in recent days for a cease-fire that would permit the waiting aid to enter, as well as give foreigners a chance to leave Gaza.</p>
<p>The AP reported Egypt's foreign minister as saying Israel "has not taken a position to open the crossing from the Gaza side." The Israeli government did not immediately answer a request from AP for comment.</p>
<p>In Gaza, Palestinians crowded hospitals and schools Monday seeking shelter as food, water and medicine remained in short supply.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Palestinians sheltering in U.N. centers are getting less than 1 liter of water per day, the AP reported. Hospitals warned of operations nearing collapse because of power and fuel shortages.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) said it was concerned about disease spread linked to mass displacements and poor water quality. Four hospitals in northern Gaza are no longer operating and 21 had received Israeli orders to close. Many doctors have so far refused, saying it would mean death for critically ill patients and people receiving breathing assistance.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>siege </strong><em>– n. </em>a military operation in which enemy forces surround an area and cut off necessary supplies</p>
<p><strong>mediator </strong>–n. a person who works with opposing sides to reach an agreement or ease a dispute</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google Says AI-powered System Is Improving City Traffic Flows  (2023/10/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/google-says-ai-powered-system-is-improving-city-traffic-flows.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google says an artificial intelligence (AI)-powered system it created is helping improve traffic flow in major world cities.</p>
<p>The system, called Project Green Light, is currently in use in 12 cities. The project aims to save fuel and lessen air pollution, or emissions, from automobiles.</p>
<p>Google first announced the program in 2021, when it was testing the system in four areas of Israel. Since then, the company has kept expanding Project Green Light. Among cities now taking part in the program are Bangalore, Budapest, Jakarta, Manchester, Haifa, Hamburg, Rio de Janeiro, and Seattle.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Vehicles are caught in congestion as the flow of traffic increases at toll road in Cikarang, West Java, Indonesia, Friday, April 29, 2022. Google says its AI-powered system helps improve traffic flow. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b34f-08db2c933873_cx16_cy17_cw79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Vehicles are caught in congestion as the flow of traffic increases at toll road in Cikarang, West Java, Indonesia, Friday, April 29, 2022. Google says its AI-powered system helps improve traffic flow. (AP Photo/Achmad Ibrahim)</span></div>
<p>In an <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/google-ai-reduce-greenhouse-emissions-project-greenlight/">online announcement</a>, Google's Yossi Matias explained the latest progress. He noted that the system is being tested in areas with severe traffic issues. Generally, this is at major crossings with heavy traffic and complex traffic lights. These areas where vehicles start and stop are known as intersections.</p>
<p>The company said research has shown that at such intersections, automobile emissions can be 29 times higher than on open roads. In addition, Google's own research found that vehicles that must stop and start account for about half of those emissions.</p>
<p>Project Green Light uses individual driver data from Google Maps. This data is combined with AI methods to produce models of each intersection where the system is in place, the company says. The data from Maps is also used to create another model on how different traffic lights interact.</p>
<p>The modeling process for intersections considers several elements. These include the structure of streets, traffic flows, signal scheduling and how the vehicles interact with lights.</p>
<p>The models are used to reduce stop and start times and create smoother traffic flows, a process called optimization. Google says one goal is to optimize multiple intersections at the same time to create "waves of green lights" for vehicles on the road.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Google and Reuters. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>efficient </strong><em>– adj.</em> working well and not wasting time and energy</p>
<p><strong>gridlock </strong><em>– n.</em> heavy traffic conditions prevented vehicles from moving in any direction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>App Shows How Ancient Greek Buildings Looked Thousand Years Ago  (2023/10/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/app-shows-how-ancient-greek-buildings-looked-thousand-years-ago.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>If you visit the Acropolis in Athens, Greece, you will see the rocky grounds high above the city that include the famous ruins of the Parthenon.</p>
<p>However, if you use a new <strong>app</strong> from Greece's culture ministry, you can see what the building and grounds looked like more than 2,000 years ago.</p>
<p>The app lets visitors see the famous place in its true <strong>glory</strong>, with the bright colors and details it had in the past. <strong>Archaeologists</strong> and other historians worked to create digital images showing how the Acropolis looked when it was new.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man holds up a tablet showing a digitally overlayed virtual reconstruction of the ancient Parthenon temple, at the Acropolis Hill in Athens, Greece on Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6a707333-5c66-4d5e-b91a-d288779f7611_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man holds up a tablet showing a digitally overlayed virtual reconstruction of the ancient Parthenon temple, at the Acropolis Hill in Athens, Greece on Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)</span></div>
<p>In the app, the Parthenon, for example, has its famous <strong>marble</strong> sculptures that are now at the British Museum in London. The app lets visitors see the sculptures where they used to be near the Parthenon. Greece wants Britain to return the sculptures.</p>
<p>Experts say the app, called Chronos, is an example of how Artificial intelligence, or AI, technology is being used to tell the stories of the past.</p>
<p>The technology that expands what people can see is called <strong>augmented reality</strong> or AR. Companies such as Meta and Apple are making big investments in apps and <strong>hardware</strong> that can bring the technology to more people.</p>
<p>Maria Engberg recently wrote a book about the subject. She said most people will first experience augmented reality through their phones at places like the Acropolis.</p>
<p>She said travelers will see the technology when they take tours. They will be able to see photos and videos as they walk around historic places. Engberg is a professor at Malmo University in Sweden.</p>
<p>"I think we will see really interesting customer experiences in the next few years as more <strong>content</strong> from museums and archives becomes <strong>digitized</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>The government and other groups are making investments in AR as more visitors come to Greece following the end of the COVID-19 pandemic. Visitors to Greece in the first half of 2023 increased by over 20 percent compared to 2022, bringing over $10 billion to the Greek economy.</p>
<p>Microsoft worked with the Greek culture ministry to create a digital tour of Olympia, the home of the first Olympic Games. Lina Mendoni leads the agency. Earlier this year, she said the new technology lets "real visitors and <strong>virtual</strong> visitors anywhere around the world share historical knowledge."</p>
<p>Cosmote is the Greek telecommunications company that worked on the Chronos app. Panayiotis Gabrielides of Cosmote said advanced smart phones and faster communications networks will permit visitors to "download even higher-quality content." He said more guides and features will be available soon.</p>
<p>But for now, visitors can use Chronos to see how the Parthenon and other parts of the Acropolis once looked.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app</strong> <em>–n.</em> (application) a computer program that does a specific task often especially designed for a smart phone</p>
<p><strong>glory </strong><em>–n.</em> a praiseworthy condition or state</p>
<p><strong>archaeologist </strong><em>–n.</em> a scientist who studies the lives of ancient people</p>
<p><strong>marble </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind of stone often used to decorate public buildings</p>
<p><strong>augmented reality </strong><em>–n.</em> technology that adds to people's senses of what reality is</p>
<p><strong>hardware </strong><em>–n. (industry specific)</em> the physical electronic devices that use software</p>
<p><strong>content </strong><em>–n.</em> media such as writing, sound and pictures</p>
<p><strong>digitized </strong><em>–adj.</em> something in electronic form that can be used by computers</p>
<p><strong>virtual </strong><em>–adj.</em> existing on computers but not in the physical world</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ugandan Business Turns Banana Fiber into Sustainable Products  (2023/10/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/ugandan-business-turns-banana-fiber-into-sustainable-products.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Banana plant <strong>stems</strong> are mostly useless following harvest of the fruit. It takes time and work to remove the stem from the ground. Then the farmers have to crush the plant waste to small pieces to spread around crops.</p>
<p>But is there a better way to deal with the plant waste? A company in Uganda says yes. The business is collecting banana stems to process the plant tissue and make products.</p>
<p>The idea is both new and <strong>sustainable </strong>in the East African country where banana plants are very important. Uganda has the highest rate of banana use in the world. The country is Africa's top banana crop producer.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A farmer cuts down a banana plant, at her farm, in Kiwenda village, Busukuma, Wakiso District, Uganda, Wednesday, Sept. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6bdd153e-f4c7-4397-9947-3543b2ee9fa2_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A farmer cuts down a banana plant, at her farm, in Kiwenda village, Busukuma, Wakiso District, Uganda, Wednesday, Sept. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Hajarah Nalwadda)</span></div>
<p>A young local business, TEXFAD, deals with the banana plant waste. Now, it says it is making a profit from all the <strong>rotting</strong> stems. TEXFAD collects some of the plant tissue and uses it to make products like floor coverings, containers for home goods and more.</p>
<p>John Baptist Okello leads the business division of TEXFAD. He told the Associated Press that the business made sense in a country where farmers "are struggling" with millions of tons of banana-related waste.</p>
<p>The company works with seven different farmers' groups in western Uganda. It pays $2.70 for a kilogram of dried fiber.</p>
<p>David Bangirana is the leader of one such group in Sheema District. He said only a small part of the stem is used for fiber. He said that the rest of the crushed plant remains is returned to the farmer for use as fertilizer.</p>
<p>TEXFAD also takes material from a third party, Tupande Holdings Ltd. Its trucks transport banana stems from farmers in central Uganda. Tupande's workers search the stems for the best candidates as fiber. Machines then turn the fiber into threads, thin long pieces of cloth.</p>
<p>Aggrey Muganga is the team leader at Tupande Holdings Ltd. He said his company deals with more than 60 farmers who continuously supply surplus raw material.</p>
<p>That number is only a small part of what is available in a country where banana crops makes up more than a million hectares of land.</p>
<p>Banana production has been increasing over the years. The Uganda Bureau of Statistics found that banana production rose from 6.5 metric tons in 2018 to 8.3 metric tons in 2019.</p>
<p>Muganga said that they put extra income in the hands of the farmers. He added, "We turn this waste into something valuable that we sell to our partners who also make things."</p>
<p>At a plant just outside the Ugandan capital Kampala, TEXFAD employs more than 30 people who use their hands to make products from banana fiber. The company is now exporting some products to Europe.</p>
<p>Such products are possible because "banana fiber can be softened to the level of cotton," Okello said.</p>
<p>The company can make some paper products with the material. It is working with researchers to experiment with possible cloth from banana fiber. However, it does not have the technology to make clothing, Okello said.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Patrick Onen and Rodney Muhumuza reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stem </strong>– <em>n</em>. the main long and thin part of a plant that rises above the soil and supports the leaves and flowers</p>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong>– <em>adj</em>. involving methods that do not completely use up or destroy natural resources</p>
<p><strong>rotting </strong>– <em>adj</em>. to decay due to the action of fungi or bacteria</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>As Tensions Rise, Canadian Colleges Confirm Indian Students Welcome  (2023/10/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/as-tensions-rise-canadian-colleges-confirm-indian-students-welcome.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Canadian universities are confirming the safety of their Indian students and providing resources after a diplomatic crisis between the two countries.</p>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau publicly accused the Indian government of being involved in the killing of an Indian separatist leader in Canada. India deplores the accusation.</p>
<p>As Canadian colleges prepare to open classes, some students are considering delaying their studies. Others are wondering whether higher education could be damaged in the current crisis.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6941-08dbcb2ac7cd_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>India by far supplies the most students to Canada's fast-growing international education business. About 40 percent of study permit holders are from India. International students provide over $14.6 billion to the Canadian economy each year.</p>
<p>Estimates by professionals in India show that over 100,000 students are preparing for an English language test and organizing financing to study in Canada next year.</p>
<p>Top universities offer programs costing up to $29,000 a year. Colleges provide short-term, less costly programs. They are connecting with students to confirm the diplomatic disagreement does not damage one of Canada's better-known exports.</p>
<p>Reporters from Reuters news agency spoke to numerous universities and professionals in Canada and India who said they were taking measures to reduce students' questions or fears.</p>
<p>Joseph Wong is vice president of the University of Toronto. He said the university has reached out to many partners in India to confirm they are committed to continuing cooperation. The University of Toronto had more than 2,400 international students from India in 2022-2023.</p>
<p>Canadian universities say the diplomatic disagreement may only be temporary. But Ashok Kumar Bhatia, President of the Association of Consultants for Overseas Studies, said many Indian students have become concerned about their safety.</p>
<p>Companies like IDP Education have been sending video messages in an effort to calm nerves.</p>
<p>John Tibbits is president of Conestoga College in Ontario. He noted about a hundred students out of the thousands that register every year were asking about delaying their study. Some current students were also seeking to attend classes online.</p>
<p>"Our biggest concern is the <strong>uncertainty</strong>. What might the Indian government do as far as visas and how might people react," Tibbits said. "We are spending $36 million a year for college on just support for students."</p>
<p>International education has seen strong growth in recent years, helping the industry become one of Canada's biggest exports. Education tops auto parts, building materials and airplanes.</p>
<p>York University's President Rhonda Lenton was in India when news of the dispute broke. She said she is sure the two governments will be able to eventually resolve the situation.</p>
<p>But in the Indian state of Punjab, families and hopeful students are worried. An estimated 25 percent of families in the state have a member studying or preparing to study in Canada. Over 5,000 students from one city in Punjab moved to Canada last year.</p>
<p>Taxi-driver Jiwan Sharma is considering whether his son should complete his recent travel plans to Canada.</p>
<p>"I have put my lifelong savings worth over 250 million rupees ($4 million) for sending our son to Canada, hoping he would settle there, and help us in old age."</p>
<p>Tensions do not seem to be decreasing. After a report that India's government asked Canada to withdraw 41 diplomats, Canadian Foreign Minister Melanie Joly said Canada wants private talks with India to resolve the diplomatic dispute.</p>
<p>Gurbakhshish Singh, a student in Punjab, told Reuters he is sad that India's relationship with a welcoming country like Canada has worsened.</p>
<p>"The government has put our future in <strong>jeopardy</strong>," the student said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Nivedita Balu, Wa Lone, and Manoj Kumar reported this story for Reuters. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>uncertainty</strong>–<em>n</em>. unknown, not knowing for sure</p>
<p><strong>jeopardy</strong>–<em>n</em>. danger of loss, harm or failure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Bad Side of Roses  (2023/10/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/the-bad-side-of-roses.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On today's program, let's talk about flowers; but not just any flowers -- roses.</p>
<p>Who doesn't love a beautiful, sweet-smelling rose? The ancient Greeks and Romans connected roses with Aphrodite and Venus, the goddess of love. In modern times, you give a red rose to your true love and a yellow one to your true friend.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Paola Orsero of Alassio, Italy smells a rose at the Royal Horticultural Society's Chelsea Flower Show in London, Britain May 19, 2015. (REUTERS/Suzanne Plunkett)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/59DFC099-9D3B-4726-9285-3E2B18BCD87C_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Paola Orsero of Alassio, Italy smells a rose at the Royal Horticultural Society's Chelsea Flower Show in London, Britain May 19, 2015. (REUTERS/Suzanne Plunkett)</span></div>
<p>But roses also have a bad side -- thorns.</p>
<p>A thorn is the very sharp part of some woody plants, like blackberry bushes and roses. A <strong>prick</strong> from a thorn is painful and can cause you to bleed. So, a rose has both beauty and pain.</p>
<p>That is where the saying <u>every rose has its thorns</u> comes from. It means that rarely is something completely good. Even a very pleasant thing, event, or situation can have a bad or unpleasant side. You also could say, <u>there's no rose without a thorn</u>.</p>
<p>Actually, there are some kinds of roses without thorns. But let's not <strong>go down that garden path</strong> and just stay with our expression for today.</p>
<p>Now, here is an example of how to use the expression, <u>every rose has its thorns</u>.</p>
<p>Let's say you were on a game show and won a new car and a trip to Mexico. You are very excited but then find out that you must pay taxes on all the winnings. As you get ready to pay the big tax bill, you could say: "Well, <u>every rose has its thorns</u>."</p>
<p>"Thorn" has another meaning. It can also be something or someone that bothers you. A<u> thorn in your side</u> is a small problem, not a serious one. After all, thorns cause pain, but they are not going to kill you.</p>
<p>A friend who always borrows money from you could become <u>a thorn in your side</u>. She is <strong>annoying</strong> but not a serious problem. But what if her money troubles led to bigger problems for her?</p>
<p>Let's say she cannot pay her bills, and she is in danger of losing her home. In that situation, we can say she has made for herself <u>a bed of thorns</u>. This expression describes a painful, difficult, or unpleasant situation.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if she finds a way to make a lot of money, and she can pay off her <strong>debt</strong>, we can say she is now <u>sleeping in a bed of roses</u>. That is a really pleasant place to be.</p>
<p>Sometimes though, we use <u>a bed of roses</u> in a <strong>negative</strong> form to describe an unpleasant situation, like in this example:</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, how's everything going? A couple of months ago you told me you were struggling to pay your bills. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I was totally <strong>broke</strong>. I had no money at all.</em></p>
<p><em>A: That sounds really stressful. </em></p>
<p><em>A: It was <u>no bed of roses</u>; I can tell you that! I can't tell you how happy I am to be out of debt!</em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. We hope that your English studies have not become <u>a thorn in your side</u>. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>prick </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to pierce slightly with a sharp point</p>
<p><strong>go down that garden path </strong><em>- idiom</em><strong> </strong>to cause (someone) to go, think, or proceed wrongly</p>
<p><strong>annoying </strong><em>– v. </em>causing irritation</p>
<p><strong>debt </strong><em>– v. </em>something owed</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong><em>– v. </em>marked by denial, prohibition, or refusal</p>
<p><strong>broke </strong><em>– v. </em>having no money</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Harry Truman: Atomic  (2023/10/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/americas-presidents-harry-truman.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Harry S. Truman. He became president of the United States in 1945, a few weeks before the end of World War II in Europe.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Harry Truman" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/756acee7-2ebb-4ed7-ad98-eb9bb6412e04_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Harry Truman</span></div>
<p>Truman took office after Franklin Roosevelt died suddenly of a cerebral hemorrhage.</p>
<p>Roosevelt had been president for 12 years. But Truman was new to the position of vice president. Two other men had earlier served in the office under Roosevelt.</p>
<p>On April 12, 1945 – less than three months after he became vice president – Truman was called to the White House. There, Roosevelt's wife, Eleanor, told Truman about her husband's death. Truman was quickly <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.defensemedianetwork.com/stories/harry-trumans-long-day-on-april-12-1945/">sworn-in as president</a>.</p>
<p>Shortly after the ceremony, the secretary of war privately told Truman about a secret project involving American scientists. They were building an extremely destructive atomic bomb.</p>
<p>Historians debate whether Truman already knew about the project, or whether the information was a complete surprise.</p>
<p>In either case, the new president had to decide whether to use the weapon, which he called "the most terrible bomb in the history of the world."</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Harry Truman came from simple beginnings. He was born in the state of Missouri. He, his parents, a brother and a sister lived in the town of Independence.</p>
<p>As a boy, Harry Truman helped his father on the family's farm, but he did not enjoy the work. And he could not play sports because he could not see very well; from the time he was a child, Truman wore eyeglasses.</p>
<p>So he developed his interests in reading and music. He was an especially good piano player.</p>
<p>Truman was also a good student, but his parents did not have enough money to send him to a four-year college.</p>
<p>Instead, Truman worked in a number of jobs, including as a bank clerk, mining company operator, and partner in an oil business.</p>
<p>When the United States became involved in World War I, Truman decided to re-join the National Guard. His guard unit became part of the U.S. Army, and Truman earned a position as a captain.</p>
<p>Truman experienced real success in the military. He was an able soldier and leader, and he and his troops fought in battle. When the war ended, Truman kept both the feeling of<strong> self-confidence</strong> and the friendships with the other solders he had formed.</p>
<p>One of Truman's first acts after the war was to get married. He married a woman from his hometown. They had been <strong>romantically</strong> linked for a long time. Her name was <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/besstruman">Elizabeth Wallace</a>, but she was called Bess. The Trumans remained happily married for more than 50 years and had a daughter named Mary Margaret.</p>
<p>In the first years after the war, Harry Truman opened a men's clothing shop with a friend from the military. But the shop – called a <strong>haberdashery</strong> -- eventually failed.</p>
<p>Truman soon found a new line of work. An operative from the Democratic Party asked Truman to be a candidate for a position as a judge.</p>
<p>Truman won the seat, as well as a public <strong>reputation</strong> for being an honest, effective public servant.</p>
<p>In time, Truman successfully won election to a seat in the U.S. Senate. For the most part, he earned a good public image there, too. He supported the social programs of President Roosevelt, and he tried to prevent big businesses or large labor unions from misusing public money.</p>
<p>Both voters and Democratic officials liked Truman enough to accept him as the party's vice presidential candidate in 1944. Truman performed well as a candidate, but he did not have a close relationship with Roosevelt or play much of a part in his government.</p>
<p>Yet in a few weeks, following Roosevelt's death, Truman was leading the country.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>Truman faced a number of difficult decisions during his two terms as president. Many of them involved foreign policy. His actions helped shape the second half of the 20<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>In his first months after taking office, Truman watched the end of World War II in Europe.</p>
<p>He then had to decide how to deal with the war in the Pacific. Japan did not want to accept the Allied forces' demand for total surrender. And Truman did not want to extend the war.</p>
<p>So he approved using the atomic bomb on Japan. Truman directed the secretary of war to drop the weapon on military targets and try to reduce civilian deaths. But the destruction was still terrible.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/08/06/world/asia/btn-atomic-bombs/index.html">An estimated</a> 192,000 people died in the attack or the effects of the bomb in Hiroshima. Most of the city was destroyed.</p>
<p>Three days later, the U.S. military dropped another atomic bomb, this time on the city of Nagasaki. More than 70,000 people died instantly.</p>
<p>The emperor of Japan called the weapon "a new and most cruel bomb." He agreed to his country's surrender on August 14, 1945. World War II came to an end.</p>
<p>Truman and his government quickly had to make other decisions about how to react to the new international situation. One of the most pressing concerns was the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Soviet officials sought to expand their influence around the country's borders, especially in Eastern Europe, Turkey and Iran. Truman and other U.S. officials believed those moves threatened American interests. The United States supported democracy and capitalism. It did not want the Soviet Union's form of communism to spread.</p>
<p>So Truman's government put in place two measures to answer the Soviet Union's influence.</p>
<p>One was a policy known as the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://history.state.gov/milestones/1945-1952/truman-doctrine">Truman Doctrine</a>. It promised American support to Greece, Turkey and other democratic nations against <strong>authoritarian</strong> forces. The measure was a new step for the United States. In the past, the country had tried to avoid conflicts that did not directly involve it.</p>
<p>Under Truman, the U.S. government was committed to helping "free peoples" anywhere by improving their living conditions.</p>
<p>A second measure came to be called the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://history.state.gov/milestones/1945-1952/marshall-plan">Marshall Plan</a>, after Truman's secretary of state, George Marshall. Marshall wanted the United States to invest a large amount of money in rebuilding Europe after World War II. Because the Soviet Union controlled much of Eastern Europe, the money eventually went to improving the market economy of Western Europe.</p>
<p>The office of the historian at the State Department notes that one effect of the Marshall Plan was to <strong>introduce</strong> foreign aid programs as an official part of U.S. foreign policy.</p>
<p>Truman also sought to guarantee peace and contain communism in other ways. He supported the United Nations, which was officially launched during his presidency.</p>
<p>And he negotiated a military alliance among Western, democratic nations. The group became known as the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or NATO.</p>
<p>Military alliances became especially important in 1950 when communist forces in North Korea invaded South Korea. The U.N. agreed to send troops to help South Korea -- although many of the troops were American, and they were led by an <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/douglas-macarthur">American general</a>.</p>
<p>Fighting in the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/korean-war">Korean War </a>lasted until 1953. As many as 5 million people died in the conflict. Neither side gained much territory.</p>
<p>But the Korean War had other effects. It fueled the Cold War between communist and democratic forces. It showed the U.S. would really defend other countries against authoritarian forces. It sharply increased Americans' spending on the defense industry.</p>
<p>And it helped make President Truman very unpopular.</p>
<p>Many Americans believed Truman was losing the battle against communism. During his presidency, the Soviet Union successfully tested a nuclear weapon, and China officially became a communist country under Mao Zedong.</p>
<p>Some U.S. lawmakers even accused Truman's government of protecting communist spies. Senator Joseph McCarthy was the most famous of these critics. He launched investigations against thousands of U.S. government employees, as well as movie actors and directors in Hollywood.</p>
<p>McCarthy did not have evidence that these people were secretly working for the Soviet Union. But his campaign helped fuel the public's concerns over communism, a fear that came to be called the Red Scare.</p>
<p>Truman grew tired of the accusations, as well as other political battles. He decided not to seek re-election in 1952.</p>
<p>Instead, he retired with his wife to their home in Missouri.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>At first, many Americans had mixed emotions about Truman's presidency. For the most part, they did not support the Korean War. And they remained suspicious that his government had included communist supporters.</p>
<p>But Truman's public reputation rose over time. He became known as a down-to-earth person who would and could fight if needed. His supporters liked to say, "Give ‘em Hell, Harry."</p>
<p>Truman is also remembered for taking some steps toward ensuring equal rights for all Americans. Truman supported the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.ourdocuments.gov/doc.php?flash=true&amp;doc=84">racial <strong>desegregation </strong>of the military</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.trumanlibrary.org/executiveorders/index.php?pid=29">banned racial discrimination in the civil service</a>.</p>
<p>But Truman is probably best remembered for the difficult decisions he made during his presidency, especially the one to drop atomic bombs on Japan. To the end of his life, he accepted responsibility for the decision and did not apologize for it.</p>
<p>Truman died of natural causes at the age of 88. His remains are buried at his presidential library in Independence, Missouri.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p>________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>self-confidence </strong>- <em>n.</em> confidence in oneself and in one's powers and abilities</p>
<p><strong>romance </strong>- <em>n.</em> love affair</p>
<p><strong>haberdashery </strong>-<em> n</em>. a shop selling notions or men's clothing and accessories</p>
<p><strong>reputation</strong> - <em>n.</em> overall quality or character as seen or judged by people in general</p>
<p><strong>authoritarian</strong> - <em>n. </em>of, relating to, or favoring a concentration of power in a leader or an elite not constitutionally responsible to the people</p>
<p><strong>introduce</strong> -<em> v. </em>to lead or bring in especially for the first time</p>
<p><strong>desegregate</strong> - <em>v.</em> to free of any law, provision, or practice requiring isolation of the members of a particular race in separate units</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Learn Another ‘Mona Lisa’ Secret  (2023/10/14) | 科学家们发现《蒙娜丽莎》又一秘密</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-learn-another-mona-lisa-secret.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The Mona Lisa is the famous Leonardo da Vinci painting of a woman with a mysterious smile.<br/>
《蒙娜丽莎》是列奥纳多·达·芬奇的名画，画中的女人带着神秘的微笑。</p>
<p>This week, the painting gave up a secret.<br/>
本周，这幅画泄露了一个秘密。</p>
<p>Scientists used X-rays to examine the chemical structure of an extremely small part of the more than 500-year-old painting. The researchers discovered a technique Leonardo used in the work.<br/>
科学家们用X射线检查了这幅有500多年历史的画作中一个极小部分的化学结构。研究人员发现了达·芬奇在这副作品中使用的一种技术。</p>
<p>A team in France and Britain discovered an oil paint used for the Mona Lisa was a special, new chemical mixture.<br/>
法国和英国的一个研究小组发现，蒙娜丽莎使用的油画颜料是一种特殊的新型化学混合物。</p>
<p>The research was published Wednesday in the Journal of the American Chemical Society. It suggests that the Italian artist may have been in an experimental mood when he set to work on the painting early in the 16th century.<br/>
这项研究于周三发表在《美国化学学会杂志》上。研究表明，这位意大利艺术家在16世纪初开始创作这幅画时，可能一直处于实验状态。</p>
<p>"He was someone who loved to experiment, and each of his paintings is completely different technically," said Victor Gonzalez. He is the study's lead writer and a chemist at France's top research organization, the National Center for Scientific Research (CNRS). Gonzalez has studied the chemical makeup of several works by Leonardo, Rembrandt and other artists.<br/>
维克多·冈萨雷斯说：“达·芬奇是一个喜欢实验的人，他的每幅画在技术层面上都是完全不同的。”冈萨雷斯是这项研究的主要作者，也是法国顶级研究机构国家科学研究中心的化学家。冈萨雷斯研究了达·芬奇、伦勃朗和其他艺术家的几件作品的化学成分。</p>
<p>"In this case, it's interesting to see that indeed there is a specific technique for the ground layer of Mona Lisa," he said in an interview with The Associated Press.<br/>
他在接受美联社采访时说：“在这种情况下，很有趣的是，《蒙娜丽莎》的画作底层确实使用了特殊的技术。”</p>
<p> Specifically, the researchers found a rare compound, plumbonacrite, in Leonardo's first layer of paint. The discovery, Gonzalez said, confirmed that da Vinci most likely used lead oxide to thicken and help dry his paint.<br/>
具体来说，研究人员在达·芬奇画作的第一层油漆中发现了一种罕见的铅化合物。冈萨雷斯说，这一发现证实了达·芬奇很可能使用氧化铅来增稠和帮助颜料干燥。</p>
<p>Carmen Bambach, a specialist in Italian art at New York's Metropolitan Museum of Art, called the research "very exciting." Bambach, who was not involved in the study, said it shows "Leonardo's spirit of passionate and constant experimentation as a painter," she wrote in an email.<br/>
纽约大都会艺术博物馆的意大利艺术专家卡门·班巴赫称这项研究“非常令人兴奋”。班巴赫没有参与这项研究，她在一封电子邮件中写道，这表明了“达·芬奇作为一名画家充满激情和不断实验的精神”。</p>
<p>The speck of paint in the imaging study is about the thickness of a human hair. It lies in the top right area of the painting.<br/>
成像研究中的油漆斑点大约有一根头发的厚度。它位于画作的右上角。</p>
<p>The scientists looked into its atomic structure using X-rays in a synchrotron. The machine moves particles at close to the speed of light, permitting researchers to look deeper into the paint structure.<br/>
科学家们利用同步加速器中的X射线研究了它的原子结构。该机器以接近光速的速度移动颗粒，使研究人员能够更深入地观察油漆结构。</p>
<p>"Plumbonacrite is really a fingerprint of his recipe," Gonzalez said. "It's the first time we can actually chemically confirm it."<br/>
冈萨雷斯说：“铅化合物确实是他配方中的特征，这是我们第一次真正用化学方法确认它。”</p>
<p>Dutch artist Rembrandt may have used a similar mixture when he was painting in the 17th century. Gonzalez and other researchers have found plumbonacrite in his work, too.<br/>
荷兰艺术家伦勃朗在17世纪绘画时可能使用了类似的混合物。冈萨雷斯和其他研究人员也在他的作品中发现了铅化合物。</p>
<p>"It tells us also that those recipes were passed on for centuries," Gonzalez said. "It was a very good recipe."<br/>
冈萨雷斯说：“它还告诉我们，这些配方已经流传了几个世纪，这是一种非常好的配方。”</p>
<p>Leonardo is thought to have melted lead oxide powder, which has an orange color, in linseed or walnut oil to make it thicker and dry faster.<br/>
达·芬奇被认为将橙色的氧化铅粉末融化在亚麻籽或核桃油中，使其更粘稠、干燥更快。</p>
<p>"What you will obtain is an oil that has a very nice golden color," Gonzalez said. "It flows more like honey."<br/>
冈萨雷斯说：“你会得到一种非常漂亮的金色的油，它流动起来更像蜂蜜。”</p>
<p>But the Mona Lisa — said by the Louvre to be a portrait of Lisa Gherardini, the wife of a Florentine silk merchant — and additional works by Leonardo still have other secrets to tell.<br/>
但是，《蒙娜丽莎》和达·芬奇的其他作品还有其他秘密要讲，卢浮宫称《蒙娜丽莎》是佛罗伦萨一位丝绸商人的妻子丽莎·格拉迪尼的肖像。</p>
<p>"There are plenty, plenty more things to discover," Gonzalez said. "What we are saying is just a little brick more in the knowledge."<br/>
冈萨雷斯说：“还有很多很多东西等待被发现，我们所说的只是这些知识里的一小部分。”</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Largest Modern Hindu Temple outside India Ready to Open in US  (2023/10/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/largest-modern-hindu-temple-outside-india-ready-to-open-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The largest Hindu religious site outside India in modern times opens to the public Monday in the American state of New Jersey. Its creators began planning the BAPS Swaminarayan Akshardham 12 years ago.</p>
<p>Artisans and volunteers spent 4.7 million hours <strong>carving </strong>by hand the temple's two million cubic feet of rock. The rock material includes marble from Italy and limestone from Bulgaria. The material was sent to India for the carving work.</p>
<p>Then, the finished pieces arrived in New Jersey. Workers fitted them together in the city of Robbinsville to build the temple. The building stands on a 51-hectare property.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Monks walk in front of the BAPS Swaminarayan Akshardham, the largest Hindu temple outside India in the modern era, on Oct. 4, 2023, in Robbinsville, N.J. (AP Photo/Luis Andres Henao)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-d81d-08dbcb3d0981_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Monks walk in front of the BAPS Swaminarayan Akshardham, the largest Hindu temple outside India in the modern era, on Oct. 4, 2023, in Robbinsville, N.J. (AP Photo/Luis Andres Henao)</span></div>
<p>The largest Hindu temple in the world is in Cambodia. The Ankgor Wat was built in the 12th century during the Khmer Empire.</p>
<p>It is now described as a Hindu-Buddhist temple, and is a UNESCO World Heritage site.</p>
<p>The Robbinsville temple is one of many built by BAPS, a worldwide religious and civic organization within the Swaminarayan <strong>sect</strong> of Hinduism.</p>
<p>The organization has built two other Akshardhams, or houses of the <strong>divine</strong>. One is in the capital of New Delhi and the other is in the Gujarat state, where BAPS is based. The sect operates more than 1,200 temples and 3,850 centers around the world. It will celebrate its 50th year in North America next year.</p>
<p>BAPS faced criticism in recent years after workers launched a legal action against the group in 2021. The action accused BAPS of carrying out policies including forced labor, low wages and bad working conditions.</p>
<p>Twelve of the 19 plaintiffs have now withdrawn their accusations and the legal action is suspended while an investigation continues.</p>
<p>The legal action claimed that Dalits, or members of the lowest caste in India, were being abused. Caste is an ancient system of social standing based on ancestry.</p>
<p>Yogi Trivedi is an expert on Hinduism at Columbia University, and a member of the religion. He said these accusations weighed heavily on community members because their religion has always taught them "to see the divine in all..."</p>
<p>"Caste and class do not divide us," Trivedi said.</p>
<p>He said the temple would not have been possible without the service of thousands of volunteers. Many of them took time off school and work to serve in different areas. This might be the first Hindu temple where women were involved in building it, Trivedi added.</p>
<p>This week, families from across the country, have been going to the site to see it from the outside.</p>
<p>Nikita Patel and her husband were among the volunteers who gave their time to create the temple.</p>
<p>"All religions, all communities are welcome here," she said, "And here, they will feel the peace."</p>
<p>Trivedi holds a similar opinion. To him, the temple stands for universal values that can be found in writings and ideas of all religions.</p>
<p>"It's not even just Indian or Indian American," Trivedi said. "What we've tried to do is express these universal values in a way that relate to all visitors."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>carve </strong><em>— v. </em> to make by cutting off pieces of the material it is made of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sect </strong><em>— n. </em>a religious group that is a smaller part of a larger group and whose members all share similar beliefs</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>divine </strong><em>— adj. </em>relating to or coming from God or a god</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Historic and Historical  (2023/10/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/historic-and-historical.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! Our question for today on <em>Ask a Teacher</em> comes from a reader in China.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Dear VOA team,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b640-08dbcb4ac044_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I happened to find a question that I'm confused about. When I was <strong>surfing </strong>the web, I found "historic" and "historical" are both adjectives. Are there any differences between them? Can you explain how to use them? Thanks.</p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p><strong><em>Albert, China </em></strong></p>
<p>Dear Albert,</p>
<p>This is an interesting question. The differences between these two words have grown over the years not based on their grammatical form, but on how people have used them. So, let's start by taking a look at what the Merriam-Webster online dictionary says about the ways people use the words.</p>
<p><strong>Historic</strong></p>
<p>The word "historic" is used for important and famous events in history. Here are two examples of that use.</p>
<p><em>The weather reporter warned of a big storm coming that will be of historic <strong>proportions</strong>.</em></p>
<p><em>Will you come to Washington, D.C. and be part of this historic event?</em></p>
<p>In these two examples, we see "historic" used for a storm and for a gathering. The word "historic" might also appear when people talk about sports.</p>
<p>You can also see the word used to describe places. In the United States, we have an organization that has information on important places, for example, the home of a former president. Here is a statement using that phrase, "historic places<em>."</em></p>
<p><em>That home is listed on the National Register of Historic Places.</em></p>
<p>And many local organizations fix up old buildings that are part of their town's history. This process is called "historic preservation."</p>
<p><em>In this neighborhood, homeowners care a lot about historic preservation.</em></p>
<p><strong>Historical </strong></p>
<p>Moving on to the word "historical," we find it used to describe history, as in "the<em> </em>historical record<em>."</em> It appears more often than the word "historic" and also appears with words like <strong>perspective</strong>, literature, and <strong>analysis</strong>. Here are some examples.</p>
<p><em>Historical evidence suggests wolves are both man's best friend and his worst enemy.</em></p>
<p><em>Isabel Allende wrote many works of historical fiction.</em></p>
<p>To sum up, if the thing itself is important or famous, you would probably use "historic"<em> </em>with it. If the thing you are talking about relates to history, something real in the past, use the word "historical."<em> </em></p>
<p>I hope this clarifies the use of these two words for you, Albert. And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em> for this week. Do you have a question for the teacher? Write to us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surf –</strong><em>v</em>. to look through information in search of something interesting or useful</p>
<p><strong>proportion </strong>– <em>n. </em>the relationship between the qualities of at least two things, for example, in size</p>
<p><strong>perspective</strong><em> – n.</em> a way of thinking about something, especially one that is influenced by your beliefs or experiences</p>
<p><strong>analysis</strong> – <em>n.</em> the process of considering something carefully or using statistical methods in order to understand it or explain it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift Releases 'Eras Tour' Movie  (2023/10/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/taylor-swift-releases-eras-tour-movie.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>"Look what you...made me do," entertainer Taylor Swift wrote on social media as she <strong>premiered</strong> <em>Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour</em> movie Wednesday night in Los Angeles, California.</p>
<p>In the music business, a tour is a series of live shows held in many cities.</p>
<p>The pop superstar announced, "We're opening up early access showings of The Eras Tour Concert Film on THURSDAY in America and Canada!!"</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Taylor Swift arrives at the world premiere of the concert film Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour on Wednesday, Oct. 11, 2023, at AMC The Grove 14 in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f60b-08dbcb2e698d_cx0_cy0_cw79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Taylor Swift arrives at the world premiere of the concert film "Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour" on Wednesday, Oct. 11, 2023, at AMC The Grove 14 in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)</span></div>
<p>The film of Swift's live performances was first planned to open on Friday. It is expected to launch with $100 million in <strong>ticket</strong> sales for the opening weekend. But early ticket sales worldwide have already been estimated to reach $140 million.</p>
<p><strong>Entertainers</strong> have released films of live performances for many years. The Korean group BTS released its <strong>concert</strong> film earlier this year. Last month, the rock band Talking Heads released such a movie after many years away from the industry.</p>
<p>But this movie release from Swift is unusual.</p>
<p>Greg Marcus is the chief executive of Marcus Corporation which runs a group of movie theaters in the United States. "This is different," Marcus said. "Take your phone out. Take <strong>selfies</strong>. Dance, sing, get up, have a good time. We want to create an atmosphere."</p>
<p>Unlike many Hollywood productions, <em>The Eras Tour</em> movie does not need any outside advertising. Swift produced the film herself and informed her 274 million followers on Instagram.</p>
<p>The film will play in movie theaters for at least 13 weeks. Adult tickets are being sold for $19.89. That is higher than the average movie ticket price but several thousand less than some tickets to see Swift live.</p>
<p>Late on Wednesday, Swift arrived at an AMC Theatre in Los Angeles. She took pictures with fans at the premiere.</p>
<p>Inside the theater, Swift thanked fans for supporting the Eras Tour, which organizers say sold all available tickets for large <strong>stadium</strong> performances around the world. "I've never had this much fun in my life as I had at the Eras Tour," she said.</p>
<p>Swift is returning to the ongoing Eras Tour next month with live performances planned in Argentina and Brazil. After that, the tour will head to Japan, Australia, Singapore and several countries in Europe.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and Reuters sources. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>premier</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to hold an event in which a movie or performance is shown for the first time</p>
<p><strong>ticket</strong> <em>–n.</em> a document you pay money for which lets you see a show, performance, or to travel on a vehicle</p>
<p><strong>entertainer </strong>–n. a person who performs for money</p>
<p><strong>concert </strong>–n. a musical performance</p>
<p><strong>selfie </strong>–n. a picture of oneself taken using the front facing camera on a smart phone</p>
<p><strong>stadium </strong>–n. a huge structure, often without a top, in which thousands of people watch sports and big events</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Marines Slow to Combine Women, Men in Training  (2023/10/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/us-marines-slow-to-combine-women-men-in-training.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Marines have officially begun combining men and women during their first major training exercises called boot camp. But so far, military leaders appear to be moving slowly to fully join the two sexes together during all training activities.</p>
<p>Reporters from the Associated Press recently visited a Marine Corps base in South Carolina that combines male and female boot camp training. They observed the training exercises and spoke with leaders about the Marines' current policy.</p>
<p>During intense heat at Marine Base Parris Island, two young <strong>recruits</strong> were battling inside a training space. Circling them, a training commander shouted orders, "Hit her! Punch her! DO something!"</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A group of U.S. Marine Corps recruits wait inline before swim training at the Marine Corps Recruit Depot pool, Wednesday, June 28, 2023, in Parris Island, S.C. (AP Photo/Stephen B. Morton)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-bdf4-08dbcb1d08ab_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A group of U.S. Marine Corps recruits wait inline before swim training at the Marine Corps Recruit Depot pool, Wednesday, June 28, 2023, in Parris Island, S.C. (AP Photo/Stephen B. Morton)</span></div>
<p>Outside the space were a mix of male and female Marine hopefuls. The recruits are appointed to one of the mixed-sex companies, or large military groups. The Marine Corps is moving slowly— and at times unwillingly— to combine training women and men at boot camp, the Associated Press reports.</p>
<p>Sometimes the joint training has been successful. Other times not.</p>
<p>In the training space, men and women are together while completing timed physical exercises or practicing firing guns. But the line of recruits around the swimming pool outside presents the opposite. There, companies are broken up into smaller groups called platoons. The platoons remain separated by sex. As the recruits line up, there is a small group of women standing at the front with groups of men behind them.</p>
<p>The boot camp training methods suggest Marine Corps leaders still intensely believe there must be some separation in training.</p>
<p><strong>Marine deactivated training unit</strong></p>
<p>It has been nearly eight years since the defense secretary at the time ordered all fighting-related jobs open to women. But the Marine Corps just deactivated a training unit at Parris Island this summer. The unit was created in 1986 to accept women.</p>
<p>Many Marine Corps officers forcefully defend the training separation. Some leaders have strongly expressed the belief that women can grow more <strong>confident</strong> quickly if they are not directly competing with often larger or stronger males.</p>
<p>Under pressure from Congress, the Marines Corps changed the unit for women into a mixed-sex group in recent years. It then officially deactivated it in June. The remaining recruit companies are either mixed-sex or all male.</p>
<p>Inside the pool, men and women struggle side by side, jumping into the water and swimming to the other end. Boot camp trainers are also a mix of men and women. They stand on the edge of the pool ready to throw a float or jump in if needed.</p>
<p>But outside, an all-male group of recruits moves through the woods. The individuals drop to move forward on their hands and knees across a stretch of burning hot sand. A second group training outside also includes no women.</p>
<p>General Walker Field, who leads Marine Base Parris Island, told the AP he believes keeping the platoons separated by sex is an important part of forming successful Marines.</p>
<p>Field explained that the Marine Corps has established proven training methods over the years. Part of this process involves breaking down recruits and then building them back up as successful team members. Field argued that the platoon model is especially important to that success.</p>
<p>Field said keeping platoons all male or female permits leaders to provide exactly what is needed for each group when they are together in the evenings. He added that being the same sex at the platoon level also makes it easier for leaders to make the best training decisions at all times.</p>
<p>Lieutenant Colonel Aixa Dones is one female Marine officer who strongly supports a continued separation. Dones served as the last commander of Parris Island's women-only unit before it was deactivated this year. She was also a recruit there and says about the experience, "I can't imagine it having gone any other way."</p>
<p>Sergeant Maria Torres is a training commander. She told the AP she thinks combining companies is a necessary, first step. But expanding it to the platoon level might have poor results, so "we'd have to start small," Torres added.</p>
<p><strong>Many disagree</strong></p>
<p>But many people disagree. They say keeping platoons separate only reinforces the idea that women are not considered equal and should be treated differently.</p>
<p>Erin Kirk is a former Marine sergeant who went through the separated training in 2010. She remembers how male recruits looked down on women in the unit, with some even criticizing the females and calling them names. The split, she said, divided them into "male Marines" and "female Marines." She believes that shaped how the men saw the women. It made it more difficult for them to work together as they moved along.</p>
<p>"It made you feel like you weren't part of the team. It made it difficult to be seen as a real Marine," said Kirk, who served for five years. She believes mixed-sex platoons would be a good way for women to be seen as equals and not as "other" recruits.</p>
<p>When asked about those issues, Lieutenant Dones disagreed that the separation presents problems for women. "Our female platoons have been outperforming our male teams, and we have had more female company honor graduates than we have had male," she said.</p>
<p>Some young female recruits spoke to the AP about the current recruitment process.</p>
<p>Nicole Momura said she chose to join the Marine Corps because she thought it was the hardest military branch. "This recruit was looking for something bigger than herself," the 22-year-old added. Momura is not concerned about the platoon separation, saying, "We're all going to be working together in <strong>the fleet</strong>."</p>
<p>Another recruit, 19-year-old Nubia Delatorre, said she is <strong>proud</strong> to be a member of the second female platoon in her company. But she admits the men and women do not interact very much. She said the females are not permitted to talk to the males.</p>
<p>However, Delatorre said she believes women and men get the same training. In her case, she said she decided to join the Marines because she wanted "to prove to myself that I could do something hard."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Lolita C. Baldor reported this story for the Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recruit</strong>–<em>n</em>. someone who is in the process of joining the armed forces but isn't fully trained yet</p>
<p><strong>confident</strong>–<em>adj</em>. strong belief in yourself</p>
<p><strong>the fleet</strong>–<em>n</em>. full military operational units; not training</p>
<p><strong>proud</strong>–<em>adj</em>. feeling very pleased about something you have done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Causing Toxic Smoke across Southeast Asia?  (2023/10/13) | 是什么导致了东南亚的有毒雾霾？</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/what-is-causing-toxic-smoke-across-southeast-asia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The problem of cross-country smoke, or haze, has caused a new disagreement in Southeast Asia.<br/>
跨国雾霾问题在东南亚引起了新的分歧。</p>
<p>Malaysia's environment minister wrote to Indonesia's government this week calling for action to help reduce smoke across Malaysia.<br/>
马来西亚环境部长本周致信印尼政府，呼吁采取行动帮助减少马来西亚各地的雾霾。</p>
<p>The letter comes just weeks after countries in Southeast Asia agreed to a haze-free area by 2030.<br/>
就在发出这封信的几周前，东南亚国家同意在2030年前建立一个无雾霾区。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What is going on?<br/>
发生了什么事？</span></p>
<p>In recent weeks, air quality reports in parts of Malaysia and Indonesia have reached readings above 150. This puts conditions at a level where people can experience unhealthy effects. And those with existing health problems could suffer greater greater health problems.<br/>
最近几周，马来西亚和印度尼西亚部分地区的空气质量报告的读数已达到150以上。这将使人们面临不健康影响。而那些存在健康问题的人可能会遭受更严重的健康问题。</p>
<p>On the Indonesian side of Borneo Island, visibility was reduced to less than 10 meters. Schools are closed in both Indonesia and Malaysia to reduce the health effects on young children.<br/>
在印尼一侧的婆罗洲岛，能见度降低到不足10米。印度尼西亚和马来西亚的学校都停课以减少对幼儿健康的影响。</p>
<p>Malaysia has blamed the haze on Indonesia, saying smoke from forest fires is being pushed across the border.<br/>
马来西亚将雾霾归咎于印尼，称森林大火产生的雾霾正被吹向边境。</p>
<p>Every few years, during the dry season, smoke from "slash and burn" land clearing takes over much of the area. Slash and burn is a method in agriculture to cut down and burn plants to clear land for planting.<br/>
每隔几年，在旱季，“刀耕火种”清理土地产生的雾霾就会占据该地区的大部分地区。“刀耕火种”是农业中砍伐和焚烧植物以清理土地进行种植的一种方法。</p>
<p>This method is used to clear land for planting palm trees. Products from palm trees include oil, pulp, and paper. But this method threatens public health, education, and businesses like tourism.<br/>
这种方法用于清理土地种植棕榈树。棕榈树的产品包括油、纸浆和纸张。但这种方法威胁到公共卫生、教育和旅游业等行业。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">How are officials dealing with the problem?<br/>
官员们是如何处理这个问题的？</span></p>
<p>Even after Malaysia called on Indonesia this week to avoid "normalizing" the haze, Indonesian officials have denied any responsibility.<br/>
即使在马来西亚本周呼吁印尼避免雾霾“正常化”之后，印尼官员也否认对此负有任何责任。</p>
<p>Indonesia's environment minister Siti Nurbaya Bakar said recently that forest fires had decreased and no haze was found moving toward any neighboring country.<br/>
印尼环境部长西蒂·努尔巴亚最近表示，森林火灾已经减少，没有发现雾霾向任何邻国移动。</p>
<p>She said Indonesia has been dealing with the fires by dropping water bombs from helicopters.<br/>
她说，印尼一直在通过直升机投掷水弹来应对火灾。</p>
<p>In the past, Indonesia has taken legal action against companies suspected of illegal burning. But each year fires continue with different degrees of severity.<br/>
过去，印度尼西亚曾对涉嫌非法焚烧的公司采取法律行动。但每年火灾都会以不同严重程度继续发生。</p>
<p>In 2015 and 2019, Indonesia saw large fires that burned millions of hectares of land. It caused record-breaking pollution and some places were surrounded by toxic yellow smoke.<br/>
2015年和2019年，印尼发生了大火，烧毁了数百万公顷的土地。它造成了破纪录的污染，一些地方被有毒的黄色雾霾包围。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Why does this keep happening?<br/>
为什么这种情况不断发生？</span></p>
<p>Under Indonesian law, burning by small, local farmers is permitted. But it must happen on an area no greater than two hectares and necessary prevention measures must be in place.<br/>
根据印尼法律，允许当地小农户焚烧。但它必须发生在不超过两公顷的地区，并且必须采取必要的预防措施。</p>
<p>All large farm holders must follow sustainable palm oil standards, which do not permit burning.<br/>
所有大型农场经营者都必须遵守可持续的棕榈油标准，不允许焚烧。</p>
<p>The rules mean that slash and burn methods continue to be used by small-holder farmers. Additionally, following the guidelines is voluntary.<br/>
这些规定意味着小农户继续使用刀耕火种的方法。此外，遵循指导方针是自愿的。</p>
<p>Unclear supply chains, land claims, and laws mean that large companies can sometimes avoid responsibility for illegal land clearing. The large operations are sometimes owned by companies based in countries like Malaysia and Singapore.<br/>
不明确的供应链、土地主张和法律意味着大公司有时可以逃避非法清理土地的责任。这些大型业务有时由马来西亚和新加坡等国的公司所有。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">How is the area responding?<br/>
该地区的反应如何？</span></p>
<p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) recently launched a center for Transboundary Haze Pollution Control (known as ACC THPC).<br/>
东南亚国家联盟（东盟）最近成立了一个跨境雾霾污染控制中心。</p>
<p>Its aim is to help members prevent, deal with, and follow cross-country haze. The center is in line with ASEAN's agreement to reach a haze-free area by 2030.<br/>
其目的是帮助成员国预防、处理和跟踪跨境雾霾。该中心符合东盟关于到2030年实现无雾霾区的协议。</p>
<p>This week ASEAN agriculture and forestry ministers also agreed to take collective action to reduce and eventually remove crop burning.<br/>
本周，东盟农业和林业部长也同意采取集体行动，减少并最终消除焚烧作物的现象。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Is climate change making it worse?<br/>
气候变化会让情况变得更糟吗？</span></p>
<p>Environmentalists say Indonesia is home to the world's third largest rainforest area and the government needs to take more action. The country is experiencing increased dry conditions because of a weather system called El Nino.<br/>
环保人士表示，印尼是世界第三大雨林区，政府需要采取更多行动。由于一种名为厄尔尼诺的天气系统，该国正经历着日益干旱的天气。</p>
<p>Greenpeace Indonesia says climate warming is making forest and land fires more intense, which is adding to the climate crisis.<br/>
印尼绿色和平组织表示，气候变暖使森林和陆地火灾更加严重，这加剧了气候危机。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·费里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Language of International Conflicts  (2023/10/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/the-language-of-international-conflicts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The war between Israel and Hamas has drawn a lot of international attention this week. News reports, videos, and social media posts have informed people about the latest events in the conflict.</p>
<p>What kinds of language do reporters, journalists, or even citizens use during these conflicts?</p>
<p>That will be the subject of this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5185-08dbca9364be_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p><strong>International conflicts </strong></p>
<p>Conflict is not a happy subject. But learning how to understand the language surrounding such events is important.</p>
<p>When we look at the language used to describe conflicts, verbs have special importance. Violent conflicts are about actions – one group doing something to another group. Verbs are the words we use to describe actions.</p>
<p>We can break apart the verbs into two general groups: active and passive forms.</p>
<p>When we say the term active verb, we mean the relationship between the verb and the subject of the sentence. We call a verb an active verb when the subject of the sentence performs the action. Consider this example:</p>
<p><em>Tom kicked the ball.</em></p>
<p>In the sentence, the subject, Tom, does the action – kicking. The action is done to the object – the ball.</p>
<p>In other words, we have this structure: subject – verb – object.</p>
<p>Passive verbs tell us when something is done to someone or something. In other words, the subject is being acted upon. The subject is not acting.</p>
<p>We make a verb passive by introducing the <strong>auxiliary verb</strong> "be," putting the verb in its <strong>past participial</strong> form, and sometimes by introducing a <strong>prepositional phrase</strong>.</p>
<p>Let's take an example.</p>
<p>Here is our active sentence:</p>
<p><em>Tom kicked the ball.</em></p>
<p>A passive sentence might be this:</p>
<p><em>The ball was kicked by Tom.</em></p>
<p>So far, we have explored active and passive verbs at the sentence level. But the same ideas hold true at the level of a clause as well. A clause has a subject and a <strong>predicate</strong>. When a clause stands on its own, we say it is a sentence. But sometimes two or more clauses make up a sentence.</p>
<p><strong>Why does this matter? </strong></p>
<p>So, why are these ideas important?</p>
<p>The language surrounding international conflicts often contains a mixture of active and passive structures. Some reports or social media posts might contain a little more of the passive voice or a little more of the active voice. But most reports will have some kind of mix.</p>
<p>Let's explore one example from the Voice of America.</p>
<p>Linda Gradstein describes some events in the conflict between Israel and Hamas. Here is some information about events in Gaza:</p>
<p><em>Palestinian health officials said several dozen Palestinians including women and children were killed in an Israeli airstrike on the Jabaliya refugee camp Monday in Gaza. </em></p>
<p>In our example, we have an active form (health officials said....) as well as a passive form (were killed).</p>
<p>The same idea – the mixing of active and passive forms – holds true in many other places in the report.</p>
<p>For example, here is some information about events in Israel.</p>
<p><em>The bodies of more than 260 young music festival goers were discovered Sunday. Hamas gunman kidnapped more than 130 Israelis – many from the festival – and took them to Gaza. </em></p>
<p><strong>Homework </strong></p>
<p>Let's use this final example for a homework assignment. You just heard a mixture of active and passive structures. Can you identify the active and passive forms?</p>
<p>Write to us your answers in the comments section of our website, www.51voa.com, or send us an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com.</a></p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>auxiliary verb </strong><em>– n.</em> a verb (such as have or be) that is used with another verb to show the verb's tense, to form a question, etc.</p>
<p><strong>past participle<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the form of the verb that is used with "be" in passive constructions</p>
<p><strong>prepositional phrase </strong><em>– n.</em> a phrase that begins with a preposition and ends in a noun, pronoun, or noun phrase</p>
<p><strong>predicate</strong> <em>– n.</em> the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Footprints in New Mexico May Be Oldest Sign of Humans  (2023/10/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/study-footprints-in-new-mexico-may-be-oldest-sign-of-humans.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>New research confirms that a <strong>fossil</strong> of human footprints found in the U.S. state of New Mexico likely represents the oldest direct evidence of humans living in the Americas.</p>
<p>The footprints were discovered at the edge of the remains of an ancient lake in White Sands National Park in southern New Mexico. The research, published recently in <em>Science</em>, suggests the fossil dates back to between 21,000 and 23,000 years ago.</p>
<p>The estimated age of the footprints was first reported in <em>Science</em> in 2021. But some researchers questioned the dates. Researchers wondered whether seeds from lake plants used in the early dating may have taken in ancient carbon from the lake. If so, this could have changed the radiocarbon test result by thousands of years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Oct. 2023 photo shows human footprints at the White Sands National Park in New Mexico. Fossil human footprints discovered in White Sands likely date back to between 21,000 and 23,000 years ago, according to scientific evidence published Thursday, Oct. 5, 2023. (NPS via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-bd4b-08dbc9a29800_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This Oct. 2023 photo shows human footprints at the White Sands National Park in New Mexico. Fossil human footprints discovered in White Sands likely date back to between 21,000 and 23,000 years ago, according to scientific evidence published Thursday, Oct. 5, 2023. (NPS via AP)</span></div>
<p>The new study presents two additional lines of evidence for the older date range. It uses two different materials found at the site, ancient tree pollen and quartz grains.</p>
<p>The reported age of the footprints questions the belief that humans did not reach the Americas until about 15,000 years ago. That was a few thousand years before rising sea levels covered the Bering land bridge between Asia and North America.</p>
<p>Thomas Urban is a scientist who studies ancient humans at Cornell University in New York. He was involved in the 2021 study but not the new one. He said it is an area "... that's always been <strong>controversial</strong>..." Urban said such studies are important because they deal with the last part "of the peopling of the world."</p>
<p>Thomas Stafford is an independent scientist who studies ancient humans and the Earth in Albuquerque, New Mexico. He was not involved in the study. He said that while he "was a bit <strong>skeptical</strong> before," he now believes it.</p>
<p>Stafford said it is an important finding if three completely different methods show findings from a similar time period.</p>
<p>The new study separated about 75,000 individual pieces of pollen from the same area in rocks where the footprints where found.</p>
<p>Kathleen Springer is an Earth scientist researcher at the United States Geological Survey and helped write the new paper. She said the process of dating pollen is very difficult. She added that scientists believe radiocarbon dating land plants gives more correct results than dating plants living in water. But she added there needs to be a large enough number of plants to study.</p>
<p>The researchers also studied damage to the structure in ancient small pieces of quartz to produce an age estimate.</p>
<p>Ancient footprints of any kind – left by humans or large animals – can give scientists some idea when they are from. They may record how and where people or animals walked and if their paths crossed. Animal footprints have also been found at White Sands.</p>
<p>Other ancient sites in the Americas point to a similar time period. These include ancient art made from animal remains in Brazil. But scientists still question whether such materials really suggest that humans were living in the Americas then.</p>
<p>Jennifer Raff is a scientist who studies ancient human genes at the University of Kansas. She was not involved in the study. Raff said, "White Sands is <strong>unique</strong> because there's no question these footprints were left by people, it's not <strong>ambiguous</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong>– <em>n</em>. something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p><strong>controversial </strong>– <em>adj</em>. relating to or causing much discussion, disagreement, or argument</p>
<p><strong>skeptical </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having or expressing doubt about something (such as a claim or statement)</p>
<p><strong>unique </strong><em>– adj.</em> used to say that something or someone is unlike anything or anyone else</p>
<p><strong>ambiguous </strong>– <em>adj</em>. able to be understood in more than one way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Did the Israel-Palestinian Conflict Start?  (2023/10/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-did-the-israel-palestinian-conflict-start.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The fighting between Israelis and Hamas militants is the latest clash in a conflict that some people believe dates back to events described in the Bible.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, Hamas launched a surprise attack in Israel from the Palestinian territory of Gaza. Hamas gunmen killed more than 1,200 people, including women and children. The group also took more than 150 people as hostages.</p>
<p>Israel answered with airstrikes of what it said were Hamas targets in Gaza. Officials in the Palestinian-controlled area said more than 1,000 have been killed, including some children. Thousands have also been wounded on both sides.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Israelis take cover from the incoming rocket fire from the Gaza Strip in Ashkelon, southern Israel, Wednesday, Oct. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Leo Correa)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c060-08dbca81a13b_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Israelis take cover from the incoming rocket fire from the Gaza Strip in Ashkelon, southern Israel, Wednesday, Oct. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Leo Correa)</span></div>
<p><strong>What started the conflict?</strong></p>
<p>The modern conflict between Israelis and Palestinians is mainly a territorial dispute in Palestine, an area now known as Israel, the Gaza Strip, and the West Bank. Parts of the land are also considered the holiest places to Jews, Christians and Muslims.</p>
<p>The Roman Empire controlled the area at the time Jesus was believed to have been born in Bethlehem. Following the death of Rome's ally, King Herod, the land was divided into five locally administered areas under Rome.</p>
<p>Later, the land then came under the Ottoman Empire's control for about 400 years until the end of World War I. After World War I, Britain controlled the area it called Palestine and expressed support for <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.un.org/unispal/history/">"the establishment in Palestine of a national home for the Jewish people."</a></p>
<p>In November 1947, the United Nations General Assembly passed a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.un.org/unispal/document/auto-insert-185393/">resolution</a> dividing the British-ruled area of Palestine into two states, one Jewish and one Arab, with Jerusalem under a UN administration. On May 14, 1948, the modern State of Israel was established for Jews fleeing persecution and seeking a homeland.</p>
<p>Arab countries rejected the UN plan, arguing that it was unfair and violated the UN Charter. In the war that followed, some 700,000 Palestinians, half the Arab population in Palestine, fled or were driven from their homes. They ended up in Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria as well as in Gaza, the West Bank, and East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel denied that it sought to drive Palestinians from their homes. The new country said it was attacked by five Arab states the day after its creation. <strong>Armistice</strong> agreements halted the fighting in 1949, but there was no official peace treaty.</p>
<p>Palestinians call the creation of Israel the "Nakba" in Arabic. It means a disaster, or catastrophe, that resulted in mass displacement and blocked their dreams of statehood.</p>
<p><strong>Other major wars</strong></p>
<p>In 1967, Israel launched the Six-Day War against Egypt and Syria. Israel has occupied the West Bank, Arab East Jerusalem, which it captured from Jordan, and Syria's Golan Heights ever since.</p>
<p>In 1973, Egypt and Syria attacked Israeli positions along the Suez Canal and Golan Heights, beginning the Yom Kippur War. Israel pushed both armies back within three weeks.</p>
<p>Israel invaded Lebanon in 1982 aiming to remove Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO) fighters under Yasser Arafat. In 2006, war erupted in Lebanon again when Hezbollah militants captured two Israeli soldiers and Israel retaliated.</p>
<p><strong>What is Hamas?</strong></p>
<p>In 1987, Sheikh Ahmed Yassin, a Palestinian refugee living in Gaza, during the first intifada, or uprising, founded Hamas. The name in Arabic means the Islamic Resistance Movement.</p>
<p>The group does not recognize Israel's right to exist. It has launched many deadly attacks, including suicide bombings against Israelis. In 1997, the U.S. State Department named Hamas a terrorist organization. So has the European Union and other Western countries.</p>
<p>In 2005, Israel withdrew from the Gaza Strip, which it had captured in 1967. Hamas won the 2006 parliamentary elections over the Palestinian Authority and took control of Gaza. The Palestinian Authority still administers the semi-autonomous, or partly self-ruling, areas of the Israeli-occupied West Bank.</p>
<p>Israel answered the Hamas takeover with a <strong>blockade</strong> on Gaza. It restricted the movement of people and goods to keep the group from developing weapons. Over the years, Hamas received support from many Arab countries. Recently, it has moved closer to Iran and its allies.</p>
<p><strong>Current issues </strong></p>
<p>For over 40 years, efforts have aimed to bring peace to the area.</p>
<p>In 1979, Egypt and Israel signed a peace treaty. Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin and PLO chief Arafat agreed in 1993 to set up Palestinian <strong>autonomy</strong> in the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. The following year, Israel signed a peace treaty with Jordan.</p>
<p>In 2002, an Arab plan offered Israel normal ties with all Arab countries in return for a full withdrawal from the lands it took in the 1967 Middle East war, the creation of a Palestinian state, and a "just solution" for Palestinian refugees.</p>
<p>The two sides, however, are far apart on most issues.</p>
<p>Hamas has rejected the two-state solution. It has sworn to destroy Israel. Israel has increasingly built new Jewish settlements on occupied land over Palestinian objections.</p>
<p>Palestinians want East Jerusalem to be the capital of the Palestinian state. East Jerusalem has areas that are holy to Muslims, Jews, and Christians. But Israel has established "indivisible" Jerusalem as the country's capital.</p>
<p>Today about 5.6 million Palestinian refugees still live in Jordan, Lebanon, Syria, the Israeli-occupied West Bank and Gaza. Palestinians have long demanded that refugees should be permitted to return home. But Israel says any resettlement of Palestinian refugees must take place outside of its borders.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this report for VOA Learning English from VOA, Associated Press, Reuters, and the United Nations sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>armistice </strong><em>–n.</em> a truce; and agreement to stop fight</p>
<p><strong>blockade</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>when a country uses force to block trade, supplies or people from entering another country</p>
<p><strong>autonomy</strong> <em>–v.</em> the right of a country to rule itself</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Seattle Business Tries to Create ‘Beanless Coffee’  (2023/10/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/seattle-business-tries-to-create-beanless-coffee.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Coffee is one of the most popular drinks in the world. But it takes a lot of plants to produce the world's coffee supply each year. This production process is having lasting environmental effects.</p>
<p>Farmers seeking to expand have to cut down old trees. In addition, many old coffee farms are not producing as many beans because of warming temperatures linked to climate change.</p>
<p>This leads coffee bean growers to move higher up hills and mountains in search of cooler areas to plant new trees. Cutting down old trees in order to plant new crops or build homes is called deforestation. And deforestation, along with the burning of <strong>fossil fuels</strong>, is a leading cause of climate change.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Atomo Coffee's 'beanless coffee', which uses superfoods and upcycled ingredients to mimic the molecular structure of coffee, is seen in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on September 29, 2023. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/249bff6e-fa84-4d8f-a7b2-15fda8aed9a0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Atomo Coffee's 'beanless coffee', which uses superfoods and upcycled ingredients to mimic the molecular structure of coffee, is seen in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on September 29, 2023. </span></div>
<p>The effects of coffee production on the environment have led one company to create a "beanless" version of the drink. The Seattle-based company is called Atomo Coffee. It has already received more than $50 million in investments.</p>
<p>Atomo's product tastes like coffee and is prepared in the same way – by pouring water over a fine grind. But it is not made with beans. It is instead made with plant material, such as seeds from a date. <strong>Caffeine</strong> for the product comes from waste during a process used to remove caffeine from tea.</p>
<p>"Coffee is causing deforestation at a pretty <strong>alarming</strong> <strong>rate</strong> - almost up to 10 (New York) Central Parks a day," Andy Kleitsch recently told Reuters. Kleitsch started Atomo Coffee about five years ago. He said the world's coffee "machine" never stops, it is "always looking for more land, and that's what we're trying to stop."</p>
<p>Studies show that by 2050, about half the land currently used to grow coffee could be unproductive.</p>
<p>Atomo hopes to do for coffee what engineered meat products such as Beyond Meat have done for meat <strong>alternatives</strong>.</p>
<p>The company has been testing out a kind of coffee called "cold brew." It uses over 90 percent less water than regular coffee and is produced with reduced carbon pollution as well. The company is also in the process of making a hot coffee product.</p>
<p>Atomo hopes coffee shops will consider offering its beanless coffee to buyers who show interest in the product.</p>
<p>But the beanless version comes with a cost. Atomo's coffee will sell for about $20 for one half kilogram. Regular coffee is usually $10 to $14 for the same amount.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong>–n. fuel, such as coal or gas, that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>caffeine</strong>–n. a substance found in coffee or tea that makes you feel awake</p>
<p><strong>alarming </strong>–adj. information that creates concern or a feeling of danger</p>
<p><strong>rate </strong>–n. the speed at which something happens over time</p>
<p><strong>alternative </strong>–adj. not usual or traditional</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>America’s Poor Math Skills Raise Concerns  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/america-s-poor-math-skills-raise-concerns.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many Americans joke about how bad they are at math. But, labor experts and others in the United States are not laughing. They say the nation's ever-decreasing math skill threatens U.S. economic competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Jim Stigler is a professor at the University of California, Los Angeles. He studies the process of teaching and learning subjects, including math. He said, "The <strong>advances</strong> in technology that are going to drive where the world goes in the next 50 years are going to come from other countries, because they have the <strong>intellectual</strong> capital and we don't."</p>
<p>The Education Reporting Collaborative, a coalition of eight news agencies, is documenting the math crisis facing schools. Members of the Collaborative are <em>AL.com</em>, <em>The Associated Press</em>, <em>The Christian Science Monitor</em>, <em>The Dallas Morning News</em>, <em>The Hechinger Report</em>, <em>Idaho Education News</em>, <em>The Post and Courier</em> in South Carolina, and <em>The Seattle Times</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Teacher Jerry Howland explains an equation during the Bridge to Calculus summer program at Northeastern University in Boston on Tuesday, Aug. 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Reba Saldanha)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7f50d41b-ac80-4bf9-ad5a-0076921ab067_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Teacher Jerry Howland explains an equation during the Bridge to Calculus summer program at Northeastern University in Boston on Tuesday, Aug. 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Reba Saldanha)</span></div>
<p>The U.S. military has called for a major program to support education in science, technology, education, and math (STEM). It argues that the U.S. is dangerously behind other nations. The Defense Department says China produces eight times as many college <strong>graduates</strong> in these study fields as the United States. It says Russia produces four times as many engineers as the U.S.</p>
<p>Government labor experts say the number of jobs in areas requiring math skill will increase by more than 30,000 each year through the end of 2030. That is much faster than most other kinds of jobs.</p>
<p>"Mathematics is becoming more and more a part of almost every career," said Michael Allen. He chairs the math department at Tennessee Technological University.</p>
<p>But most American students are not prepared for those jobs. In the most recent Program for International Student Assessment tests in math (PISA), U.S. students tested lower than students from 36 other education systems around the world. Students in China tested the highest.</p>
<p>Only one in five American high school students planning to attend college is prepared for college-level study in STEM, say experts at the National Science and Technology Council, a government group.</p>
<p>However, students from other countries are preparing to lead in these areas, reports the National Foundation for American Policy, a non-profit organization. It says only one in five graduate students in math-heavy fields at U.S. universities are American. The rest come from other countries. Most will leave the U.S. when they finish their programs.</p>
<p>In Massachusetts, employers are expecting a shortage over the next five years of 11,000 workers in the life sciences alone.</p>
<p>"It's not a small problem," said Edward Lambert Jr. He is director of the Massachusetts Business Alliance for Education. "We're just not starting students, <strong>particularly</strong> students of color and from lower-resourced families, on career paths related to math and computer science and those things in which we need to stay competitive, or starting them early enough," he said.</p>
<p>"This is not an educational question alone," said Josh Wyner, a vice president of the Aspen Institute, a <strong>think tank</strong>. In July, it warned that other nations are gaining near to America's technological power.</p>
<p>It urged decision makers to make education an important national security goal. "We are no longer keeping <strong>pace</strong> with other countries, particularly China," the Aspen report says, calling this a "dangerous" failure.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jon Marcus reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advances </strong>– <em>n</em>. progress in the development or improvement of something</p>
<p><strong>intellectual </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to the ability to think in a logical way</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to earn a degree or diploma from a school, college, or university</p>
<p><strong>particularly </strong><em>– adv.</em> more than usually</p>
<p><strong>think tank </strong><em>– n.</em> an organization that consists of a group of people who think of new ideas on a particular subject or who give advice about what should be done</p>
<p><strong>pace </strong><em>– n.</em> the speed at which something happens</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Grower Sets World Record for Heaviest Pumpkin  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/us-grower-sets-world-record-for-heaviest-pumpkin.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American teacher from Minnesota has set a record for growing the world's heaviest pumpkin, which weighed 1,247 kilograms.</p>
<p>Travis Gienger was named the winner Monday of the 50th World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, California.</p>
<p>The 43-year-old won the same contest in 2022. His winning pumpkin last year weighed 1,161 kilograms. Still, Gienger told The Associated Press he was surprised to win the world record. "I was not expecting that," he said. "It was quite the feeling."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Travis Gienger of Anoka, Minn., reacts after winning the Safeway 50th annual World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, Calif., Monday, Oct. 9, 2023. Gienger won the event with a pumpkin weighing 2749 pounds. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0c80-08dbc9b23820_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Travis Gienger of Anoka, Minn., reacts after winning the Safeway 50th annual World Championship Pumpkin Weigh-Off in Half Moon Bay, Calif., Monday, Oct. 9, 2023. Gienger won the event with a pumpkin weighing 2749 pounds. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)</span></div>
<p>Gienger is a teacher at Anoka Technical College in Anoka, Minnesota. He teaches agriculture and growing methods and has been producing pumpkins for nearly 30 years. Gienger says his father also raised pumpkins and this got him interested.</p>
<p>The past world record for the heaviest pumpkin was set by a grower in Italy who produced a 1,226-kilogram <strong>gourd</strong> in 2021, the Guinness World Records organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://newsroom.ap.org/detail/Pumpkinweighing2749poundswinsCaliforniacontestsetsworldrecordforbiggestgourd/dbe2b22743e332998c204f2191b2a46f/text?Query=pumpkin%2520contest&amp;mediaType=text&amp;sortBy=&amp;dateRange=Anytime&amp;totalCount=1&amp;currentItemNo=0">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Gienger – who grows the pumpkins on his home property – said this year he decided to give his plants extra care. This included watering them up to 12 times a day and feeding them food, or fertilizer, a little more than usual.</p>
<p>Gienger first competed in Half Moon Bay's yearly contest in 2020. He has won three of the city's last four pumpkin contests. "I put in the work so that I can put a smile on people's faces and it's just so nice coming out here to see everyone in this town," Gienger said.</p>
<p>The pumpkin champion won a $30,000 prize for growing the biggest pumpkin and setting a world record.</p>
<p>Gienger's pumpkin will be shown along with the runner-up winners at the city's upcoming Art and Pumpkin Festival. At the event, visitors will be able to look at the pumpkin prizes and take pictures with the growers.</p>
<p>In the United States, pumpkins are popular throughout the autumn.</p>
<p>During the U.S. holiday Halloween – on October 31 – many people <strong>decorate</strong> the orange gourds and turn them into "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/jack-o--lantern-why-is-it-named-jack-/5630153.html">jack-o'-lanterns</a>." A jack-o'-lantern is a pumpkin that has been <strong>carved</strong>, usually to show a frightening or funny face.</p>
<p>Pumpkins are also a seasonal favorite for Americans to make pumpkin pie. This <strong>dessert</strong> food is traditionally eaten on Thanksgiving Day, which this year falls on November 23.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gourd</strong> <em>– n.</em> a large fruit with a hard shell</p>
<p><strong>decorate</strong> <em>– v. </em>to add something to an object or place, especially to make it more inviting</p>
<p><strong>carve</strong> <em>– v. </em>to make something by cutting into something</p>
<p><strong>dessert</strong> <em>– n.</em> a sweet food usually eaten at the end of a meal</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France Worries about Bedbugs as 2024 Summer Olympics Near  (2023/10/11) | 巴黎奥运将近 臭虫困扰法国</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/france-worries-about-bedbugs-as-2024-summer-olympics-near.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Officials in France are worried about the spread of an insect called the bedbug as Paris prepares to hold the 2024 Summer Olympic Games.<br/>
在巴黎准备举办2024年夏季奥运会之际，法国官员担心一种名为臭虫的昆虫的传播。</p>
<p>Prime Minister Elizabeth Borne called a meeting of ministers to deal with the bedbug crisis. The country's transportation minister, Clé ment Beaune, recently met with transportation companies to make a plan for monitoring and disinfecting.<br/>
法国总理伊丽莎白·博尔内召开了一次部长会议以应对臭虫危机。法国交通部长克莱门特·伯恩最近会见了交通公司，制定了监测和消毒计划。</p>
<p>Beaune also spoke about reducing worry caused by reports on social media. He told reporters there is no increase in bedbug cases. He added that 37 cases reported in the bus and Metro train system and many other reports from trains have proved false.<br/>
博恩还谈到了减少社交媒体报道引起的担忧。他告诉记者，臭虫案例没有增加。他补充说，公共汽车和地铁系统报告的37起案例以及火车上的其它许多报告都被证明是虚假的。</p>
<p>The National Agency for Health and Food Safety reported that 11 percent of households had a bedbug problem between 2017 and 2022. Because many people might not want to say in public that they have a bedbug problem, the agency used a poll by the company Ipsos to collect the information.<br/>
法国国家卫生和食品安全局报告称，2017年至2022年间，该国11%的家庭发生过臭虫问题。由于许多人可能不想在公开场合说他们遇到臭虫问题，该机构利用益普索公司的一项民意调查来收集信息。</p>
<p>The insects are about the size of an apple seed. They neither jump nor fly. However, they have become more resistant to chemicals used to kill insects. And they can stay alive for up to a year with no food.<br/>
这些昆虫大约有苹果籽那么大。它们既不跳也不飞。然而，它们对用来杀死昆虫的化学物质具有更强的抵抗力。而且它们可以在没有食物的情况下存活长达一年。</p>
<p>The carbon dioxide humans give off makes the insects become active and try to bite, explained Jean-Michel Berenger. He is a scientist who studies insects. He raises bedbugs in his laboratory in the infectious diseases division of the Méditerranée University Hospital in the city of Marseille.<br/>
让-米歇尔·贝林格解释说，人类释放的二氧化碳使这种昆虫变得活跃并试图叮咬。他是一位研究昆虫的科学家。他在马赛市地中海大学附属医院传染病科的实验室里饲养臭虫。</p>
<p>For now, Berenger said, this much is clear: "Bedbugs have infested the media."<br/>
贝林格说，就目前而言，这一点很清楚：“媒体都在说臭虫。”</p>
<p>Experts say it makes no difference if a home is clean or dirty. The insects simply want to bite people to get blood, explained Berenger.<br/>
专家说，家里脏与不脏没什么区别。贝伦格解释说，这些昆虫只是想咬人吸血。</p>
<p>"Whether you live in a dump or a palace, it's the same thing to them," he said.<br/>
他说：“无论你住在垃圾场还是宫殿里，对他们来说都是一样的。”</p>
<p>Worry about bedbugs has increased business for insect control companies in France. They use dogs to smell the special odor that bedbugs make. Then, they use hot steam to kill the bugs.<br/>
对臭虫的担忧让法国昆虫防治公司的业务增加。他们用狗来闻臭虫产生的特殊气味。然后，他们用热蒸汽杀死虫子。</p>
<p>Kevin Le Mestre is director of Lutte Antinuisible, a company that removes unwanted insects and animals such as rats. He said that in the past, people would not call his company even if they had been bitten by a bedbug. But now he said his company is getting many calls from people worried about the insects.<br/>
凯文·勒·梅斯特雷是病虫害防治公司的董事，该公司负责消灭老鼠之类不受欢迎的昆虫和动物。他说，过去即使被臭虫叮咬，人们也不会给他的公司打电话。但现在他说，他的公司接到了许多担心昆虫的人打来的电话。</p>
<p>The increase in public worry began about a month ago after reports of bedbugs at a Paris movie theater. Videos began popping up on social media, showing the little insects on trains and buses.<br/>
大约一个月前，巴黎一家电影院传出臭虫的报道后，公众的担忧开始加剧。社交媒体上开始出现视频，显示这些小昆虫在火车和公共汽车上。</p>
<p>Some government officials want to create new rules to fight against bedbugs.<br/>
一些政府官员希望制定新的规则来对抗臭虫。</p>
<p>Lawmaker Mathilde Panot recently brought a glass container of bedbugs to the Parliament to criticize the government, claiming it had let the insects spread quickly.<br/>
议员玛蒂尔德·帕诺最近带着一个装有臭虫的玻璃容器来到议会，批评政府，声称政府让臭虫迅速传播。</p>
<p>Because bedbugs travel easily on clothing or in luggage, they are a cause of worry for officials ahead of the 2024 Olympic games.<br/>
由于臭虫在衣服或行李上很容易传播，因此它们是官员们在2024年奥运会之前担心的一个原因。</p>
<p>"All human population movements are profitable for bedbugs because they go with us, to hotels, in transport," said Berenger.<br/>
贝林格说：“所有的人口流动都对臭虫有利，因为它们会和我们一起去酒店、乘坐交通工具。”</p>
<p>Beaune, the transport minister, is hopeful that steps can be taken to reduce the public's fear. But, he added, "It's hell, these bedbugs."<br/>
交通部长博恩希望能够采取措施来减少公众的恐惧。但是，他补充道，“这些臭虫糟糕透了。”</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mining Companies Consider Renewable Energy  (2023/10/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/mining-companies-consider-renewable-energy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Mining companies produce important metals needed to build electric car <strong>batteries</strong> and <strong>solar panels</strong>.</p>
<p>Devices called <strong>smelters</strong> process the rock and minerals so the metal can be purified and sold to manufacturers. The work requires a lot of energy.</p>
<p>The advisory business McKinsey &amp; Company says mining operations produce between four and seven percent of the world's <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> emissions. Those are gases released into the atmosphere that some scientists say are warming the planet.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A worker in a protective suit pokes a metal rod to tap slag from a smelting furnace at PT Vale Indonesia's nickel processing plant in Sorowako, South Sulawesi, Indonesia, Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/eb483678-ce6d-4fff-a549-e13673714c3e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A worker in a protective suit pokes a metal rod to tap slag from a smelting furnace at PT Vale Indonesia's nickel processing plant in Sorowako, South Sulawesi, Indonesia, Tuesday, Sept. 12, 2023.</span></div>
<p>Some of the companies that use mined materials include Apple, Hyundai and Mercedes. Those companies are now putting pressure on mining companies to use less energy. Many of those companies have environmental, social and governance, or ESG, <strong>commitments</strong>. The ESG commitments require companies such as Apple and carmaker Volvo to choose materials that are made in a less harmful way when possible.</p>
<p>Some mining companies are thinking about how they can change their business methods to use less energy and create less pollution.</p>
<p>The pressure is changing the way mines in Indonesia, Chile and Canada operate.</p>
<p>On the island of Sulawesi in Indonesia, the Brazilian mining company Vale runs its smelters using hydroelectric power instead of diesel fuel. The hydroelectric power comes from three dams the company built years ago. Vale now says it can reduce its carbon dioxide by over 1 million tons per year. The company says its greenhouse gas emissions are down by one-fifth since 2017.</p>
<p>The smelter in Sulawesi produces 75,000 tons of nickel each year. The metal is used for batteries, electric cars and many machines used around the home. While the company runs the smelter on hydroelectric power, other machines still require coal power.</p>
<p>The demand for metals such as nickel and cobalt is rising as more people drive electric cars and use solar panels to power their homes. But as new mines open and active mines increase operations, environmental activists wonder if the mining companies can continue to reduce pollution.</p>
<p>Activists say pressure is important to get industries to create less pollution. In Chile, mines that produce copper, lithium and other materials use some energy from solar farms. In Canada, the Raglan mine in the far northern part of Quebec produces nickel with the help of wind power.</p>
<p>Michael Goodsite teaches civil and environmental engineering at the University of Adelaide in Australia. He said the mines that are moving away from diesel fuel are setting a good example.</p>
<p>"How they move from fossil fuel operations to other energy sources can and should be learned from by others," he said.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, President Joko Widodo has pushed for his country to develop its own industries. One of those industries is mining. Indonesia is the world's largest producer of nickel and Vale recently signed a deal for a $4.5 billion processing center. Some of the investment came from Ford, the U.S.-based automaker.</p>
<p>Ford is concerned about how its materials are produced. Ford official Christopher Smith said the company can "help <strong>ensure</strong> that the nickel we use in electric vehicle batteries is mined ... produced within the same ESG standards as...our business around the world."</p>
<p>But mining companies may not be able to change fast enough for people worried about climate change.</p>
<p>Coal is used to power some of Vale's metal processing in Indonesia. Febriany Eddy is chief of Vale Indonesia. She said the company plans to change from coal to liquefied natural gas. Experts say the gas is not as bad as coal.</p>
<p>Eddy said it is the best current choice. The company believes better options may not be available for 15 to 20 years.</p>
<p>She said she could wait for the perfect solution, or she can work with natural gas saying, "it is a transition, only." Eddy said natural gas will reduce emissions by 40 percent.</p>
<p>Some climate activists say natural gas still produces methane and carbon dioxide, which, they say, hurt the environment.</p>
<p>But Eddy said Vale can save money in the long run by producing its own energy in Indonesia. She said hydroelectric power reduces the company's carbon emissions and also permits the company to save money. "We are no longer that (<strong>vulnerable</strong>) to fuel and coal costs – because we have hydropower," she said.</p>
<p>Some products will still be made by businesses that are not making energy changes Goodsite, the university professor in Australia, said when asked about China.</p>
<p>He added that some of the changes will come because businesses want to reduce their energy use. However, he said change will happen if people, who he called "end users," who buy cars and mobile phones and other products choose to buy things made from different materials.</p>
<p>And he said people have to be ready to pay a lot more for these new products. "We all need to be prepared to pay a significant <strong>premium</strong> for that," Goodsite said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennet. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>battery </strong>–n. a device that stores electricity and provide direct electrical current</p>
<p><strong>solar panel </strong>–n. a device that turns strong sunlight into direct electrical current</p>
<p><strong>smelter </strong>–n. a machine that melts rock that contains minerals to purify the mineral or metal</p>
<p><strong>greenhouse gas </strong>–n. a gas believed to trap heat in the Earth's atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>commitment </strong>–n. a promise to do something</p>
<p><strong>ensure </strong>–v. to make something likely to happen</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong>–adj. easily hurt, harmed or weakened</p>
<p><strong>premium </strong>–n. something with an added cost compared to a regular cost</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Study Long-lasting Ancient Structures  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/scientists-study-long-lasting-ancient-structures.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ancient builders across the world created structures that are still standing today, thousands of years later.</p>
<p>Roman engineers built thick <strong>concrete</strong> sea barriers, for example. Mayan builders created sculptures to their gods, and Chinese builders raised walls against invaders.</p>
<p>But there are many recent structures that are already starting to fail. The concrete that makes up much of our modern world lasts around 50 to 100 years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Visitors tour the interior of the Pantheon's dome in Rome, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4a21-08dbc522a635_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Visitors tour the interior of the Pantheon's dome in Rome, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)</span></div>
<p>A growing number of scientists have been studying materials from long-ago. They are breaking apart pieces of buildings and reading historical texts hoping to learn how they have stood for thousands of years.</p>
<p>The research has turned up a surprising list of materials that were mixed into old buildings. They include tree bark, volcanic ash, rice, beer and even urine. These unexpected materials could have the ability to get stronger over time and "heal" cracks when they form.</p>
<p>Figuring out how to copy these features could have real impacts today. While our modern concrete has the strength to hold up very tall buildings and heavy <strong>infrastructure</strong>, it cannot compete with the <strong>endurance</strong> of these ancient materials.</p>
<p>With the rising threats of climate change, there is a growing call to make construction more <strong>sustainable</strong>. A recent UN report estimates that the built environment is responsible for more than a third of carbon dioxide <strong>emissions </strong>worldwide. Cement production alone makes up more than 7 percent of those emissions.</p>
<p><strong>Is ancient Roman concrete better?</strong></p>
<p>Many researchers have turned to the Romans. Starting around 200 BCE, the Roman Empire was building concrete structures that have stood the test of time. That includes the Pantheon to the <strong>aqueducts</strong> that still carry water today.</p>
<p>Even in places where seawater has been hitting structures for ages, you will find concrete "basically the way it was when it was poured 2,000 years ago," said John Oleson. He is an archaeologist at the University of Victoria in Canada.</p>
<p>Most modern concrete starts with Portland cement, a powder made by heating limestone and clay to super-high temperatures and grinding them up. That cement is mixed with water to create a <strong>paste</strong>. Then, materials like rock and gravel are added.</p>
<p>Records from ancient builders show the Roman process was similar. The ancient builders mixed materials like burnt limestone and volcanic sand with water and gravel, creating chemical reactions to tie everything together.</p>
<p>Now, scientists think they have found an important reason why some Roman concrete has held up structures for thousands of years. The ancient material has an unusual power to repair itself. Exactly how is not yet clear, but scientists are starting to find reasons why.</p>
<p>Admir Masic is a civil and environmental engineer at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. In a study, he said this power comes from <strong>chunks</strong> of limestone throughout the Roman material that is not mixed in evenly. Researchers used to think these chunks were a sign that the Romans were not mixing up their materials well enough.</p>
<p>Instead, the scientists found that the chunks could fuel the material's "self-healing" abilities. When cracks form, water enters the concrete, Masic explained. That water activates the leftover lime, creating new chemical reactions that can fill in the damaged sections.</p>
<p><strong>Ancient Roman ... skyscrapers?</strong></p>
<p>Today's builders cannot just copy the ancient processes. Even though Roman concrete lasted a long time, it could not hold up heavy buildings. "You couldn't build a modern skyscraper with Roman concrete," Oleson said. "It would collapse when you got to the third story."</p>
<p>Instead, researchers are trying to take some of the ancient materials and add them into modern mixes. Masic is part of a company that is trying to build new projects using "self-healing" concrete.</p>
<p>People do not need to make things last quite as long as the Romans did to have an impact, Masic said. If we add 50 or 100 years to concrete's lifespan, he said, "we will require less <strong>demolition</strong>, less maintenance and less material in the long run."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>concrete </strong><em>— n. </em>a hard, strong material that is used for building and made by mixing cement, sand, and broken rocks with water</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>— n. </em>the basic equipment and structures that are needed for a country, region, or organization to function properly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>endurance </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability to do something difficult for a long time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be used without being completely used up or destroyed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emissions </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>aqueduct </strong><em>— n. </em>a structure that looks like a bridge and that is used to carry water over a valley</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>paste </strong><em>— n. </em>a soft, wet mixture of usually a powder and a liquid</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>chunk </strong><em>— n. </em>a thick piece of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>demolition </strong><em>— n. </em>deliberate destruction of a building or other structure</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>WHO Approves a Second Malaria Vaccine  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/who-approves-a-second-malaria-vaccine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) approved a second malaria vaccine last week. The decision could offer a less costly and readily available shot to help fight the disease.</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said the U.N. health agency approved the new malaria vaccine based on advice from two expert groups. They suggested the shot could be given to children at risk of the disease.</p>
<p>"As a malaria researcher, I used to dream of the day we would have a safe and effective vaccine against malaria. Now we have two," Tedros said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A nurse administers the malaria vaccine to an infant at the Lumumba Sub-County hospital in Kisumu, Kenya, July 1, 2022. (REUTERS/Baz Ratner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-aadd-08dbc3833ea3_cx17_cy13_cw82_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A nurse administers the malaria vaccine to an infant at the Lumumba Sub-County hospital in Kisumu, Kenya, July 1, 2022. (REUTERS/Baz Ratner)</span></div>
<p>Britain's Oxford University developed the new three-shot vaccine along with the Serum Institute of India. Research suggests it is more than 75 percent effective. The vaccine can protect people for another year with an additional shot called a booster. Tedros said the shot would cost about $2 to $4 and could be available in some countries next year.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, health officials in the African countries of Ghana and Burkina Faso also approved the vaccine.</p>
<p>Infected mosquitos spread the <strong>parasitic</strong> disease when they bite people.</p>
<p>"This is one more tool we will now have, but it's not going to replace bed nets and <strong>spraying</strong> <strong>insecticides</strong>," said John Johnson of the aid group Doctors Without Borders. "This is not the vaccine that's going to stop malaria," he added. Johnson was not part of the expert groups that advised the WHO.</p>
<p>The WHO approved the first malaria vaccine in 2021. The U.N. agency described the vaccine development as an "historic" effort to end the deadly disease in Africa. The continent is home to most of the world's estimated 200 million malaria cases and 400,000 malaria deaths.</p>
<p>But that vaccine, known as Mosquirix and made by GSK, is only about 30 percent effective. The treatment requires four shots and becomes less effective within months.</p>
<p>WHO experts, however, said the data to date on the GSK and Oxford-developed vaccines does not show which one is more effective.</p>
<p>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation had been one of the GSK vaccine's biggest financial supporters. But, the non-profit ended its support for Mosquirix last year. It said the GSK shot was less effective than officials would like and that money would be better used elsewhere.</p>
<p>"The big difference with these two vaccines is <strong>access</strong>," Johnson told the <em>Associated Press</em>. He noted that about 10 countries or more could get the GSK vaccine in the next few years.</p>
<p>GSK has said it can only produce about 15 million treatments a year. The Serum Institute has said it could make up to 200 million treatments of the Oxford vaccine a year.</p>
<p>Alister Craig is with Britain's Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine. He said countries still waiting for the GSK vaccine should turn to the Oxford vaccine instead.</p>
<p>If the new vaccine is widely available across Africa, it could greatly reduce severe sickness and deaths caused by malaria in a few years, Craig said.</p>
<p>Neither of the vaccines stops <strong>transmission</strong> of malaria. As a result, immunization campaigns alone would not be enough to prevent epidemics. And, reports of resistance to malaria drugs are on the rise.</p>
<p>"You would be foolish to think that this vaccine is going to be the end of the malaria story," Craig said.</p>
<p><strong>Dengue vaccine</strong></p>
<p>In a separate decision, the WHO's expert group also approved the dengue vaccine made by Takeda. European Union drug officials approved the dengue vaccine earlier.</p>
<p>The WHO advised that the dengue vaccine be used in children aged 6 to 16 in countries where the disease is widespread.</p>
<p>Dengue killed almost 1,000 people this year in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Maria Cheng reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>parasitic</strong> - <em>adj</em>. living in another animal or person</p>
<p><strong>spray</strong> - <em>v</em>. to put a stream of small drops of liquid on (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>insecticide</strong> - <em>n</em>. a chemical substance used to kill insects</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> - <em>n</em>. a way to get to something</p>
<p><strong>transmission</strong> - <em>n</em>. the act or process by which something is spread or passed on</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>London’s Pointe Black Ballet School Aims to Break Racial Barriers  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/london-s-pointe-black-ballet-school-aims-to-break-racial-barriers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>It was a criticism about her Afro-<strong>braided</strong> hair that led Ruth Essel to create what she calls a safe space for Black dancers.</p>
<p>The founder of Pointe Black Ballet School in London said when she was a child, teachers and others all but punished her for not following the traditional <strong>ballerina </strong>way.</p>
<p>"I'll never forget my first time about to dance on a West End <strong>stage</strong>," said Essel. That was the time the 10-year-old wore her hair braided at dance practice. Her mother had spent her last $120 to get her hair done.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ruth Essel of Pointe Black Ballet School teaches finishing positions in south London, Britain, July 22, 2023. Essel sees it as a safe space for Black dancers and a way to create a network of studios, dancers, and teachers. (REUTERS/Alishia Abodunde) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-2d67-08dbc59e9311_cx7_cy2_cw92_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ruth Essel of Pointe Black Ballet School teaches finishing positions in south London, Britain, July 22, 2023. Essel sees it as a safe space for Black dancers and a way to create a network of studios, dancers, and teachers. (REUTERS/Alishia Abodunde) </span></div>
<p>Her happiness disappeared when her teacher pointed at her in an almost all-white group of dancers. The teacher told her to take out her braids because it looked like "a <strong>mess</strong>."</p>
<p>That was just one of several times Essel was made to feel bad about being different. "These are all things that happened before I was 16 years old, and I didn't know any better," she said.</p>
<p>These difficulties led Essel to establish Pointe Black in 2020 at the age of 26.</p>
<p>"I wanted there to be a Black environment. I wanted there to be people who looked like me. I wanted there to be a teacher that looked like me," she said.</p>
<p>She said it felt like she was given power when she could finally wear black clothes and shoes rather than the traditional pink color for ballerinas, "because it was closer to my color."</p>
<p>Ballet has expanded across the world with famous ballet dancers from Asia, South America, and Cuba. But many still think of ballet dancers as light skinned. And classical ballet companies try to have a similar look for dancers in classical works like <em>Swan Lake</em>. That makes it harder for dancers of color.</p>
<p>Some 2.2 percent of dancers at the top four ballet companies in Britain are of Black ancestry. That percentage is in line with the country's Black population at 3 percent, said Sandie Bourn of Britain's Society for Dance Research in 2017.</p>
<p>A spokesperson noted that keeping <strong>diversity </strong>is important to everyone at The Royal Academy of Dance, saying "Dance is for everybody."</p>
<p>But Essel wants to speed up change by introducing new ideas. She said her shows use African dances and music. And dancers wear different hairstyles, including twists, rolls and afros. She added, "... it's really just about celebrating the person no matter where they come from."</p>
<p>Maya Beale-Springe is a 10-year-old student at Pointe Black and another ballet school. She enjoys exploring different kinds, or types, of ballet.</p>
<p>"I get to experience different types of ballet, different music," she said after a perfect practice for an upcoming show.</p>
<p>Essel teaches all the classes in her school. She said, "Everything about my school is what my younger self would have wanted."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Alishia Abodunde and Muvija M reported this story for Reuters. </em><em>Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>braid </strong>– <em>n</em>. an arrangement of hair made by weaving three sections together</p>
<p><strong>ballet </strong>– <em>n</em>. a kind of dancing that is performed on a stage and that uses dance, music, costumes, and scenery to tell a story</p>
<p><strong>stage </strong>– <em>n</em>. a raised platform in a theater, auditorium where the performers stand</p>
<p><strong>mess </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very dirty or untidy state or condition</p>
<p>and that you will not allow anyone or anything to stop you</p>
<p><strong>diversity </strong><em>– n.</em> the state of having people who are different races or who have different cultures in a group or organization</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Nobel Economics Prize Goes to Professor Studying Gender in Workplace  (2023/10/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/nobel-economics-prize-goes-to-professor-studying-gender-in-workplace.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Nobel Prize in economics has been awarded to Claudia Goldin for her work on the <strong>gap</strong> between men and women in the workplace.</p>
<p>The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences announced the prize on Monday. The 77-year-old Goldin is only the third woman among 93 past Nobel economics prizewinners. She is a professor at Harvard University.</p>
<p>Goldin's research has shown that even in the field of economics, women earn about 13 percent less than men. The pay gap prevents some women from continuing their education.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="US economist Claudia Goldin, who was awarded the Nobel prize in economics, talks to the press at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, on October 9, 2023. (Photo by Lauren Owens Lambert / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6926e4c1-0b1b-4996-a508-6207161b2226_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">US economist Claudia Goldin, who was awarded the Nobel prize in economics, talks to the press at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, on October 9, 2023. (Photo by Lauren Owens Lambert / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The Nobel committee credits Goldin with finding missing data to better explain continuing differences between both the pay and work involvement, or participation, of men and women.</p>
<p>The group called Goldin "a <strong>detective</strong>" who found new data sources and "creative ways to use them to measure these unknowns."</p>
<p>Goldin studied information related to female participation in the workplace over 200 years and found that their pay started low and never caught up to men.</p>
<p>She looked at women whose jobs went uncounted, such as those who worked on farms alongside their husbands or made clothing at home. Goldin said the pay gap that existed then still exists today, even as women gain higher levels of education than men.</p>
<p>In the 1990s, she said, American women led the world in their labor participation rate. But the rate has dropped since then.</p>
<p>"I think something has happened in America," Goldin said. "We have to ... ask questions about piecing together the family, the home ... with the marketplace and employment."</p>
<p>Even as women have made education gains, Goldin notes, they still often feel pressure to stay at home to care for children or to choose jobs that permit them to be available to children.</p>
<p>"They graduate from college at much higher rates than men. They do better in high school than men do. So why are there these differences?" Goldin asked.</p>
<p>Randi Hjalmarsson of the Nobel committee said Goldin's work does not provide specific solutions to the problem. However, she said Goldin did identify "the source of the gap, and how it's changed over time ..."</p>
<p>Hjalmarsson added, "By finally understanding the problem and calling it by the right name, we will be able to pave a better route forward."</p>
<p>Goldin suggested men need to do a better job sharing childcare and work responsibilities. Women, she said, often miss out on career progress that comes with working longer hours or on weekends because they feel pressure to care for children.</p>
<p>She also suggested that the U.S. government put more money into after-school programs. "Very few of us have jobs that finish at 3 p.m.," she said. Goldin noted that women in Canada, France and Japan currently have a higher labor participation rate than those in the U.S.</p>
<p>Goldin said some of the work still needs to be done by <strong>couples</strong>. She notes that "couple equity also leads to more gender equity." Goldin also noted that girls pay attention to how their mothers participated in work and that "each generation (learns) from the successes and failures of <strong>preceding</strong> generations."</p>
<p>The prize comes with an award of about $1 million and will be presented at a ceremony in Sweden later this year.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this report for VOA Learning English based on reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gap </strong>–n. the distance between two things, such as man's pay and a woman's pay</p>
<p><strong>couple </strong>–n. two people who live together and have a romantic or sexual relationship</p>
<p><strong>detective </strong>–n. a person who solves a mystery or finds an answer to something unknown</p>
<p><strong>preceding </strong>–adj. existing or happening before</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>China Aims to Grow Influence in Space with ‘Tiangong’ Station  (2023/10/9) | 中国计划利用“天宫”空间站扩大太空影响力</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/china-aims-to-grow-influence-in-space-with-tiangong-station.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>China plans to increase the size of its space station in the coming years.<br/>
中国计划在未来几年扩大其空间站的规模。</p>
<p>The station will offer astronauts from other countries a different choice for near-Earth missions. The International Space Station (ISS), led by NASA, is nearing the end of its service life.<br/>
该空间站将为其他国家的宇航员提供近地任务的不同选择。由美国宇航局主导的国际空间站的使用寿命即将结束。</p>
<p>The China Academy of Space Technology (CAST) said the operational lifetime of the Chinese space station will be more than 15 years. The organization is China's main space contractor. Chinese officials made the estimate recently at the 74th International Astronautical Congress in Baku, Azerbaijan.<br/>
中国空间技术研究院表示，中国空间站的使用寿命将超过15年。该研究院是中国的主要太空承包商。中国官员最近在阿塞拜疆巴库举行的第74届国际宇航大会上做出了这一估计。</p>
<p>That new operational lifetime would be more than the 10 years announced earlier.<br/>
这一新的运营寿命将比之前宣布的10年更长。</p>
<p>China's space station, known as Tiangong, or the Celestial Palace in Chinese, has been operational since late 2022. It holds up to three astronauts and orbits 450 kilometers above Earth.<br/>
中国天宫空间站自2022年底开始运行。它最多可容纳三名宇航员，在地球上空450公里的轨道上运行。</p>
<p>After an increase from three to six modules, Tiangong will be about 180 metric tons.<br/>
在从三个模块增加到六个模块后，天宫号将达到约180公吨。</p>
<p>Tiangong is 40 percent of the mass of the ISS, which can hold a crew of seven astronauts. But the ISS, in orbit for more than 20 years, is expected to stop service after 2030.<br/>
天宫的质量相当于国际空间站的40%，国际空间站可容纳7名宇航员。但国际空间站在轨道上运行了20多年，预计将在2030年后停止服务。</p>
<p>China has said it expects to become "a major space power". Chinese state media said last year as Tiangong became fully operational that China would be no "slouch" as the ISS headed toward retirement. State media added that "several countries" had asked to send their astronauts to the Chinese station.<br/>
中国表示，它希望成为“一个重要的太空大国”。中国官方媒体在去年天宫全面投入使用时表示，随着国际空间站即将退役，中国将会毫不逊色。官方媒体补充说，已经有“数个国家”要求将宇航员送往中国空间站。</p>
<p>But, the European Space Agency (ESA) said this year it did not have the financial or "political" approval to take part in Tiangong.<br/>
但是，欧洲航天局今年表示，它没有获得参加天宫的财政或“政治”批准。</p>
<p>The announcement suspended a plan that had been developed over years for a visit by European astronauts.<br/>
该公告暂停了一项多年来为欧洲宇航员访问制定的计划。</p>
<p>The Global Times wrote at the time: "Giving up cooperation with China in the manned space domain is clearly short-sighted, which reveals that the U.S.-led camp confrontation has led to a new space race."<br/>
中国《环球时报》当时写道：“放弃与中国在载人航天领域的合作显然是短视的，这表明美国领导的阵营对抗导致了一场新的太空竞赛。”</p>
<p>Tiangong has become a symbol of China's growing influence and belief in its space missions. U.S. law bans China from any work, direct or indirect, with NASA.<br/>
天宫已经成为中国在太空任务日益增长的影响力和信心的象征。美国法律禁止中国与美国宇航局进行任何直接或间接的合作。</p>
<p>Russia is highly involved in the ISS and has similar space diplomacy plans. Russia suggested that its partners in the BRICS group - Brazil, India, China and South Africa - could build a module for its new space station.<br/>
俄罗斯高度参与了国际空间站，并有类似的太空外交计划。俄罗斯建议其在金砖国家集团的合作伙伴——巴西、印度、中国和南非——可以为其新的空间站建造一个模块。</p>
<p>Roscosmos, the Russian space agency, said last year that it was planning to build a space station. The goal is for the station to have six modules that could hold up to four astronauts.<br/>
俄罗斯航天局去年表示，它正计划建造一个空间站。空间站的目标是拥有六个模块，最多可容纳四名宇航员。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA to Launch Spacecraft to Observe Metal-rich Asteroid  (2023/10/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/nasa-to-launch-spacecraft-to-observe-metal-rich-asteroid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA is preparing to launch a spacecraft designed to observe an <strong>asteroid</strong> made mostly of metal.</p>
<p>The launch of the vehicle, called Psyche, is set for October 12 from Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>
<p>The spacecraft will fly to an asteroid also called Psyche. It orbits the sun between Mars and Jupiter. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/asteroids/16-psyche/">says</a> the asteroid was discovered by an Italian astronomer in 1852. Since it was the 16th asteroid discovered, it is sometimes also called 16 Psyche.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This artist illustration depicts NASA's Psyche spacecraft, which will conduct a direct exploration of an asteroid thought to be a stripped planetary core. (NASA/JPL-Caltech)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/EDAA46D5-5DD0-4769-8218-15C4E58F711D_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This artist illustration depicts NASA's Psyche spacecraft, which will conduct a direct exploration of an asteroid thought to be a stripped planetary core. (NASA/JPL-Caltech)</span></div>
<p>Psyche will be NASA's first trip, or mission, to an asteroid that contains a large amount of metal. Past missions explored asteroids made mostly of rock or ice.</p>
<p>Astronomers say the asteroid Psyche is about 280 kilometers at its widest point. They believe it may be part of a center, or core, of a planetesimal. This is an object thought to be the metallic remains of an early rocky planet. Scientists think Psyche is made up mostly of iron and nickel, similar to Earth's center.</p>
<p>NASA believes the asteroid could have separated during violent crashes that happened during our solar system's early creation. Scientists think data collected on the asteroid could provide new details about how rocky planets, including Earth, formed.</p>
<p>But NASA says the object could also turn out to be something else, such as "a different kind of iron-rich body that formed from metal-rich material somewhere in the solar system."</p>
<p>The space agency <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/press-kits/psyche/mission">expects</a> Psyche to travel about 3.6 billion kilometers over six years to reach the asteroid. If the spacecraft reaches its target as planned in August 2029, it will then start orbiting the object for at least two years.</p>
<p>Once in orbit, the mission team will examine data gathered by several science instruments aboard the spacecraft. Psyche will take pictures, map the asteroid's surface and collect data on what materials are contained in the object.</p>
<p>NASA says once Psyche separates from its launch vehicle, it will use a different kind of <strong>propulsion</strong> system never tried in missions beyond the moon.</p>
<p>The system to be used is called solar electric propulsion. Large solar <strong>panels</strong> will be extended outward from the main part of the spacecraft to collect light from the sun. The panels then change, or convert, this sunlight into electricity that powers the spacecraft's <strong>thrusters</strong>.</p>
<p>Psyche will depend on solar electric propulsion to reach its target. NASA describes the thrust as "gentle," but strong enough to push the spacecraft through its long trip. The spacecraft is also set to get a gravitational push when it passes by Mars in May 2026.</p>
<p>NASA said experiments have shown that solar electric propulsion can be highly effective. Scientists estimate Psyche's thrusters "could operate nearly nonstop for years without running out of fuel."</p>
<p>In addition, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/solar-electric-propulsion-makes-nasas-psyche-spacecraft-go">says</a> Psyche will be carrying nearly 1,000 kilograms of propellant, xenon gas, in its tanks. Xenon is also used in automobile headlights and some televisions. Agency engineers have estimated the mission would need to burn through about 15 times that amount of propellant if the Psyche spacecraft used traditional chemical thrusters.</p>
<p>Lindy Elkins-Tanton, with Arizona State University, is the lead investigator for the mission. She said NASA had always planned on having Psyche use an electric propulsion system. "Without it, we wouldn't have the Psyche mission," Elkins-Tanton said.</p>
<p>NASA says the Psyche mission also includes a technology demonstration involving a laser-based data communications system. This experiment is designed to "test the ability of lasers to <strong>transmit</strong> data at increased rates beyond the moon."</p>
<p>The technology to be tested in the demonstration is known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/solar-system/deep-space-optical-communications-dsoc/">optical communications</a>." It is meant to one day replace the radio communication systems long used by NASA to transmit data between Earth and space. NASA says a laser-based communication method will permit the agency to send and receive data faster and more effectively.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and Reuters.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong><em>– n.</em> a force that pushes something forward</p>
<p><strong>panel </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
<p><strong>thruster </strong>– <em>n. </em>an engine that produces propulsion by releasing a jet of fluid or a stream of particles</p>
<p><strong>transmit </strong>– <em>v. </em> to send</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Columbus or Indigenous Peoples’ Day?  (2023/10/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/columbus-or-indigenous-peoples-day.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>This Monday is Columbus Day in the United States.</p>
<p>The U.S. government established Columbus Day as a national holiday in 1934 to honor the explorer Christopher Columbus. The day recognizes Columbus's arrival in the Americas in October 1492.</p>
<p>Recently, critics have said that Columbus did not "discover" America since native people already lived there. His explorations helped open the way for a huge migration of Europeans to what they called The New World. This brought war, disease and death to many native peoples.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by Johnston, R.I., Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr., a statue of Christopher Columbus stands in a park Tuesday, Sept. 26, 2023, in Johnston, Rhode Island. (Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr. via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-bf0a-08dbc5cc1ffd_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by Johnston, R.I., Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr., a statue of Christopher Columbus stands in a park Tuesday, Sept. 26, 2023, in Johnston, Rhode Island. (Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena, Jr. via AP)</span></div>
<p>Some American states have since moved away from honoring Columbus and instead observe a day for Native American people.</p>
<p>In 2021, President Joe Biden issued the first-ever presidential proclamation of Indigenous Peoples' Day. The day is to be celebrated along with Columbus Day.</p>
<p>The May 2020 death of George Floyd, an unarmed Black man in the state of Minnesota, led to nationwide protests against police use of force and racial injustice. Protestors directed some of their anger at statues and monuments honoring Confederate officials from the American Civil War. Many cities then removed the statues and monuments said to be connected to racial injustice, racism and slavery.</p>
<p>The anger led to protest attacks on memorials to Columbus around the country. Statues of the explorer were taken down in Boston, Chicago and many other cities.</p>
<p><strong>A statue was removed, then returned</strong></p>
<p>In the Rhode Island capital of Providence, a statue of Christopher Columbus was also removed in June 2020. The removal came after protestors covered it with red paint and a sign, reading "Stop celebrating genocide." The statue was placed in storage and then purchased for about $50,000 by former Providence Mayor Joseph Paolino.</p>
<p>After three years out of the public eye, the statue will return to a park in the city of Johnston, about 14 kilometers west of the capital. The statue will be officially uncovered on Monday.</p>
<p>Johnston Mayor Joseph Polisena Jr. said people of his heavily Italian-American town are pleased to give the statue a new home.</p>
<p>"It's important and not just for Italian Americans. It's American history. It's world history, if you look at it from a historical <strong>perspective</strong>," he said. "People should learn about him, the good and the bad."</p>
<p>Not everyone is happy with the return of the explorer's statue.</p>
<p>Harrison Tuttle is president of Black Lives Matter Rhode Island PAC. Tuttle said he understands the connection that many of Italian ancestry feel for Columbus. But he wished the mayor had spoken with members of the community who were offended by the decision to return the statue.</p>
<p>"My grandmother who helped raise me was Italian and I grew up in a majority Italian neighborhood," he said. "At the same time, there are better ways to celebrate your <strong>heritage</strong> and culture without celebrating someone who in my opinion is the exact opposite of what Italian culture is."</p>
<p>Darrell Waldron, director of the Rhode Island Indian Council, is the son of a Narragansett father and a Wampanoag mother. He said he and others hoped that the statue would have been sold off and kept out of public view, with money going toward a new statue.</p>
<p>"I would love to see a statue of Native women," he said. "It doesn't always have to be a man."</p>
<p>The debate over the statue in Rhode Island is part of a larger debate in America about what to call the federal holiday that falls on Monday, October 9, this year.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Mario Ritter, Jr. of VOA and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>perspective</strong> - n. a way of thinking about or understanding something</p>
<p><strong>heritage</strong> - n. traditions, achievements, beliefs, etc... that are part of the history of a group ore nation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Universities Work to Protect American Wine Grapes from Wildfire Smoke  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/universities-work-to-protect-american-wine-grapes-from-wildfire-smoke.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>The West Coast of the United States produces over 90 percent of America's wine, an alcoholic drink. However, the area is also <strong>prone</strong> to wildfires.</p>
<p>Such fires cost the American wine industry billions of dollars in 2020. The smoke affects the<strong> flavor</strong> of the growing grapes that later become the wine. And, the flavor is undesirable, say some wine drinkers.</p>
<p>So, wine experts from state universities in the area are working together to protect wine grapes from wildfire smoke.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Oregon State University students show Pinot noir grapes at the university's vineyard near Alpine, Ore., on Friday, Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Selsky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/89dfdbd5-1502-41d4-9d8a-52b64f3da6b0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Oregon State University students show Pinot noir grapes at the university's vineyard near Alpine, Ore., on Friday, Sept. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Andrew Selsky)</span></div>
<p>In 2020, economists say, wildfires caused billions of dollars of losses, which included the wine industry.</p>
<p>As a result, the U.S. Department of Agriculture is paying for grape research at some state schools. They include University of California, Davis (UC Davis), Oregon State University and Washington State University. The research investment is worthy, agriculture officials say, because wine grapes are America's highest-value crop.</p>
<p>Tom Collins is a wine scientist at Washington State. He said "the ability to continue to make wine" is at risk in areas where smoke might be more common.</p>
<p>Cole Cerrato is a researcher working on the problem in Oregon. He stood in Oregon State's vineyard, near the small town of Alpine. He lit a fire and blew the smoke through a hose and into a row of grapes covered in plastic.</p>
<p>Cerrato and other researchers have done this before. They turned the treated grapes into wine. The result was, the wine had an unpleasant flavor of smoke and ash.</p>
<p>The scientists are working to find a way to keep the smoke from getting through the grape skins and creating a bad taste in the wine.</p>
<p>Some are trying to create a process that will treat wine and remove the smokiness. But they are concerned such a process might remove some of the wine's good flavors, too.</p>
<p>Others think they can combine smoke-affected grapes with other grapes. The mix might lessen the smoky flavor.</p>
<p>And Collins is working on a <strong>spray</strong> made from water and a kind of clay that would protect the grapes from smoke. But all the grapes would need to be washed first before being turned into wine.</p>
<p>Oregon State is experimenting with a similar spray treatment for grapes.</p>
<p>In addition, the USDA has provided $7 million toward setting up smoke sensors in vineyards.</p>
<p>Anita Oberholster is leading the efforts to save the wine grapes at UC Davis. In an internet post by UC Davis, she said a network of <strong>sensors</strong> would help grape growers learn if their grapes are at risk. In addition, the readings from the sensors will permit the growers to prove their grapes are free from smoke damage.</p>
<p>Winemakers are glad that the universities are working to help the industry. Greg Jones runs the Abacela winery in southern Oregon and is the director of the state's winemaking trade group.</p>
<p>He said the research has "gone a long way." Now the grape-growers can quickly find out if the fruit has been hurt by the smoke. In the past, winemakers would not know about the wine until it was ready to drink.</p>
<p>"I think it's increasingly clear that we're not likely to find a magic <strong>bullet</strong>," Collins said. But, he said, the researchers will find ways to keep the wine business successful.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>prone</strong>–adj. likely to do or suffer from something</p>
<p><strong>flavor </strong>–n. the taste of something</p>
<p><strong>spray</strong>–n. liquid forced out of a container in very small drops</p>
<p><strong>sensor </strong>–n. a device that detects something, such as the presence of smoke</p>
<p><strong>bullet </strong>–n. a piece of metal shot out of a gun</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do You Stay 'In Shape'?  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/how-do-you-stay-in-shape.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give you definitions, examples, and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today, we talk about <strong>fitness</strong> and exercise. <u>Keeping in shape</u> is a common expression for staying physically fit!</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People exercise inside Warren Hills cemetery in Harare, Zimbabwe, November 24 ,2022. (REUTERS/Philimon Bulawayo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/03370000-0aff-0242-02cc-08dad585c86c_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People exercise inside Warren Hills cemetery in Harare, Zimbabwe, November 24 ,2022. (REUTERS/Philimon Bulawayo)</span></div>
<p>What sort of exercise do you enjoy? How do you get in shape? If you are already in shape, how do you stay in shape?</p>
<p>I used to walk a lot for work and that kept me in good shape. Five days a week I would walk to the train station, walk to the office and then climb stairs. At lunch, my coworkers and I would take a walk outside. Our office is in a beautiful area of Washington, D.C., surrounded by <strong>museums</strong> and <strong>monuments</strong>. So that adds up to a lot of walking!</p>
<p>But then, in 2020 like so many others, I started working from home. I became worried that without all that walking, I would quickly get out of shape! So, I made time for more swimming and short walks around my <strong>neighborhood</strong>. Those two kept me in shape.</p>
<p>Using the word "shape" when talking about fitness and health makes sense. Sometimes, we can describe the human body in terms of size and shape. But we can also use the word "shape" to talk about our projects, our activities, our actions and behaviors.</p>
<p>So, <u>shape up</u> also means to correct bad behavior. For example, a boss might warn an underperforming employee to <u>shape up</u>. The boss may take this expression one step further. She or he might add a threat by saying <u>shape up or ship out.</u></p>
<p>Talking about ships, we also describe things that are clean or running smoothly as <u>shipshape</u>. A ship that is orderly and clean runs more smoothly and is safer. Remember, on a ship, you can be very far away from help. So, keeping things in good order prevents accidents and big problems.</p>
<p>So, what happens if a situation or a project was in trouble but is now going well? Well, we can say <u>things are shaping up</u>. If it's not going well, we can say the project is in <u>bad shape</u>.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear two friends use some of these expressions.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, how's the project going?</em></p>
<p><em>B: It's going well. Everything is <u>shipshape</u> now.</em></p>
<p><em>A: What do you mean ‘now'?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, last week we ran into some trouble. An employee <strong>wasn't pulling his weight</strong> and things weren't getting done. </em></p>
<p><em>A: What did you do?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I told him, "<u>Shape up or ship out</u>." </em></p>
<p><em>A: That's pretty <strong>harsh</strong>! </em></p>
<p><em>B: Maybe, but he <u>shaped up</u>. Now he's a valuable member of the team. I think he was overworked and dealing with some personal issues.</em></p>
<p><em>A: We all run into trouble sometimes. Hey, talking about being overworked ... let's take a break in a bit. I need a walk!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Sounds good. The project is in good shape. But I have to make sure I stay in good shape too!</em></p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. We hope you enjoyed learning some "shape" expressions and verbal phrases.</p>
<p>Practice using them the next time you want to talk about getting or staying physically fit.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fitness </strong><em>–n.</em> physical health and strength</p>
<p><strong>museum </strong><em>–n.</em> a building where interesting or valuable things are collected, shown to the public, or studied</p>
<p><strong>monument </strong><em>–n.</em> a building, artwork or place dedicated to the memory of a person or event</p>
<p><strong>neighborhood </strong><em>–n. </em>the people living near one another</p>
<p><strong>to pull your weight </strong><em>–idiom</em> to do a fair share of work</p>
<p><strong>harsh </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is unpleasant or difficult to accept</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Franklin Roosevelt: Powerful (Part 2)  (2023/10/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt-part-2.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Earlier we told about his rise to power, and his health problems. When he was 39 years old, FDR – as he was often called – became <strong>paralyzed</strong> from the waist down. He was never able to walk independently again.</p>
<p>But that did not prevent him from becoming one of the country's most powerful presidents.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7839e5c5-a69d-40ca-b953-5e64fe4efbf2_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Franklin D. Roosevelt</span></div>
<p><strong>Presidency: The Great Depression and the New Deal</strong></p>
<p>When FDR took office, the United States was in a severe economic depression. Many farmers were not able to sell their crops for profit. Banks across the country had failed. A number of Americans lost their savings and their homes. And more than 25% of the workforce did not have a job.</p>
<p>Yet when FDR took office in 1933, he told people, "The only thing we have to fear is fear itself."</p>
<p>When Americans think of FDR, they often think of that statement. It showed his spirit of hope and <strong>confidence</strong> for which he became known.</p>
<p>Americans also remember FDR for the way he began his presidency. In his <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/first-100-days-meaning/3824866.html">first 100 days</a>, he signed more than 70 bills into law. Some led to major changes in the country. They helped calm the country's banking industry, provided federal aid directly to farmers and the unemployed, and created public works programs.</p>
<p>The acts formed the base of what FDR and others called the New Deal.</p>
<p>Some New Deal programs – including the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/civilian-conservation-corps">Civilian Conservation Corps</a> and the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/history-of-the-tva">Tennessee Valley Authority</a> – created government-funded jobs. In addition to providing a paycheck for workers, the programs were meant to improve and care for the country's natural resources. For example, workers planted trees, made roads, and built dams and power plants.</p>
<p>Americans continue to experience the effects of these programs today.</p>
<p>FDR is also remembered for the way he communicated with the public. At that time, as many as 90% of Americans owned a radio. So, from time to time, FDR spoke to the public on radio broadcasts that became known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/fireside-chats">fireside chats</a>."</p>
<p>The term created an image of the president sitting <strong>comfortably</strong> near a fireplace, talking informally with a few close friends. In fact, FDR gave these talks from his office in the White House. But his voice was warm, and he spoke in an easy, conversational way to listeners, whom he called "my friends."</p>
<p>The combination of FDR's hope, energy, and affectionate concern for everyday Americans made him popular with many voters. He was re-elected easily in 1936.</p>
<p>But FDR had critics, too. Some pointed out that many of his programs failed. They cost a lot of money or were simply not effective.</p>
<p>Others said that FDR's policy of massive government intervention was not American. It restricted capitalism and the free market.</p>
<p>Still others observed that FDR's programs did not help everyone equally. Many New Deal programs aimed to put young, white American men to work. Women, racial minorities, and older Americans were often overlooked.</p>
<p>Critics and supporters alike also noted that FDR greatly expanded the power of the presidency. He added a number of full-time positions to the <strong>executive</strong> branch of government. And he took on the power of Congress to make laws.</p>
<p>Even the Supreme Court found that FDR had, in some cases, gone too far. It ruled that some of his actions were illegal.</p>
<p>FDR worried that the Supreme Court would block many of his other New Deal programs, too. So he proposed a rule. It would give the president power to appoint six new members to the nine-member court. His appointments would almost certainly make sure that his New Deal programs could continue.</p>
<p>Many historians point to FDR's efforts at "court-packing" as one of the most extreme examples of his attempts to expand presidential power.</p>
<p>But Congress did not accept FDR's proposal. Nine justices remained on the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>However, those justices went on to approve FDR's actions anyway. They supported programs such as <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/fdr-signs-social-security-act">Social Security</a>, which was set up to help older adults, disabled people, and others who needed support; and the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Wagner-Act">Wagner Act</a>, which permitted workers to organize in a trade union.</p>
<p>While these efforts and other programs were important parts of FDR's reform efforts, they did not stop the Great Depression. None of the New Deal programs really did. The economy continued to struggle.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: Declaration of war</strong></p>
<p>For several years, the president had been warning lawmakers and other Americans about the political forces in Japan, Germany, and Italy. Leaders in those countries supported nationalist movements and had already invaded or taken control of other areas.</p>
<p>By 1941, more than 30 countries were involved in the conflict.</p>
<p>Many Americans had wanted the U.S. to remain neutral. They regretted becoming involved in World War I. For years, they had taken steps to prevent another major international conflict. Lawmakers had even banned the U.S. government from selling or giving weapons to warring countries.</p>
<p>But FDR believed World War II was different. He believed that Germany was the clear aggressor and needed to be stopped.</p>
<p>So, in the 1930s, FDR received permission from Congress to provide weapons to the countries opposing Germany. After Germany took control of France, FDR received permission to give direct military aid to Britain.</p>
<p>In addition, FDR began preparing the U.S. military for war.</p>
<p>On December 7, 1941, Japanese forces bombed American ships at the U.S. Navy base in Pearl Harbor, Hawaii. More than 2,400 Americans died at Pearl Harbor, and more than 1,700 were wounded.</p>
<p>The day after Pearl Harbor was attacked, Congress quickly approved FDR's request to declare war against Japan.</p>
<p>Three days later, Germany and Italy declared war on the United States. American lawmakers responded <strong>in kind</strong>. The U.S., which had remained neutral for many years, was now completely involved in World War II.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: World War II</strong></p>
<p>During the war, FDR directed much of his attention to what would happen after the fighting stopped. He wanted to create an international order that would improve peace and cooperation. To that end, he helped organize 26 countries into a group he called the United Nations.</p>
<p>FDR also believed that the world's future security depended, in large part, on cooperation between the U.S. and the Soviet Union. He worked hard to create friendly relations with the Soviet leader, Joseph Stalin.</p>
<p>Stalin, FDR, and British prime minister Winston Churchill all famously met at the Russian town of Yalta.</p>
<p>There, the three men discussed plans to bring World War II to an end. They decided to demand that Germany surrender unconditionally. They also talked about diplomatic relations after the war ended.</p>
<p>At the time, many Americans believed the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://history.state.gov/milestones/1937-1945/yalta-conf">Yalta conference</a> was a success. Soviet officials agreed to enter the war against Japan. In return, U.S. officials said the Soviet government could re-gain control over parts of Northeastern China. Soviet officials also agreed to let countries in Eastern Europe hold free elections, and to share rights to veto U.N. decisions.</p>
<p>In the eyes of many Americans, the Yalta agreement showed that the United States and the Soviet Union would be able to cooperate.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>FDR did not live to see the effects of the Yalta agreement, or even the end of the conflict.</p>
<p>He had been president for 12 years. A few weeks before the Yalta Conference, he had been sworn-in yet again.</p>
<p>FDR had already served longer than any U.S. president. All others before him had followed the custom set by the first president, George Washington. They had served no more than two terms.</p>
<p>In the winter of 1944, FDR was beginning his fourth term. But people close to him said he did not look well. Doctors also warned Roosevelt that his health was suffering.</p>
<p>So, in April, FDR went to a warm water<strong> resort</strong> in Georgia where he often rested and recovered his strength. There, he suffered a cerebral hemorrhage. In other words, his brain began to bleed.</p>
<p>World leaders, including Stalin and Churchill, said they were shocked he had died. Many Americans felt the same. They stood alongside train tracks as his body was carried from Georgia to his childhood home in New York.</p>
<p>He is buried there, at Hyde Park. In 1962, his wife Eleanor died and was buried next to him.</p>
<p>Today, Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt are important <strong>figures</strong> in U.S. history. Many programs from the New Deal are still in effect now. FDR also changed the position of president into an active, powerful leader who legally intervenes in the economy and seems to have a personal relationship with Americans.</p>
<p>And Eleanor Roosevelt developed a strong voice of her own. Her humanitarian efforts and work on behalf of civil rights and women's rights have given her a <strong>legacy</strong> independent from her husband.</p>
<p>Both admirers and critics point to the Roosevelts' influence as evidence of their strong feelings about the couple.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>paralyzed</strong> - <em>adj. </em>unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
<p><strong>comfortably</strong> - <em>adv. </em> in a relaxed and easy way</p>
<p><strong>executive</strong> -<em> n. </em>the executive branch of a government (related to the presidency)</p>
<p><strong>in kind </strong>- <em>phrase </em> in a way that is equal or very similar to what someone else has done for you</p>
<p><strong>resort </strong>- <em>n. </em>a place where people go for vacations</p>
<p><strong>figures</strong> - <em>n.</em> people who have a specified status or who are regarded in a specified way</p>
<p><strong>legacy</strong> - <em>n.</em> something that happened in the past or that comes from someone in the past</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
