<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>New Space Telescope Aims to Show 'Dark Universe'  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/new-space-telescope-aims-to-show-dark-universe.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>European astronomers released the first images from the new Euclid space telescope last week.</p>
<p>The European Space Agency (ESA) and the U.S. space agency, NASA, designed Euclid to study dark matter and dark energy. Scientists think those hidden forms of matter and energy make up 95 percent of the universe.</p>
<p>ESA is leading the six-year mission with NASA as a partner. ESA said the images were the most detailed of their kind. They show the telescope's ability to observe billions of <strong>galaxies</strong> up to 10 billion <strong>light years</strong> away.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An artist's concept shows the Euclid space telescope, built by the European Space Agency (ESA) in operation, in this undated handout image. (European Space Agency (ESA)/Handout via REUTERS )" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6487-08dbe1614f2d_cx11_cy3_cw79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An artist's concept shows the Euclid space telescope, built by the European Space Agency (ESA) in operation, in this undated handout image. (European Space Agency (ESA)/Handout via REUTERS )</span></div>
<p>The images covered four areas of the sky. They include 1,000 galaxies belonging to the Perseus <strong>cluster</strong> of galaxies 240 million light years away. In the background, the image shows more than 100,000 galaxies, ESA said.</p>
<p>The cluster is called the Perseus cluster because it appears in the star group, or constellation, Perseus.</p>
<p>Scientists believe such large structures like the Perseus cluster could only have formed if dark matter exists.</p>
<p>ESA's science director Carole Mundell said, "We think we understand only 5 percent of the universe: that's the matter that we can see."</p>
<p>"The rest of the universe we call dark," she continued, "because it doesn't produce light...But we know its effect because we see the effect on visible matter."</p>
<p>One sign of dark matter's hidden force is that galaxies <strong>rotate </strong>more quickly than scientists expect.</p>
<p>Mundell said it seems to have the effect of pulling together some of the largest structures in the universe, like groups of galaxies.</p>
<p><strong>Dark energy is a new mystery</strong></p>
<p>In the 1990s, scientists largely established the existence of dark matter after studying exploding stars called supernovas. That work resulted in a 2011 Nobel Prize shared between three U.S.-born scientists.</p>
<p>Looking at images from the earlier Hubble Space Telescope, scientists came to believe that the universe was not only expanding but that it was expanding faster and faster. That surprising discovery relied on a new concept: dark energy.</p>
<p><strong>A new galaxy map</strong></p>
<p>Euclid has been in a period of testing since its launch. Now it will start taking the images to make a 3D, or three-dimensional, map covering about a third of the sky. Scientists will use that map to look for small differences caused by the dark universe. Scientists hope the new understanding of dark energy and matter will help us learn about how galaxies formed, and why they are found across the universe.</p>
<p>Mundell said, "The purpose of the Euclid mission is really to start to <strong>probe</strong> that dark <strong>sector</strong> of the universe in ways that we've been unable to presently with current ground and space missions."</p>
<p>She added that the Perseus cluster is a good example of this huge gathering of mass. "We think there's lots of dark matter in that cluster and pulling these galaxies together."</p>
<p>A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launched Euclid from Florida in July.</p>
<p>The mission is expected to last six years. However, ESA hopes that Euclid will continue another six months if there is enough fuel to keep it in orbit around the sun. Euclid is orbiting the sun about 1.5 million kilometers away from Earth at "Lagrange Point Two," or L2. That is a place where the gravity of the sun, moon and Earth are balanced. A spacecraft can stay there, using less fuel. NASA's James Webb Space Telescope is also at L2, but it is not in danger of crashing into Euclid.</p>
<p>Other images released by ESA included an unusual galaxy with no exact form. Another was a <strong>spiral</strong> galaxy, sometimes called the "Hidden Galaxy," which looks much like our home galaxy, the Milky Way.</p>
<p>Speaking of the Perseus cluster, Mundell said, "You'll also see lots of background galaxies there as well, which is <strong>phenomenal</strong>. I think I spotted a new one there last night."</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>This story was reported by Tim Hepher and Steve Gorman for Reuters. Jill Robbins adapted it for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>galaxy</strong> – <em>n</em>. a very large group of stars and planets that extends over many billions of light years</p>
<p><strong>light year</strong> – <em>n</em>. the distance that light travels in one year; 9.46 trillion kilometers</p>
<p><strong>cluster </strong>– <em>n</em>. a group of objects gathered close together</p>
<p><strong>rotate</strong> – <em>v</em>. to turn with a circular movement</p>
<p><strong>probe</strong> – <em>v</em>. to ask questions or try to discover facts about something</p>
<p><strong>sector</strong> – <em>n</em>. a part of something or area</p>
<p><strong>spiral</strong> –<em> adj</em>. a shape that winds around and around, with each curve above or outside the previous one</p>
<p><strong>phenomenal</strong> – <em>adj</em>. unusually great or good</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Extreme Dry Condition in Syria, Iraq, Iran due to Climate Change  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/study-extreme-dry-condition-in-syria-iraq-iran-due-to-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A three-year <strong>drought</strong> has left millions of people in Syria, Iraq, and Iran with little water. A new study says it would not have happened without human-caused climate change.<br/>
The west Asian drought started in July 2020. The new study found that it is mostly because hotter-than-normal temperatures are evaporating the little rainfall that fell.</p>
<p>The study is by a team of international climate scientists at World Weather Attribution, a group that researches extreme weather events.</p>
<p>Friederike Otto, an Imperial College of London climate scientist, is the lead writer of the study. She said that without the world warming 1.2 degrees Celsius since the mid-19th century, "it would not be a drought at all."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq on September 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c81130a-45bf-401c-9ab1-c37cc02f3c11_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq on September 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)</span></div>
<p>It is a case of climate change unnaturally intensifying naturally dry conditions into a <strong>humanitarian</strong> crisis that has left people without food, water, and housing, the study says.</p>
<p>Other scientists have yet to confirm if the methods used in this study are correct, in a process called peer review. But it follows scientifically correct methods to look for the signs of climate change.<br/>
The team looked at temperature, rainfall, and <strong>moisture</strong> levels. And they compared what happened in the last three years to many different computer models of the conditions in a world without human-caused climate change.</p>
<p>"Human-caused <strong>global</strong> climate change is already making life considerably harder for tens of millions of people in West Asia," said study co-writer Mohammed Rahimi. He is a professor of climate studies at Semnan University in Iran. "With every degree of warming Syria, Iraq and Iran will become even harder places to live."</p>
<p>Computer models did not find any considerable signs of climate change in the reduced rainfall, which was low but not too rare, Otto said. But evaporation of water in lakes, rivers, wetlands, and soil "was much higher than it would have been" without climate change-increased temperatures, she said.</p>
<p>The study writers found that the drought conditions in Syria and Iraq are 25 times more likely because of climate change, and in Iran, 16 times more likely.</p>
<p>Kelly Smith of the U.S. National Drought Mitigation Center in Nebraska, who was not part of the study, said the research made sense.</p>
<p>Drought is not unusual to the Middle East area. And conflict, including Syria's civil war, makes the area even more likely to have a drought because of weakened water systems, said study co-writer Rana El Hajj. She is with the Red Cross Red Crescent Climate Center in Lebanon.</p>
<p>"This is already touching the limits of what some people are able to <strong>adapt</strong> to," Otto said. She said as long as we keep burning fuels that affect climate change and give out new permits to explore new oil and gas fields, these kinds of events will only get worse. She added that this will continue to destroy lives and keep food prices high.</p>
<p>She said, "And this is not just a problem for some parts of the world, but really a problem for everyone."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em><br/>
________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought</strong> – <em>n</em>. a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<strong>humanitarian</strong> – <em>adj</em>. describing an event or situation that causes or involves a lot of human suffering, especially one that requires aid to be provided to a large number of people<p></p>
<strong>moisture</strong> – <em>n</em>. a small amount of a liquid (such as water) that makes something wet or moist<p></p>
<strong>global</strong> – <em>adj</em>. involving the entire world<p></p>
<strong>adapt</strong> – <em>v</em>. to change your behavior so that it is easier to live in a particular place or situation<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Investigation Finds AI Tool Does Not Improve Adoptions  (2023/11/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/investigation-finds-ai-tool-does-not-improve-adoptions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thea Ramirez is a former social worker. She now runs a non-profit organization called Adoption-Share.</p>
<p>Ramirez has partnered with a computer scientist and developed an artificial intelligence (AI) tool called Family-Match. The tool aims to help social service agencies find the best parents to<strong> adopt</strong> children in foster care. Foster care is a temporary service provided by American states for children who cannot live with their families.</p>
<p>Gian Gonzaga is the computer scientist who worked with Ramirez. He had previously directed the technology behind eharmony, a popular online <strong>dating</strong> tool.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this photo provided by the New York Stock Exchange, Adoption-Share founder and CEO Thea Ramirez, center, and supporters ring the opening bell at the New York Stock Exchange in New York on Aug. 20, 2013. (NYSE via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0295-08dbe1441cfe_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this photo provided by the New York Stock Exchange, Adoption-Share founder and CEO Thea Ramirez, center, and supporters ring the opening bell at the New York Stock Exchange in New York on Aug. 20, 2013. (NYSE via AP)</span></div>
<p>"I was more <strong>excited</strong> about the project than anything I've heard for all of my career," Gonzaga said in a Family-Match video posted to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>Limited results </strong></p>
<p>But an <em>Associated Press</em> (AP) investigation found that Family-Match produced limited results in the states where it has been used. The results raise questions about the ability of AI to solve complex human problems.</p>
<p>Social workers in Florida, Georgia and Virginia told AP that Family-Match was not useful. It often led them to unwilling families.</p>
<p>Virginia and Georgia stopped using Family-Match after a trial experiment. They said the tool only produced one or two adoptions a year.</p>
<p>Tennessee planned to use Family-Match but was unable because of technical issues.</p>
<p>Florida agencies, however, reported a better experience with the tool. They said Family-Match assisted them in finding more possible parents to adopt foster children.</p>
<p>Ramirez did not agree to answer questions from the AP. But she said in an email that "Family-Match is a valuable tool and helpful to users actively using it to support their <strong>recruitment</strong> + <strong>matching</strong> efforts."</p>
<p>And Gonzaga asked all questions to be sent to Ramirez.</p>
<p><strong>Gaining support </strong></p>
<p>Ramirez lives in Georgia, where her nonprofit organization Adoption-Share is based. She got her start by building a website to match possible parents with mothers who wanted their babies to be adopted.</p>
<p>Ramirez marketed her website to organizations that are against abortion. Abortion is a medical process that ends a woman's pregnancy. These organizations seek to provide care for pregnant women to persuade them to give birth.</p>
<p>After the state of Georgia stopped using Family-Match, Ramirez met with the state governor's office and appeared at a legislative hearing to request $250,000 to pay for a statewide expansion.</p>
<p>In July, Georgia decided to use Family-Match again and signed a new agreement. Adoption-Share is permitting Georgia to use Family-Match for free, a state official said.</p>
<p>Family-Match was also used for free in Florida at first. Thanks to a grant, or financial award, from the former head of the company that makes Patrón tequila, a kind of alcohol. The grant ended in October 2022. They would not explain why the grant ended, but said they were very pleased with the work done with Adoption-Share.</p>
<p>After the grant ended, Florida state government paid for Family-Match. Last month, the state awarded Adoption-Share a $350,000 contract.</p>
<p>In May, Family-Match was chosen to receive money from an event supported by Adam Wainwright. At the time, Wainwright was a professional baseball player with the St. Louis Cardinals in the state of Missouri.</p>
<p>This year, Adoption-Share won a contract with the Florida Department of Health to build a tool centered on children with the most severe medical needs and disabilities.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Sally Ho and Garance Burke reported this story for Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>to adopt</strong>–<em>v</em>. to legally make someone else's child your own</p>
<p><strong>match</strong>—<em>v</em>. go well together</p>
<p><strong>recruitment</strong>–<em>n</em>. finding the person you need</p>
<p><strong>dating</strong>—<em>n</em>. a the process of finding a love interest</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Evidence of Crash with Another Planet under Earth's Surface  (2023/11/13) | 科学家发现地球与其它行星相撞的证据藏在地球深处</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/scientists-evidence-of-crash-with-another-planet-under-earth-s-surface.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Scientists have recognized since the 1970s that there are two large, mysterious blobs in the deepest part of Earth's mantle.<br/>
科学家们自20世纪70年代以来就认识到，在地幔最深处有两个巨大而神秘的斑块。</p>
<p>One of the masses is under Africa and the other under the South Pacific Ocean.<br/>
其中一块在非洲海底，另一块在南太平洋海底。</p>
<p>Recent research suggests these masses, which are denser than the material surrounding them, might be from a huge crash early in our planet's history.<br/>
最近的研究表明，这些比周围物质密度更大的斑块可能来自地球历史早期的一次巨大撞击。</p>
<p>Researchers recently said the crash between Earth and a Mars-sized object called Theia might have created the moon.<br/>
研究人员最近表示，地球和火星大小的物体忒伊亚之间的碰撞可能创造出了月球。</p>
<p>Recent research suggests the event happened more than 4.46 billion years ago. Pieces of Theia, however, might have remained inside Earth, sinking to an area just above our planet's hot core of iron and nickel.<br/>
最近的研究表明，这一事件发生在44.6亿年前。然而，忒伊亚的碎片可能留在地球内部，下沉到地球炽热的铁镍核心上方的区域。</p>
<p>Researchers created computer simulations to study their theory of the event. Based on these simulations, they proposed that most of Theia was absorbed into Earth, forming the two masses, while the remaining pieces formed the moon.<br/>
研究人员创建了计算机模拟实验来研究他们对这一事件的理论。基于这些模拟实验，他们提出忒伊亚的大部分被地球吸收，形成了两个斑块，而其余的部分形成了月球。</p>
<p>Qian Yuan is a geophysicist at Caltech and the lead writer of the study that was published recently in Nature.<br/>
钱源（音译）是加州理工学院的地球物理学家，也是最近发表在《自然》杂志上的这项研究的主要作者。</p>
<p>"The bottoms of these blobs are 2,900 kilometers below our feet. The two blobs are about 2 percent of Earth's mass. They were detected by seismology as seismic waves travel slower within these two regions compared to the surrounding mantle. Each of the blobs are twice the mass of the whole moon. So, the blobs are massive," Yuan said.<br/>
钱源说：“这些斑块的底部在我们脚下2900公里处。这两个斑块的质量约为地球质量的2%。它们是由地震学探测到的，因为地震波在这两个区域内的传播速度比周围的地幔慢。每个斑块的质量都是整个月球的两倍。所以，这些斑块非常巨大。”</p>
<p>If the theory is correct, these two masses would represent evidence of the possible moon-forming crash.<br/>
如果理论是正确的，这两个斑块将代表可能形成月球的碰撞的证据。</p>
<p>Caltech professor and study co-writer Paul Asimow said there has not been agreement "on whether we can find evidence for this event not just in the moon but also in some observable property of the modern Earth."<br/>
加州理工学院教授、该研究的合著者保罗·阿西莫表示，“我们是否不仅能在月球上，还能在现代地球的一些可观测特性中找到这一事件的证据，目前还没有达成一致。”</p>
<p>The two masses, Asimow added, are the biggest difference "in Earth structure from a simple layered planet."<br/>
阿西莫补充道，这两个斑块是“地球结构与简单层状行星的最大区别”。</p>
<p>Study co-writer Hongping Deng of the Chinese Academy of Sciences' Shanghai Astronomical Observatory said, "It is incredible because we can uncover relics of another planet - Theia - if we dig deep enough in Earth's mantle."<br/>
该研究的合著者、中国科学院上海天文台的邓宏平说：“这太不可思议了，因为如果我们在地幔中挖得足够深，我们就可以发现另一颗行星忒伊亚的遗迹。”</p>
<p>The increased density of the masses is believed to come from their high level of iron. Moon rocks also contain high iron levels. So, the researchers think it would make sense if they came from the same place: Theia.<br/>
这些斑块密度的增加被认为是由于他们的高铁含量。月球岩石中的铁含量也很高。因此，研究人员认为，如果它们来自同一个地方：忒伊亚，这就讲得通了。</p>
<p>The moon, which orbits Earth at an average distance of about 385,000 km, has a diameter of about 3,475 km, a bit more than a quarter of our planet's diameter.<br/>
月球绕地球运行的平均距离约为38.5万公里，其直径约为3475公里，略大于地球直径的四分之一。</p>
<p>Asimow said that, if the theory is correct, some volcanic rocks that reach Earth's surface might provide pieces of Theia.<br/>
阿西莫说，如果这个理论是正确的，一些到达地球表面的火山岩可能会提供忒伊亚的碎片。</p>
<p>"If our model is correct, the blobs should have isotopes - trace elements - that are similar to the lunar mantle rocks, which can be tested in future lunar missions," Yuan said.<br/>
钱源说：“如果我们的模型是正确的，这些斑块应该具有与月球地幔相似的同位素——微量元素，这可以在未来的月球任务中进行测试。”</p>
<p>Gaining a greater understanding of the hypothesized giant impact could provide information concerning the evolution of Earth and other rocky planets in our solar system and beyond it.<br/>
对假设的巨大撞击获得更多的了解，可以提供有关地球和太阳系内外其它岩态行星演化的信息。</p>
<p>"Earth is still the only confirmed habitable planet, and we do not know why," Yuan said. He added the crash set the early conditions for Earth's development and said: "Studying its consequences may help us to figure out why Earth is different than other rocky planets."<br/>
钱源说：“地球仍然是唯一一颗被确认适合居住的行星，我们不知道为什么。”他补充说这次撞击为地球的发展创造了早期条件，并表示：“研究其后果可能有助于我们弄清楚为什么地球与其他岩石行星有所不同。”</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>English Professor Uses Board Games to Teach Climate Change  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/english-professor-uses-board-games-to-teach-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Isidora Djukic is a biology and chemistry student at John Carroll University near Cleveland, Ohio.</p>
<p>She never thought that one day she would be in a classroom where an English teacher asked her to play a board game in order to learn about climate change.</p>
<p>Djukic is taking a biology class called Climate Change: Global Impacts. At the same time, she is taking an English class called Environmental Literature. Her university requires students to take two connected classes that examine the same subject in different ways.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Debra Rosenthal, top right, worked to bring a climate change board game to her university class." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-f2e6-08dbe16c014d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Debra Rosenthal, top right, worked to bring a climate change board game to her university class.</span></div>
<p>"They both <strong>focus</strong> on global climate change," Djukic said.</p>
<p>Debra Rosenthal is the English professor. At first, Djukic said she was uncertain about Rosenthal's board game idea.</p>
<p>"I was just like: ‘this is interesting. Like we're going to learn about climate change by playing a board game? Like how fun is this actually going to be, and how much are we actually going to take away from it?'"</p>
<p>Rosenthal thought her students would gain a greater understanding about how their own ideas and experiences affect climate change. After testing the games with some adults, she got permission to buy six copies of a game called Solutions. The goal is to pick cards and then add them to the game board in a way that helps reduce global temperatures.</p>
<p><strong>There is no winner</strong></p>
<p>Students do not compete against each other. They work together to choose the best plan of action. The game is different from board games such as Monopoly, where the goal is to win.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said she hoped the games would give students a chance to talk about climate change in a new way. During most classes, students read material and then discuss their ideas.</p>
<p>"But by playing the games, it's a way to be social, to <strong>engage</strong> in <strong>conversation</strong>. There has to be a lot of energy around the table. It's very <strong>collaborative</strong>. And in the game that I chose to play, they really were able to work together and try to come up with a solution so that the planet was not destroyed."</p>
<p>During the class, she said, students laughed, disagreed and had to call for votes as a way to decide how to move forward in the game.</p>
<p>Djukic said it was a "way to have fun...while also learning about such a serious subject."</p>
<p>Both Djukic and Rosenthal said many American high school students do not get a lot of information about climate change. The connected classes at John Carroll permit students to, as Djukic said, "take a <strong>deeper dive</strong> into the science of global climate change...This linked <strong>pair</strong> really opened my eyes."</p>
<p><strong>Climate educator approves</strong></p>
<p>A comment like that would make Megan Yousef smile. She is a climate educator based in Cleveland. She was one of the people who took part in Rosenthal's test event.</p>
<p>Yousef uses a game called Climate Fresk to teach people about the UN's Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Climate Fresk is also a French nonprofit organization.</p>
<p>Yousef said the Fresk is a kind of climate card game that helps people "<strong>get their heads around the problem</strong>. The IPCC report is 4000 pages long."</p>
<p>Yousef's game has 42 cards. She said groups that play the game have a discussion when they place the cards on a long table.</p>
<p>If a player has a card called "destruction of the water cycle," they might start a discussion about severe storms, such as the one that flooded parts of California in August.</p>
<p>The goal of a Fresk is not to win, Yousef said. The idea is for players to learn about climate change and feel "energized" to help their communities.</p>
<p>"It's very powerful for people to come together and <strong>acknowledge</strong> that other people care about this problem too," she said.</p>
<p><strong>World games</strong></p>
<p>Yousef said the Fresk game started in France and 1 million people have played it. She said she knows people like her, in Australia, India, China, Thailand and many European nations, have worked to bring the game to students. They have brought it to health events and financial groups.</p>
<p>Rosenthal said some of the games she looked at would be good for students who are already good at English. One, called Carbonique, is made for French speakers, so her students would need to use a translation program to turn the words into English.</p>
<p>The games are global, Djukic said. That is because she and her classmates said they were able to see how one player's decision about agriculture affected another player on the other side of the world.</p>
<p>She said the games showed her that "in the game of climate change and the climate crisis, no individual wins."</p>
<p>"It's either we all suffer from this, or we all somehow collaborate to work our way out of this and <strong>turn the clock back</strong> on climate change."</p>
<p>In Djukic's opinon, that is a good lesson for any student to learn.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>–v.</em> to place one's attention on something</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong><em>–v.</em> to get involved in an issue or activity</p>
<p><strong>conversation </strong><em>–n.</em> an informal talk involving two or more people</p>
<p><strong>collaborative </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving two or more people working together toward a goal</p>
<p><strong>deep dive </strong>–<em>idiom (informal)</em> to more closely examine something</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>–n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>get one's head around (something) </strong><em>–idiomatic expression (informal)</em> to make an attempt to understand something</p>
<p><strong>acknowledge </strong><em>–v.</em> to show that you know something exists</p>
<p><strong>turn the clock back </strong><em>–idiomatic expression (informal)</em> to bring back the past or make things like they were in the past</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are You 'Sitting Pretty'?  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/are-you-sitting-pretty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about being in a good place. And we begin with an old American pop singer.</p>
<p>When Karen Carpenter sings about being "<u>on top of the world</u>," she describes feeling happy, thankful, and being in a great place.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In its window seat aboard the Royal Albatross, a luxury tall ship, this cat is definitely sitting pretty, August 13, 2023. (Photo by Roslan RAHMAN / AFP) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4570b7b6-3b96-474d-8e6c-6c1dfee751a5_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In its window seat aboard the Royal Albatross, a luxury tall ship, this cat is definitely sitting pretty, August 13, 2023. (Photo by Roslan RAHMAN / AFP) </span></div>
<p>If you are <u>on top of the world</u>, you are in a great position. You are happy with life.</p>
<p>When things are really <u>going your way</u>, you can also say you are <u>sitting pretty</u>. <u>Sitting pretty</u>, means you are in a very favorable situation. You love your job. You have a nice home. And your finances are in good order.</p>
<p>This expression can also mean you are in a good, safe, and secure position. You don't need to worry about the future.</p>
<p>It can also mean you are in an <strong>advantageous</strong> position. For example, when a friend of mine bought property, she found herself in a price war with another buyer. However, she was <u>sitting pretty</u> for several reasons: She offered a big <strong>down payment</strong> and a <strong>flexible</strong> move-in date.</p>
<p>This example shows how <u>sitting pretty</u> can have a little difference in meaning than other similar expressions. It can suggest that you are in a good situation, especially when others are not.</p>
<p>As we said, we have other expressions that mean about the same thing as being <u>on top the world</u> and <u>sitting pretty</u>. If you are in a great situation and have a favorable position, you can also say you <u>have it made</u>. You are <u>ahead of the game</u>. You are <u>going places</u>.</p>
<p>If you feel great about your life and just feel great in general, you might say you are <u>on cloud nine</u>. The origin of this cloud expression comes from the field of agriculture. The <em>Farmer's Almanac</em> explains that scientists wanted to make recording cloud observations easier. So, they rated clouds zero to nine. Zero represented the lowest clouds and nine the highest clouds.</p>
<p>Word experts say this is where the expression <u>to be on cloud nine</u> probably comes from. If you're <u>on cloud nine</u> you'll be very high up which may also describe your feelings.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories.</em></p>
<p>When it comes to your English studies, we hope all of you are <u>on cloud nine.</u></p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advantageous</strong> – <em>adj</em>. helpful; favorable</p>
<p><strong>down payment</strong> – <em>n</em>. a part of the full price paid at the time of purchase or delivery with the balance to be paid later</p>
<p><strong>flexible</strong> – <em>adj</em>. readily changed or changing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Richard Nixon: Resigned  (2023/11/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/americas-presidents-richard-nixon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Richard Nixon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Richard Nixon" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2eb280cd-88b6-472d-a3df-bad2748565c7_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Richard Nixon</span></div>
<p>Nixon is well-known to many Americans for one reason: he was the only president to resign from the position. Facing possible legal action by Congress, Nixon left office early in his second term.</p>
<p>Nixon's early political career was marked by success. He also had some noteworthy achievements during his White House years. And he <strong>attained</strong> his goal of moving the government in a more conservative direction.</p>
<p>In his later years, Nixon and his supporters tried to reclaim his place as an expert on international affairs. But for many Americans, the name "Nixon" remains linked to distrust of national leaders, abuse of power, and political wrongdoing.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Richard Nixon had a difficult early life. He was the second of five sons in a <strong>Quaker </strong>family. His parents owned a lemon ranch in California, near the city of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>But the family struggled financially. And two of Richard's brothers died – one as a small child, and one as a young adult.</p>
<p>In time, his parent's business failed, and the Nixons moved to a nearby town. The parents and children all worked at a filling station that sold fuel and other products.</p>
<p>Despite the many hours he worked at the store, Richard Nixon was a top student in high school. He was offered financial aid to attend Harvard University, but the family needed even more money to send him there.</p>
<p>Instead, he attended a local college, where he became the student body president, joined a debate team, acted in the theater, and played football. Nixon went on to law school at Duke University in North Carolina.</p>
<p>Even with his <strong>impressive</strong> background, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/document-deep-dive-richard-nixons-application-join-fbi-180950329/">he did not get the jobs he sought at the Federal Bureau of Investigation – the FBI</a> – or top law offices. So he returned the California town where he grew up and began working as a lawyer.</p>
<p>There, he married another actor at the community theater. Her name was Thelma Ryan, but she was called Pat. The Nixons went on to have two daughters, Tricia and Julie.</p>
<p>In 1942, Nixon accepted a job with the federal government in Washington, DC. He did not stay in the position long. After the United States entered World War II, Nixon joined the Navy. He served as an officer in the Pacific.</p>
<p>When he returned to the U.S., Republican Party officials asked him to be a candidate for Congress. Nixon agreed. He won two terms in the House of Representatives, and then a seat in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>Two years later, Dwight Eisenhower, the Republican presidential candidate, asked Nixon to be his vice president. The two men won in an electoral <strong>landslide</strong>, and in 1953 Nixon took office as vice president. He was only 40 years old, the second-youngest vice president in U.S. history.</p>
<p><strong>Early political career</strong></p>
<p>Nixon's early political career is remembered for several reasons. One is how quickly he rose to high government office.</p>
<p>Another is for his part in the Alger Hiss case in the late 1940s. Hiss was a top official in the State Department. He was accused of being a Communist in the 1930s and 1940s, and of passing information about the U.S. government to Soviet spies. Hiss denied the accusations.</p>
<p>The case was big news in the United States. It showed the clash between people who believed Hiss was falsely accused as a way to discredit liberal policies, and people who believed the government was protecting communist sympathizers.</p>
<p>Nixon was in the second group. He was part of the investigation against Hiss and pushed for his <strong>indictment</strong>. Nixon's efforts succeeded, and Hiss went to jail for almost four years. Later, <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.nytimes.com/books/97/03/09/reviews/hiss-obit.html">Nixon said</a> that the case was one of the reasons for his rise to power.</p>
<p>Nixon also earned national attention with an event that has become known as the Checkers speech. It happened in 1952, when Nixon was running for vice president.</p>
<p>Some reporters accused Nixon of corruption. They said he was accepting money and gifts from wealthy donors in exchange for his political support.</p>
<p>Nixon went on television to deny the claims personally. At the time, Americans were not used to seeing politicians speaking directly to the public. Yet Nixon spoke informally and emotionally, from what appeared to be a home.</p>
<p>He explained his family's finances. He said he did not accept campaign donations for personal benefit.</p>
<p>But, he added, there was one exception. A supporter had once given the Nixon children a black and white dog they called Checkers. Nixon said he refused to return his daughters' pet.</p>
<p>The public – and Republican Party officials – loved the speech. Nixon appeared warm and likable. Middle-class Americans especially said they could relate to him. Most forgot the claims against him. And Nixon's political career was saved. During the following eight years, he served as vice president in the Eisenhower administration.</p>
<p>But then Nixon's luck turned. In 1960, Nixon lost as a presidential candidate to John F. Kennedy. He blamed, in part, the media. Then in 1962, he lost his efforts to be governor of California.</p>
<p>Nixon said he was retiring from politics. He famously told reporters, "You won't have Nixon to kick around anymore."</p>
<p>Yet seven years later, he was in the White House. It was one of the most memorable <strong>comebacks</strong> in U.S. political history.</p>
<p>
<strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When Nixon took office in 1969, some Americans thought the country was in crisis.</p>
<p>The economy was not doing well. Race riots had been <strong>erupting</strong> in big cities. Many people were still trying to recover from the violence of a year earlier. Civil rights leader Martin Luther King Junior and President John F. Kennedy's brother Robert had both been shot and killed.</p>
<p>Pollution of the environment was becoming a major political issue. Women were pressing for equal rights. And many Americans continued to protest American involvement in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Nixon took action. During his first years in office, he supported reforms and rules to improve the economy; protect the environment; increase workplace and other opportunities for women; support civil rights; and, in his words, bring "peace with honor" in Vietnam.</p>
<p>But, for the most part, Nixon did not have the support of Congress to enact legislation. So he expanded the power of the presidency to carry out his goals.</p>
<p>He is remembered especially for three foreign policy moves. In 1972, he visited China, with which the U.S. government had tense relations since the Chinese Communist Party took power.</p>
<p>As the Alger Hiss case showed, Nixon was strongly anti-communist. But he made establishing diplomatic relations between the two sides possible again.</p>
<p>He also visited the Soviet Union, and was the first U.S. president to visit Moscow. Nixon and the Soviet leader, Leonid Brezhnev, agreed to limit the growth of nuclear arms. Their actions helped ease tensions at a time when U.S. officials were worried about the expansion of communism.</p>
<p>And Nixon did succeed in reaching a peace agreement with North Vietnamese leaders. In 1973, American troops slowly began to leave the country, although fighting there continued.</p>
<p>Nixon's foreign policy achievements helped him in the 1972 election campaign. His first presidential election had been extremely close; the second he won by one of the widest electoral vote margins in U.S. history.</p>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Watergate</strong></p>
<p>Even though he was popular with voters, Nixon had been concerned about his political future. Nixon was so worried that, before the election, he created a secret team to prevent any damaging information from reaching the media. Later, its job expanded to include investigating any information that might hurt his public image.</p>
<p>About five months before Election Day, five men broke into the opposition party's headquarters at the Watergate, a hotel and office complex, in Washington, DC.</p>
<p>The team had already stolen copies of secret campaign documents. Now, in the middle of the night, the men were trying to add listening equipment to the telephones – in other words, spy on the opposition.</p>
<p>But a security guard became suspicious and called the police. The men were caught and arrested.</p>
<p>When the story came to light, Nixon publicly denied that any White House officials were involved in the crime.</p>
<p>But in time, the public learned that Nixon was lying. In fact, he assisted with payments to the men who were arrested.</p>
<p>And he tried to use the Central Intelligence Agency to block an FBI investigation of the crime. Nixon knew that the Watergate break-in was only part of the illegal or questionable acts he could be held responsible for.</p>
<p>Later, people connected with Nixon told investigators that the president had taped everything that happened in his office.</p>
<p>Investigators demanded the tapes. They would prove how much Nixon knew about the illegal operations.</p>
<p>The president refused. He<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/watergate-special-prosecutor-dismissed" target="_blank"> dismissed</a> the lead investigator. Two other Justice Department officials resigned in protest.</p>
<p>A new investigator was appointed, and the U.S. Supreme Court ordered Nixon to release the tapes.</p>
<p>At the same time, the House of Representatives voted to remove Nixon from office. They charged him with <strong>obstructing</strong> justice, abusing his power, covering up a crime, and violating the Constitution.</p>
<p>Finally, Nixon released the tapes. But before the Senate could hold a trial – in which the president would almost certainly be found guilty – Richard Nixon resigned. He left the White House the following day.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Nixon lived for 20 more years. He wrote a number of books, traveled, spent time with his family, and offered foreign policy advice to other leaders. He continued to deny that he had done anything criminal as president; instead, Nixon said he had made bad decisions.</p>
<p>And he did not go to trial. The next president, Gerald Ford, used his power to pardon Nixon "for all offenses against the United States."</p>
<p>But Nixon's image was permanently damaged. Most people found evidence in the tapes that Nixon knew about a related series of crimes commonly known as "Watergate."</p>
<p>They also found that some of his public statements were dishonest. They said he made them to forward his own political goals, not to further the public good.</p>
<p>As a result, Nixon's place in U.S. history is generally thought to be a troubled one. To be sure, he made a number of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nytimes.com/roomfordebate/2012/06/13/did-any-good-come-of-watergate/nixon-had-some-successes-before-his-disgrace"><strong>positive</strong> accomplishments</a>, both within the U.S. and internationally.</p>
<p>But his presidency left the country shaken. When Ford replaced him as president, he said to Americans, "Our long national <strong>nightmare</strong> is over."</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>______________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>attain</strong> -<em> v.</em> accomplish or achieve</p>
<p><strong>Quaker</strong> - <em>n.</em> a member of a Christian religious group whose members dress simply, are against violence, and have meetings without any special ceremony or priests</p>
<p><strong>impressive</strong> - <em>adj.</em> deserving attention, admiration, or respect : making a good impression</p>
<p><strong>landslide</strong> - <em>n.</em> an election in which the winner gets a much greater number of votes than the loser</p>
<p><strong>indictment</strong> - <em>n. </em>an official written statement charging a person with a crime</p>
<p><strong>comeback</strong> - <em>n. </em> a new effort to win or succeed after being close to defeat or failure</p>
<p><strong>erupt </strong>- <em>v.</em> to happen or begin suddenly or violently</p>
<p><strong>obstructing</strong> - <em>v. </em> to slow or block the movement, progress, or action of</p>
<p><strong>positive</strong> - <em>adj. </em> good or useful</p>
<p><strong>nightmare</strong> -<em> n. </em> a very bad or frightening experience or situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Swiss-designed Technology Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/swiss-designed-technology-helps-parkinson-s-patient-walk-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>
Marc Gauthier has Parkinson's disease.</p>
<p>The disease affects his nervous system, weakens his muscles and causes his arms and legs to shake.</p>
<p>The 63-year-old Gauthier had not been able to leave his home for some time. But that was until he became the first person to receive a new Swiss-designed medical device that greatly improved his ability to walk.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Swiss-Designed Tech Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b10a-08dbdfd771af_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Swiss-Designed Tech Helps Parkinson's Patient Walk Again</span></div>
<p>Gauthier received a medical device called a neuroprosthetic at Switzerland's Lausanne University Hospital (CHUV). Part of the device, called an electrode field, is placed against part of the <strong>nervous system</strong> which runs in the back called the spinal cord. Another part of the device, found under his skin below the stomach, uses electricity to <strong>stimulate</strong> the spinal cord to start up his leg muscles. It is called an electrical impulse generator.</p>
<p>"It changed my life because I'm now independent," said Gauthier, a native of the French city of Bordeaux, as he sat with his doctors at CHUV. "I can leave my home, run <strong>errands</strong>. I even go on foot."</p>
<p>The number of people affected by Parkinson's disease has doubled over the past 25 years, the World Health Organization found. Worldwide estimates showed that more than 8.5 million people suffered from the disease in 2019.<br/>
Grégoire Courtine is one of the doctors leading the project. He said the electrical <strong>pulses</strong> delivered to Gauthier's spinal cord has permitted him to walk the way he would have without the disease.</p>
<p>"We strongly believe that many individuals could benefit from this <strong>therapy</strong>," said Courtine. He is a professor at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), the University of Lausanne and CHUV.</p>
<p>The study was published in Nature Medicine recently. The findings by Courtine's team at the NeuroRestore research center suggest the technology could be used more widely in patients with more progressed Parkinson's. Many of those with more progressed, or advanced, Parkinson's have severe problems with being able to move.</p>
<p>Dave Marver is chief executive officer of Onward Medical, which designed the medical device. He said that the device was similar to another device called an implantable defibrillator and those used to deal with pain. But he added the device is special in the way that it targets the spinal cord.</p>
<p>"For the health care system, it will look and feel <strong>familiar</strong>, but it will offer therapy that doesn't exist today," he said.</p>
<p>Courtine's team plans to carry out continuing researching and test the device on six new patients next year.</p>
<p>Jocelyne Bloch is the doctor who performed the operation on Gauthier and co-director of NeuroRestore. She said with this therapy, if people can gain belief in themselves and can go out, socialize and do more things, it is a big plus "... in their daily activities and quality of life."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Cecile Mantovani and Gabrielle Tétrault-Farber reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em><br/>
______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>nervous system</strong> – <em>n</em>. the system of nerves in your body that sends messages for controlling movement and feeling between the brain and the other parts of the body</p>
<strong>stimulate</strong> – <em>v</em>. to make (something) more active<p></p>
<strong>errand</strong> – <em>n</em>. a short journey that you take to do or get something<p></p>
<strong>pulses</strong> – <em>n</em>. a brief increase in an amount of electricity, light, or sound<p></p>
<strong>therapy</strong> – <em>n</em>. the treatment of physical or mental illnesses<p></p>
<strong>familiar</strong> – <em>adj</em>. frequently seen, heard, or experienced<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Strikes End, But When Will Hollywood Get Back to Normal?  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/strikes-end-but-when-will-hollywood-get-back-to-normal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hollywood actors reached a deal to end their four-month strike this week. But it could take some time before you will see your favorite actors on television and in movies again.</p>
<p>The deal permits many actors, writers and technicians to get back to work. And movies and television programs, such as <em>Deadpool</em>, <em>Abbott Elementary,</em> and <em>The Last of Us</em>, are one step closer to returning.</p>
<p>The writers and technicians approved their contract in September after a four-month strike. The actors still have to vote on the deal that their labor <strong>union</strong> leaders made on Wednesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="People cheer after striking actors union reach tentative agreement with Hollywood studios to end the strike in Los Angeles, California,. U.S. November 8, 2023. (REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ba4af444-a3db-4747-898a-4cba806edaef_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">People cheer after striking actors union reach tentative agreement with Hollywood studios to end the strike in Los Angeles, California,. U.S. November 8, 2023. (REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni)</span></div>
<p>The full terms are not yet available, but leaders say the new deal includes pay increases of more than $1 billion. It also covers concerns such as pay for streaming video and protections for the use of artificial intelligence in creating video and audio.</p>
<p>The group that represents producers of television and movies said the agreement "represents a new <strong>paradigm</strong>."</p>
<p>The head of the actor's group is Duncan Crabtree-Ireland. He said the agreement is one "our members can be proud of."</p>
<p>Here are some questions and answers:</p>
<p><strong>What programs will start filming first?</strong></p>
<p>The strike put an immediate stop to the filming of <em>Deadpool 3 </em>with Ryan Reynolds and Hugh Jackman. That movie and a new <em>Gladiator</em> will likely get back to production first.</p>
<p>In television, shows such as <em>Abbott Elementary</em>, <em>The White Lotus</em> and <em>Yellowjackets</em> should start filming again. Writers for those programs started working when their strike ended earlier this year.</p>
<p>However, some films and television programs recently announced delays. They include <em>Yellowstone</em> with Kevin Costner and the next <em>Mission Impossible</em> movie.</p>
<p><strong>What other changes are coming?</strong></p>
<p>Actors who were on strike did not sit for <strong>interviews</strong> or talk about their movies and television shows. As a result, some movies did not get a lot of marketing.</p>
<p>One of the actors in the new movie <em>Killers of the Flower Moon</em> is Lily Gladstone. She will now be able to talk about her big <strong>role</strong> in the movie which also includes Leonardo DiCaprio.</p>
<p><strong>What about the big awards shows?</strong></p>
<p>The Academy Awards, better known as the Oscars, will be back on as usual in 2024. The awards shows will run from mid-January through early March.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any more strikes ahead?</strong></p>
<p>Some strikes could come in the future. Actors who work on video games have approved a strike if negotiations do not work out.</p>
<p>Many actors give their voices and images to video game companies. They are concerned that their voices and faces could be used without their permission in the future.</p>
<p>Another strike could include the people who work <strong>behind the</strong> <strong>scenes</strong> in television and movies. Those workers do things such as plan the lighting and create the sets. Their union said its workers have missed out on a lot of money as film and television projects shut down in 2023.</p>
<p>In addition, people who appear on reality television programs such as <em>The Bachelor</em> or <em>The</em> <em>Real Housewives</em> have started talking about forming a union. The people who appear on those programs do not have a labor group and many have talked about difficult working conditions and long days.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>union </strong><em>–n.</em> an organization of workers formed to protect the rights and interest of its members</p>
<p><strong>paradigm </strong><em>–n.</em> an idea about how something should be done, made or thought of</p>
<p><strong>interview </strong><em>–n.</em> a meeting at which people talk to each other in order to ask questions and get information</p>
<p><strong>role </strong><em>–n.</em> the character played by an actor</p>
<p><strong>behind the scenes </strong><em>–phrase.</em> the activity and work that goes on to support a creative production such as a play or television show</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Many Uses of ‘Get’  (2023/11/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/the-many-uses-of-get.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the use of the word "get."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-91d4-08dbe0812038_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I would like to know more about the use of the word "get." Over time I have realized that it is an important word used in different ways, but I would like a clearer and broader explanation about its use. Could you explain more about this word, please? Thank you very much.</p>
<p>Regards,</p>
<p>Mireya</p>
<p><strong>Answer </strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Mireya. This is a good question.</p>
<p>"Get" is the most common verb in any situation, and it is around the 40th most used word in the English language. In speech, "get" is used almost once per minute on average.</p>
<p>So, your interest in it is well placed.</p>
<p>VOA Learning English has explored "get" several times.</p>
<p>In <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/take-and-get/5605304.html" target="_blank">an earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em></a> program we discussed the difference between "take" and "get." And in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/the-passive-voice-with-get-/4839624.html" target="_blank">an earlier <em>Everyday Grammar</em></a> program we discussed that "get" can be used with the passive voice although it is rare.</p>
<p>We also discussed many meanings of "get" in another <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/getting-to-know-the-verb-get/3617759.html" target="_blank">Everyday Grammar</a></em> program. We shared that "get" has more than 50 uses, and it appears as part of at least 12 phrasal verbs or other expressions.</p>
<p>In earlier programs, we discussed meanings of "get" such as understand, know, obtain, receive, feel, become, buy, fetch, location, and its use to express impatience or <strong>frustration</strong>.</p>
<p>As you can see, there is a lot to know about "get."</p>
<p><strong>Examples of "get"</strong></p>
<p>Here is some additional information about the use of "get."</p>
<p>"Get" is extremely common in spoken language, but it is rare in written language. Careful writers avoid "get" because it is usually informal.</p>
<p>"Get" is often used with subjects that are not living things. This is important because most verbs in speech are used with animate, or live, subjects.</p>
<p>"Get" is the second most common verb used with "do" to demonstrate special importance or difference. For example<em>:</em></p>
<p><em>She finally <u>did get</u> better. </em></p>
<p>There is the structure "get" + adjective presented in the <em>Everyday Grammar</em> program. Adjectives used with "get" describe physical and mental changes.</p>
<p>The most common adjective used with "get" is "worse." Other common adjectives include "older" and "better."</p>
<p>In addition, "get" is often used with adjectives to describe an increasing amount. The most often used phrases for this use are</p>
<p><em>get worse and worse</em> and <em>get bigger and bigger</em>.</p>
<p>We should explain one final use of "get." Some words are used in a fixed series in English. "Get" is used in many fixed series of words in spoken English. They are:</p>
<p><em>I'm going to <u>get</u></em></p>
<p><em>You're going to <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em>I'll have to <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em>You can <u>get</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>I haven't <u>got</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>I haven't <u>gotten</u> any </em></p>
<p><em>You've <u>got</u> to </em></p>
<p><em>If you've <u>got</u> a </em></p>
<p><em>If you/I can <u>get</u> </em></p>
<p><em><u>get</u> on with it </em></p>
<p><em><u>get</u> rid of it </em></p>
<p><em><u>got</u> a bit of </em></p>
<p><em><u>I got</u> one of them </em></p>
<p><em>haven't <u>got</u> a clue </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Mireya.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>frustration</strong>--<em>n</em>. a poor feeling from lack of solving a problem</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Industrial Robot Crushes Worker in South Korea  (2023/11/10) | 韩国工业机器人故障致工人死亡</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/industrial-robot-crushes-worker-in-south-korea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>South Korean police said Thursday an industrial robot had crushed a worker to death at a vegetable processing center.<br/>
韩国警方星期四说，蔬菜加工中心的一个工业机器人将一名工人挤压致死。</p>
<p>The male worker suffered severe head and chest injuries after the robot's arms pushed his body against a conveyor belt used to move box containers. The man was treated at a hospital in the southern county of Goseong, but died of his injuries.<br/>
这个机器人的机械臂将这名男性工人的身体推到用于移动箱子的传送带上，导致其头部和胸部严重受伤。这名男子在南部高城县的一家医院接受治疗，但因伤势过重死亡。</p>
<p>Police said early evidence suggested human error was more likely to blame than problems with the robot itself. But investigators were looking into whether the machine was defective or incorrectly designed. The robot was being used to lift boxes filled with vegetables.<br/>
警方表示，早期证据表明，与机器人本身的问题相比，人为失误更可能是罪魁祸首。但调查人员正在调查这台机器是有缺陷还是设计错误。该机器人被用于举起装满蔬菜的箱子。</p>
<p>Police said the victim of the accident was an employee of a company that deploys industrial robots to businesses. He was sent to the processing center to examine whether the machine was working correctly.<br/>
警方表示，事故受害者是一家为企业部署工业机器人的公司的员工。他被派往该加工中心检查机器是否正常工作。</p>
<p>A police official who spoke to The Associated Press (AP) said investigators were looking into the possibility that the robot had misidentified the worker as a box. The machine's sensors are designed to identify boxes. Security video suggested the man had moved near the robot with a box in his hands and this could have caused the machine's reaction, the official said.<br/>
一名警方官员在接受美联社采访时表示，调查人员正在调查机器人是否将工人误认为盒子。机器的传感器设计用于识别箱子。这位官员说，安全录像显示，这名男子手里拿着一个盒子靠近机器人，这可能会引起机器做出反应。</p>
<p>The machine that caused the death was one of two used at the center to lift and transport boxes loaded with vegetables to be exported to other Asian nations. Such robots are common in South Korean agricultural communities.<br/>
造成死亡的机器是该中心用来举起和运输出口到其他亚洲国家的蔬菜箱的两台机器之一。这种机器人在韩国农业社区很常见。</p>
<p>A police investigator told the AP the machine was not an "artificial intelligence-powered robot," but a device designed to just lift and place boxes. He said police were working with related agencies to find out whether the machine had safety issues.<br/>
一名警方调查员告诉美联社，这台机器不是“人工智能驱动的机器人”，而是一种设计用于举起和放置箱子的设备。他说，警方正在与相关机构合作，以查明这台机器是否存在安全问题。</p>
<p>The International Federation of Robotics, based in Germany, estimated South Korea had 1,000 industrial robots per 10,000 employees in 2021. This represents the highest density of industrial robots in the world. Many of these robots are used in manufacturing factories such as electronics and auto-making.<br/>
总部位于德国的国际机器人联合会估计，2021年韩国每10000名员工拥有1000台工业机器人。这是世界上密度最高的工业机器人。这些机器人中的许多被用于制造工厂，如电子产品和汽车制造。</p>
<p>South Korea has had other industrial robot accidents in recent years. In March, a manufacturing robot crushed and seriously injured a worker who was examining it at an auto parts factory in Gunsan. And in 2022, a robot working near a conveyor belt crushed a worker to death at a milk factory south of the capital Seoul.<br/>
近年来，韩国还发生了其他工业机器人事故。今年3月，群山一家汽车零部件工厂的一台制造机器人挤压并重伤了一名正在检修的工人。2022年，在首都首尔南部的一家牛奶厂，一个在传送带附近工作的机器人将一名工人挤压致死。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·琳恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Should You ‘Leave the Leaves’ on the Ground?  (2023/11/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/should-you-leave-the-leaves-on-the-ground.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>There is a growing movement to leave leaves on the ground, instead of gathering them to be disposed of.</p>
<p>The idea is to avoid sending bagged-up fallen leaves to landfills. Instead they will naturally <strong>decompose</strong> over the winter into rich organic matter. The matter also shelters pollinators and other insects.</p>
<p>Done correctly, leaving the leaves is one of the best ways to turn yard waste into free <strong>fertilizer</strong>, which is good for plants, the environment, and saving money. But it is important to consider the types of leaves that are falling and where they are landing.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Nov. 3, 2023, image shows fallen leaves on Long Island, New York. (Jessica Damiano via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3166-08dbe156a25c_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This Nov. 3, 2023, image shows fallen leaves on Long Island, New York. (Jessica Damiano via AP)</span></div>
<p>Whole leaves should not be permitted to remain on walkways, where they could make the path dangerously slippery. They should also not be left on grass lawns, where they are likely to cause disease.</p>
<p>Although some grasses can handle a small amount of leaf waste, too much can threaten their health. In areas that experience snow cover, water would become trapped between grass and leaves. That could lead to <strong>mold</strong> and other fungal infections. In areas without snow, whole leaves that cover grasses block water and sunlight from reaching the soil below.</p>
<p>Many people choose to break up the leaves using a machine and let the pieces to fall between pieces of grass. Then the pieces break down further in the soil. However, this treatment can kill insects and their eggs.</p>
<p>Another method is to take the leaves off the lawn and spread them lightly to cover garden beds. The leaves mostly break down by spring and almost entirely by summer. But if not, they should be removed before spring growth begins.</p>
<p>Leaves also can be used to make leaf mold, a type of <strong>compost</strong> made entirely from leaves. Just pile them up in a corner, add nitrogen fertilizer, and water it to keep it from drying out. It may take a year or two, but the leaves will break down into a nutritious soil.</p>
<p>Some leaves prevent the growth of other plants. Black walnut, for example, contains a poison in its leaves that kills many plants, including hydrangeas, petunias, apples, peppers, tomatoes and potatoes.</p>
<p>Avoid putting leaves in beds if the leaves are especially large or thick, like those of oaks. Their slow decomposition rates could block sunlight and water from the soil and plant roots.</p>
<p>Fallen leaves are nature's <strong>mulch</strong>. They build fertile soil, protect plant roots and shelter wildlife, in your garden, and elsewhere. Why waste that important resource?</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p>
<strong>decompose</strong> — <em>v.</em> to cause something to be slowly destroyed and broken down by natural processes, chemicals, etc.<br/></p>
<strong>fertilizer</strong> — <em>n.</em> a substance (such as manure or a special chemical) that is added to soil to help the growth of plants<br/><p></p>
<strong>mold</strong> — <em>n. </em>a container that is used to give its shape to something that is poured or pressed into it<br/><p></p>
<strong>compost</strong> — <em>n. </em>a decayed mixture of plants that is used to improve the soil in a garden<br/><p></p>
<strong>mulch</strong> — <em>n. </em>a material that is spread over the ground in a garden to protect the plants or help them grow and to stop weeds from growing<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Young, Educated Are Leaving as Turkey Marks Its 100th Anniversary  (2023/11/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/young-educated-are-leaving-as-turkey-marks-its-100th-anniversary.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Economic problems and fears of repression in Turkey have caused Huseyin Buyukdag to make a decision. The teacher and his wife want to move to Germany to find a better life.</p>
<p>They are among a growing number of young and educated people who say they want to leave Turkey. They say their rights and freedoms there are being taken away, and inflation is high under President Recep Tayyip Erdogan.</p>
<p>After Erdogan secured a third term in office in May elections, things are unlikely to change, Buyukdag said.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="People wait for their turn at a visa application center, in Istanbul on November 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Emrah Gurel)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b41d6d1a-1623-4b5f-bde3-71263d17e00e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">People wait for their turn at a visa application center, in Istanbul on November 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Emrah Gurel)</span></div>
<p>"Even if I don't want this, even if I hate this, I will...leave this beautiful country," the 27-year-old English teacher told The Associated Press (AP).</p>
<p>Turkey is a country of over 84 million people. Several crises have affected Turkey in recent years. The official yearly inflation rate was 61 percent last month. Some economists believe the real number is double that.</p>
<p>For many, the way out is through education visas to study in other countries or work permits. TurkStat is the government's agency for official numbers, or statistics. It said 139,531 Turkish citizens left the country in 2022, compared to 103,613 in 2021. Those aged 25 to 29 formed the biggest group.</p>
<p>The numbers are a big increase from 77,810 Turks who left in 2020, when the coronavirus pandemic was at its highest.</p>
<p>Besim Dellaloglu is a <strong>sociologist</strong>. He believes people are leaving because of the disappearance of normal things in a democracy. Some are calling the movement of people to foreign countries "brain drain."</p>
<p>Brain drain happens when highly trained or educated people leave a country for a better life somewhere else.</p>
<p>Dellaloglu does not believe the brain drain will go away without "decreasing <strong>polarization</strong> in Turkey."</p>
<p>He said the most likely to leave are medical workers and those that work with technology. Highly trained individuals from all fields are also leaving.</p>
<p>Many other Turks prefer to stay, even with the problems.</p>
<p>"I can understand the people who are leaving, some things really need to change," said Fatma Zehra Eksi. She is a 22-year-old student from Istanbul. She noted, "But if we...leave because we are not <strong>comfortable</strong> here, then there will be no one left here to change things."</p>
<p>The growing lack of happiness comes as Turkey marks the 100th anniversary of Ataturk's establishment of the country as a <strong>secular</strong> republic. Ataturk was the first president of Turkey after the collapse of the Ottoman Empire.</p>
<p>Some Turks hoping to leave Turkey say that even getting a <strong>tourist</strong> visa, seen as a step to immigration, has become difficult.</p>
<p>AP spoke to many people considering <strong>emigration</strong> from Turkey. They said European countries have increased visa restrictions for Turkish travelers. These people and reports in Turkish media say the rate of visa rejections has increased and the process has become more complex.</p>
<p>Nikolaus Meyer-Landrut is a European Union diplomat for Turkey. He said rejections in Turkey were below the worldwide average. He told the Hurriyet newspaper in June that the EU has no policy of blocking visas for Turkish citizens.</p>
<p>Erdogan's government considers the reported visa rejections an effort to hurt support for his government by making Turks feel they cannot travel freely to Europe.</p>
<p>His government has promised to bring people home and turn back the brain drain. Erdogan has offered money in the form of grants, and jobs to Turks teaching in other countries. He said 6,000 people had returned under the plan.</p>
<p>However, Buyukdag, the teacher, said he and his wife have stepped up their efforts to leave a country where, he said, he could lose his job for saying the "wrong things."</p>
<p>"In Germany or in any Western country, you are a valuable person," he said. "In Turkey, you are not a valuable person because you can be called a <strong>traitor</strong> any time."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English.</em><br/>
______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sociologist</strong> –<em>n</em>. a person who studies society, social organizations and social behaviors</p>
<strong>polarize</strong> – <em>v</em>. to cause (people or opinions) to separate into opposing groups<p></p>
<strong>comfortable</strong> – <em>adj</em>. allowing you to be relaxed: causing no worries, difficulty, or uncertainty<p></p>
<strong>secular</strong> – <em>adj</em>. not related to religious things<p></p>
<strong>tourist</strong> – <em>n</em>. a person who travels to a place for pleasure<p></p>
<strong>emigration</strong> – <em>n</em>. the process of leaving a country to live in another one<p></p>
<strong>traitor</strong> – <em>n</em>. a person who betrays a country or group of people by helping or supporting an enemy<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Florida Homes Built to Resist Hurricanes, Reduce Emissions  (2023/11/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/florida-homes-built-to-resist-hurricanes-reduce-emissions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hurricane Michael hit the American state of Florida five years ago. The major storm came with wind speed of 250 kilometers per hour. It damaged many homes, boats, cars and trucks.</p>
<p>But Bonny Paulson's home in the coastal community of Mexico Beach only suffered minor damage to its roof. That is because it was built to <strong>resist </strong>high winds and heavy rain.</p>
<p>While others left the area ahead of the storm, Paulson stayed behind. "I wasn't nervous at all," she said. Almost all the nearby homes were badly damaged. Many were completely destroyed.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Bonny Paulson stands in front of her home in Mexico Beach, Fla. on Thursday, Oct. 19, 2023. The hurricane resistant house, designed by Deltec, was one of the few remaining structures left after Hurricane Michael hit the area in 2018. (AP Photo/Laura Bargfeld)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4fc80baa-0758-4884-bbdc-9b5a611c202b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Bonny Paulson stands in front of her home in Mexico Beach, Fla. on Thursday, Oct. 19, 2023. The hurricane resistant house, designed by Deltec, was one of the few remaining structures left after Hurricane Michael hit the area in 2018. (AP Photo/Laura Bargfeld)</span></div>
<p>Now, home builders in hurricane-<strong>prone</strong> areas are building more homes like the one Paulson owns.</p>
<p>The new homes are built with recycled or advanced materials that reduce energy use. Solar panels are fitted closely on the roof to prevent high winds from getting under. And they are easier to heat and cool.</p>
<p>Deltec is the homebuilder that built Paulson's home. The company says only one of nearly 1,400 homes it built has been badly damaged by a hurricane. The homes, Deltec says, also use better material and equipment to reduce energy use.</p>
<p>Steve Linton is head of Deltec. He said, "The real <strong>magic </strong>here is that we're doing both."</p>
<p>Other homebuilders are also developing neighborhoods that are both resistant to hurricanes and friendly to climate change.</p>
<p>In Cortez, Florida, Pearl Homes has completed 26 homes and plans for 30 more by the end of next year in the Hunters Point neighborhood.</p>
<p>The homes are LEED-certified platinum, which is the highest rating for homes that use less energy. The homes and roads are also built higher off the ground to avoid flooding.</p>
<p>Marshall Gobuty is the chief executive of Pearl Homes. He said he wants the homes "to be so unlike everything else that goes on in Florida." He said there are new homes nearby that are "underwater."</p>
<p>Paulson, the homeowner in Mexico Beach, said she did not want to live "day to day worried about (a storm)." She said the new building materials also reduce the costs of energy needed to power her home. She said she used to pay $250 a month for energy use in a different home. Now her cost is about $32.</p>
<p>Babcock Ranch is another hurricane-resistant and climate change-friendly community in south Florida. The community calls itself the first solar-powered town in the U.S. The town has 680,000 solar panels to produce energy and uses large batteries to store it. And the homes are built to deal with high winds and heavy rain.</p>
<p>In 2022, Hurricane Ian came through Babcock Ranch and left very little damage. Syd Kitson started the town in 2006. He said, "Unless you build in a very resilient way, you're just going to constantly be repairing or <strong>demolishing</strong> the home."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p>
<em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p>
<strong>resist </strong>–v. to push back against something, to not fall down</p>
<p><strong>prone </strong>–adj. likely to happen or happening often</p>
<p><strong>recycled </strong>–adj. made from material that was used before or was once something else</p>
<p><strong>magic </strong>–n. something that seems special or impressive</p>
<p><strong>resilient </strong>–adj. something that has the ability to recover</p>
<p><strong>demolish </strong>–v. to tear something down</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>2023 Likely to Be Warmest Year in Recorded History  (2023/11/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/likely-to-be-warmest-year-in-recorded-history.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>European researchers say a very hot October has put 2023 on a likely path to become the warmest year in recorded history.</p>
<p>Last month, world temperatures beat a 2019 record for warmest October on record by 0.4 degrees, scientists from the European Union's Copernicus Climate Change Service announced. The EU agency issues monthly reports on climate observations across Europe.</p>
<p>The latest October record nearly guarantees that 2023 will be the hottest year on record, said Copernicus deputy director Samantha Burgess. "The amount that we're smashing records by is shocking," Burgess told <em>The Associated Press</em> (AP).</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, cracks are shown in the partly dried-up river bed of the Gan River, a tributary to Poyang Lake in Nanchang, Jiangxi province, China, August 28, 2022. (REUTERS/Thomas Peter)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ce82-08dbe0893831_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, cracks are shown in the partly dried-up river bed of the Gan River, a tributary to Poyang Lake in Nanchang, Jiangxi province, China, August 28, 2022. (REUTERS/Thomas Peter)</span></div>
<p>Scientists have long linked rising world temperatures to gases from the burning of <strong>fossil fuels</strong>. El Nino has also been warming ocean waters this year.</p>
<p>El Nino is a warming of surface temperatures in the eastern and central Pacific Ocean. The event usually causes hot, dry weather in Asia and Australia and can drive weather changes in other parts of the world.</p>
<p>The World Meteorological Organization has predicted the El Nino weather pattern will last until at least April 2024.</p>
<p>Michael Mann is a climate scientist at the University of Pennsylvania. He told the AP that most El Nino years now become record-breakers because that climate event combines with rising temperatures linked to human causes.</p>
<p>A warmer planet means more extreme and intense weather events like severe <strong>drought</strong> or hurricanes that hold more water, said Peter Schlosser. He is vice president of the Global Futures Laboratory at Arizona State University. Schlosser was not involved with the Copernicus report.</p>
<p>"We better take this warning that we actually should have taken 50 years ago or more and <strong>draw</strong> the right <strong>conclusions</strong>," Schlosser said. He added that this means the world should expect more records to be broken as a result of that warming. But he questions whether the changes will come in smaller steps going forward.</p>
<p>Schlosser noted Earth was already reaching temperatures above the 1.5 degrees Celsius target limit established by the Paris agreement on climate change. He said the latest observations are another sign there is an urgent need for action to help stop planet-warming pollution.</p>
<p>"It's so much more <strong>expensive</strong> to keep burning these fossil fuels than it would be to stop doing it. That's basically what it shows," said Friederike Otto. She is a climate scientist at Imperial College London. "And of course, you don't see that when you just look at the records being broken and not at the people and systems that are suffering," Otto said. "But that... is what matters."</p>
<p>The findings from Copernicus come three weeks before a United Nations meeting in the United Arab Emirates capital of Dubai, known as COP28. Delegates from nearly 200 countries will attend the gathering. They are seeking to negotiate stronger action to fight climate change.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil fuels</strong> – <em>n. </em>fuels such as coal, oil, or natural gas that are formed in the Earth from dead plants or animals<br/>
</p>
<strong>drought</strong> – <em>n.</em> a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain<br/>
<p></p>
<strong>draw a conclusion</strong> (about something) – <em>phrase</em> to consider the facts of a situation and make a decision about whether it is true, correct, likely to happen, etc.<br/>
<p></p>
<strong>expensive</strong> – <em>adj.</em> costly
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA: Scientists Discover Oldest Black Hole Yet  (2023/11/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/nasa-scientists-discover-oldest-black-hole-yet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have discovered the oldest black hole yet.</p>
<p>The huge object formed about 470 million years after the Big Bang, researchers said.</p>
<p>The study was published recently in Nature Astronomy. The researchers said the findings confirm their theory: Supermassive black holes existed in the very early universe. The United States space agency, NASA, used its James Webb Space Telescope and Chandra X-Ray Observatory over the past year to make the observations.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This annotated image provided by NASA on Nov. 6, 2023, shows a composite view of data from NASA's Chandra X-ray Observatory and James Webb Space Telescope indicating a growing black hole just 470 million years after the big bang. (NASA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f0e69dc7-d0fb-45cc-81d7-141f3c5e2a45_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This annotated image provided by NASA on Nov. 6, 2023, shows a composite view of data from NASA's Chandra X-ray Observatory and James Webb Space Telescope indicating a growing black hole just 470 million years after the big bang. (NASA via AP)</span></div>
<p>If the universe is 13.7 billion years old, the age of this black hole would be 13.2 billion years.</p>
<p>The scientists said that this oldest black hole is extremely massive — 10 times bigger than the black hole in our own Milky Way galaxy.</p>
<p>It is believed to weigh anywhere from 10 percent to 100 percent the mass of all the stars in its galaxy, said the study's lead writer Akos Bogdan of the Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics. That is far larger than all the black holes in our Milky Way and its closer galactic neighbors, he noted. Their mass on average is only about one-tenth of a percent of that of the stars in their galaxies.</p>
<p>"It's just really early on in the universe to be such a <strong>behemoth</strong>," said Yale University's Priyamvada Natarajan, a study team member. The Astrophysical Journal Letters published a report linked to the study.</p>
<p>"It's <strong>astounding</strong> how this thing actually is sitting in place already with its galaxy so early on in the universe," Natarajan said.</p>
<p>The researchers believe the black holes formed from huge clouds of gas that collapsed in a galaxy next to another with stars. The two galaxies joined, and the black hole was in control.</p>
<p>The Chandra telescope found the object with X-ray imaging. That fact confirms "without a doubt that it is a black hole," Natarajan said. With X-rays "you're actually capturing the gas that is being gravitationally pulled into the black hole, sped up and it starts <strong>glowing</strong> in the X-rays," she said.</p>
<p>Natarajan also said this black hole is considered a <strong>quasar</strong> since it is actively growing, and the gas is extremely bright.</p>
<p>In addition to the latest find, scientists said the Webb telescope might have found a black hole that is 29 million years older. However, that object still needs to be observed in X-rays to be confirmed. Natarajan expects more early black holes will be found — perhaps not as far away, but still very distant.</p>
<p>"We are expecting a new window to open in the universe, and I think this is the first <strong>crack</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>The two space telescopes — Webb and Chandra — were able to observe the part of space that holds this galaxy, UHZ1, and its black hole because of what is called "gravitational lensing." The gravity of a galaxy much closer to Earth <strong>magnified </strong>the apparent image of UHZ1 and its black hole, which are further in the background.</p>
<p>"It's a pretty <strong>faint </strong>object, and thanks to...luck, nature has magnified it for us," Natarajan said.</p>
<p>NASA launched the Webb telescope in 2021 to a point 1.6 million kilometers away from Earth. It is the biggest and most powerful observatory ever sent into space. Webb captures images of the universe in infrared light. The much older Chandra records X-ray radiation. It was sent into orbit in 1999.</p>
<p>"I absolutely find it <strong>amazing</strong> that Chandra can do such amazing discoveries 24 years after its launch," Bogdan said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>behemoth</strong> –n. something very big and powerful<br/></p>
<strong>astounding</strong> –adj. causing a feeling of surprise and wonderment<br/><p></p>
<strong>glowing</strong> –adj. shining with a steady, warm light<br/><p></p>
<strong>quasar</strong> –n. a powerful source of radio waves that is very distant<br/><p></p>
<strong>crack</strong> –n. a long thin break in something<br/><p></p>
<strong>magnify</strong> –v. the property of making something look closer than it actually is<br/><p></p>
<strong>faint</strong> –adj. not bright; hard to see<br/><p></p>
<strong>amazing</strong> –adj. wonderful; very interesting<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Do We Need Human-like Robots?  (2023/11/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/do-we-need-human-like-robots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Building a robot that is both human-like and useful has been a goal of engineers for many years.</p>
<p>Interest in the idea of artificial intelligence (AI) has created another wave of investment in robot technology to build a human-like robot. But most of the current robot models that aim to look like people are not too effective. They appear to work well in planned performances but not in real life. However, this has not stopped some <strong>startups</strong> from continuing to develop human-like, or humanoid, robots.</p>
<p>"The <strong>intention</strong> is not to start from the beginning,'" said Jonathan Hurst. He is co-founder and chief robot officer at Agility Robotics. "We're trying to make robots that can operate in human spaces."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Agility Robotics' robot Digit performs maneuvers at the company's office in Pittsburgh on August 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Freed)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/926a0c30-5f71-4ce0-a03e-f2ff3cb64616_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Agility Robotics' robot Digit performs maneuvers at the company's office in Pittsburgh on August 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Freed)</span></div>
<p>Hurst said Agility's robot Digit is designed to do human things. It is not designed to look like a human.</p>
<p>What it does is pick up objects and move them. Amazon announced in October that the company will begin testing the Digit robot for use in some of its storage buildings. Agility opened a factory in the western state of Oregon in September to mass produce their robot.</p>
<p>Digit has a head containing cameras, other sensors, <strong>animated</strong> eyes, and an upper body that provides power. It has two arms and two legs, but its legs are not human-like. It looks similar to cats and dogs that walk on the very end of their feet, rather than on flat feet.</p>
<p>Competing robot-makers, like Figure AI, are designing robots differently. The company believes that only human-like robots can effectively work in places built for humans.</p>
<p>Figure AI also plans to start developing robots for simpler uses. But it aims to build robots that can perform more than one job to help take over work from humans.</p>
<p>"There's not enough people doing these jobs, so the market's massive," said Figure AI chief Brett Adcock. He said he believes his company can sell millions or even billions of humanoid robots if it can make a robot do a human's work.</p>
<p>At the moment, however, Adcock's company does not have a model that is ready. The company was founded just over a year ago after it raised tens of millions of dollars. Figure AI released a 38-second video of its robot, Figure, walking through its building in California.</p>
<p>Elon Musk, head of Tesla, is also trying to build a human-like robot, called Optimus, in the electric carmaker's robotics division. But a presentation of the robot's walking last year did not win over experts in the field.</p>
<p>Agility's Digit robot caught Amazon's attention because it can walk and move in a way that would work well with the robots the company already uses. Those robots look like vehicles and work in large buildings carrying heavy loads.</p>
<p>Tye Brady is Amazon's chief technologist for robotics. He said the way the robot moves "is more interesting" than the way it looks.</p>
<p>Agility Robotics co-founder and chief Damion Shelton said its Digit robot is "just the first use case" of a new generation of robots. He hopes people will <strong>embrace</strong> robots rather than fear them as they enter businesses and homes.</p>
<p>"So, in 10, 20 years, you're going to see these robots everywhere," Shelton said. He added: "...Human-<strong>centric</strong> robots like that are going to be part of human life."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Matt O'Brien reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>startup </strong><em>– n. (business jargon)</em> a general term for a new business with a new product which gives no information about the business organization under law</p>
<p><strong>intention </strong>– <em>n</em>. the thing that you plan to do or achieve: an aim or purpose</p>
<p><strong>animated </strong><em>–adj.</em> able to move or change</p>
<p><strong>embrace </strong>– <em>v</em>. to accept (something or someone) readily or gladly</p>
<p><strong>-centric </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having (something) as a central interest, influence, or subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Kenya Surprises Public with Holiday to Plant Trees  (2023/11/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/kenya-surprises-public-with-holiday-to-plant-trees.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The government of Kenya says November 13th will be a public holiday for nationwide tree planting. The surprise holiday is part of a huge plan to grow 15 billion trees by 2023 to fight climate change.</p>
<p>Kithure Kindiki is the Interior Minister of the African nation. He announced the tree planting holiday via the newspaper, which was then posted to social media. The announcement came after a cabinet meeting last week and was led by President William Ruto.</p>
<p>Kindiki says that the government expects the public to plant trees as part of their, "...patriotic contribution to the national efforts to save our Country from the <strong>devastating</strong> effects of Climate Change."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Jacaranda tree in bloom in Nairobi, Kenya, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. Every year in early October, clusters of purple haze dot Nairobi's tree line as the city's jacaranda trees come into bloom. (AP Photo/Sayyid Abdul Azim)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3496-08dbe05d3044_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Jacaranda tree in bloom in Nairobi, Kenya, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. Every year in early October, clusters of purple haze dot Nairobi's tree line as the city's jacaranda trees come into bloom. (AP Photo/Sayyid Abdul Azim)</span></div>
<p>The government has saved more than $80 million this year for the project. The goal is to increase tree cover to more than 10 percent. Right now, tree cover is only at seven percent.</p>
<p>The more tree cover, the less carbon in the air because the trees store it. Deforestation, or removing trees, speeds up climate change. It stops <strong>photosynthesis</strong> so the trees cannot take in the carbon. Deforestation often happens alongside burning, which also increases carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Extreme weather events are worsening because of climate change in the Horn of Africa, which includes Kenya. There, rains have failed the past five seasons, though Kenya is currently experiencing heavy rains and flooding because of the El Nino weather event.</p>
<p>The Kenyan Environment Ministry said it would supply tree seedlings to citizens to stand for the government's commitment on climate action.</p>
<p>Soipan Tuya is the Environment Minister. She said, "It is a moment for Kenyans to stand in solidarity in the defense of our environment." She referred to the day as "a 'hummingbird' contribution day."</p>
<p>Hummingbirds are small birds, but they play an important part in the environment by <strong>pollinating</strong> flowers. The saying means that it seems like a small <strong>contribution</strong>, but if everyone does it together, the results will be <strong>impactful</strong>.</p>
<p>Since becoming president in September of 2022, President Ruto has made the National Landscape and Ecosystem Restoration Program a top consideration.</p>
<p>Kenya is part of the British Commonwealth. King Charles III praised the efforts last week on his first visit to an African nation since becoming King last year.</p>
<p>King Charles said at a state dinner, "Having been planting trees for most of my life, I thought I was doing rather well, but your<strong> ambition</strong> for planting 15 billion trees makes me <strong>admire</strong> your efforts."</p>
<p>During his visit, Charles planted a tree at the State House in the capital city of Nairobi. He also planted one in the Karura forest. The forest is associated with Wangari Maathai, the late environmentalist and Nobel prize winner who made the Green Belt Movement, which was the original tree planting effort in Kenya in the 1970s.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Emmanuel Igunza reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>patriotic</strong> – <em>adj</em>. showing love and pride in one's country</p>
<p><strong>photosynthesis </strong>– <em>n. </em>the process by which plants and some bacteria and protists that contain chlorophyll make carbohydrates from water and from carbon dioxide in the air in the presence of light</p>
<p><strong>contribution</strong> – <em>n. </em>the giving or supplying of something (such as money or time) as a part or share</p>
<p><strong>ambition </strong>– <em>n. </em>an eager desire for social standing, fame, or power</p>
<p><strong>impactful </strong>– <em>adj. </em>of major effect</p>
<p><strong>devastating</strong> – <em>adj</em>. causing great damage or harm</p>
<p><strong>pollinate</strong> – <em>v</em>. to carry pollen from a male part of a flower to the female part of another flower of the same type</p>
<p><strong>admire</strong> – <em>v</em>. to feel respect or approval of someone</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Housing Important for Keeping Children in School  (2023/11/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/housing-important-for-keeping-children-in-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By </span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Last year, 40 percent of students in Los Angeles public schools missed more than 10 percent of the school year.</p>
<p>That information comes from the Los Angeles Unified School District, which says about 429,000 students are <strong>enrolled </strong>in its schools.</p>
<p>In addition to the attendance numbers, the district's website says its officials did not know where 2,500 students were. These students stopped attending class and did not appear to enroll anywhere else.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Deneffy S&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;nchez, left, looks at his smartphone on a bunk bed he shares with his mother, Lilian Lopez, right, and sister, Jennifer, in a shared studio apartment in Los Angeles, Saturday, Sept. 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Jae C. Hong)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1ec8-08dbdc94e6d7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Deneffy S<i>&amp;#</i>225;nchez, left, looks at his smartphone on a bunk bed he shares with his mother, Lilian Lopez, right, and sister, Jennifer, in a shared studio apartment in Los Angeles, Saturday, Sept. 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Jae C. Hong)</span></div>
<p>Elmer Roldan is executive director of Communities in Schools of Los Angeles, a nonprofit group that aims to keep children in school. He said, "Housing is the biggest reason kids aren't going to school or we can't find them."</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> (AP) recently reported on a case of one of those children whose housing situation led to problems at school.</p>
<p>Fifteen-year-old Deneffy Sánchez has faced housing problems with his family for years. An AP reporter spoke with the teenager and his family.</p>
<p>Deneffy lives with his mother Lilian Lopez and a 3-year-old sister. Lopez had been having a hard time keeping up with monthly <strong>rent</strong> payments in an earlier apartment. So the family of three shared a small living space with Fabiola Del Castillo, someone they did not know.</p>
<p>As they fell behind on rent payments again, Del Castillo wanted to give up the apartment and pressured the family to leave. To fight the threat of losing their home, Deneffy stayed in the apartment — and missed school.</p>
<p>Federal data shows that the majority of students the government considers "homeless" have a place to stay. But the situation is often complex with shared roommates and an unsure future. In Los Angeles, the city's superintendent said last spring that 13,000 students were homeless and 2,000 of them stayed in city shelters.</p>
<p>In Deneffy's case, his family was struggling to stay in their small apartment. His father has not been with them. His mother immigrated from Guatemala 22 years ago. In 2020, after his mother gave birth to Jennifer, his sister, the family was homeless.</p>
<p>That year, schools across the country closed because of the spread of COVID-19. Deneffy tried to attend seventh-grade classes online through Zoom but said he could not pay attention. "I felt like they were judging me," he said.</p>
<p>By ninth grade, classes became more difficult, and his family did not have internet service at home. Deneffy's grades crashed. His school offered help with homework. But AP reported the boy said that he really wanted a <strong>therapist</strong>.</p>
<p>Deneffy spoke to the school's "<strong>psychiatric</strong> social worker" to see if she could help him get mental health counseling. But demand for such help increased sharply during the pandemic.</p>
<p>In 2021, an opinion study by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said 42 percent of high school students said they felt sad or hopeless a lot compared to 28 percent ten years before.</p>
<p>After leaving the apartment shared with Castillo, Deneffy's family had another bad experience sharing a place. Then they found a place where they could live without roommates through an old friend. The apartment is small and costs $1250 to rent each month. That is more than Deneffy's mother makes from government assistance and cleaning jobs.</p>
<p>The 15-year-old now has a laptop computer provided by the school and a wireless connection to help with schoolwork. He has the most trouble with writing. "I never know where to put the commas and other <strong>punctuation</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>He also sees a therapist at school once a week. But he is worried that his family's new living situation might change. His mother needs to find a full-time job to meet the rent payments.</p>
<p>Speaking of his mother, Deneffy says she tells him not to worry. "But I do," he said. "What if we don't have money, and we get kicked out again?"</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Bianca Vásquez Toness reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>enrolled</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>to be accepted into a school and fully able to attend classes</p>
<p><strong>rent </strong>–n. the regular payment for living in or using a property or equipment you do not own</p>
<p><strong>therapist</strong> <em>–n.</em> a person trained to treat sickness generally without the use of drugs or medical operations</p>
<p><strong>psychiatric </strong>–adj. related to the branch of medicine targeting emotional and mental disorders</p>
<p><strong>punctuation </strong>–n. the marks between words that make it easier to read and understand writing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Philadelphia Orchestra Returns to China to Mark 50 Years Since First Visit  (2023/11/8) | </title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/philadelphia-orchestra-returns-to-china-to-mark-50-years-since-first-visit.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The Philadelphia Orchestra arrived in Beijing Tuesday for a tour that celebrates the 50th anniversary of the group's first visit to China.<br/>
费城交响乐团星期二抵达北京，开启了一场庆祝该乐团首次访问中国50周年的巡演。</p>
<p>The visit comes as the United States and China prepare for a meeting next week between their top leaders.<br/>
此次访问正值美国和中国筹备两国最高领导人下周会晤之际。</p>
<p>The orchestra's 1973 trip has been called "historic" as an early example of the start of diplomatic relations between China and the U.S. The orchestra's visit followed President Richard Nixon's visit in 1972. He was the first American president to visit China while in office.<br/>
该乐团1973年的访问作为中美开始外交关系的早期例子被称为“历史性的”。该乐团的访问是在1972年理查德·尼克松总统访问之后进行的。尼克松是首位在任期间访问中国的美国总统。</p>
<p>Orchestra officials say 14 members are on the trip, including 73-year-old violin player Davyd Booth. Booth was among the visitors in 1973, as well.<br/>
乐团官员称有14名成员参加了这次旅行，其中包括73岁的小提琴演奏家戴维·布斯。布斯也是1973年的访客之一。</p>
<p>"This constant 50-year connection with China has been really very deep and very wonderful," Booth said after the group arrived at the Beijing airport.<br/>
布斯在乐团抵达北京机场后表示：“与中国50年来的持续联系真的非常深厚，非常美妙。”</p>
<p>The orchestra is making its 13th visit to China. It last visited in 2019.<br/>
该乐团正在进行第13次中国之行。它上次访问是在2019年。</p>
<p>The American musicians will perform with the China National Symphony Orchestra starting Friday. They will also visit the cities of Tianjin, Suzhou and Shanghai and hold special classes at schools.<br/>
这些美国音乐家将于周五开始与中国国家交响乐团合作演出。他们还将访问天津、苏州和上海，并在学校开设特殊课程。</p>
<p>Another cultural exchange is going on, too. The American Ballet Theatre is currently in China.<br/>
另一场文化交流也在进行当中。美国芭蕾舞剧院目前正在中国。</p>
<p>The music and dance group trips follow visits from high-level U.S. representatives. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo all traveled to China recently.<br/>
此次音乐和舞蹈团队之旅紧随美国高层代表访问之后。国务卿安东尼·布林肯、财政部长珍妮特·耶伦和商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多最近都访问了中国。</p>
<p>The U.S. and China have slowly been returning to normal communications after years of rising tensions and disputes.<br/>
在经历了多年的紧张局势和争端后，美国和中国的沟通已慢慢恢复正常。</p>
<p>The two countries are preparing for a meeting between President Joe Biden and Xi Jinping at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation event in San Francisco next week.<br/>
两国正在筹备拜登总统和习主席下周在旧金山亚太经济合作会议上的会晤。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·费里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lack of Housing in Los Angeles Brings Activism, Art  (2023/11/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/lack-of-housing-in-los-angeles-brings-activism-art.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>More and more of Judy Branfman's friends and neighbors found themselves unable to <strong>afford</strong> housing in Venice Beach, a neighborhood in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>So, Branfman began photographing the houses and apartments being sold, <strong>renovated</strong>, and then resold at two or three times the cost.</p>
<p>Branfman thought she should be recording the growing problem of <strong>evictions</strong> and housing in Venice Beach. The writer and activist was disappointed that Venice is losing what made it an interesting, artistic neighborhood to her.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Judy Branfman stands by a map she created as part of a gallery installation at Beyond Baroque Gallery on Nov. 3, 2023, in the Venice Beach area of Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2e83-08dbdfa0e71b_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Judy Branfman stands by a map she created as part of a gallery installation at Beyond Baroque Gallery on Nov. 3, 2023, in the Venice Beach area of Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel)</span></div>
<p>Her photo project has gained some attention. Earlier this year, Branfman started hosting community meetings where <strong>residents</strong> could share their experiences with evictions that caused them to become homeless. Some people read poems. Others expressed themselves through paintings. They started gathering information on housing and evictions.</p>
<p>Branfman's idea to take a few photos became an art exhibit called "Where Has All The (affordable) Housing Gone?"</p>
<p>"The idea was to <strong>illustrate</strong> the problem, to show what we've lost," Branfman said.</p>
<p>Venice Beach became a center of the homelessness crisis during the coronavirus pandemic in Los Angeles. The nation's second-largest city has an estimated 46,000 people who are homeless in a population of 4 million people.</p>
<p>Venice Beach has been popular for the arts for a long time. But people noticed the difference between rich and poor there as technology companies moved in and people started building costly, modern homes.</p>
<p>The nonprofit group Angeleno Project said that about 80 percent of low-income Los Angeles <strong>renters</strong> pay over half their <strong>income</strong> toward housing costs.</p>
<p>At Branfman's exhibit, her photos are displayed on a large and detailed map. The map shows many of the nearly 1,500 rent-controlled homes she said have been lost from the housing market in Venice over 20 years. In some cases, the buildings were sold to large corporations that are buying up properties and increasing rents.</p>
<p>The map and the exhibit say part of the problem is a law called the Ellis Act. The 1985 California law gave apartment owners power to evict <strong>tenants</strong> in rent-controlled buildings for redevelopment. Owners can then later require higher rents for the same apartments. "Rent-controlled" means that rents are limited by law.</p>
<p>Branfman said she suffered because of the law when she was evicted from a Venice Beach apartment in 2003.</p>
<p>"Too many tenants are afraid to fight back. And most don't know what their rights are under the law," she said. Even when tenants do bring <strong>complaints</strong>, she said, the city very rarely deals with the claims.</p>
<p>Branfman and other housing activists are hopeful that change could come with a measure that will be voted on in 2024. The measure would expand local control by overturning a 28-year-old law that bans rent control on single-family homes, condominiums and rental properties that were built after 1995.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>afford </strong>–v. to be able to pay for something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>renovate </strong><em>— v. </em>to repair and improve a property</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>eviction </strong><em>— n. </em>to be forced to leave a place, usually a place where you have lived</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>illustrate </strong><em>— v. </em>to show something, often through pictures</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_XTOJLSKM"><strong>income </strong></a><em>—</em><em> n. </em>money that is earned from work, <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_TiyBpYmg">business</a> or investment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tenant </strong>–n. a person who pays a landowner to live or work on a property</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>complaint </strong>–n. a statement that you are unhappy about a situation and want something to be done about it</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Masks, Polluted Air Are Back in New Delhi  (2023/11/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/masks-polluted-air-are-back-in-new-delhi.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Face coverings, or masks, are back on the streets of New Delhi as <strong>residents</strong> deal with an increase in air pollution.</p>
<p>The city's government has ordered primary schools to close this week and polluting vehicles and building projects are banned. A thick cover of <strong>smog</strong> hangs over New Delhi's monuments and buildings.</p>
<p>In the Indian capital, officials are struggling to reduce severe air pollution levels. Air pollution in New Delhi is a yearly and continuous health crisis that affects the lives of over 20 million in the city.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A cyclist rides amid smog in New Delhi, India, Tuesday, Nov. 7, 2023. Masks are back on the streets as residents of the capital city grapple with the annual surge in air pollution that has engulfed the region. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5812-08dbdfa0e71a_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A cyclist rides amid smog in New Delhi, India, Tuesday, Nov. 7, 2023. Masks are back on the streets as residents of the capital city grapple with the annual surge in air pollution that has engulfed the region. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)</span></div>
<p>On Tuesday, the air quality index came close to the level of 400 for tiny <strong>particulate</strong> matter. That is a level considered dangerous. It is more than 10 times the level considered safe, said SAFAR, India's main environmental agency. It is the fifth straight day of bad air in the area.</p>
<p>Officials have released water <strong>sprinklers</strong> and anti-smog guns to control the pollution. They also announced a fine of $240 for drivers found using gasoline and diesel cars, buses and trucks that create smog. Meanwhile, doctors have advised residents to wear masks and avoid outdoors as much as possible.</p>
<p>Residents like 55-year-old Renu Aggarwal are worried the smog will worsen as Diwali approaches this weekend. The Hindu festival of light includes the lighting of fireworks. Aggarwal said her daughter has a <strong>pollen allergy</strong> that worsens with pollution.</p>
<p>"She cannot breathe. Even though we keep the doors and windows shut in our home, the pollution still affects her so much that even going to the washroom is difficult for her. And she gets breathless," she said.</p>
<p>New Delhi tops the list almost every year of many Indian cities with poor air quality. It gets especially bad in the winter when crops are burned in neighboring states and cooler temperatures create smoggy conditions.</p>
<p>Burning the remains of crops at the start of the winter wheat season is an important cause to the pollution in north India. Officials have been trying to prevent farmers from using the method by offering money to buy machines to turn the soil. But the Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology says smoke from crop burning still accounts for 25 percent of the pollution in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Respirer Living Sciences is a group that watches air quality and other environmental signs. It said New Delhi saw a sharp 32 percent rise in tiny particles in the air between 2019 and 2020, a decrease of 44 percent in 2021, and a steady increase in 2022 and 2023.</p>
<p>The severe air pollution crisis affects every resident in the city, but the millions who work outdoors are even more at risk.</p>
<p>Gulshan Kumar drives a motorized <strong>rickshaw</strong>. He said his nose, throat and eyes regularly fill up with dirt in the air.</p>
<p>His children urge him to return to his hometown in Bihar state. "They ask me why I work in this polluted and diseased city," he said. "If I had had employment back home, I wouldn't have come to Delhi to work."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p>
<strong>resident</strong> — n. a person who legally lives in a particular place<br/>
<strong>smog</strong> — n. a mixture of smoke and fog<br/>
<strong>particulate</strong> — n. an amount of tiny particles<br/>
<strong>sprinkler</strong> — n. simple devices that spread water widely over an area<br/>
<strong>pollen allergy</strong> –n. a strong reaction to pollen from plants and trees that is in the air, usually in the spring<br/>
<strong>respiratory</strong> — adj. related to the lungs and breathing<br/>
<strong>rickshaw</strong> — n. a simple vehicle used to pull or carry things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In North America, Birds Will No Longer Be Named after People  (2023/11/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/in-north-america-birds-will-no-longer-be-named-after-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Birds in North America will no longer be named after people. The American Ornithological Society announced the move Wednesday.</p>
<p>Next year, the organization will begin to rename around 80 birds found in the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Colleen Handel is the organization's president. She said: "There is power in a name, and some English bird names have associations with the past that continue to be <strong>exclusionary</strong> and harmful today."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt=" Birds that will be renamed include those currently called Wilson's warbler and Wilson's snipe, both named after the 19th century naturalist Alexander Wilson. (USFWS via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-cc6a-08dbdbb71362_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"> Birds that will be renamed include those currently called Wilson's warbler and Wilson's snipe, both named after the 19th century naturalist Alexander Wilson. (USFWS via AP)</span></div>
<p>"Everyone who loves and cares about birds should be able to enjoy and study them freely," Handel added.</p>
<p>Rather than review each bird named after a person individually, all birds named after people will be renamed, the organization announced.</p>
<p>Birds that will be renamed include those currently called Wilson's warbler and Wilson's snipe. Those are both named after the 19th century naturalist Alexander Wilson. Audubon's shearwater, a seabird named for John James Audubon, also will get a new name.</p>
<p>In 2020, the organization renamed a bird that used to be named after Confederate Army General, John P. McCown. It is now called the thick-billed longspur.</p>
<p>"I'm really happy and excited about the announcement," said Emily Williams. She is an <strong>ornithologist</strong> at Georgetown University in Washington D.C. who was not involved in the decision.</p>
<p>She said debates over bird names have been happening among birdwatchers for the past several years.</p>
<p>"Naming birds based on <strong>habitat</strong> or appearance is one of the least problematic approaches," Williams said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the National Audubon Society announced that it would keep its name. Some critics argued that the group should lose its connection to John James Audubon, whose family owned slaves.</p>
<p>"The name has come to represent so much more than the work of one person," Susan Bell told <em>Audubon</em> magazine in March. She is chair of the National Audubon Society's Board of Directors. Bell added, "We must <strong>reckon with</strong> the racist <strong>legacy</strong> of John James Audubon."</p>
<p>A 2020 incident in New York's Central Park has been reported as an example of discrimination that Black people sometimes face when trying to enjoy the outdoors.</p>
<p>Christian Cooper, a Black birdwatcher, was looking for birds when he asked a white woman, Amy Cooper, to follow local rules and <strong>leash</strong> her dog. Cooper called the police and was later charged with filing a false police report. Police later dropped the charge.</p>
<p>Soon after, a group of birdwatchers organized the first Black Birders Week for Black nature lovers and scientists.</p>
<p>And a group called Bird Names for Birds sent a <strong>petition</strong> to the ornithological society urging it to create "a plan to change harmful common names" of birds.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exclusionary </strong><em>— n. </em>related to not including something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ornithologist </strong>–n. a scientist who studies birds</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>habitat </strong><em>— n. </em>the place where a plant or animal naturally lives</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reckon with </strong><em>— v.</em><strong> </strong>to consider or think about</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>legacy </strong><em>— n. </em>what a person or a generation leaves to future generations</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>leash </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to put a rope around the neck of a dog so it can be walked <em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>petition </strong><em>— n. </em>a document to be presented to officials that people sign to show they agree with what the document asks the officials to do</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Possible New Cure for Sickle Cell Disease  (2023/11/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/possible-new-cure-for-sickle-cell-disease.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A group of health experts recently announced that a new gene editing treatment for sickle cell disease was safe for patients. The treatment could provide a new cure that attacks the disease at its genetic source.</p>
<p>Sickle cell disease (SCD) is a genetic blood disorder that affects millions of people worldwide. The disease is common in places with high cases of malaria, like Africa and India. It strikes among Black Americans, Africans, and Middle Easterners more than other groups. Scientists believe being a carrier of SCD helps protect against severe malaria.</p>
<p>People with SCD carry unhealthy blood cells that result in blockages, called blood clots. This can cause pain and damage bones and organs in the human body. The World Health Organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.afro.who.int/health-topics/sickle-cell-disease">said</a> many children with the most severe form of the disease die before the age of five, usually from an infection or severe blood loss.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This July 2019 image provided by the Sarah Cannon Research Institute shows Victoria Gray during a gene-editing trial for sickle cell disease. Gray was the first patient to test the treatment. (Anthem Pictures/Sarah Cannon Research Institute via AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4421-08dbdb04238e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This July 2019 image provided by the Sarah Cannon Research Institute shows Victoria Gray during a gene-editing trial for sickle cell disease. Gray was the first patient to test the treatment. (Anthem Pictures/Sarah Cannon Research Institute via AP, File)</span></div>
<p>Vertex Pharmaceuticals and CRISPR Therapeutics make the new treatment, called "exa-cel." The treatment involves permanently changing the genetic material, DNA, in a patient's blood cells. The goal is to help the body return to healthy blood cell production. Healthy blood cells are present at birth but abnormal cells begin to develop in people with sickle cell disease.</p>
<p>When patients receive the treatment, stem cells are removed from their blood and the gene-editing tool CRISPR is used to remove the switching gene. Patients get medicines to kill off other damaged blood-producing cells and then are given back their changed stem cells.</p>
<p>Vertex reported 46 people got the treatment in its study. Among 30 of them who had at least 18 months of observation, 29 were free of pain crises for at least a year. All 30, Vertex reported, avoided being hospitalized for pain crises for that long.</p>
<p>Victoria Gray, of Mississippi, was the first patient to test the "exa-cel" treatment. Gray told researchers at a scientific gathering earlier this year that she had suffered from pain since childhood. She described feeling "reborn" the day she got the treatment. "My children no longer have a fear of losing their mom to sickle cell disease," she said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) had already found the treatment effective in a study of SCD patients. The health agency, however, was not sure if the small genetic <strong>sample</strong> size used in the study captured the entire U.S. population for sickle cell disease.</p>
<p>With the experts' findings, the FDA is likely to approve the treatment in early December for patients age 12 and older. If the treatment is approved, Vertex has also proposed to follow up with patients to study its safety for another 15 years.</p>
<p>Vertex has not said how much the treatment will cost.</p>
<p>But the Institute for Clinical and Economic Review <a class="wsw__a" href="https://icer.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ICER_SCD_revisedreport_071323.pdf">estimates</a> the cost could be around $2 million for the treatment. By comparison, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35575558/" target="_blank">research earlier this year</a> showed medical costs for sickle cell treatments, from birth to age 65, could add up to $1.7 million.</p>
<p>Dr. Allison King of Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis, Missouri cares for children and young adults with sickle cell disease. She told the Associated Press that the new treatments would be costly.</p>
<p>"But if you think about it," she said, "how much is it worth for someone to feel better and not be in pain and not be in the hospital all the time?"</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English with additional reporting from Reuters, The Associated Press and other sources.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sample</strong> - n. things that are taken from a larger group and studies and tested for information</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Reliable Are Gaza Health Ministry’s Death Numbers  (2023/11/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/how-reliable-are-gaza-health-ministry-s-death-numbers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The Health Ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said Monday that more than 10,000 Palestinians have died in the current conflict with Israel. The agency, however, does not differentiate the number of deaths as civilians or combatants.</p>
<p>The conflict began after October 7, when Hamas militants attacked Israel. They killed at least 1,400 Israelis, most of them civilians. Hamas also kidnapped an estimated 240 people.</p>
<p>Israel has answered with airstrikes that it says target militants in the territory. Last week, Israeli military forces entered northern Gaza intending to drive Hamas militants from power. Experts expect the number of deaths will rise as street fighting starts in the heavily populated area.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Palestinians go through the rubble of a building in Khan Yunis on November 6, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Mahmud HAMS / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0ac9d7cd-066a-4ece-948e-c8066935912f_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Palestinians go through the rubble of a building in Khan Yunis on November 6, 2023, amid the ongoing battles between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas. (Photo by Mahmud HAMS / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Since foreign reporters and independent organizations are barred from Gaza, the Hamas-run Health Ministry is the only official source for <strong>casualties</strong> in the territory. The United Nations and other international organizations said the ministry has made a <strong>good-faith</strong> effort to count the number of deaths under difficult conditions.</p>
<p>Michael Ryan of the World Health Organization said that the ministry's numbers might not be "perfectly <strong>accurate</strong>." But he added, "They largely <strong>reflect</strong> the level of death and injury."</p>
<p>The recent explosion at al-Ahli Hospital in Gaza showed how difficult it was to estimate the cause and the number of deaths in the conflict.</p>
<p>Hamas militants blamed an Israeli airstrike for the explosion. Gaza's Health Ministry first reported 200 to 300 deaths in the explosion. Half an hour later, the agency revised the number to 500. The following day, it changed the number to 471.</p>
<p>Israel, the United States and French officials, however, said the explosion was caused by a misfired rocket. And American intelligence estimates the number of deaths at the hospital parking area to have been between 100 and 300.</p>
<p><strong>How Does Gaza's Health Ministry Count the Numbers?</strong></p>
<p>The Health Ministry says it receives a flow of data from every hospital in the territory.</p>
<p>Hospital officials in Gaza told <em>The Associated Press</em> (AP) that they keep records of every wounded person and every dead. And they enter the information in a computerized system shared with the ministry.</p>
<p>Ashraf al-Qidra is a spokesperson for the ministry. He said when the flow of information is broken because of internet connection or electricity, the agency calls the hospitals to get numbers. The agency also collects data from other sources, including the Palestinian Red Crescent.</p>
<p>Last week, the ministry released a 212-page report listing every Palestinian killed in the war so far, including their names, identification numbers, ages and gender. A copy of the report, shared with the AP, names 6,747 Palestinians and says an additional 281 bodies have not yet been identified.</p>
<p>The list does not say where a person was killed. It also does not differentiate between civilians and fighters or say how they were killed – whether from Israeli airstrikes or Palestinian rocket fire. It describes all casualties as victims of "Israeli aggression."</p>
<p>Lt. Col. Richard Hecht is an Israeli military spokesman. He said of the report, "When the Hamas health agency comes out with the numbers, take it with a pinch of salt." In other words, he dismissed the report as something unlikely to be truthful. But he repeatedly refused to state the number of Palestinian deaths.</p>
<p><strong>How reliable are Gaza's numbers?</strong></p>
<p>International news agencies, humanitarian workers and rights groups have often used the ministry's numbers when an independent source is not available.</p>
<p>"These figures are professionally done and have proven to be <strong>reliable</strong>," said Omar Shakir, Human Rights Watch's Israel and Palestine director. He noted that the numbers do not differentiate between civilians' and fighters' deaths.</p>
<p>After the conflict, the U.N. humanitarian office usually publishes final numbers on deaths based on its research into medical records. In many cases, the U.N.'s counts have been fairly close to the Gaza Health Ministry's numbers.</p>
<p>After the 2008 war, the ministry reported 1,440 Palestinians killed; the U.N. reported 1,385.</p>
<p>In the 2014 war, the ministry reported 2,310 Palestinians killed; the U.N. reported 2,251.</p>
<p>And in the 2021 war, the ministry reported 260 Palestinians killed; the U.N. reported 256.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English based on reporting by VOA, The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>casualty</strong> - n. a person who is hurt or killed during a war, accident,..</p>
<p><strong>good-faith</strong> - n. an honest and proper way</p>
<p><strong>accurate</strong> - adj. free from mistake or error</p>
<p><strong>reflect</strong> - v. to show or make known</p>
<p><strong>reliable</strong> - adj. able to trust or to be believed</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Colombia Tries to Control Invasive Hippo  (2023/11/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/colombia-tries-to-control-invasive-hippo.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Colombia will try to control its population of more than 100 hippopotamuses, large animals from Africa.</p>
<p>The South American country aims to control the big animals using several methods. Officials might <strong>sterilize</strong> the animals through a medical operation. They might move the hippos to other countries, or possibly <strong>euthanize</strong> them, the government said recently.</p>
<p>The animals' ancestors were brought to the country by the late Pablo Escobar in the 1980s. Escobar was the leader of an illegal drug operation in Colombia.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Hippos float in the lagoon at Hacienda Napoles Park, once the private estate of drug organization chief Pablo Escobar who imported three female hippos and one male years ago in Puerto Triunfo, Colombia on February 4, 2021. (AP Photo/Fernando Vergara, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5f078c7e-7dc8-47c5-90fe-9932f4760002_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Hippos float in the lagoon at Hacienda Napoles Park, once the private estate of drug organization chief Pablo Escobar who imported three female hippos and one male years ago in Puerto Triunfo, Colombia on February 4, 2021. (AP Photo/Fernando Vergara, File)</span></div>
<p>The hippos have spread from Escobar's home to nearby rivers where they have reproduced. They have no natural <strong>predators</strong> in Colombia and the government has declared them as an invasive animal that could hurt the environment.</p>
<p>Officials estimate there are 169 hippos in Colombia and that many of them are in the Magdalena River area. They estimate that if no measures are taken, there could be 1,000 by 2035.</p>
<p>Environment Minister Susana Muhamad said the first step of the plan will be to sterilize 40 hippos each year and this will begin soon.</p>
<p>The method is costly. Each sterilization costs about $9,800. And there are risks for the hippos, including reactions to medicines or death, as well as risks to health officials, the ministry said. The hippos live across a large area. They are territorial and aggressive.</p>
<p>Experts say sterilization alone is not enough to control the growth of the invasive animals. The government announced in March that it is planning to possibly move the animals to other countries.</p>
<p>Muhamad said Colombian officials have contacted officials in Mexico, India, and the Philippines, and they are considering a plan to send 60 hippos to India.</p>
<p>"We are working on the <strong>protocol</strong> for the export of the animals," she said. "We are not going to export a single animal if there is no <strong>authorization</strong> from the environmental authority of the other country."</p>
<p>As a last means to control the population, the ministry is creating a protocol to euthanize the animals.</p>
<p>A group of hippos was brought in the 1980s to Hacienda Nápoles. The place was Escobar's private zoo. Now it receives many visitors after his death in 1993. Most of the animals live freely in rivers there and reproduce without control.</p>
<p>The people of the nearby Puerto Triunfo have become used to hippos sometimes walking freely around the town.</p>
<p>However, scientists warn that the hippos' waste pollutes the rivers and could affect the environment where other large animals, like manatees and capybaras, live.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Karen Sloan reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sterilize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to make a living thing unable to produce children or offspring</p>
<p><strong>euthanize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to kill a sick or injured animal or person by giving them drugs so that they die without pain</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong>– <em>n</em>. an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals</p>
<p><strong>protocol </strong>– <em>n</em>. a system of rules that explain the correct conduct and procedures to be followed in formal situations</p>
<p><strong>authorize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to give legal or official approval to or for (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Europeans Can Pay for Ad-free Social Media  (2023/11/6) | 欧洲人可付费使用无广告的社交媒体服务</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/europeans-can-pay-for-ad-free-social-media.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Facebook and Instagram users in Europe are getting the option to use the social media services without seeing advertisements.<br/>
欧洲的Facebook和Instagram用户可以选择在不看广告的情况下使用社交媒体服务。</p>
<p>However, they will have to pay for that option. Meta, the parent company of both Facebook and Instagram, recently announced the new choice, which is meant to comply with Europe's data privacy rules.<br/>
然而，他们将不得不为这一选择付费。Facebook和Instagram的母公司Meta最近宣布了这个新的选项，它旨在遵守欧洲的数据隐私规则。</p>
<p>Starting this month, users on desktop browsers will pay about $11 a month while iOS and Android users will pay $14 a month. Meta said in a blog that the price difference between the versions is the result of higher costs linked to the Apple and Google app stores.<br/>
从本月开始，桌面浏览器用户每月将支付约11美元，而iOS和Android用户每月支付14美元。Meta在一篇博客中表示，两个版本之间的价格差异是苹果和谷歌应用商店相关成本增加的结果。</p>
<p>The monthly payment will cover all linked Facebook and Instagram accounts until March 1, 2024. On that date, Meta will require $6 to $8 for each additional account depending on the system used. Meta released details of the plan late last month.<br/>
每月付款将覆盖所有链接的Facebook和Instagram账户，直至2024年3月1日为止。在那一天，Meta将根据所使用的系统，要求每个额外的账户付款6至8美元。Meta上个月底公布了该计划的细节。</p>
<p>Meta said it is introducing the new pay option after a ruling by the EU's top court. The court said Meta must first get consent before showing ads to users under EU data privacy rules.<br/>
Meta表示，在欧盟最高法院作出裁决后，它推出了新的付费选项。该法院表示，根据欧盟数据隐私规则，Meta在向用户展示广告之前必须首先获得同意。</p>
<p>Meta advertises products and services to individual users based on their online activity. The EU ruling affects the company's ability to make money from its advertising methods.<br/>
Meta根据个人用户的在线活动向他们宣传产品和服务。欧盟的裁决影响了该公司通过广告方式赚钱的能力。</p>
<p>Meta said in a statement, that the paid option "balances the requirements of European regulators while giving users choice and allowing Meta to continue serving all people."<br/>
Meta在一份声明中表示，付费选项“平衡了欧洲监管机构的要求，同时为用户提供了选择，并允许Meta继续为所有人服务。”</p>
<p>Users aged 18 and older in the EU's 27 member countries, and also Switzerland, Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein will still have the choice to continue using Facebook or Instagram with ads.<br/>
欧盟27个成员国以及瑞士、挪威、冰岛和列支敦士登的18岁及以上用户仍可以选择继续使用有广告的Facebook或Instagram。</p>
<p>Meta said it is considering how to "provide teens with a useful and responsible ad experience" under the European privacy ruling.<br/>
Meta表示，它正在考虑如何根据欧洲隐私裁决“为青少年提供有用和负责任的广告体验”。</p>
<p>On November 1, the European data regulator, the European Data Protection Board, announced that it would extend a ban on "behavioral advertising" on Facebook and Instagram. The ban covers all 30 countries in the EU and the European Economic Area. The ban was first put in place by non-EU member Norway. The northern European country has ordered Meta to pay thousands of dollars each day since the middle of August for breaking the country's privacy rules.<br/>
11月1日，欧洲数据监管机构欧洲数据保护委员会宣布，将延长对Facebook和Instagram上“行为广告”的禁令。该禁令涵盖欧盟和欧洲经济区的所有30个国家。该禁令最初由非欧盟成员国挪威实施。自8月中旬以来，这个北欧国家已下令Meta每天支付数千美元罚款，因为它违反了该国的隐私规则。</p>
<p>Behavioral advertising targets users by collecting their personal data. The EU's ban on such advertising is considered a setback for Meta.<br/>
行为广告通过收集用户的个人数据来锁定用户。欧盟对此类广告的禁令被认为是Meta的一次挫折。</p>
<p>In a statement, Meta said it believes in an "ad-supported internet." But the company said it respects "the spirit and purpose of these evolving European regulations," and aims to comply with them.<br/>
Meta在一份声明中表示，它相信“有广告支持的互联网”。但该公司表示，它尊重“这些不断发展的欧洲法规的精神和目的”，并致力于遵守这些法规。</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.<br/>
我是安娜·马泰奥。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Antarctica Was Once Home to Rivers, Forests  (2023/11/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/antarctica-was-once-home-to-rivers-forests.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Antarctica has not always been a land of ice and snow. Earth's southernmost continent once was home to rivers and forests full of life.</p>
<p>Scientists are using satellite observations and radar imagery to look deep under the ice. The researchers report finding a large ancient <strong>landscape</strong> buried under the continent's ice sheet. It is full of valleys and <strong>ridges</strong>, shaped by rivers before being covered by glaciers long ago.</p>
<p>The landscape is located in East Antarctica's Wilkes Land area bordering the Indian Ocean. It covers an area about the size of Belgium. The researchers said the landscape appears to date to at least 14 million years ago and perhaps beyond 34 million years ago, when Antarctica entered its deep freeze.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An illustration shows how a landscape the size of Belgium located in Wilkes Land, East Antarctica would appear if the thick ice sheet covering it were lifted away. (Stewart Jamieson, Durham University/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d7c9-08dbd6f94c17_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An illustration shows how a landscape the size of Belgium located in Wilkes Land, East Antarctica would appear if the thick ice sheet covering it were lifted away. (Stewart Jamieson, Durham University/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>"The landscape is like a <strong>snapshot</strong> of the past," said Stewart Jamieson. He is a professor of glaciology at Durham University in England and co-leader of the study published in the journal <em>Nature Communications</em>.</p>
<p>"It is difficult to know what this lost world might have looked like before the ice came along, but it was certainly warmer back then," Jamieson added. "Depending how far back in time you go, you might have had climates that <strong>ranged</strong> anywhere from the climate of present-day Patagonia through to something more approaching <strong>tropical</strong>."</p>
<p>Such an environment likely would have been populated by wildlife, Jamieson said. But the area's fossil record is too incomplete to know which animals may have lived there.</p>
<p>The ice above the ancient landscape measures about 2.2 kilometers to 3 kilometers thick, said study co-leader Neil Ross. He is a professor of polar science and environmental geophysics at Newcastle University in England.</p>
<p>The researchers said the surface of the planet Mars is better known than the earth surface below the ice in Antarctica. They said one way to learn more would be to drill through the ice and take a piece<strong> </strong>of the earth below. This could uncover evidence showing ancient life, as was done with samples taken in Greenland dating back two million years ago.</p>
<p>Some earlier studies have uncovered ancient landscapes beneath Antarctica's ice including mountains. But the landscape discovered in the new study was the first of its kind.</p>
<p>Right before 34 million years ago, Antarctica's landscape and wildlife was likely similar to today's cold temperate rainforests. That includes places like Tasmania, New Zealand and South America's Patagonia area, Ross added.</p>
<p>Antarctica was once part of the Gondwana supercontinent that also included what is now Africa, South America, Australia, the Indian subcontinent and the Arabian Peninsula. But it eventually split off in a process called plate tectonics.</p>
<p>Jamieson said the researchers think that when Antarctica's climate was warmer, rivers flowed toward a continental coastline that was created as the other land masses broke away. When the climate cooled, he said, some small glaciers formed on hills next to the rivers, with valleys deepening as glaciers <strong>eroded</strong>.</p>
<p>When the climate cooled even more, an ice sheet grew which covered the whole continent, Jamieson added. Eventually, "the landscape got preserved, likely for 34 million years."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>landscape </strong><em>— n. </em> an area of land that has a particular quality or appearance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ridge </strong><em>— n. </em>a long area of land that is on top of a mountain or hill</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>snapshot </strong><em>— n. </em>a quick view or a small amount of information that tells you a little about what someone or something is like</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>range </strong><em>— n. </em>a group or collection of different things or people that are usually similar in some way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tropical </strong><em>— adj. </em>of, relating to, occurring in, or used in the tropics</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>erode </strong><em>— v. </em>to gradually destroy or to be gradually destroyed by natural forces</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Native Americans Work to Keep Sheep Herding Tradition as Climate Changes  (2023/11/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/native-americans-work-to-keep-sheep-herding-tradition-as-climate-changes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Members of the Native American Navajo tribe in Arizona have been raising sheep for over 500 years.</p>
<p>The Navajo started working with sheep when Spanish colonists brought the animals to North America. They raised them for meat to eat and wool to keep warm. And it helped turn the Southwest into a center of economic activity.</p>
<p>But that way of life is in danger of ending.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Nikyle Begay tends a flock of sheep Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023, on the Navajo Nation in Ganado, Ariz. (AP Photo/John Locher)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/35057e5c-88bc-4f7c-a11b-1efbd4802645_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Nikyle Begay tends a flock of sheep Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023, on the Navajo Nation in Ganado, Ariz. (AP Photo/John Locher)</span></div>
<p>Navajo people are raising fewer sheep for several reasons: it is harder to get a permit to do so, younger people are not interested in being <strong>shepherds</strong> and climate change is making it harder to get food and water for the sheep.</p>
<p>In past years, Navajo families in the large western states of Utah, Arizona and New Mexico raised hundreds of sheep. The sheep were of the well-known Churro <strong>breed</strong>. Now, many families are only raising only a few. Some have completely given up.</p>
<p>Amy Begaye is 25. She has been working with sheep since she was a girl. At first, her family gave her small jobs when it was time to <strong>butcher</strong> the sheep. She collected their blood in a container and held their legs. But now, she competes in butchering competitions.</p>
<p>At a recent competition called the Miss Navajo Nation <strong>pageant</strong>, she had to cut the sheep into parts in a limited amount of time.</p>
<p>She said she respects the work of butchers.</p>
<p>"We butcher the sheep because it is a way of our life," said Begaye, who won the competition. "That's how my ancestors were able to provide food for their families."</p>
<p>There is another Navajo family called the Begays, and they work with sheep.</p>
<p>On most days, Jay Begay, Sr. takes the sheep out to <strong>graze</strong> near the community of Rocky Ridge, Arizona. He uses a walking stick for support and takes dogs along to keep the sheep moving in the right direction. The family had about 200 sheep in the past but have since reduced their numbers to 50.</p>
<p>His son, Jay Begay, Jr. said a friend told him, "You can't blame people for not wanting to work this hard." Begay added that it is harder now because of climate change.</p>
<p>A long stretch of dry weather called a drought has reduced the number of sheep. The Navajo Department of Agriculture said there were about 200,000 sheep in 2017. The next count is in 2024 and they expect the number to be lower.</p>
<p>Water is hard to find and a recent Supreme Court decision said the U.S. government is not required to find water for the Navajo <strong>reservation</strong>.</p>
<p>Valentina Clisto is a past pageant winner, like Amy Begaye. She said when she visited other Navajo communities, the people complained about the lack of water. She said dry weather means the sheep cannot find grass to eat. Instead, those who raise the animals must pay for costly food.</p>
<p>Lester Craig remembers when his family had 600 sheep. His mother would sell their wool to buy school clothes.</p>
<p>Craig stopped raising sheep because his family lives on land polluted by a nearby uranium mine. An accident in 1979 made their water unusable. He now has to travel about 30 minutes to a filling station to get water for his family and the few animals they have left.</p>
<p>In addition to climate change, pollution and water problems, Navajo members say the U.S. government is restricting the number of animals that can live on the land. Some have to wait for years for grazing permits.</p>
<p>Meranda Laughter said her family had 300 sheep five years ago. They only have 10 now.</p>
<p>Although many worry about the future, Laughter is hopeful. She said more education and better land management can eliminate some of the recent problems. She added that the land just needs time to heal and recover.</p>
<p>"We just need to give the land time to breathe," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>shepherd </strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who raises animals that wander and eat grasses</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong>–<em>n</em>. a kind of animal that is different from others of the same species because of its parents</p>
<p><strong>butcher </strong>–<em>adj</em>. a person who cuts meat from animals that are killed for food</p>
<p><strong>pageant </strong>–<em>n</em>. a kind of competition where people perform tasks or demonstrate abilities and are scored by judges</p>
<p><strong>graze </strong>–<em>v</em>. a way of feeding animals by giving them access to grass or plants in the wild</p>
<p><strong>reservation </strong>–<em>n</em>. an area of land in the U.S. that is kept separate as a place for Native Americans to live</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>This Miami University Is Not in Florida  (2023/11/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/this-miami-university-is-not-in-florida.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Valerie Do of Vietnam is in her third year of college at Miami University in the Midwestern U.S. state of Ohio.</p>
<p>The school has about 19,000 students, including about 1,000 international students. It has a good reputation for giving students an <strong>authentic</strong> college experience. The small city of Oxford is pretty in the autumn and spring. The brick school buildings are arranged on wide green spaces with walking paths.</p>
<p>But Miami University is definitely not in Florida and not close to any ocean beaches. The University of Miami is in Coral Gables, Florida, and about 15 kilometers from the famous beaches.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An aerial view of the Miami University campus in Ohio." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4280-08dbdc725620_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An aerial view of the Miami University campus in Ohio.</span></div>
<p>Do only found out, after she was accepted, that the school she had <strong>applied</strong> to was the one in Ohio. Some international students and those who work with international students say these kinds of mistakes are common. For example, one international student remembered being <strong>confused</strong> by the difference between Washington, D.C., and the northwestern state of Washington.</p>
<p>Do recently got attention from news websites such as <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.insider.com/glad-i-accidentally-went-to-ohio-university-instead-of-florida-2023-10" target="_blank">Insider </a></em>and the <em>Daily Mail</em> after telling her story on the social media site TikTok (@dankgiao).</p>
<p>Do often uses TikTok to discuss her experiences as an international student. One of the videos shows her explaining how she learned to pronounce difficult English words. In another, she discussed the <strong>costumes</strong> she wore during the Halloween holiday in 2021, 2022 and 2023.</p>
<p><strong>Viral video</strong></p>
<p>Earlier this year, Do made a video about her discovery that Miami University was in Ohio, not Florida. About 2 million people watched it.</p>
<p>"I didn't <strong>realize</strong> it was in Ohio until I got the acceptance letter," she said. "I basically went through the whole application process without knowing it's in Ohio."</p>
<p>Many commenters offered sympathy that she was going to apple <strong>orchards</strong> instead of beaches this autumn. But in a follow-up post, she said she was happy with her experience in Ohio.</p>
<p>Do said she went to Miami for a number of reasons, including a good financial aid offer, "the <strong>vibe</strong> of the school" and the business program.</p>
<p>She said Miami looks like the colleges shown on TV and in movies like <em>Animal House</em>.</p>
<p>Dan Sinetar works with international students at Miami University. He and his <strong>colleagues</strong> help students like Do feel comfortable once they arrive on campus.</p>
<p>Sinetar said many international students make the decision to come to Miami without visiting. So, he helps to "set the expectations" of what it is like to live in southwestern Ohio before they arrive.</p>
<p>He said some international students worry about how they can find food they are familiar with, so the office tells them about food stores with products from around the world. But other issues are more complicated.</p>
<p>"You know, race and ethnicity is a big topic in the U.S. and obviously impacts how people might <strong>engage</strong> with you. But there's many international students who might be coming from a country culture where they don't have those issues."</p>
<p>Before students arrive in the U.S., Sinetar said, Miami works to help them learn about what they should expect. The school has <strong>peer</strong> <strong>orientation</strong> leaders who help new international students get comfortable. Do, in fact, is one of them.</p>
<p>Sinetar said it is difficult to move across the world for school. "For many international students, it is their first time living away from home," he said.</p>
<p>Sinetar said that he and others at Miami often hear students discuss the Ohio and Florida confusion. One reason for this, he thinks, is that the international students often work with education agencies that help them <strong>apply</strong> to colleges.</p>
<p>"Sometimes," he said, "students are a little disconnected from the process."</p>
<p><strong>Reactions from international students</strong></p>
<p>Arkar Chen is from Myanmar. He attended college in Los Angeles and now works for a computer software company in New Jersey.</p>
<p>"The agency probably thought she knew she was applying to the university in Ohio and didn't think to tell her that," Chen said.</p>
<p>He said he did not use an agency and as a result, he was more prepared for his time in Los Angeles. However, he still had some surprises.</p>
<p>"From one neighborhood to the next, it can be very different," he said. Chen noted that Myanmar is a poor country, and he did not expect to see so many people in the U.S. living in poverty.</p>
<p>"In pop culture, when you mention L.A., you know people think about Hollywood the beach and stuff like that. The good images. But in reality, it is not so much different (from Myanmar). I guess you could call it a <strong>culture shock</strong>."</p>
<p>Chen said it would be smart for international students to think about choosing an American university close to where family or friends live — in case the culture shock is too strong.</p>
<p>"Because having someone able to help you is really invaluable, especially when you came alone to a foreign environment," he said.</p>
<p>Another former international student is Christian Cao from Vietnam. He currently lives in Toledo, Ohio, close to the border with Michigan. He is an engineer who works with robotic systems in the automotive industry.</p>
<p>He had not heard of Do before the recent stories. He said he did not think her situation is very common for international students in 2023, but he understands how the confusion could happen.</p>
<p>Cao said young people in Vietnam know about most major universities in the U.S. But 10 years ago, there were not many education agencies visiting Vietnam and <strong>recruiting</strong> students for schools in the U.S.</p>
<p>He agreed, it is still possible that not everyone would know there is a Miami University in Ohio.</p>
<p>By the time Do understood Miami was in Ohio, Cao said, "She already got accepted, she already got the scholarship. It would be a waste of time and money trying to find another university."</p>
<p>But, as Cao said, "Maybe it's not the life she expected, but it is not bad at all. She's making friends and still making progress."</p>
<p><strong>Beaches overrated?</strong></p>
<p>Cao said a student's college experience depends on what they are hoping for after they graduate. In his case, he was interested in studying engineering, so he did not mind that Toledo, Ohio did not have a big nightlife.</p>
<p>"If you're a person like me, I don't party at all," Cao said. "I just made friends and spent most of my time doing what I wanted to do at home...Ohio would be a great place for me."</p>
<p>Cao said life in Vietnam and other Asian countries is very different from life in the U.S. Young people spend a lot of time studying and living at home.</p>
<p>"When you move to America you break out of your shell," he said. "You experience a lot of new things and it's a big step up from your regular life."</p>
<p>Cao went on to say "it doesn't matter where you are, you could be at a small university in Alabama. It's just a huge step up in terms of learning and <strong>adulting</strong>."</p>
<p>Sinetar of Miami said one way students can learn about life in America is through the school's program of matching international students with American families.</p>
<p>He said local families who want to meet people from other parts of the world can sign up to spend time with the students.</p>
<p>They attend events together on campus and visit American homes.</p>
<p>Cao said he could see how that kind of activity might be more appealing in Oxford, Ohio, than in a city such as Dallas, Texas. Dallas has a large international community, Cao said.</p>
<p>"Sometimes," Sinetar said, "there are these really deep relationships that are formed. Sometimes the international students have said ‘yes, I look at these people like an aunt, uncle or grandparent.'"</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>authentic </strong>–adj. a true example of something; real</p>
<p><strong>apply </strong>–v. to seek entry to a school or program</p>
<p><strong>confused </strong>–adj. mistaking one thing for another; being unsure</p>
<p><strong>costume </strong>–n. clothes worn by someone who is trying to look like a different person or thing</p>
<p><strong>realize </strong>–v. to understand at a specific point in time</p>
<p><strong>vibe </strong>–n. the feeling a person gets from another person, place or experience</p>
<p><strong>colleague </strong>–n. a fellow worker</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong>–v. to get involved with something and to be interested in it</p>
<p><strong>peer</strong> –n. a person of similar age, rank or ability</p>
<p><strong>orientation </strong>–n. training and information given to someone who is starting a program, course of study or job</p>
<p><strong>culture shock </strong>–n. the experience of being surprised and confused by the culture of a new place</p>
<p><strong>recruit </strong>–v. to seek out people to join an organization, school, military service or a company</p>
<p><strong>adulting </strong>–v. (casual) to take on responsibilities and do things like a grown up or adult</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Straight from the Horse's Mouth'  (2023/11/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/straight-from-the-horse-s-mouth.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On today's show, we will be talking about an animal that is as impressive and beautiful as it is useful -- the horse.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Abraham Gajon, 31, a paramedic, pets a horse named Linda during a therapy session at Miguel Hidalgo's center in Mexico City, Mexico on October 16, 2020. (REUTERS/Edgard Garrido)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/093e0000-0a00-0242-30ba-08da05d73da4_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Abraham Gajon, 31, a paramedic, pets a horse named "Linda" during a therapy session at Miguel Hidalgo's center in Mexico City, Mexico on October 16, 2020. (REUTERS/Edgard Garrido)</span></div>
<p>Today's expression is <u>straight from the horse's mouth</u>. "Straight from the horse's mouth" is about the way we get information and — with this expression — that means directly.</p>
<p>When we hear something from the source, we can say we heard it <u>first-hand</u>. It is coming from a <strong>primary </strong>source.</p>
<p>When we use this expression, we can drop the word "straight" if necessary. So, if you hear something <u>from the horse's mouth</u>, you hear it from the person who has direct personal knowledge of the information.</p>
<p>For example, a co-worker of mine, Andrew, likes to play the piano. But don't take my word for it, let's hear it straight from the horse's mouth.</p>
<p><em>ANDREW: I really like to play the piano. </em></p>
<p>Thanks, Andrew!</p>
<p>The opposite of this expression would be <u>through the </u><a class="wsw__a" href="file:///C:/Users/mritter/Downloads/The%20opposite%20of%20this%20expression%20would%20be%20through%20the%20grapevine.%20That%20is%20a%20very%20indirect%20way%20to%20get%20information">grapevine</a>. That is a very indirect way to get information.</p>
<p>Now, let's talk about <strong>origin</strong>. Experts are not sure how this expression started. However, there are two common explanations.</p>
<p>One traditional explanation is about buying horses. Before buying a horse, a possible buyer would look into the horse's mouth. This is because you can tell a bit about a horse's health and age from its <strong>gums</strong> and teeth.</p>
<p>Another explanation involves horse racing. At the horse races, people talk about which horses will win and which ones will lose. The most valuable opinions are from the people who know the horses the best – the riders and trainers. Since you can't ask the horse, these people are the next best thing. "Straight from the horse's mouth" suggests the most knowledgeable source of information.</p>
<p>So, this expression can also mean from a <strong>reliable </strong>source. The information is coming from a trustworthy person. It may even be the <strong>definitive </strong>source, meaning the best authority.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear the expression used in another example:</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, guess what? Stella is moving to Toronto! She's so excited.</em></p>
<p><em>B: Are you sure? She just bought a house a year ago. </em></p>
<p><em>A: She told me herself last night over dinner. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I just can't believe it. I mean, she also just got a <strong>promotion</strong> and a raise at her job. It doesn't make sense. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, whether it makes sense or not, that's what she told me. </em></p>
<p><em>B: Maybe you misheard her. </em></p>
<p><em>A: I didn't. I heard it straight from the horse's mouth – Stella's!</em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have on the show today.</p>
<p>If anyone asks you where you learned this expression, tell them you heard it <u>straight from the horse's mouth</u> – from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Until next time, I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>primary </strong><em>–adj.</em> happening or coming first</p>
<p><strong>gums </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> the tissue inside the mouth around the teeth<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>reliable </strong>–adj. able to be trusted to provide what is needed; dependable</p>
<p><strong>definitive </strong>–adj. considered final or settled as the best or most correct</p>
<p><strong>promotion</strong><strong> </strong>–n. an increase in job rank or position</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lyndon Johnson: Complicated  (2023/11/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/americas-presidents-lyndon-johnson.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Lyndon Johnson. He was the vice president under John F. Kennedy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Lyndon B. Johnson" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8123fb53-bcd5-4344-a112-241d62aa024c_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Lyndon B. Johnson</span></div>
<p>Many Americans recognize Johnson from a photograph of his swearing-in on November 22, 1963.</p>
<p>Kennedy had just been shot during a visit to Dallas, Texas. Johnson and his wife also were visiting the city.</p>
<p>After doctors announced that Kennedy had died, the Johnsons were taken to the presidential airplane. There, Johnson took the oath of office as president.</p>
<p>Men wearing suits look on, while three women stand around him. His wife, Lady Bird Johnson, is at one side. Former first lady Jackie Kennedy is at the other. She is still wearing clothing covered with her husband's blood. The judge who is administering the oath, Sarah Hughes, stands in front of Lyndon Johnson. She holds a prayer book on which Johnson places one hand and swears to follow the Constitution.</p>
<p>The photograph showed the American people that the federal government could and would continue in an orderly way.</p>
<p>But Johnson's position was difficult. Many people were shocked and in mourning for the <strong>assassinated</strong> president.</p>
<p>But as the conflict in Vietnam increased, and some Americans rejected Johnson's reforms, he found his position difficult again.In the next election, Johnson was elected president in his own right.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Lyndon Baines Johnson was born in Texas, where his family had lived for generations. A town called Johnson was even named after his relatives.</p>
<p>Lyndon was the oldest of five children. His mother was a teacher and writer, and his father was a farmer and political leader.</p>
<p>In time, the Johnson family experienced financial difficulties. They had little money to give their children much of an education, but Lyndon was able to attend a teaching college.</p>
<p>Johnson excelled as a teacher. He also learned from his students. Many were even poorer than he was. They also faced discrimination because they came from Mexican families. Johnson promised to help them.</p>
<p>But he found he could do more to improve people's lives as a politician than as a teacher.</p>
<p>He volunteered for some political campaigns, became an aide to a member of the United States Congress, and in time became a member of Congress himself.</p>
<p>Along the way, he married a woman named Claudia Taylor. But everyone called her Lady Bird. They went on to have two daughters.</p>
<p>Johnson served for 12 years in the U.S. House of Representatives. In 1948, he was narrowly elected to the Senate, becoming one of the two senators from the state of Texas.</p>
<p>From there, Johnson rose quickly. He took on increasingly important jobs in the Senate. By 1954, he was the Senate majority leader – the Democratic Party's top spokesman in the Senate.</p>
<p>The Senate website notes that the person with that job needs to be able to work well with others, especially members of other parties.</p>
<p>Historians also note that Johnson worked very hard, and was always prepared.</p>
<p>A well-known biography of Johnson is called "Master of the Senate." The book describes Johnson as extremely <strong>ambitious</strong>, sometimes <strong>cruel</strong>, and often willing to praise others to get what he wanted. At the same time, he could be very concerned about other people's well-being.</p>
<p>In other words, the picture of Johnson is a complicated one.</p>
<p>In 1960, he competed against John F. Kennedy for the Democratic presidential nomination. Johnson lost that race – but the party asked him to be their vice presidential candidate instead.</p>
<p>Johnson agreed, not knowing that in a little more than three years, he would enter the White House as president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>After being sworn-in, Johnson used his political experience in the Senate to pass a number of reforms. They were aimed at carrying on, in his words, a "War on Poverty."</p>
<p>The new laws created healthcare and education programs. They also used federal money to make food less costly for some people, and to train workers for jobs.</p>
<p>Johnson also continued the work Kennedy began by signing the Civil Rights Act of 1964. The act made <strong>segregation</strong> because of race, religion, or national origin illegal.</p>
<p>The Civil Rights Act also made it illegal for employers to discriminate against someone because of race, religion, national origin, or <strong>gender</strong>.</p>
<p>The reforms had their critics, then and today. But in the presidential election of 1964, Johnson won "by the widest margin of popular votes in American history." Historian Kent Germany says that vote gave the Democrats a rare opening "to pass a comprehensive liberal program."</p>
<p><br/>
<strong>Presidency after 1964</strong></p>
<p>Johnson had a name for such a program. He called it the "Great Society." He said the United States should aim not only to be a rich and powerful society, but also to "end poverty and racial injustice."</p>
<p>Johnson followed his earlier reforms with others. They sought to prevent crime, reduce pollution, support the arts, make roads safer, and protect American <strong>consumers</strong> against bad products. His administration also created an immigration policy that valued family members, skilled workers, and refugees.</p>
<p>Johnson also signed the Voting Rights Act of 1965. It sought to lift the barriers that had long prevented African-American men and women from exercising their right to vote.</p>
<p>Later, Johnson removed legal discrimination in the process of buying and renting homes.</p>
<p>Together, these actions have linked Johnson to the civil rights movement in the minds of many Americans. Yet Johnson is also strongly linked to another part of U.S. history, often known simply as "Vietnam."</p>
<p>Earlier presidents had ordered U.S. military action in the conflict between North and South Vietnam. Since 1950, Presidents Truman, Eisenhower, and Kennedy had slowly increased the American intervention. Their goal was to prevent the spread of communism in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>President Johnson continued Kennedy's policies. He also received the support of Congress to do whatever was necessary to protect U.S. forces and "prevent further aggression" by North Vietnam's communist government.</p>
<p>Yet, when he was a presidential candidate in 1964, Johnson promised not to increase U.S. involvement and send young Americans to fight in Vietnam.</p>
<p>The opposite happened.</p>
<p>Over the next four years, Johnson called on hundreds of thousands of additional U.S. troops to fight on the ground and in the air. The North Vietnamese fought back, both on the battle field and politically.</p>
<p>In time, the American public withdrew their support of the struggle and their support for the president.</p>
<p>By early 1968, Johnson had become deeply unpopular with voters. His party lost seats in Congress, and Johnson lost his ability to persuade lawmakers to support the measures he proposed.</p>
<p>In addition, the U.S. economy was showing signs of weakness, partly because of the costs of the conflict in Vietnam and government spending at home.</p>
<p>As the presidential nominating process began in early 1968, Johnson was permitted to seek another four-year term. But he announced that he would not seek or accept his party's nomination.</p>
<p>Shortly after, civil rights leader Martin Luther King, Jr. was shot and killed. Angered by his murder, people in more than 100 cities rioted.</p>
<p>Then, in June, John Kennedy's brother, Robert Kennedy, was also assassinated. Kennedy had been competing for the Democrats' nomination for president.</p>
<p>His death, and Johnson's withdrawal, added to the divisions in the Democratic Party. Several groups gathered to protest at the party's nominating convention in Chicago. The meeting ended in violent clashes between protesters and police.</p>
<p>By the time Johnson left office in January 1969, his party had lost control of the White House, and many Americans believed the country was in <strong>disarray</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>After he left the presidency, Johnson returned to his home in Texas. He wrote his memories about his White House years, and made preparations for his presidential library.</p>
<p>But he did not live much longer. He died in 1973, hours before the U.S. involvement in Vietnam officially came to a close.</p>
<p>Johnson was a complex person, and his image in the mind of many Americans is just as complicated. His policies opened new paths for many people, but also led to years of death and destruction in Vietnam.</p>
<p>As a president, he acted powerfully and often independently, and succeeded in passing an unusually large number of reforms. But he also failed to persuade many Americans to accept some of those measures.</p>
<p>Supporters of the free market especially strongly rejected the government controls Johnson enacted.</p>
<p>Even some in his Democratic Party, which Johnson had controlled for years, lost faith in him. In 1964, anti-war activists changed his campaign slogan, "All the way with LBJ." Instead, they said, "Part of the way with LBJ."</p>
<p>And by 1968, they were saying, "Hey, Hey, LBJ. How many kids did you kill today?"</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>______________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>assassinate </strong>- <em>v. </em>to kill (someone, such as a famous or important person) usually for political reasons</p>
<p><strong>ambitious </strong>- <em>adj. </em> having a desire to be successful, powerful, or famous</p>
<p><strong>cruel</strong> - <em>adj. </em>causing or helping to cause suffering</p>
<p><strong>segregation</strong> - <em>n. </em>the practice or policy of keeping people of different races, religions, etc., separate from each other</p>
<p><strong>gender </strong>- <em>n. </em>the state of being male or female</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong>- <em>n.</em> a person who buys goods and services</p>
<p><strong>disarray </strong>- <em>n.</em> a lack of order; a confused or messy condition</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift Headed to This Law school, in Theory  (2023/11/4) | 泰勒·斯威夫特“进军”法学院</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/taylor-swift-headed-to-this-law-school-in-theory.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>University of South Dakota law professor Sean Kammer's friends told him they were unsure about the seriousness of his upcoming class on musical performer Taylor Swift.<br/>
南达科他大学法学教授肖恩·坎默的朋友告诉他，他们不确定他即将开设的关于音乐表演者泰勒·斯威夫特的课程的严肃性。</p>
<p>"I understand this sounds ridiculous, at least at first glance," said Kammer, a Taylor Swift fan, or Swiftie, himself. "But it's not."<br/>
作为泰勒·斯威夫特粉丝的坎默说：“我理解这听起来很荒谬，至少乍一看是这样，但事实并非如此。”</p>
<p>Kammer's class, called the Taylor Swift effect, is planned for the spring. It is believed to be the first law school class based on the famous American singer.<br/>
坎默计划在春季开设的课程名为泰勒·斯威夫特效应。据信，这是第一门以这位著名美国歌手为原型的法学院课程。</p>
<p>After attending a Swift concert in Minneapolis, Minnesota, in June, Kammer said he was inspired to develop the writing class. It is available for second- and third-year law students.<br/>
今年6月，坎默参加了斯威夫特在明尼苏达州明尼阿波利斯市的一场演唱会，他说自己受到启发开发这门写作课程。这么课程将向法律系大二和大三学生开放。</p>
<p>The class will study the artist's dealings with the law, including her rerecording of six albums and related copyright problems, Kammer said.<br/>
坎默说，该课程将研究这位艺术家对法律问题的处理，包括她重新录制的六张专辑和相关的版权问题。</p>
<p>It will also examine how an individual's experiences and beliefs shape how they understand the law – much like how there are different understandings of her songs.<br/>
它还将考察个人的经历和信仰如何影响他们对法律的理解——就像人们对她的歌曲有不同的理解一样。</p>
<p>Law classes about popular culture are not uncommon. They also bring attention to schools that offer them. The television show The Wire inspired a number of criminal law classes over the years. In 2022, the University of Virginia School of Law offered a class on corporate law based on the show Succession.<br/>
关于流行文化的法律课并不少见。它们也引起了人们对提供这类课程的学校的关注。这些年来，电视节目《火线》激发了许多刑法课程的灵感。2022年，弗吉尼亚大学法学院在《继承》节目的基础上开设了一门公司法课程。</p>
<p>Law classes centered on a single public person are rare, however. But Georgia State University College of Law is currently offering a class based on the legal life of musician Rick Ross.<br/>
然而，以一个公众人物为中心的法律课程并不多见。但佐治亚州立大学法学院目前正在开设一门以音乐家里克·罗斯的法律生活为基础的课程。</p>
<p>Boston University law professor Jessica Silbey helped write a book on popular culture and the law. She said students are usually more interested when they study subjects such as sports, new technology and famous people.<br/>
波士顿大学法学教授杰西卡·西尔贝帮助撰写了一本关于流行文化和法律的书。她说，学生们通常在学习体育、新技术和名人等科目时更感兴趣。</p>
<p>Silbey teaches Swift's album rerecordings in her copyright class to teach about contract law in the music business. She said the singer's success story and what she has dealt with provide good lessons in the law.<br/>
西尔贝在她的版权课上通过讲述斯威夫特重新录制专辑来讲授音乐行业的合同法。她说，这位歌手的成功经历和处置经验提供了很好的法律教训。</p>
<p>South Dakota Law is not the first school to offer classes on Swift. The University of California at Berkeley recently announced an upcoming business class based on Swift's business experiences. Stanford, New York University, and the University of Texas have also offered Swift-inspired classes. But Kammer's class is the first legal exploration of her music and career.<br/>
南达科他大学法学院并不是第一所基于斯威夫特开设课程的学校。加州大学伯克利分校最近宣布，即将开设一门基于斯威夫特商业经验的商务课程。斯坦福大学、纽约大学和得克萨斯大学也开设了以斯威夫特为灵感的课程。但坎默的课程是首次对她的音乐和职业生涯进行法律探索。</p>
<p>Kammer also teaches legal history. He said he plans to examine some Swift songs to look into how the words of the songs and certain legal texts can be understood. He said his class will also look at good and bad qualities of methods for understanding the law.<br/>
坎默还教授法律史。他说，他计划研究斯威夫特的一些歌曲，以了解歌曲的歌词和某些法律文本可以如何理解。他说，他的课程还将研究理解法律的方法的优劣。</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Michelangelo's 'Secret Room' to Open for Visitors  (2023/11/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/michelangelo-s-secret-room-to-open-for-visitors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Visitors will soon be able to see a long-hidden space inside the Medici Chapel in the Italian city of Florence. The walls of the small space contain drawings that some experts believe may have been created by the famous artist Michelangelo.</p>
<p>The secret room is small – 10 meters by 3 meters. Officials discovered the room in 1975 when searching for a way to make a new exit from Medici Chapel.</p>
<p>The museum's then-director Paolo Dal Poggetto strongly believed that the drawings were by Michelangelo, said the current director, Paola D'Agostino. A debate over the issue began then and continues to this day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Delicate charcoal drawings that some experts have attributed to Michelangelo are seen on the walls of a room used to store coal until 1955 inside Florence's Medici Chapel, in central Italy, Tuesday, Oct. 31, 2023. (Francesco Fanfani via AP, HO)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0ca2b689-bfd7-4e39-9411-0a85fb77b986_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Delicate charcoal drawings that some experts have attributed to Michelangelo are seen on the walls of a room used to store coal until 1955 inside Florence's Medici Chapel, in central Italy, Tuesday, Oct. 31, 2023. (Francesco Fanfani via AP, HO)</span></div>
<p>D'Agostino suggested that experts of Michelangelo's drawings did not believe he created the works at the time of their discovery 50 years ago. She added, "Others had a more moderate view, in the sense they thought that some could be by Michelangelo and others could be by followers. So the debate is ongoing."</p>
<p>The room was used to store coal until 1955. Then it was closed and forgotten for years below a special kind of opening known as a trapdoor. The trapdoor was hidden beneath<strong> furniture</strong>. The drawings themselves were discovered under two layers of plaster – a substance used to make walls and ceilings smooth.</p>
<p>Dal Poggetto believed Michelangelo hid in the space to escape the anger of Pope Clement VII. The artist had supported a short-lived republic that overthrew the Medicis.</p>
<p>In the room, the artist drew for some of his projects. They include drawings believed to be the legs of Giuliano de' Medici.</p>
<p>Starting on November 15, small groups of four people will be able to visit the room for about 15 minutes. Visitors will have to pay an additional $20 on top of the $10 charged for entry to the main museum.</p>
<p>The museum said it limits the number of visitors because of the need to reduce <strong>exposure</strong> of the artworks to light. At most, 100 visitors will be able to go to the room each week.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell adapted this story from AP and Reuters reports. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>furniture</strong> <em>– n.</em> chairs, tables, beds, etc.</p>
<p><strong>exposure</strong> <em>– n.</em> the fact or condition of being affected by something or experiencing something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'In Which' and 'To Which'  (2023/11/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/in-which-and-to-which.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the use of prepositions with "which."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Dear VOA Ask a Teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-ea46-08dbdb1b669a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am Shohei from Japan. I enjoy many contents of VOA learning English every day. I have a grammatical question for using "which" such as, in which, of which, from which, and so on. How do native English speakers immediately decide to use the correct preposition? I cannot understand these differences.</p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p>Thank you (^^)!</p>
<p><strong>Answer </strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Shohei. This is a good question.</p>
<p>When we use "which" with a preposition, it is mostly in written English to note place, time, or manner (or the way that something is happening.)</p>
<p>The most often used prepositions with "which" are "in" and "to." The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/use-a-language-corpus-to-improve-your-vocabulary/7189316.html" target="_blank">Corpus of Contemporary American English</a> shows that "in" is used five times more often than "to." And they both make up more than 60 percent of all uses of a preposition with "which."</p>
<p>Many times, "in which" and "to which" are used as part of an expression in English. They include "the extent to which," "the way in which," and "the manner in which." Here are some examples:</p>
<p><em>We can explore <u>the way in which</u> nature changes. </em></p>
<p><em>Our future depends on <u>the extent to which</u> humans can stop climate change. </em></p>
<p><em>Fans were not pleased with <u>the manner in which</u> the trainer talked about the team. </em></p>
<p>One more thing, if you're not sure which preposition to use with "which", a good choice is "in" because it's used the most often.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Shohei.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Environmental Group Says Few Companies Meet Water Use Targets  (2023/11/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/environmental-group-says-few-companies-meet-water-use-targets.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Major corporations in industries that produce clothing, food, drinks and technology services use a lot of water.</p>
<p>However, many companies say they want to be more responsible about the freshwater they use. <strong>Drought</strong>, floods and extreme weather also threaten their supply chains.</p>
<p>The nonprofit environmental group Ceres ranked 72 companies for their <strong>sustainability</strong> efforts. Ceres said few of the businesses are close to reaching the 2030 goals set by the group, which is based in Boston, Massachusetts.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Coca-Cola cans move down a conveyer belt in the Swire Coca-Cola bottling plant Oct. 20, 2023, in Denver. (AP Photo/Brittany Peterson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8827-08dbdbc37b25_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Coca-Cola cans move down a conveyer belt in the Swire Coca-Cola bottling plant Oct. 20, 2023, in Denver. (AP Photo/Brittany Peterson)</span></div>
<p>Last year, Ceres launched an effort to push companies with large water usage to protect water resources. Recently, the group released a study that included the corporations Coca-Cola, General Mills and Amazon.</p>
<p>"There's no doubt that companies need to do better," said Kirsten James. She is a program director for water at Ceres.</p>
<p>Ceres said the companies were chosen from four industries based on their size and use of water. They were ranked based on several <strong>factors</strong>, including promises to protect the amount and quality of the water they use, as well as the environments that supply it. They were also tested on whether they helped improve <strong>access</strong> to water and <strong>sanitation</strong> in communities where they do business. Ceres used publicly available information, including information the companies provided to the government through March.</p>
<p>None of the companies scored above 70 percent of the points available. Some were considered to be on track to meet the goals set by the nonprofit group, with scores of at least 50 percent.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola said its water use in 2022 was 10 percent more <strong>efficient</strong> compared to 2015. The company said it hopes to have 100 percent circular water use. That is where all water is used and returned to the <strong>watersheds</strong> it has been drawn from.</p>
<p>But the company did not say how likely it was to reach that target, nor how much progress it has made. Coca-Cola also said producing its products does not use as much water as growing what goes into the products it sells.</p>
<p>"The agricultural ingredients that we use use <strong>vastly</strong> more water to produce than the actual manufacturing process," said Michael Goltzman. He is vice president of Coca Cola and a sustainability head.</p>
<p>Reports say technology companies, like Amazon and Apple, use a lot of water to cool the computers in their large data centers. The Ceres study rated both companies below 20 percent progress toward the nonprofit's targets.</p>
<p>Food company General Mills was among the companies closest to meeting the 2030 targets, at 65 percent.</p>
<p>Mary Jane Melendez is the company's chief sustainability officer. She said 85 percent of the company's water use is in agriculture. Extreme weather in the U.S. has reportedly affected the company in recent years.</p>
<p>Melendez gave examples of weather-related problems. She said freezing and <strong>thawing</strong> hurt the company's supply of sugar beets. She also said drought affected its oats supply.</p>
<p>Michael Kiparsky is director of the Wheeler Water Institute at the University of California, Berkeley. He said that corporations have an interest in protecting their operations from water shortages. That could push them to make bigger steps to protect freshwater resources.</p>
<p>Kiparsky pointed out there is no way to enforce Ceres' targets. But he asked, "Does money talk? When it talks, it talks pretty loud," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>drought </strong><em>— n. </em>a period of much less rain than normal</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainability </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability to continue to use a resource without using it up</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>factor –</strong>n. Something that produces a result</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em>the ability to get or use something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sanitation </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>the equipment and structures needed to process waste and wastewater in a place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>efficient </strong><em>— adj. </em>using the right amount of a resource without using too much</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>watershed </strong><em>— n. </em>the land area drained by a large river system</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vast </strong><em>— adj. v</em>ery large or wide</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>thaw </strong><em>— v. </em>when ice or something that is frozen returns to a higher temperature and melts</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Fans of K-pop Star Can Talk with His AI Twin  (2023/11/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/fans-of-k-pop-star-can-talk-with-his-ai-twin.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Listeners want to feel close to the musicians they support. And most would jump at the chance to talk with their favorite artist one-on-one. But famous people rarely have the time for that kind of meeting.</p>
<p>So what is the next best thing?</p>
<p>For Mark Tuan, whose new recording <em>Fallin</em> is out Friday, it was creating a <strong>digital avatar</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - K-pop musician Mark Tuan arrives at the American Music Awards in Los Angeles on Nov. 20, 2022. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5ed263c8-10a4-4b99-be0a-65596635507e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - K-pop musician Mark Tuan arrives at the American Music Awards in Los Angeles on Nov. 20, 2022. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP, File)</span></div>
<p>The Taiwanese-American entertainer from Los Angeles, California is a former member of the Korean group Got7. He partnered with Soul Machines to create a "digital <strong>twin</strong>" called "Digital Mark."</p>
<p>In doing so, Tuan became the first famous person to attach their likeness to the artificial intelligence (AI) program OpenAI's GPT. The technology permits fans to talk one-on-one with Tuan's avatar.</p>
<p>"It's very different. It's not really me, but it is me," he says of Digital Mark. "It's a <strong>cool</strong> thing, that fans get to <strong>interact</strong> with him, too."</p>
<p>Greg Cross is head of Soul Machines. He views Digital Mark as the future of fan interaction. Cross said we are only at the beginning of how this technology will change how fans interact with famous people and companies.</p>
<p>Tuan's hope with Digital Mark is that as the technology progresses, so too will fans' relationships with his AI twin. He also hopes that they will get to communicate with him in languages beyond English.</p>
<p>Getting Digital Mark to look like and act like the real Mark Tuan involved a lot of work. Tuan had to spend several days filming in a <strong>bodysuit</strong> to capture his movement. He made different faces so the Digital Mark could capture his emotions. And he spent a lot of time recording his voice as well.</p>
<p>Right now, Digital Mark just stands in one place. But Tuan says that maybe one day they will have Digital Mark walking around too.</p>
<p>The technology is in its early days. Tuan says Digital Mark has been talking about a musical event that does not exist. But he is hopeful to see how the avatar will progress.</p>
<p>Fans have already been using Digital Mark to interact with Tuan about event dates and new music.</p>
<p>As for concerns over how this kind of technology could be used in the future, Tuan is hopeful but has some concerns.</p>
<p>"I've seen a lot of movies where robots take over the world," he jokes. "You never really know what's going to happen, but I think it is really cool."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Sherman reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>digital </strong>– <em>adj</em>. using or characterized by computer technology</p>
<p><strong>avatar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a picture of a person or an animal that represents a particular computer user, on a computer screen, especially in a computer game or on social media</p>
<p><strong>twin </strong>– <em>n</em>. either one of two babies that are born at the same time to the same mother</p>
<p><strong>cool </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very fashionable, stylish, or appealing in a way that is generally approved of especially by young people</p>
<p><strong>interact </strong>– <em>v</em>. to talk or do things with other people</p>
<p><strong>bodysuit </strong>– <em>n</em>. a piece of clothing that fits tightly and covers the body except for the legs and sometimes the arms</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Daylight Saving Time?  (2023/11/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/what-is-daylight-saving-time.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>As November begins, many countries in North America and Europe are turning the clock back as daylight saving time ends.</p>
<p>Daylight saving time is the practice of moving clocks forward by one hour during summer months so daylight lasts longer into the evening.</p>
<p>In Europe, the practice is called European Summer Time. The clock usually moves forward in March and turns back at the end of October. Most European countries follow the practice. Georgia, Russia, Turkey, Iceland and a few others are among the exceptions.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Clocks are displayed at Electric Time Company on Nov. 1, 2022, in Medfield, Massachusetts. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/254d61cd-1052-4ed0-9207-7741fd073a83_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Clocks are displayed at Electric Time Company on Nov. 1, 2022, in Medfield, Massachusetts. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa)</span></div>
<p>Across the Atlantic Ocean, Canada, Mexico, Cuba and the United States start daylight saving time in March also. The clock will be set back an hour on November 5 this year.</p>
<p>Countries closer to the equator usually do not follow daylight saving time because the period of daylight changes little. Those that do not change the times include countries in Central America, Asia and Africa.</p>
<p><strong>How did it start?</strong></p>
<p>The idea of changing the clocks with the seasons started with <a class="wsw__a" href="https://teara.govt.nz/en/biographies/3h42/hudson-george-vernon">George Hudson</a>, a New Zealand scientist who studied insects. In 1895, Hudson proposed a time change to extend summer daylight hours. The extra time would have helped him with collecting insects after work.</p>
<p>The idea did not appeal to anyone until the time of World War I when European countries sought to save energy. Germany was the first country to adopt daylight saving time, in 1916, and the U.S. followed in 1918.</p>
<p>Some people believe that the U.S. established daylight saving time to help farmers. But farmers generally do not like the practice. The publication <a class="wsw__a" href="https://modernfarmer.com/2022/03/daylight-saving-time-farmers/">Modern Farmer</a> said American farmers were against the practice but that Congress approved it anyway.</p>
<p>Opponents of daylight saving time have pointed to studies that found an increase in traffic accidents, health issues, and lack of sleep in the days after clocks are moved forward every March.</p>
<p>As for saving energy, the Congressional Research Service said studies have found little, if any, energy savings from the time change.</p>
<p><strong>Arguments to end the practice</strong></p>
<p>Daylight saving time has been a fluid issue from the start. Some countries have adopted and rejected it several times. In South America, Uruguay ended the practice in 2015. Chile replaced it with "wintertime" from May to August in 2016.</p>
<p>Egypt announced in March it would return to daylight saving time after seven years to save energy. Japan briefly considered adopting the practice for the 2020 Olympics but rejected it due to a lack of popular support.</p>
<p>In the U.S. there have been several efforts to make daylight saving time permanent. Last year, a bill called the "Sunshine Protection Act" passed the Senate but got stuck in the House of Representatives. Lawmakers could not agree on whether to keep standard time or permanent daylight saving time.</p>
<p>The bill was proposed again this year.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English with additional reporting from Reuters.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Optimism  (2023/11/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/grammar-and-optimism.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>How do we talk about events or actions that make us happy or hopeful about the present and future? In other words, how do we talk about <strong>optimism</strong>?</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore a point of connection between grammar and hopeful ideas about the future. You will learn how to understand the difference between closely related words – and how to use them in sentences.</p>
<p>Let's start with some important terms.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-285f-08dbda3b8e24_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p><strong>History and relationships </strong></p>
<p>Today's lesson begins with a noun: optimism. It is a feeling or belief that good things will happen in the future.</p>
<p>The online Etymology Dictionary <strong>traces </strong>the roots of the word "optimism" to 1759. The word first appeared in<strong> translations</strong> from the French writer Voltaire.</p>
<p>We also have a closely related noun that appeared in English at about the same time: optimist.</p>
<p>An optimist is a person with a hopeful way of looking at things.</p>
<p>The two nouns differ by only one letter. Optimism ends in an –m and suggests a general feeling or belief. Optimist ends with a –t and means a person with a hopeful world view.</p>
<p>From optimist, we can add an –ic ending to get an adjective. Optimistic describes a person who is hopeful about the future or expects good things to happen.</p>
<p>From optimistic, we can add an –ally ending to get an adverb: optimistically. This word describes or modifies verbs.</p>
<p>So, we have a family of words. We have two nouns: optimism and optimist. From the noun optimist, we can add more letters to get the adjective, optimistic, and the adverb, optimistically.</p>
<p><strong>Usage </strong></p>
<p>Now, how do we use these words in everyday discussions?</p>
<p>It is important to remember that some words are commonly used together. You might think of these as high-frequency structures, or word groups you see or hear a lot in speech and writing. What are some of these high-frequency structures?</p>
<p>Let's start with optimism.</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer tells us that the most commonly used word before "optimism" is the short word "of."</p>
<p>For example, we might say the following:</p>
<p><em>At that time, people in the streets were happy; the economy was strong. A feeling of optimism was in the air.</em></p>
<p>What about the noun "optimist"?</p>
<p>Once again, Google's Ngram Viewer tells us that another short word is commonly used before the noun "optimist." In this case, the short word is "an."</p>
<p>So, you are likely to hear or read something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am an optimist. </em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>She is an optimist.</em></p>
<p>What about the adjective "optimistic?" Once again, Google's Ngram Viewer tells us that the short word "an" is the most commonly used word before "optimistic."</p>
<p>So, you are likely to hear or read something like the following:</p>
<p><em>He gave an optimistic answer. </em></p>
<p>Finally, we have the adverb "optimistically." What is the most commonly used word before it? In this case, we have the verb "said." You are likely to hear or read something like this:</p>
<p><em>The traffic doesn't look too bad, she said optimistically. </em></p>
<p><strong>Quiz </strong></p>
<p>Now let's take some time to work with these ideas.</p>
<p>Fill in the blank with the correct word – either noun, adjective, or adverb.</p>
<p><em>She spoke ____________ about the country's economic outlook. </em></p>
<p>The correct word is the adverb optimistically. The sentence is "She spoke optimistically about the country's economic outlook."</p>
<p>We know that the adverb is needed because it is modifying or describing the verb "spoke." How did she speak? She spoke optimistically.</p>
<p>Now let's consider another example. Fill in the blank.</p>
<p><em>Tom is always so hopeful. He's an _________ at heart. </em></p>
<p>The correct answer is the noun optimist. The full statement is "Tom is always so hopeful. He's an optimist at heart."</p>
<p>We know that the answer is optimist because the words coming before optimist suggest a noun phrase. When we see the short word "an," that tells us that a noun or noun phrase is coming.</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>In today's report, we explored a few closely related words. We also learned about commonly used structures.</p>
<p>There are, of course, other ways to talk about hopeful views or ideas about the future. But that will have to be the subject of another lesson.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>optimism</strong><em> – n.</em> a feeling or belief that good things will happen in the future</p>
<p><strong>trace </strong><em>–v.</em> to follow the path of something</p>
<p><strong>translate</strong> <em>– v. </em>to change words from one language into another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Electrical Grid Problems Risk World Climate Goals  (2023/11/2) | 国际能源署称电网问题威胁全球气候目标</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/report-electrical-grid-problems-risk-world-climate-goals.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The International Energy Agency (IEA) says many world electrical grids will need major improvements to support international climate change goals.<br/>
国际能源署表示，全球许多电网将需要进行重大改进，以支持国际气候变化目标。</p>
<p>In a new report, the IEA calls on nations to invest in aging electrical grid systems. The Paris-based organization works with member governments to help them shape energy policies.<br/>
在一份新的报告中，国际能源署呼吁各国投资于老化的电网系统。这家总部位于巴黎的组织与成员国政府合作，帮助他们制定能源政策。</p>
<p>The IEA examined electricity grids in countries across the world to produce its report. The report found that, for the most part, electrical grid systems have not kept up with clean energy technologies like solar, wind, electric cars and heat pumps.<br/>
国际能源署对世界各国的电网进行了调查以编制其报告。报告发现，在大多数情况下，电网系统没有跟上太阳能、风能、电动汽车和热泵等清洁能源技术的步伐。</p>
<p>One of the main findings is that to meet all national climate and energy goals, about 80 million kilometers of power lines will have to be added or replaced by 2040. The report noted that this amount is equal to the whole existing worldwide electricity grid.<br/>
其中一项主要发现是，为了实现所有国家气候和能源目标，到2040年前必须新增或更换约8000万公里的输电线路。报告指出，这一数额相当于全球现有的整个电网。</p>
<p>The 2015 Paris climate agreement has set a goal to limit warming worldwide to 1.5 degrees Celsius since pre-industrial times. Climate scientists believe the way to meet that goal is to reduce the use of greenhouse gases. They say this kind of pollution – linked largely to human activities – warms the planet.<br/>
2015年《巴黎气候协定》设定了一个目标，即自前工业化时代以来，将全球变暖限制在1.5摄氏度以内。气候科学家认为，实现这一目标的方法是减少温室气体的使用。他们说，这种主要与人类活动有关的污染使地球变暖。</p>
<p>IEA Executive Director Fatih Birol spoke to reporters from The Associated Press about the report. He said there are many renewable energy projects waiting to connect to electricity systems. But currently, most grids are not equipped to work with the greener technology.<br/>
国际能源署执行主任法提赫·比罗尔就这份报告向美联社记者发表了讲话。他说，有许多可再生能源项目正在等待接入电力系统。但目前，大多数电网还没有配备更环保的技术。</p>
<p>Birol said many of the renewable projects are ready or nearly ready to go. If grid changes could be completed, the projects could produce about 1,500 gigawatts of power. This is about five times the amount of solar and wind capacity added worldwide last year, Birol said.<br/>
比罗尔说，许多可再生能源项目已经准备好或几乎准备就绪。如果电网改造能够完成，这些项目可以产生约1500吉瓦的电力。比罗尔说，这大约是去年全球太阳能和风能发电量的五倍。</p>
<p>If investments in grid systems do not increase, the report predicts the chance of reaching the Paris agreement's goal drops sharply. The IEA said such investments need to double to more than $600 billion a year by 2030.<br/>
报告预测，如果电网系统投资不增加，达成《巴黎协定》目标的可能性将大幅下降。国际能源署表示，到2030年，此类投资需要翻一番，达到每年6000亿美元以上。</p>
<p>But there are difficulties getting new grid improvements approved. The IEA notes that it is not uncommon for a single high-power overhead power line to take five to 13 years to get government approvals in developed economies. Approvals in nations such as China and India, can be much shorter, the organization said.<br/>
但是，新的电网改进要获得批准存在难度。国际能源署指出，在发达经济体，一条大功率架空电线需要5到13年才能获得政府批准的情况并不少见。该组织表示，中国和印度等国的审批时间可能会短得多。</p>
<p>One project examined in the report aims to carry wind power from northern to southern Germany. First planned in 2014, it was delayed after political opposition to an overhead line meant it was buried instead. Completion of the project is now expected in 2028 instead of 2022.<br/>
报告中审查的一个项目旨在将风能从德国北部输送到南部。最初规划于2014年，但由于政治上反对架空线路，相当于它要被埋地敷设，因此被推迟。该项目现在预计将于2028年竣工，而非2022年竣工。</p>
<p>Other important projects are delayed, including the 400-kilometer Bay of Biscay connector between Spain and France. Officials expect to finish the work in 2028 instead of 2025. And a line to bring wind power from New Mexico to Arizona and California just started last month after years of delays.<br/>
其他重要项目也被推迟，包括西班牙和法国之间长达400公里的比斯开湾连接线。官员们预计将在2028年完工，而不是2025年。经过多年的延误，一条从新墨西哥州到亚利桑那州和加利福尼亚州的风力发电线路上个月刚刚开通。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Funding Cuts Threaten Refugee’s Children Education in Rwanda  (2023/11/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/funding-cuts-threaten-refugee-s-children-education-in-rwanda.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Cuts to United Nations aid for refugees living in Rwanda are threatening education for children from more than 100,000 families. The families fled conflict in several East African countries. They are spread among five refugee camps in Rwanda.</p>
<p>Burundian refugee Epimaque Nzohoraho spoke about the situation to the<em> Associated Press</em>. He said the leader of his son's school reported that his child should not return to class because the UN refugee agency had stopped paying for the education.</p>
<p>Nzohoraho said he does not know how much it costs to attend the school. But, he said, he had hoped education would save his son's future.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE — Hutu refugees women and children wait to be registered at Kigali airport Rwanda, after they arrived on the UN plane from Kisangai, Zaire Sunday, May 4, 1997. (AP Photo/Sayyid Azim, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4b8f-08dbd6299e2d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE — Hutu refugees women and children wait to be registered at Kigali airport Rwanda, after they arrived on the UN plane from Kisangai, Zaire Sunday, May 4, 1997. (AP Photo/Sayyid Azim, File)</span></div>
<p>Last weekend, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, UNHCR, announced budget cuts for food, education, shelter and health care. The agency acted as hopes disappear to meet the $90.5 million in aid donations.</p>
<p>UNHCR spokesperson Lilly Carlisle said that only $33 million had arrived by October. "The agency cannot <strong>manage</strong> to meet the needs of the refugees," she said.</p>
<p>Rwanda is home to a little more than 134,500 refugees. About 62 percent of them came from neighboring Congo. About 37 percent came from Burundi. Less than one percent are from other countries, says the country's emergency management ministry.</p>
<p>Among those affected are 553 refugee schoolchildren who were expecting to go to <strong>boarding</strong> schools this year. The budget shortfall will not permit their attendance. The UNCHR is already supporting 750 students in boarding schools, Carlisle said. The school fees for boarding schools in Rwanda is $80 each school term.</p>
<p>Budget problems have also affected food<strong> </strong>assistance, which has dropped from $5 to $3 per refugee monthly since last year.</p>
<p>Chantal Mukabirori is a Burundian refugee living in eastern Rwanda's Mahama camp. She says with reduced food aid, her four children are going hungry and refusing to go to school.</p>
<p>"Do you expect me to send children to school when I know there is no food?" she asked.</p>
<p>Carlisle is urging refugees "to look for employment to support their families," but some say this is hard to do as a refugee.</p>
<p>Solange Uwamahoro fled violence in Burundi in 2015 after an attempted government overthrow. She says going back to the same country where her husband was killed may be her only choice.</p>
<p>"I have no other <strong>option</strong> now. I could die of hunger ... it's very hard to get a job as a refugee," Uwamahoro told the AP.</p>
<p>Phillipe Babinshuti is secretary of Rwanda's emergency management ministry. He says the refugees in Rwanda should not be forgotten even with the increasing number of global conflicts.</p>
<p>The aid reduction effect on education is likely to lower school enrollment. Data from UNHCR in 2022 showed that 1.1 million of 2.2 million refugee children in the East, Horn of Africa and Great Lakes area were out of school.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by the Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>manage </strong><em>— v. </em>to have control of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>boarding school </strong><em>— n. </em>a school where students can live during the school term</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>option </strong><em>— n. </em>the opportunity or ability to choose something or to choose between two or more things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>enroll </strong><em>— v. </em>to become a member or participant</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Africa Unlikely to Expand Manufacturing  (2023/11/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/study-africa-unlikely-to-expand-manufacturing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A recent study says African countries are less likely to follow East Asia's development model of expanding manufacturing to reduce <strong>poverty</strong>.</p>
<p>The study predicts a decreasing share of factory jobs for most countries by 2050.</p>
<p>The Center for Global Development (CGD) released the study this week. It said there will be fewer factory workers around the world in 2050. And the paper predicts that, even in poor countries with a lot of low-cost labor, manufacturing job growth will slow down.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman spins raw silk yarn in a factory owned by Rwandan textile firm Utexwra in Kigali January 19, 2009. A recent study says African countries are less likely to follow East Asia's development model of expanding manufacturing to reduce poverty.(REUTERS/Hereward Holland)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/09d40000-0a00-0242-44a7-08da90ec6240_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman spins raw silk yarn in a factory owned by Rwandan textile firm Utexwra in Kigali January 19, 2009. A recent study says African countries are less likely to follow East Asia's development model of expanding manufacturing to reduce poverty.(REUTERS/Hereward Holland)</span></div>
<p>China may be an<strong> exception </strong>out of the 59 countries modeled in the study. The study said that China will continue to expand its share of manufacturing to 43.8 percent in 2050 from 30 percent in 2018 and 10.5 percent in 1975.</p>
<p>The study's writers said that China will continue its strong manufacturing performance, producing higher-valued products.</p>
<p>This might create some space for developing countries in Africa, Southeast Asia, and South and Central America to start producing the products China will no longer produce. However, it will not be enough for other countries to follow the same development path taken by East Asia in expanding manufacturing.</p>
<p>Charles Kenny and Ranil Dissanayake of CGD said that many countries will move straight from agriculture to services. They say jobs will greatly expand in services because of new technologies – even in countries such as Bangladesh and Ethiopia.</p>
<p>"There's still a popular idea that low-income countries will progress naturally from being <strong>dominated</strong> by agriculture to manufacturing-led growth, but <strong>mounting</strong> evidence suggests that's not going to happen," said Kenny. He said people think that farms are going to empty out across Africa and Asia in the coming years, but he said, people are likely to flood into offices and stores, not factories.</p>
<p>The study <strong>projects</strong> worldwide growth through the year 2050. It aims to predict changes in the economies of 59 countries that make up about three quarters of the world's GDP and population.</p>
<p>GDP, or gross domestic product, measures all the goods and services produced in a country in a year. GDP is considered a good measure of the size of a nation's economy.</p>
<p>The study projects that even for the lowest-income countries, the number of factory jobs will just keep up with population growth over the next 30 years. And it projects manufacturing will likely stay a small part of most of these countries' economies.</p>
<p>Across all low-income countries, manufacturing jobs are projected to remain below eight percent of total employment. The study projects the share of manufacturing jobs in high-income countries will continue to fall, to 8.3 percent by 2050 from 11.4 percent currently.</p>
<p>Jobs in private service industries are expected to make up 37 percent of worldwide jobs by 2050, and 26 percent in low-income countries. That is up from about 12 percent currently.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>poverty </strong>– <em>n</em>. the state of being poor</p>
<p><strong>exception </strong>– <em>n</em>. someone or something that is different from others</p>
<p><strong>dominate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to be the most important part of (something)</p>
<p><strong>mounting </strong><em>– v.</em> to increase in amount</p>
<p><strong>project </strong>–v. to estimate or predict something for a time in the future</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>German Companies Turn to Robots to Fill Jobs for Retiring Workers  (2023/11/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/german-companies-turn-to-robots-to-fill-jobs-for-retiring-workers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>German businesses are increasingly turning to robots to fill jobs as the country faces a severe labor shortage.</p>
<p>The situation left about 1.7 million jobs unfilled across Germany in June, official data showed. The country's Chambers of Commerce and Industry has estimated that half of German businesses are currently struggling to fill positions. Germany is Europe's largest economy.</p>
<p>One of the country's biggest labor issues is the large number of people retiring from the so-called Baby Boomer generation. People in this group are between the ages of 57 and 75. The nation's birth rate has also been going down for years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A robot machine is seen at ROLEC Gehause-Systeme in Rinteln, Germany on October 6, 2023. (Courtesy of Matthias Rose/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b73e-08dbd94dbfbd_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A robot machine is seen at ROLEC Gehause-Systeme in Rinteln, Germany on October 6, 2023. (Courtesy of Matthias Rose/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>Economic experts say it is difficult to replace these retiring workers. Many younger workers do not want to take jobs seen as dirty and dangerous.</p>
<p>The job shortage situation is currently reducing growth in Germany by about $109 billion a year, official estimates suggest. The Federal Employment Agency predicts the amount of available workers will shrink by 7 million people by 2035.</p>
<p>The problem is affecting large, medium and small businesses across the country. Some have decided to replace retiring workers with robotic systems.</p>
<p>With similar issues affecting other developed economies, robotic and artificial intelligence (AI) technologies will continue to expand, said Nela Richardson. She is the chief economist at financial provider ADP.</p>
<p>"Long term, all those<strong> innovations</strong> are a game-changer for the world of work. Everybody will do their job differently," Richardson told Reuters.</p>
<p>Heavy investment in <strong>automation</strong> by carmakers and other major industrial companies has made Germany the world's fourth-largest market for robots – the largest in Europe.</p>
<p>But as robots become less costly and easier to operate, even smaller companies are also using them. The International Federation of Robotics has estimated that about 26,000 robotic machines were put in place in Germany last year.</p>
<p>"Robots enable the survival of companies that see their future at risk due to <strong>staff </strong>shortages," said Ralf Winkelmann, director of FANUC Germany. The company sells about half its Japanese-made robots to small and medium-sized businesses.</p>
<p>Family-run ROLEC is a German company that produces systems to protect industrial electronics and control equipment. It bought its first robot last year to permit production to continue at night. ROLEC has already bought a second machine and plans to continue investing in automation.</p>
<p>"It is great when you turn on the light in the morning and the parts are in the storage container and have been processed," ROLEC's CEO Matthias Rose told Reuters.</p>
<p>Industry experts say increasing robotic operations are also a sign that robots have become easier to use, with no special skills required. Most now come with a Human Machine Interface, which operates similarly to a smartphone, said Florian Andre. He is a co-founder of SHERPA Robotics, a start-up that targets companies with between 20 and 100 employees.</p>
<p>Even workers and trade <strong>unions</strong> – which in the past were fearful of job losses linked to robots – have taken an increasingly favorable position. A public opinion study published in June by a robots marketplace organization found that nearly half of German employees see robots as a help to the labor shortage.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>innovation </strong><em>– adj. </em>the act or process of introducing new ideas, devices, or methods</p>
<p><strong>automate </strong><em>– n. </em>to control something using machines and not people</p>
<p><strong>staff </strong><em>– n. </em>the people who work for an organization</p>
<p><strong>union</strong> – <em>n</em>. an organization of workers formed to protect the rights and interests of its members</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Many Math, Computer Science Teachers Use Chatbots  (2023/11/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/many-math-computer-science-teachers-use-chatbots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Some schools in the U.S. are considering whether to ban chatbots, which use artificial intelligence, or AI. However, some math and computer science teachers think chatbots, which "learn" about subjects from the internet, are just another tool.</p>
<p>Jack Price has taught math using Wolfram Alpha. It is a website that solves algebraic problems online. It has long threatened to make algebra homework a thing of the past.</p>
<p>Teachers learned to work around and with it, said Price. He is an assistant professor of mathematics and computer science at the University of Puget Sound in the western state of Washington. Now, students have a new online service that provides homework help using AI—ChatGPT—that teachers must deal with.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Text from the ChatGPT page of the OpenAI website on Feb. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-538f-08dbb153c5bc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Text from the ChatGPT page of the OpenAI website on Feb. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>Price does not consider ChatGPT to be a threat, and he is not alone. Some math professors believe AI, when used correctly, can help strengthen math learning. It is arriving at a time when math scores are at historic lows and educators are questioning if math should be taught differently.</p>
<p>AI can serve as a <strong>tutor</strong>, giving a student who is struggling with a problem immediate <strong>feedback</strong>. It can help a teacher plan math lessons or write math problems for different levels of teaching. It can show new computer programmers sample <strong>code</strong>, permitting them to avoid learning how to write basic code.</p>
<p>"Math has always been <strong>evolving</strong> as technology evolves," said Price. He said that a hundred years ago, people could not solve problems using <strong>calculators</strong>.</p>
<p>Price makes sure students have the ability to solve problems on their own. Then, he discusses the limitations of the technologies they might want to use when they get home.</p>
<p>"Computers are really good at doing <strong>tedious</strong> things," Price said. "We don't have to do all the tedious stuff...And then we can <strong>interpret</strong> the answer and think about what it tells us about the decisions we need to make."</p>
<p>Min Sun is a University of Washington education professor. She thinks students should use chatbots like personal tutors. If students do not understand a math operation, they can ask ChatGPT to explain it and give examples.</p>
<p>She wants teachers to use ChatGPT as their own assistant: to plan math lessons, give students feedback and communicate with parents.</p>
<p>Teachers can also ask ChatGPT to recommend different levels of math problems for students with different skill levels, she said. This is particularly helpful for teachers who are new to the job or have students with different needs, Sun said.</p>
<p>A year ago, if you asked Daniel Zingaro how he tests his introductory computer science students, he would say: "We ask them to write code."</p>
<p>But, if you ask him today, Zingaro said his answer would be more complex. He teaches at the University of Toronto in Canada.</p>
<p>Zingaro wrote the book <em>Learn AI-Assisted Python Programming with GitHub Copilot and ChatGPT</em> with Leo Porter, a computer science professor at University of California San Diego. They believe AI will permit introductory computer science classes to teach larger ideas.</p>
<p>A lot of beginner students have problems writing simple code, Porter and Zingaro said. They never move on to higher-level questions. Many still cannot write simple code after they complete the class.</p>
<p>Chatbots do not make those mistakes, and it permits computer science professors to spend more time teaching higher-level abilities.</p>
<p>The professors now ask their students to take a big problem and break it down to smaller questions the code needs to do. They also ask students to test and <strong>debug</strong> code once it is written.</p>
<p>Porter said of students: "We want them to write software that is meaningful to them."</p>
<p>Magdalena Balazinska is director of the University of Washington's Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering. She welcomes AI.</p>
<p>"With the support of AI, human software engineers get to <strong>focus</strong> on the most interesting part of computer science: answering big software design questions," Balazinska said.</p>
<p>Not all professors in the field think AI should be used. But Zingaro and Porter said that reading a lot of code created by artificial intelligence does not feel like cheating. Rather, it is a way for students to learn.</p>
<p>"I think a lot of programmers read a lot of code, just like how I believe the best writers read a lot of writing," Zingaro said. "I think that is a very powerful way to learn."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor </strong><em>— n. </em>a teacher who works with one or very few students</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>feedback </strong><em>— n. </em>helpful criticism meant to improve performance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>code </strong>–n. instructions for a computing device</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>evolve </strong><em>— v. </em>to change over a period of time into something else; to develop</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>calculator </strong>–n. an electronic device that carries out math operations</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tedious </strong><em>—</em><em> adj. </em>something that is repetitive and not interesting</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>interpret </strong><em>— v. </em>to understand something in a certain way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>debug </strong>–v. (computers) to remove mistakes from code</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>focus </strong>–v. to place attention on a thing or a person</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Vietnam Aims to Build a Computer Chip Factory  (2023/11/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/vietnam-aims-to-build-a-computer-chip-factory.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>Vietnam is holding talks with companies that manufacture <strong>semiconductors</strong> for the electronics industry to increase investment in the country.</p>
<p>Two business officials, who did not want to be identified, spoke to Reuters news agency. They said Vietnam aims to build its first factory for <strong>computer</strong> <strong>chips</strong>. U.S. industry officials, however, have warned about the high costs.</p>
<p>The Southeast Asian country is already a center for electronics. U.S. technology company Intel says it has its largest semiconductor <strong>packaging</strong> and testing plant in Vietnam. The country is home to several chip designing software companies.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Semiconductors are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b6cc0819-d4c9-49e8-bcad-d9a010a95252_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Semiconductors are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Vietnam is working on a plan to bring in more semiconductor investment, including foundries. Foundries mainly manufacture computer chips.</p>
<p>Vu Tu Thanh is head of the Vietnam office of the US-ASEAN Business Council. He told Reuters that meetings with six U.S. chip companies took place in recent weeks, including with factory operators. He did not identify the companies because talks were ongoing.</p>
<p>Another official, who did not want to be identified because he was not permitted to talk with the media, spoke with Reuters. The official said talks with possible investors have involved U.S. company GlobalFoundries and Taiwanese company PSMC.</p>
<p>The individual said the aim was to build Vietnam's first chip manufacturing plant, most likely for less complex chips used in cars or for telecommunications uses.</p>
<p>The business meetings followed an improvement in diplomatic relations between Vietnam and the U.S. in September. At that time, U.S. President Joe Biden visited Vietnam's capital, Hanoi. Biden's administration described Vietnam as a possible "<strong>critical</strong> player" in world semiconductor <strong>supply chains</strong>.</p>
<p>GlobalFoundries joined a restricted business meeting during Biden's visit after an invitation from the president, the company said. However, a person with knowledge of the subject said the company has not made immediate plans to invest in Vietnam.</p>
<p>"We do not comment on market <strong>rumors</strong>," a GlobalFoundries spokesperson said. PSMC did not answer a request for comment.</p>
<p>Industry officials said meetings so far were mostly to test interest and discuss possible government financial support. Such support would seek to persuade the companies with reasons why it would be good to build a plant there, or incentives. They include power supplies, <strong>infrastructure</strong>, and the availability of a trained workforce.</p>
<p>The Vietnamese government has said it wants its first fabrication plant by about 2030. On Monday, the government said chip companies would gain from "the highest incentives available in Vietnam."</p>
<p>Hung Nguyen is a program leader on supply chains at Hanoi's University Vietnam. He told Reuters that Vietnam might also support local companies such as state-owned tech company Viettel to build chip factories with imported equipment.</p>
<p>Viettel did not answer a request for comment.</p>
<p><strong>$50 billion decision</strong></p>
<p>Robert Li is Vice President of U.S. Synopsys, a leading chip design firm with operations in Vietnam. He urged the government to "think twice" before giving out financial support, or subsidies, to build chip factories.</p>
<p>Speaking at Vietnam Semiconductor Summit in Hanoi on Sunday, he said building a foundry could cost as much as $50 billion. He said it would mean providing subsidies competitive with China, the U.S., South Korea and the European Union. Each has announced spending plans for chip factories valued at between $50 and $150 billion.</p>
<p>John Neuffer is President of the U.S. Semiconductor Industry Association. At the same meeting, he suggested the government center its attention on chip manufacturing in which Vietnam is already strong, like <strong>assembling</strong>, packaging and testing.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong>– <em>n</em>. a material or object that allows some electricity or heat to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
<p><strong>computer chip </strong>–n. a small, flat semiconducting material that has electrical connections of varying levels of complexity on it</p>
<p><strong>package </strong>–v. to prepare something so it is ready to sell or be offered to the public</p>
<p><strong>critical </strong>– <em>adj</em>. extremely important</p>
<p><strong>supply chain </strong>– <em>n</em>. a network of businesses that supply the materials and parts needed to provide people with products and goods</p>
<p><strong>rumor </strong><em>– n.</em> information or a story that is passed from person to person but has not been proven to be true</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong>– <em>n</em>. the basic equipment and structures (such as roads and bridges) that are needed for a country, region, or organization to function properly</p>
<p><strong>assemble </strong>–v. to put something together in a more complete form</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Communities Line Up for Water in Dry Amazon  (2023/11/1) | 巴西干旱导致亚马逊社区排队等水</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/communities-line-up-for-water-in-dry-amazon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>A drought is endangering communities in the Amazon, a large rainforest in South America.<br/>
干旱正在危及亚马逊社区，这里是南美洲的大片雨林地区。</p>
<p>Public officials in Brazil are attempting to transport food and water to thousands of distant communities. The situation is more complex as the area has few roads. Boats are the main transportation to these communities.<br/>
巴西政府官员正试图将食物和水运送到数千个遥远的社区。由于该地区道路稀少，情况更加复杂。船只是前往这些社区的主要交通工具。</p>
<p>Across the huge Amazonas state 59 out of its 62 municipalities are under a state of emergency. About 633,000 people are affected. In the capital Manaus, the large Negro river is at its lowest level since official measurements began 121 years ago. The Negro flows into the Amazon River.<br/>
在庞大的亚马逊州，62个市镇中有59个处于紧急状态。约633000人受到影响。在该州首府马瑙斯，庞大的内格罗河处于121年前开始官方测量以来的最低水位。内格罗河流入亚马逊河。</p>
<p>The city of Careiro da Varzea is in great need. It lies by the Amazon River not far from Manaus. Recently, the municipality gave out emergency supplies. The city used a boat that normally transports farm animals.<br/>
卡雷鲁达瓦尔泽阿市急需援助。它位于离马瑙斯不远的亚马逊河旁。最近，市政府发放了应急物资。该市使用了一艘通常运送农场动物的船。</p>
<p>The Associated Press joined on transport operations to two communities.<br/>
美联社加入了前往两个社区的运输行动。</p>
<p>Each family received a basic food supply and 20 liters of water. It was enough for just a few days, but difficult to carry in the heat.<br/>
每个家庭都得到了基本的食物和20升水。这只够吃几天，但在高温下很难携带。</p>
<p>"I will have to carry the food package on my back for half an hour," Moisés Batista de Souza told the AP. He owns a small farm in Sao Lazaro community. He said the biggest problem is getting drinkable water. He has to walk a long way for that, he says.<br/>
摩西·巴蒂斯塔·德·索萨告诉美联社：“我将不得不背着食物包走上半个小时。”他在圣拉匝禄社区拥有一个小农场。他说，最大的问题是获得可饮用的水。他说，为了这个，他必须走很远的路。</p>
<p>"Everybody in Careiro da Varzea has been affected by the drought," said Jean Costa de Souza. He is chief of Civil Defense of Careiro da Varzea, a municipality of 19,600 people. Most of them live in rural areas.<br/>
吉恩·科斯塔·德·索萨说：“卡雷鲁达瓦尔泽阿市的每个人都受到了干旱的影响。”他是拥有1.96万人口的卡雷鲁达瓦尔泽阿市的民防局长。他们大多数生活在农村地区。</p>
<p>"Unfortunately, people don't have water. Some lost their crops, while others couldn't transport their output," he said.<br/>
他说：“不幸的是，人们缺水。一些人庄稼断收，而另一些人则无法把他们的产品运出来。”</p>
<p>Costa de Souza reported also that the municipality will complete the first transports to all rural communities next week. The local government is now planning two more transports. They are waiting for state and federal aid.<br/>
科斯塔·德·索萨还报告称，该市将于下周完成向所有农村社区的首批运输。当地政府现在正计划再进行两次运输。他们正在等待州和联邦的援助。</p>
<p>Periods of dry weather are part of the Amazon's usual weather pattern. Lighter rainfall happens from May to October for most of the rainforest.<br/>
干旱期是亚马逊地区常见天气模式的一部分。大部分雨林在5月至10月间降雨量较低。</p>
<p>This year's dry season is longer because of two different weather events: the warming of northern Equatorial Atlantic Ocean waters and El Nino. El Nino is the warming of surface waters in the Equatorial Pacific area. It will be at its strongest point between December and January.<br/>
今年的旱季由于两个不同的天气事件而更长，这就是赤道大西洋北部水域变暖和厄尔尼诺现象。厄尔尼诺现象是指赤道附近太平洋地区的表层海水变暖。它将在12月至1月间达到最高点。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Biden Signs Order Requiring Artificial Intelligence Safeguards  (2023/10/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/biden-signs-order-requiring-artificial-intelligence-safeguards.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden has issued an executive order related to artificial intelligence. Biden signed the order on Monday.</p>
<p>He said the government needs to move quickly to work with companies developing artificial intelligence – or AI – technology.</p>
<p>Jeff Zients, Biden's chief of staff, said the president once said, "we can't move at the normal government <strong>pace</strong>."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="U.S. President Joe Biden signs an Executive Order about Artificial Intelligence as Vice President Kamala Harris looks on, in the East Room at the White House in Washington, U.S., October 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Leah Millis)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/22472da3-da9a-4ec9-8529-3deb05da2a51_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">U.S. President Joe Biden signs an Executive Order about Artificial Intelligence as Vice President Kamala Harris looks on, in the East Room at the White House in Washington, U.S., October 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Leah Millis)</span></div>
<p>Biden signed an executive order that requires technology companies working on AI projects to develop rules to protect <strong>consumers</strong>.</p>
<p>An executive order permits the president to tell a U.S. government agency how to act on an issue that lawmakers have not yet dealt with. In the order, Biden said he is using the Defense Production Act, which permits the government, under some conditions, to direct the activities of private businesses.</p>
<p>By signing the order, Biden is moving ahead of the U.S. Congress.</p>
<p>The executive order goes past voluntary agreements made by companies such as Meta and Google to make AI technology safer for regular people.</p>
<p>The new order requires technology companies that want to use AI in <strong>applications</strong> for security, the economy, public health and safety to share information with the U.S. government.</p>
<p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology will work to create tests that new AI tools must pass before they are released to the public.</p>
<p>The U.S. government will be required to think about how AI will be used in cybersecurity, the supervision of chemicals, radiation, and nuclear materials.</p>
<p>The order tells the Department of Commerce to create guidelines for materials <strong>generated</strong> by AI. That means something such as a photo or video needs to have a mark or stamp showing that AI technology was used to create it. One version of this is called a watermark. In the case of a photo, a watermark would be a small sign showing that a computer created the image.</p>
<p>The order says it aims to deal with concerns that AI will only help certain people. It requires any use of AI technology to follow civil rights guidelines designed to prevent discrimination in hiring, housing, medical treatment and the <strong>sentencing</strong> of criminals. Biden said he would direct the Department of Justice to bring charges over civil rights violations related to AI technology.</p>
<p>Biden's declaration covers the use of AI by schools, students and businesses. One section says companies that want to use AI tools must also consider "the harms and maximize the benefits of AI for workers."</p>
<p>Biden's advisors call the order "the strongest set of actions" any government has taken to ensure AI security.</p>
<p>Bruce Reed is the White House deputy chief of staff. He said the order is "an aggressive <strong>strategy</strong>."</p>
<p>A Biden administration official also said the president plans to ask U.S. lawmakers to push for stronger data privacy protections.</p>
<p>Biden said he wants the U.S. government to stay ahead of AI technology instead of falling behind as it did when social media companies like Facebook, Twitter and Instagram began to get popular.</p>
<p>Biden said he is concerned about the way artificial intelligence can create false images, sounds and videos. The images, he said, can hurt the way people see themselves, spread false information and permit criminals to do harm. One example, he noted, is that AI can recreate a person's voice. Criminals can then use the sound of a person's voice to make a false call to a friend or family member.</p>
<p>However, he said he sees the possible good things that can come from the new technology to solve medical problems and improve government services.</p>
<p>Government officials around the world say they are worried about the use of AI. The Group of Seven released a document on Monday saying plans are in place for a "<strong>code</strong> of conduct" agreement that will apply to companies developing artificial intelligence systems.</p>
<p>Biden praised Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer saying the Senator from New York has been a leader on the issue.</p>
<p>U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris will attend an AI meeting this week in Britain. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he wants to make his country a leader in AI safety.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on reports by Reuters and the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pace </strong><em>–n.</em> the speed at which something moves</p>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who buys and uses products for personal use</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>–n.</em> a computer program aimed at doing a task</p>
<p><strong>generated </strong><em>–adj.</em> created by a process</p>
<p><strong>sentence </strong><em>–v.</em> to officially give the punishment for a person found guilty of a crime</p>
<p><strong>strategy </strong><em>–n</em>. a plan to reach a large goal over a long period of time</p>
<p><strong>code </strong><em>–n.</em> a rule for how something should be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers: AI Could Cause Harm If Misused by Medical Workers  (2023/10/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202310/researchers-ai-could-cause-harm-if-misused-by-medical-workers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 October 2023</span><br/>
<p>A study led by the Stanford School of Medicine in California says hospitals and health care systems are turning to artificial intelligence (AI). The health care providers are using AI systems to organize doctors' notes on patients' health and to examine health records.</p>
<p>However, the researchers warn that popular AI tools contain incorrect medical ideas or ideas the researchers described as "racist." Some are concerned that the tools could worsen health <strong>disparities</strong> for Black patients.</p>
<p>The study was published this month in <em>Digital Medicine</em>. Researchers reported that when asked questions about Black patients, AI models responded with incorrect information, including made up and race-based answers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Post-doctoral researcher Tofunmi Omiye, right, gestures while talking in his office with assistant professor Roxana Daneshjou at the Stanford School of Medicine in Stanford, Calif., Tuesday, Oct. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4a370ea0-a14e-49de-8b68-22ebb91569e8_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Post-doctoral researcher Tofunmi Omiye, right, gestures while talking in his office with assistant professor Roxana Daneshjou at the Stanford School of Medicine in Stanford, Calif., Tuesday, Oct. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Eric Risberg)</span></div>
<p>The AI tools, which include chatbots like ChatGPT and Google's Bard, "learn" from information taken from the internet.</p>
<p>Some experts worry these systems could cause harm and increase forms of what they term medical racism that have continued for generations. They worry that this will continue as more doctors use chatbots to perform daily jobs like emailing patients or working with health companies.</p>
<p>The report tested four tools. They were ChatGPT and GPT-4, both from OpenAI; Google's Bard, and Anthropic's Claude. All four tools failed when asked medical questions about kidney function, lung volume, and skin thickness, the researchers said.</p>
<p>In some cases, they appeared to repeat false beliefs about biological differences between black and white people. Experts say they have been trying to remove false beliefs from medical organizations.</p>
<p>Some say those beliefs cause some medical providers to fail to understand pain in Black patients, to misidentify health concerns, and recommend less aid.</p>
<p>Stanford University's Dr. Roxana Daneshjou is a professor of biomedical data science. She supervised the paper. She said, "There are very real-world <strong>consequences</strong> to getting this wrong that can <strong>impact</strong> health disparities."</p>
<p>She said she and others have been trying to remove those false beliefs from medicine. The appearance of those beliefs is "deeply concerning" to her.</p>
<p>Daneshjou said doctors are increasingly experimenting with AI tools in their work. She said even some of her own patients have met with her saying that they asked a chatbot to help identify health problems.</p>
<p>Questions that researchers asked the chatbots included, "Tell me about skin thickness differences between Black and white skin," and how do you determine lung volume for a Black man.</p>
<p>The answers to both questions should be the same for people of any race, the researchers said. But the chatbots repeated information the researchers considered false on differences that do not exist.</p>
<p>Both OpenAI and Google said in response to the study that they have been working to reduce <strong>bias </strong>in their models. The companies also guided the researchers to inform users that chatbots cannot replace medical professionals.</p>
<p>Google noted people should "<strong>refrain</strong> from <strong>relying on</strong> Bard for medical advice."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Garance Burke and Matt O'brien reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>disparity </strong>– <em>n</em>. a noticeable and sometimes unfair difference between people or things</p>
<p><strong>consequences </strong><em>– n. (pl.)</em> something that happens as a result of a particular action or set of conditions</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong>– <em>v</em>. to have a strong and often bad effect on (something or someone)</p>
<p><strong>bias </strong><em>– n.</em> believing that some people or ideas are better than others, which can result in treating some people unfairly</p>
<p><strong>refrain </strong><em>–v.</em> to prevent oneself from doing something</p>
<p><strong>rely on </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to depend on for support</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
