<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Thousands More Chemicals in Plastics than Estimated  (2024/3/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/report-thousands-more-chemicals-in-plastics-than-estimated.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A recently released report from European scientists says there are 16,000 chemicals in plastic materials around the world.</p>
<p>The report said not enough is known about the safety of all those chemicals. They estimate that about 25 percent of these chemicals are possibly harmful to human health or the environment.</p>
<p>The Norwegian Research Council supported the creation of the report. It was released as officials are negotiating a United Nations treaty on plastic pollution. The U.N. estimates 400 million metric tons of plastic waste are produced every year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A soldier pauses while cleaning plastic and other debris on the shores of Montesinos beach, in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic July 19, 2018. (REUTERS/Ricardo Rojas/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8a71acb2-da56-4651-83df-00e5008d89cf_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A soldier pauses while cleaning plastic and other debris on the shores of Montesinos beach, in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic July 19, 2018. (REUTERS/Ricardo Rojas/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Jane Muncke helped write the report. She is with the Swiss nonprofit Food Packaging Forum. She said to deal with plastic pollution, people must look at the "full <strong>life cycle</strong> of plastics."</p>
<p>Researchers fear chemicals from plastics can spread into water and food.</p>
<p>Muncke said, "We're finding hundreds, if not thousands, of plastic chemicals in people now and some of them have been linked to <strong>adverse</strong> health outcomes."</p>
<p>Activists say such effects include possible harm to the reproductive system and <strong>cardiovascular</strong> disease.</p>
<p>Martin Wagner is the lead writer of the study. He is an environmental scientist at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology. He said researchers find hundreds, if not thousands, of chemicals in everyday products when they look for them.</p>
<p>Kimberly Wise White is with the American Chemistry Council, an industry group. She said the findings "ignore real-world <strong>exposures</strong>." She added the findings "paint an incomplete picture" for policy makers and the public. The plastics industry has said any worldwide treaty should support <strong>recycling</strong> and re-use of plastic.</p>
<p>But the writers of the recent report said that only dealing with plastic waste does not go far enough. They said there is a need for more information on chemicals in plastics, including recycled products. About 25 percent of the chemicals found lacked information on their chemical identity, the report said.</p>
<p>Wagner said the problem "is the chemical complexity of plastics." He is a leading member of the Scientists' Coalition for an Effective Plastics Treaty. It is an organization of scientists and experts seeking to advise the plastics treaty process.</p>
<p>Wagner said, "Often producers don't really know which kind of chemicals they have in their products and that comes from very complex value chains."</p>
<p>Six percent of the chemicals found in plastics are <strong>regulated</strong> internationally. Wagner said that without regulations, there is no reason for companies to identify what is in the plastics.</p>
<p>Last year, the United Nations Environment Program (UNEP) said there were around 13,000 chemicals in plastics.</p>
<p>Negotiations will continue in Ottawa, Canada. The aim is to finish a version of a treaty by December in the South Korean city of Busan.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gloria Dickie reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>life cycle </strong>– <em>n</em>. the series of changes that a product might go through form when it is made to when its use is over</p>
<p><strong>adverse </strong><em>– adj. </em>bad or unfavorable: not good</p>
<p><strong>cardiovascular </strong><em>– adj. </em>of or relating to the heart and blood vessels</p>
<p><strong>exposure </strong><em>– n.</em> the fact or condition of being affected by something or experiencing something</p>
<p><strong>recycle </strong><em>– v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
<p><strong>regulate </strong><em>– v.</em> to make rules or laws that control (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Approves Weight-loss Drug to Reduce Heart Disease Risk  (2024/3/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-approves-weight-loss-drug-to-reduce-heart-disease-risk.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the <em>Health &amp; Lifestyle</em> report.</p>
<p>In 2021, the U.S. food and drug agency approved the drug Wegovy for weight loss. Now, the Food and Drug Administration (or, FDA) says the drug can reduce the risk of death from stroke or heart attack in adults who have <strong>cardiovascular</strong> disease or are overweight.</p>
<p>The FDA approved a usage change requested by drugmaker Novo Nordisk. The change expands the use of semaglutide, the general or <strong>generic</strong> name of the drug. Wegovy is the brand name given by the company that sells it.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pictured here is an injection pen of Novo Nordisk's weight-loss drug Wegovy. (REUTERS/Victoria Klesty/illustrated archive photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-21a6-08dbaf0b74ac_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pictured here is an injection pen of Novo Nordisk's weight-loss drug Wegovy. (REUTERS/Victoria Klesty/illustrated archive photo)</span></div>
<p>The FDA based its decision on the results of a study that found Wegovy cut the risk of serious heart problems. The study also found that overweight patients with heart disease but not diabetes were 20 percent less likely to experience those problems. Researchers compared the results of patients who took the drug with those who took a <strong>placebo</strong>, or inactive injections.</p>
<p>Wegovy is the first medication approved to help prevent possibly life-threatening disease in overweight people, the agency said.</p>
<p>Dr. John Sharretts directs the FDA's Division of Diabetes, Lipid Disorders, and Obesity. He said, "Providing a treatment <strong>option</strong> that is proven to lower this cardiovascular risk" is good for public health.</p>
<p>Dr. Martha Gulati said the decision will change the way many heart patients are treated. Gulati is a cardiologist at Cedars-Sinai Medical Center in Los Angeles. The research also confirms that the new class of obesity medications are useful for improving health, not just losing weight.</p>
<p>"The hope is that insurers will start understanding that this is not a <strong>vanity </strong>drug," Gulati said. So-called vanity drugs are drugs that serve no medical purpose. Some researchers call them "lifestyle" drugs. Gulati estimates that nearly 70 percent of her heart patients could be <strong>eligible </strong>for treatment.</p>
<p>Wegovy is a high-<strong>dose</strong> version of the drug Ozempic. Ozempic is a diabetes treatment. The FDA approved the drug to cut the risk of serious heart problems in people with disease. The weight-loss drug costs about $1,300 a month.</p>
<p>Novo Nordisk has also asked European Union officials to expand the use of the drug for heart problems.</p>
<p>The FDA warned that Wegovy carries the risk of serious side effects. These included thyroid <strong>tumors</strong> and certain cancers. Other possible side effects can include low blood sugar. Organs in the body can be affected such as the pancreas, gallbladder, kidney, or eye. Another possible side effect is suicidal behavior or thinking.</p>
<p>The <strong>clinical trial, </strong>which resulted in the drug's approval, involved more than 17,600 people. About one third of them reported serious side effects. About 17 percent of the group that took Wegovy and about eight percent of those who received a placebo left the study because of reported side effects.</p>
<p>The new approval could mean that Medicare might increase coverage to the drug. Medicare is the federal health coverage program for retirement-aged citizens. U.S. law bars Medicare from covering drugs for weight loss alone. Recent estimates say nearly $3 billion was spent in 2021 covering Ozempic to treat diabetes.</p>
<p>Tricia Neuman is a Medicare expert at KFF, a nonprofit organization based in San Francisco that researches health policy. She said the change "... will open the door to allow more people on Medicare to gain access to Wegovy."</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the industry group America's Health Insurance Plans said private health coverage companies will consider the new guidance for Wegovy.</p>
<p>Drugmakers and activists for lower <strong>obesity</strong> rates have been pushing for expanded coverage. This includes legislation that would require Medicare to pay for the obesity drug. The cost of the drug needs to be balanced by reduced spending on medical care related to obesity and heart disease.</p>
<p>Another problem is a limited supply of the drug. The FDA said there has been a shortage for more than a year. Novo Nordisk officials said they are aiming to increase production.</p>
<p>For Gulati, the heart specialist, wider use cannot come soon enough.</p>
<p>"Everybody (is) waiting to get this medication," she said. "Lower the cost, do (not) be <strong>greedy </strong>and make sure the drug is available for use."</p>
<p>And that's the<em> Health &amp; Lifestyle</em> report. I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Jonel Aleccia</em> <em>reported this story for the Associate Press. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cardiovascular </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to the circulatory system including the heart</p>
<p><strong>generic </strong><em>–adj.</em> a class of product that is not sold under a brand name because its production and sale is no longer restricted by government patent protections</p>
<p><strong>placebo </strong><em>–n.</em> an amount of an inactive substance whose effect is compared to that of a drug that is being tested</p>
<p><strong>option </strong><em>–n.</em> a choice among several that can be made</p>
<p><strong>vanity </strong><em>–n.</em> the feeling of mainly paying attention to your own appearance, feelings and comfort</p>
<p><strong>dose </strong><em>–n.</em> the amount of a medicine needed to be effective</p>
<p><strong>tumor </strong><em>–n.</em> an abnormal growth that can be linked to cancer</p>
<p><strong>eligible </strong><em>–adj.</em> able to do or to receive a treatment<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>clinical trial </strong><em>–n.</em> a medical test done on real patients</p>
<p><strong>obesity </strong><em>–n.</em> the condition of being severely overweight</p>
<p><strong>greedy </strong><em>–adj.</em> wanting more for yourself than is fair or right</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Vernal Equinox Marks Arrival of Spring  (2024/3/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/vernal-equinox-marks-arrival-of-spring.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>This year, the vernal equinox officially arrives on Tuesday, March 19 at 11:06 pm in Washington, D.C. That is 3:06 UTC on Wednesday, March 20. At that time, the sun will be exactly above the Earth's equator.</p>
<p>The word vernal comes from the Latin word <em>vernalis</em>, meaning "of the spring." And equinox comes from the Latin words <em>aequus</em>, meaning equal, and <em>nox</em>, meaning night. The day has 12 hours of daylight and 12 hours of nighttime.</p>
<p>And in the Northern Hemisphere, the day marks the beginning of spring.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People take photographs of cherry blossom trees that have begun to bloom, Monday, March 20, 2023, along the tidal basin in Washington, on the first day of the National Cherry Blossom Festival. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ba8d-08db2abb984e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People take photographs of cherry blossom trees that have begun to bloom, Monday, March 20, 2023, along the tidal basin in Washington, on the first day of the National Cherry Blossom Festival. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)</span></div>
<p>On this day, people living in colder areas of the Northern Hemisphere hope they can put away their winter clothes. They also may soon start planting flowers and vegetables in a garden.</p>
<p>Here in Washington, D.C., March 20 also marks the first day of the National Cherry Blossom Festival. Each year, people from around the world come to see the beautiful pink and white blossoms on the thousands of flowering cherry trees. For Washingtonians, the cherry blossoms are a welcome sign that spring has arrived.</p>
<p>In ancient times, some cultures built structures to signal the start of spring. Around the year 1000 A.D., for example, the Maya built a <strong>pyramid </strong>in what is now Mexico's Yucatan. It sits within an ancient city called Chichen Itza.</p>
<p>On the spring equinox, the sunlight hits in a way that makes the structure look like a snake. The Maya called this day "the return of the Sun <strong>serpent</strong>."</p>
<p>Today, cultures worldwide have their own ways of identifying and celebrating the arrival of spring.</p>
<p><strong>Cherry blossoms</strong></p>
<p>In Japan, spring is marked with a huge cherry blossom festival, known as <em>hanami.</em> The tradition dates back more than a thousand years. People gather under the <strong>blooming </strong>trees to eat, drink tea, celebrate and enjoy the cherry blossoms, known as <em>sakura</em> in Japanese. Artists and poets celebrate the short-lived blooms as a symbol of beauty.</p>
<p>In 1912, Japan gave 3,000 cherry trees to the U.S. capital city of Washington, D.C. The gift was to honor the lasting friendship between the United States and Japan. </p>
<p><strong>Nowruz</strong></p>
<p>For many countries in Central Asia and the Middle East, the vernal equinox also marks the beginning of a new year. The celebration is called Nowruz. The words "now" and "ruz" mean "new day" in Farsi.</p>
<p>Countries along the ancient Silk Road trading path, including Afghanistan, Iran, Turkey, Uzbekistan, and other Central Asian nations, celebrate Nowruz.</p>
<p>In the past, Iran was the only country where Nowruz was an official holiday. But after countries gained their independence following the fall of the Soviet Union, many made Nowruz a national holiday, as well.</p>
<p>During Nowruz, people visit family members and friends and exchange gifts. Iranian families set up a "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nowruz-in-america/3774295.html" target="_blank">haft seen</a>" <strong>display</strong> of seven special items that represent spring and new beginnings.</p>
<p>In Uzbekistan and other places in Central Asia, people watch wrestling events, horse races and a special horseback game called, in Uzbek, <em>Kopkari</em>. In this game, two teams of players on horseback try to get the body of a headless goat into a goal. A similar game is called <em>buzkashi </em>in Afghanistan and <em>oghlak tartish </em>in Kyrgyzstan and Uyghur-speaking areas.</p>
<p><strong>Holi festival</strong></p>
<p>Many in India and Nepal mark the arrival of spring with the Holi festival, known also as the festival of colors or the festival of love.</p>
<p>This year, Holi will take place on March 25.</p>
<p>People celebrate the festival by covering each other in -- you guessed it -- colors! Children especially enjoy the festival, as they get to throw colored <strong>powder</strong> and water-filled balloons at others.</p>
<p>Some say the festival comes from a story of the burning of the devil Holika. It represents the victory of good over evil, or the arrival of spring after a long, dark winter.</p>
<p>Others say the celebration was inspired by the story of two young lovers with different skin colors. Krishna, who has blue skin, was in love with Radha. So, he colored Radha with paint leading to the modern-day colorful festival of love.</p>
<p><strong>Las Fallas</strong></p>
<p>People in Valencia, Spain, have their spring celebration called <em>Las Fallas</em>. It is a wild street festival involving fire.</p>
<p>The festival centers on the creation – and burning – of huge colorful <strong>statues</strong> made of wood, paper and plastic. The statues are meant to look like real people. Valencian communities and organizations work all year to create these structures and place them throughout the city, with fireworks inside.</p>
<p><em>Las Fallas </em>celebrations began on March 15, with events like bullfights, parades, and cooking and beauty competitions. Then, at midnight on March 19, the city turns off all its streetlights and the statues<em> </em>are set on fire.</p>
<p>This marks the end of the festival and the beginning of spring.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson. And I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English. Ashley Thompson was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>What do people do to mark the beginning of spring where you live? Let us know! Write to us in the Comments Section or on 51VOA.COM. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>serpent </strong>- n. a large snake</p>
<p><strong>pyramid </strong>- n. a very large structure built especially in ancient Egypt that has a square base and four triangular sides which form a point at the top</p>
<p><strong>blooming </strong>- adj. producing flowers</p>
<p><strong>display </strong>- n. an arrangement of objects intended to decorate or inform people about something</p>
<p><strong>powder </strong>- n. a dry substance made up of very tiny pieces of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Secrets of US Presidential Diaries  (2024/3/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/secrets-of-us-presidential-diaries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 March 2024</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">One early morning in Washington, D.C., many years ago, the president of the United States took off his clothes and jumped into the Potomac river. Moments later, he saw a dead man float to the surface.</p>
<p>The president was John Quincy Adams, the nation's sixth leader. And we know about the incident because he wrote about it in his diary.</p>
<p>A diary is a daily record of events of one's life, especially of personal experiences and thoughts.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Archivist of the U.S John Carlin stands behind a 1947 Harry Truman presidential diary, July 10, 2003, at the National Archives in Washington. Presidents from George Washington to Joe Biden have kept presidential diaries. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d363-08dc476d8301_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Archivist of the U.S John Carlin stands behind a 1947 Harry Truman presidential diary, July 10, 2003, at the National Archives in Washington. Presidents from George Washington to Joe Biden have kept presidential diaries. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer, File)</span></div>
<p>American presidents from George Washington to Joe Biden, have been known to keep diaries. The men wrote about everyday experiences and thoughts. They also wrote about important decisions they made and the reasoning behind such decisions.</p>
<p>Adams called his diary his "second <strong>conscience</strong>." Barack Obama said his diary is a process of turning thoughts into writing that "makes you ask <strong>tougher</strong> questions."</p>
<p>Jimmy Carter left the White House with more than 5,000 pages of such notes. He said, "I seldom exercised any restraint on what I <strong>dictated</strong>."</p>
<p>Dwight Eisenhower wrote about disputes within a scientific advisory group and some of its proposals about Soviet atomic bombs. And Donald Trump's daily writing was seen by the public on Twitter, now known as X.</p>
<p><strong>Secrets in diaries</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes, the presidential diaries contain secrets that they should not.</p>
<p>Robert Hur was the special <strong>counsel</strong> who investigated Biden's handling of <strong>classified</strong> information after his time serving as vice president. He reported that Biden's diary contained notes from intelligence briefings, including some classified as "top secret."</p>
<p>The 1978 Presidential Records Act says that the U.S. government has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/44/2202" target="_blank">"complete ownership, possession, and control"</a> of all presidential and vice presidential records. The act does not cover personal diaries. But classified information is not supposed to be in those.</p>
<p>Hur noted in his report that both Jimmy Carter and George H.W. Bush had classified information in their diaries.</p>
<p>Ronald Reagan left the White House in 1989. He took with him eight years of handwritten diaries, the report says, "which he appears to have kept at his California home even though they contained Top Secret information."</p>
<p>Hur wrote, "Historically, after leaving office, many former presidents and vice presidents have knowingly taken home sensitive materials related to national security from their administrations without being charged with crimes."</p>
<p>Both Biden and former President Donald Trump have been investigated for their handling of classified information. But only Trump is being accused of resisting demands to return them.</p>
<p><strong>Values of diaries</strong></p>
<p>Students of history have always been interested in presidential diaries.</p>
<p>They "provide <strong>unique</strong> windows into the presidency, helping us better understand how policy is made and power is used," said Marc Selverstone, director of Presidential Studies at the University of Virginia's Miller Center.</p>
<p>As for John Quincy Adams, all 15,000 pages of his diaries written over 68 years are available to the public. The Massachusetts Historical Society, which publishes them online, said his diaries represent "the longest continuous record of any American of the time."</p>
<p>On <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.masshist.org/publications/jqadiaries/index.php/document/jqadiaries-v49-1825-07-22-p865" target="_blank">July 22, 1825</a>, Adams wrote, "I <strong>stripped</strong> and went in to the river; I had been not more than ten minutes swimming when the drag boat started, and they were not five minutes from the shore when the body floated immediately opposite the rock; less than one hundred yards from the <strong>shore</strong>."</p>
<p>The entry noted the death of Mr. Shoemaker, a post office worker seen swimming about in the water earlier.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Calvin Woodward reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conscience</strong> – <em>n. </em>knowledge of right and wrong and a feeling one should do what is right</p>
<p><strong>tough</strong> – <em>adj</em>. difficult to accomplish, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/resolve#h1">resolve</a>, endure, or deal with</p>
<p><strong>dictate</strong> – <em>v. </em>to speak or read for a person to transcribe or for a machine to record</p>
<p><strong>counsel</strong> – <em>n. </em>a lawyer engaged in the trial or management of a case in court</p>
<p><strong>classified</strong> – <em>adj. </em><strong> </strong>withheld from general circulation for reasons of national security</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong> – <em>adj</em>. being the only one of its kind</p>
<p><strong>strip </strong>– <em>v. </em>to remove clothing, covering, or surface matter from</p>
<p><strong>shore </strong>– <em>n. </em>land along a body of water</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Documents Headaches Experienced by Astronauts in Space  (2024/3/18) | 宇航员在太空中出现头痛</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/study-documents-headaches-experienced-by-astronauts-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Research in the growing field of space medicine has identified many ways in which zero-gravity and other conditions can affect the human body. Now, a new study finds that astronauts are more likely to experience headaches in space than previously known.<br/>
太空医学领域的研究已经确定了零重力和其他条件对人体产生影响的多种方式。现在，一项新的研究发现，宇航员在太空中比以前更容易出现头痛。</p>
<p>The study involved 24 astronauts from the U.S., European and Japanese space agencies. They all traveled aboard the International Space Station for up to 26 weeks. All but two of them reported experiencing headaches in space.<br/>
这项研究涉及来自美国、欧洲和日本航天机构的24名宇航员。他们都在国际空间站上旅行了长达26周。除两人外，其他人都报告在太空中出现头痛。</p>
<p>Headaches struck a larger number of astronauts than the scientists had expected. The headaches continued even after the crew had been in space long enough for the body to adjust. The process takes place in the first two weeks in space.<br/>
头痛困扰的宇航员人数超过了科学家们的预期。即使乘员在太空中停留了足够让身体适应的时间，头痛仍在继续。这个过程发生在太空的前两周。</p>
<p>The headaches during the early period often presented similarly to migraines. Those experienced later in space travel presented more like a tension headache, the study found.<br/>
早期的头痛通常与偏头痛相似。研究发现，太空旅行者后期经历的更像是一种紧张性的头痛。</p>
<p>Neurologist WPJ van Oosterhout of Zaans Medical Center and the Leiden University Medical Center in the Netherlands was lead author of the study. He said the research suggests different processes "are involved for the early headache episodes - the first one to two weeks in space - versus later headache episodes."<br/>
荷兰Zaans医学中心和莱顿大学医学中心的神经学家WPJ·范·奥斯特霍特是这项研究的主要作者。他说，研究表明，“在太空前一到两周出现的早期头痛发作与后期头痛发作涉及不同的过程。”</p>
<p>The study was published this week in the journal Neurology.<br/>
这项研究发表在本周的《神经病学》杂志上。</p>
<p>"In the first week, the body has to adapt to the lack of gravity, known as space adaptation syndrome. This phenomenon is similar to motion sickness, and can cause nausea, vomiting and dizziness, and headaches," Van Oosterhout said. "The later headaches could result from ... more fluid accumulating in the upper part of the body and head...."<br/>
范·奥斯特霍特说：“在第一周，身体必须适应重力不足，这被称为空间适应综合征。这种现象类似于晕动病，会导致恶心、呕吐、头晕和头痛。后来的头痛可能是由于更多液体积聚在身体上部和头部。”</p>
<p>Migraines experienced on Earth are often throbbing, and last four to seven hours, along with symptoms like nausea, vomiting and sensitivity to light and sound, Van Oosterhout said. Tension headaches on Earth usually are a dull pain felt over the whole head, he said.<br/>
范·奥斯特霍特说，地球上经历的偏头痛通常是有规律性抽痛，它会持续四到七个小时，伴有恶心、呕吐、对光和声音敏感等症状。他说，紧张性头痛在地球上通常是一种感觉到整个头部的隐隐作痛。</p>
<p>The astronauts, 23 men and one woman, had an average age of about 47. They visited the International Space Station for missions that took place from November 2011 to June 2018. A total of 378 headaches were reported by 22 of the 24 astronauts during a total of 3,596 days in orbit. None of the 24 reported headaches in the three months after returning to Earth. None had ever had migraines before their time in space and none had a history of usual headache attacks.<br/>
这些包括23男1女的宇航员的平均年龄约47岁。2011年11月至2018年6月，他们访问了国际空间站执行任务。24名宇航员中的22人在总共3596天的轨道任务中总共报告了378次头痛。这24人在返回地球后的三个月内都没有报告头痛。在进入太空之前，没有人患过偏头痛，也没有人有常见的头痛发作史。</p>
<p>Documented effects of space travel include bone and muscle weakening, or atrophy, changes in the brain, cardiovascular system and immune system. Astronauts have also experienced effects on the inner ear and a condition involving the eyes. The risk of cancer from high radiation levels in space is another concern.<br/>
有文献记载的太空旅行的影响包括骨骼和肌肉减弱或萎缩、大脑、心血管系统和免疫系统的变化。宇航员还经历了内耳和眼睛的影响。太空中高辐射水平导致癌症的风险是另一个令人担忧的问题。</p>
<p>Experts are unsure how much of a barrier these effects might have on human space travel over long periods, like trips to Mars or beyond.<br/>
专家们不确定这些影响对人类长期太空旅行（如火星或更远的地方）可能会产生多大的影响。</p>
<p>"The honest answer is that we don't know the effects of long-duration space travel - possibly years - on the human body," Van Oosterhout said, adding, this "is a clear task for the field of space medicine."<br/>
范·奥斯特霍特说：“老实说，我们不知道可能几年的长时间太空旅行对人体的影响。”他补充道，这“是太空医学领域的一项明确任务。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>North America Prepares for 2024 Total Solar Eclipse  (2024/3/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/north-america-prepares-for-2024-total-solar-eclipse.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A total solar eclipse will take place in North America on April 8. Millions of people will be able to fully experience the event, which is expected to darken the sky for more than four minutes.</p>
<p>A total solar eclipse happens when the sun, moon and Earth perfectly line up. This results in sunlight being blocked. The quality of the observations will depend on weather and the position where people watch the eclipse from.</p>
<p>The path of totality – meaning places where people will see a total blockage of the sun – will stretch across areas of Mexico, the United States and Canada. People in North America who are outside of this path will still be able to see a partial eclipse.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The progression of a total solar eclipse is seen with the moon passing in front of the sun above Siem Reap in northwestern Cambodia, on Tuesday, Oct. 24, 1995. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7e80-08dc446b2d55_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The progression of a total solar eclipse is seen with the moon passing in front of the sun above Siem Reap in northwestern Cambodia, on Tuesday, Oct. 24, 1995. (AP Photo/Richard Vogel, File)</span></div>
<p>The American space agency NASA says the eclipse will begin over the South Pacific and reach Mexico's Pacific coast at around 11:07 a.m. Pacific Time. It will then enter the United States in Texas.</p>
<p>The path of totality will then pass through a series of states before heading out from the northernmost state of Maine. The eclipse will enter Canada in Ontario and move across the nation before leaving northeastern Canada into the Atlantic.</p>
<p>An estimated 44 million people live inside the 185-kilometer-wide path of totality, with about 32 million in the U.S.</p>
<p>The eclipse is expected to last four minutes and 28 seconds, about twice as long as the one that darkened skies in 2017. The U.S. is not set to see another coast-to-coast total solar eclipse until 2045.</p>
<p>NASA's eclipse watch program is led by Kelly Korreck. She told The Associated Press the eclipse will permit many people to experience the "wonder of the universe without going very far."</p>
<p>People outside the path of totality will still be able to see a partial eclipse. The farther these people are from the path, the less the sun will be covered. For example, experts say Americans farthest from this path – such as in the northwestern cities of Seattle and Portland – will see about one-third of the sun blocked.</p>
<p>As was the case with past eclipse events, people are being warned about the dangers of looking directly at the sun during the event. Since normal sunglasses are not considered effective protection, special eclipse glasses are suggested for eclipse watchers. The glasses should only be removed during moments when the sun's face is covered during complete totality.</p>
<p>A total solar eclipse develops in several different parts, or stages. The event starts with a partial eclipse as the moon begins to pass between Earth and the sun. During this stage, a partial blockage leaves the sun looking a bit like a banana.</p>
<p>During the next stage, called Baily's Beads, points of light from the sun shine around the moon's edges. This effect is produced by the moon's differing <strong>landscapes</strong>. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://science.nasa.gov/eclipses/future-eclipses/eclipse-2024/what-to-expect/">notes</a> this stage is quite short and "may not last long enough to be <strong>noticeable</strong> to all observers of the total solar eclipse."</p>
<p>In the Diamond Ring stage, a single bright spot appears along the lunar edge even as the sun's atmosphere leaves a ring of light around the moon. This effect – which comes right before totality – looks similar to a diamond ring.</p>
<p>After totality, the other stages then repeat as the moon keeps moving along its path until the end of the eclipse.</p>
<p>Total solar eclipses generally happen every few years, often in the middle of nowhere like the South Pacific or Antarctic. The next total solar eclipse will arrive in 2026. It will be observable along the northern edges of Greenland, Iceland and Spain.</p>
<p>North America will not experience totality again until 2033, with that one only passing over Alaska. It will happen next in 2044, with totality limited to Western Canada and the U.S. states of Montana and North Dakota.</p>
<p>The next coast-to-coast total solar eclipse in the U.S. is expected to happen in 2045. NASA says that one will stretch from Northern California to Cape Canaveral, Florida.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>landscape </strong><em>– n. </em>all visible features of an area of land</p>
<p><strong>notice </strong><em>– v. </em>the act of observing or paying attention to something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Bird Flu Spread Increasing, Killing South American Wildlife  (2024/3/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/bird-flu-spread-increasing-killing-south-american-wildlife.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The deadly H5N1 bird flu virus is spreading more aggressively than ever before since its arrival in South America in 2022. It is killing wild birds and marine mammals on the continent.</p>
<p>Reuters recently spoke to eight experts in bird flu science. All said the current spread raises the risk of the virus becoming a bigger threat to humans.</p>
<p>The more immediate concern is that the disease, which once affected mostly birdlife, appears to be spreading between mammals.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A dead pig and a dead penguin lie on the Atlantic Ocean's coast, during a Bird Flu outbreak, in Sao Jose do Norte, in the State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Diego Vara/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6e74-08dc445d2d6c_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A dead pig and a dead penguin lie on the Atlantic Ocean's coast, during a Bird Flu outbreak, in Sao Jose do Norte, in the State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Diego Vara/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>The disease has already killed several dolphins in Chile and Peru. It has also killed about 50,000 seals and sea lions along the coasts and at least half a million birds across South America.</p>
<p>Scientists have not yet tested infections in living animals to confirm mammal-to-mammal passage of the virus. But they believe it is very likely.</p>
<p>"It's almost <strong>certainly</strong> happened," said Richard Webby. He is a virologist at St. Jude's Children's Research Hospital in Memphis, Tennessee. "It's pretty hard to explain some of these large infections and die off without having mammal-to-mammal spread."</p>
<p>The same version of the virus has appeared in many bird species. Among them are migrating species, scientists told Reuters.</p>
<p>As climate change continues, animals are forced to move into new territories, often mixing with animals -- and viruses -- that are new to them.</p>
<p>"It's a matter of time before you will <strong>detect</strong> the first South American strain in North America," said Alonzo Alfaro-Nunez, a viral ecologist at the University of Copenhagen in Denmark.</p>
<p><strong>Human risk</strong></p>
<p>The growing concern led the intergovernmental Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) to gather health experts and officials for a meeting this week in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</p>
<p>The group plans to launch the world's first <strong>regional</strong> program to supervise bird flu spread. The program will run observation and <strong>response</strong> efforts, a PAHO official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Since the virus was first detected in Colombia in October 2022, there have been two known cases in humans on the continent. One was in Ecuador. The other was in Chile. Birds passed the virus in each case.</p>
<p>The patients survived. But often, H5N1 kills. About 60 percent of human cases of the virus end in death.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization is unlikely to raise the H5N1 risk level for humans from the current "low" right now. The experts would require evidence of human-to-human transmission or signs of viral changes that would target humans, experts said.</p>
<p>Several drugmakers have said they are developing bird flu vaccines for humans.</p>
<p>"We're seeing (the virus) do... little <strong>evolutionary</strong> steps that are on the long-term moving towards a <strong>potential</strong> human infection," said Ralph Vanstreels. He is a researcher at the University of California, Davis. He is studying South American variants of H5N1.</p>
<p><strong>Regional response</strong></p>
<p>With health officials and experts meeting in Rio this week, Latin American countries will be pressured to increase disease surveillance in the wild.</p>
<p>The region's data is lacking and limited resources have left scientists struggling to understand how the disease is spreading in the wild. Scientists expect the number of cases is probably much higher than reported. Some cases are not getting laboratory testing.</p>
<p>Bolivia, for example, did not register a case in the wild last year. But the disease has been reported in surrounding countries, said Manuel Jose Sanchez Vazquez, a disease expert for PAHO's animal health center.</p>
<p>Overseeing<strong> </strong>the disease response can also be complex, Sanchez noted. Public health officials deal with threats to humans. Agricultural experts and <strong>veterinarians</strong> deal with health threats to farm animals, including birds, cows and pigs. But for wild animal health, care and supervision is provided mostly by environmental officials.</p>
<p>The new regional commission is expected to be announced on Thursday. The group would aim to set methods for observing, treating and reporting cases among government agencies. It could also help in sharing laboratory resources.</p>
<p>"We are worried and we are <strong>vigilant</strong>," Sanchez said. "The more <strong>adaptation</strong> of the virus to mammals, the more likely it is that transmission to humans could happen."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>detect </strong><em>— v. </em><strong> </strong>to discover or determine the existence, presence, or fact of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>region </strong><em>— n. </em>an administrative area, division, or district</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>response </strong><em>— n. </em><strong> </strong>an act or instance of replying; answer</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>evolution </strong><em>— n. </em>a process of change in a certain direction</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>potential </strong><em>— adj. </em>existing in possibility <strong>: </strong>capable of development into actuality</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vigilant </strong><em>— adj. </em>alert to signs of danger</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adaptation </strong><em>— n. </em>modification of an organism or its parts that makes it more fit for existence under the conditions of its environment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>veterinarian </strong><em>— n. </em>a medical doctor of animals</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Lessons From Flowers  (2024/3/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/lessons-from-flowers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note:</strong> This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>My name is Nadiia Kyba. I am from Cherkasy. And this is my essay.</p>
<p>They come in white, red, orange, brown, and yellow. They are the flowers in the gardens of Ukraine. And they are the lessons that I learned from childhood.</p><p><img alt="FILE - A woman poses for a picture at a flower exhibition in Kyiv, Ukraine, August 21, 2015. (REUTERS/Gleb Garanich)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/352B5EC8-B177-4CCF-8AD0-5B32B8C7B41C_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman poses for a picture at a flower exhibition in Kyiv, Ukraine, August 21, 2015. (REUTERS/Gleb Garanich)</span></p>
<p>As a child, I remember plenty of snowdrops in my grandmother's garden. The fragile petals managed to blossom despite a heavy snowstorm. I wanted to bring the white flowers into the house. But I was not permitted to step on them or to pick them. My parents said, "We must all cherish the snowdrops. There is no use in withered flowers."</p>
<p>Little did I know back then that snowdrops were very rare, and they almost disappeared. I did not know it was more important to have them in the garden. Luckily, there were people who knew better. They created a reserve in Kholodnyi Yar to protect and care for those beautiful white flowers. They taught me to care for and protect even the smallest things.</p>
<p>I lived in a village where children always helped to take care of its flowerbeds. At school, our class weeded beds of roses nearby. It was great fun to be outdoors in the fresh air. Moreover, the roses looked splendid. They smelled sweet in the sun, and girls used to pin them in their hair. Even now, when I close my eyes, I can still smell the beautiful roses.</p>
<p>The first time I worked in a bed of roses, I prickled my hand with small but sharp thorns. I did not know that such beauty could hurt you. I understood then that it took much pain to gain something so beautiful.</p>
<p>That was one of the most important lessons in my life. If I want something, I must be ready to work hard for it. The roses taught me to be persistent and hardy. And the roses showed me "no pain, no gain."</p>
<p>What comes to your mind when you hear the word "garden"?</p>
<p>I see marigolds. I see orange, brown, and yellow marigolds. There are so many marigolds in the gardens of Ukrainians, that it is hard not to notice them. People sing songs about marigolds. They are everywhere, under the apple trees, in the strawberries, near the fences, in the flowerbeds, and even on the roads.</p>
<p>I used to plant marigolds with my mother. We gathered the seeds in autumn. Then we shared and exchanged the seeds with our friends or neighbors. I have warm memories of my family sitting on the bench in front of the marigold beds. My father told stories. And we chatted and joked.</p>
<p>Marigolds remind me of home and the best moments of our lives. They taught me to share and communicate, to be a daughter and a friend.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>_____________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the writer</h2>
<p>Born to a big family in the small village of Dumantsi, Nadiia Kyba has lived all her life in the Cherkasy region of Ukraine. She began her teaching career in 2013 and has been working in the Khutory school since 2020.</p>
<p>Seeing her patience and thoughtfulness with children, her father inspired her to be a teacher. As a teacher, Nadiia believes in the power of failure and mistakes. She teaches her students to learn from them as they are opportunities to improve and grow. She believes this learning mindset is vital for their future lives.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI Adding to Threat of Election Disinformation Worldwide  (2024/3/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/ai-adding-to-threat-of-election-disinformation-worldwide.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is adding to the threat of election disinformation worldwide.</p>
<p>The technology makes it easy for anyone with a smartphone and an imagination to create <strong>fake </strong>– but convincing – content aimed at fooling voters.</p>
<p>Just a few years ago, fake photos, videos or audio required teams of people with time, skill and money. Now, free and low-cost generative artificial intelligence services from companies like Google and OpenAI permit people to create high-quality "deepfakes" with just a simple text entry.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An advertising banner with a slogan about AI is fixed at a building at the Davos Promenade, alongside the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Markus Schreiber, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1395462a-a385-4366-8108-5652f0125761_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An advertising banner with a slogan about AI is fixed at a building at the Davos Promenade, alongside the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Markus Schreiber, File)</span></div>
<p><strong>Expanding threats</strong></p>
<p>A wave of AI deepfakes tied to elections in Europe and Asia has already appeared on social media for months. It served as a warning for more than 50 countries having elections this year.</p>
<p>Some recent examples of AI deepfakes include:</p>
<p>— A video of Moldova's pro-Western president throwing her support behind a political party friendly to Russia.</p>
<p>— Audio of Slovakia's liberal party leader discussing changing ballots and raising the price of beer.</p>
<p>— A video of an opposition lawmaker in Bangladesh — a conservative Muslim majority nation — wearing a <strong>bikini</strong>.</p>
<p>The question is no longer whether AI deepfakes could affect elections, but how influential they will be, said Henry Ajder, who runs a business advisory company called Latent Space Advisory in Britain.</p>
<p>"You don't need to look far to see some people ... being clearly confused as to whether something is real or not," Ajder said.</p>
<p><strong>Challenge to democracy</strong></p>
<p>As the U.S. presidential race comes closer, Christopher Wray, the director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation issued a warning about the growing threat of generative AI. He said the technology makes it easy for foreign groups to attempt to have a bad influence on elections.</p>
<p>With AI deepfakes, a candidate's image can be made much worse or much better. Voters can be moved toward or away from candidates — or even to avoid the polls altogether. But perhaps the greatest threat to democracy, experts say, is that the growth of AI deepfakes could hurt the public's trust in what they see and hear.</p>
<p>The complexity of the technology makes it hard to find out who is behind AI deepfakes. Experts say governments and companies are not yet capable of stopping the problem.</p>
<p>The world's biggest tech companies recently — and voluntarily — signed an agreement to prevent AI tools from disrupting elections. For example, the company that owns Instagram and Facebook has said it will start <strong>labeling</strong> deepfakes that appear on its services.</p>
<p>But deepfakes are harder to limit on apps like Telegram, which did not sign the voluntary agreement. Telegram uses <strong>encrypted </strong>messages that can be difficult to uncover.</p>
<p><strong>Concerns about efforts to limit AI</strong></p>
<p>Some experts worry that efforts to limit AI deepfakes could lead to unplanned results.</p>
<p>Tim Harper is an expert at the Center for Democracy and Technology in Washington, DC. He said sometimes well-meaning governments or companies might crush the "very thin" line between political commentary and an "<strong>illegitimate </strong>attempt to<strong> smear </strong>a candidate."</p>
<p>Major generative AI services have rules to limit political disinformation. But experts say it is too easy to defeat the restrictions or use other services.</p>
<p>AI software is not the only threat.</p>
<p>Candidates themselves could try to fool voters by claiming events that show them in bad situations were manufactured by AI.</p>
<p>Lisa Reppell is a researcher at the International Foundation for Electoral Systems in Arlington, Virginia.</p>
<p>She said, "A world in which everything is suspect — and so everyone gets to choose what they believe — is also a world that's really challenging for...democracy."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Ali Swenson and Kelvin Chan reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>fake </strong>– n. not true or real</p>
<p><strong>bikini </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>a piece of clothing in two parts that a woman wears for swimming</p>
<p><strong>label </strong><em>-- v. </em>to use a word or phrase that describes or identifies something or someone</p>
<p><strong>encrypted -</strong><em>- v.</em><strong> </strong>to change (information) from one form to another</p>
<p><strong>illegitimate </strong><em>-- adj. </em> not allowed according to rules or laws</p>
<p><strong>smear </strong><em>-- v.</em><strong> </strong> to make untrue statements about someone</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>When Do You 'Go Against the Grain'?  (2024/3/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/when-do-you-go-against-the-grain.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Have you ever looked closely at a piece of wood? If you have, you might have noticed its beautiful grain.</p>
<p>When talking about wood, grain describes the appearance of cell fibers in the wood. A wood's grain is important when choosing the right sort of wood for a project. Different kinds of wood have different grains, which affect their appearance, strength, and usefulness.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this picture taken on August 19, 2023, a worker crafts a Kashmiri willow wood cricket bat at a factory in Kashmir's Sangam village. (Photo by Tauseef MUSTAFA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f6d2-08dbbe55a392_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this picture taken on August 19, 2023, a worker crafts a Kashmiri willow wood cricket bat at a factory in Kashmir's Sangam village. (Photo by Tauseef MUSTAFA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Paying attention to a wood's grain helps you to know how to work with it. For example, if you are cutting a wood <strong>board</strong> with the grain, you would use a tool called a rip saw. If you are cutting across the grain, you would use a crosscut saw.</p>
<p>Cutting against the grain is more difficult. If you work against the wood grain, you might tear out pieces of wood or even damage your tools.</p>
<p>And that brings us to our expression: <u>to go against the grain.</u></p>
<p>If you go against the grain, you do something differently from what is normal or usual.</p>
<p>An idea or action that goes against the grain is difficult to do or accept. Usually, it goes against a person's ideals, beliefs, or principles.</p>
<p>If an idea or action goes against the grain, it is the opposite of what you believe is right or normal. You might find it difficult to accept. In some situations, it takes courage to go against the grain of what others are saying or doing and stand up for what you believe in.</p>
<p>Let's say a friend of yours is offered a sales job. To do the job well, he must <strong>convince</strong> people to buy things they don't need. He is a very honest man. So, for him this job goes against the grain.</p>
<p>To go against the grain can also mean to do things differently from others. Sometimes we want to go against the grain. We don't want to do things the way everyone else does. Artists often try to go against the grain and ignore the common, popular <strong>trends </strong>of the day.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear the expression used between two friends.</p>
<p><em>A: Did you hear about Jenny taking that corporate banking job? </em></p>
<p><em>B: I did! I'm really happy for her. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Happy? You must be kidding. Jenny is an artist. In college, we used to protest against big banks.</em></p>
<p><em>B: I know we did. But life is different now. We're older and have bills to pay. And I think Jenny wants to send her little sister to college. </em></p>
<p><em>A: I know. But a corporate job? Jenny? It just goes against the grain for her. </em></p>
<p><em>B: Look, we need to support our friend. Anything less would go against the grain for me.</em></p>
<p>And that's the end of this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>board</strong> –n. a flat piece of wood used for building things</p>
<p><strong>convince </strong>–v. to persuade a person to do or believe something</p>
<p><strong>trend </strong>–n. the way things are going; a general direction of change</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Implements Much-debated New Citizenship Law  (2024/3/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/india-implements-much-debated-new-citizenship-law.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>India has put into effect a new law that makes it easier for non-Muslim minorities to seek Indian citizenship.</p>
<p>The much-debated law was first approved by India's parliament in 2019. But the government of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi delayed <strong>implementing</strong> the measure because of huge protests by groups opposed to it.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of people took part in demonstrations against the law shortly after it was approved in December 2019. At the time, news organizations reported at least 23 people were killed during days of protests.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Students protest against the Citizenship Amendment Act (CAA) in Guwahati, India, Tuesday, March 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fc2a-08dc442cd0f8_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Students protest against the Citizenship Amendment Act (CAA) in Guwahati, India, Tuesday, March 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)</span></div>
<p>The law seeks to give Indian citizenship to Hindus, Christians, Buddhists and other minorities who fled Bangladesh, Pakistan and Afghanistan to escape mistreatment based on religion. Muslims are not covered by the law.</p>
<p>Modi's Hindu nationalist-led government has said the law is designed to ease the suffering of many people who long faced unfair treatment in India. Critics say the measure is a government attempt to <strong>marginalize</strong> India's 200 million Muslims.</p>
<p>A message issued by the prime minister's office confirmed the new law had been activated. "The Modi government announces implementation of Citizenship Amendment Act," a spokesperson wrote in a text message.</p>
<p>The measure is an important policy of Modi's ruling Bharatiya Janata Party. The spokesperson said the measure clears the way "for the <strong>persecuted</strong> to find citizenship in India."</p>
<p>A statement by the Home Ministry said the law aims to remove legal barriers to citizenship for refugees in order to provide a "<strong>dignified</strong> life" to those who have long suffered in India.</p>
<p>The statement added that "many <strong>misconceptions</strong>" had been spread among the public about the law. "This Act is only for those who have suffered persecution for years and have no other shelter in the world except India," it said.</p>
<p>The government said citizenship seekers can begin the process by entering their information online through an official website.</p>
<p>Human rights group Amnesty India criticized implementation of the law, saying it "<strong>legitimizes</strong> discrimination based on religion."</p>
<p>Opponents have argued that if the law aims to protect persecuted minorities, it should have included Muslim religious minorities. The critics say these groups – including Ahmadis in Pakistan and Rohingyas in Myanmar – have already faced persecution in their own countries.</p>
<p>The opposition Communist Party of India – which rules the southern state of Kerala - called for state-wide protests to demonstrate their opposition to the measure.</p>
<p>Kerala's Chief Minister, Pinarayi Vijayan, said in a statement he sees the law leading to more divisions and believes it is not in line with the country's constitution. "This move to <strong>stratify</strong> Indian citizens who have equal rights, must be opposed unitedly."</p>
<p>India's 200 million Muslims make up a large minority group in the country's 1.4 billion population. Muslims live in almost every part of the country. They have been targeted in a series of attacks since Modi first came to power in 2014.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>implement </strong><em>– v. </em>to start using a plan, law or system</p>
<p><strong>marginalize </strong><em>– v. </em>to treat someone or something like they are not important</p>
<p><strong>persecute </strong><em>– v. </em>to treat someone poorly or unfairly</p>
<p><strong>dignified </strong><em>– adj. </em>something controlled, serious and calm that deserves respect</p>
<p><strong>misconception </strong><em>– n.</em> an idea that is wrong because it is based on a failure to understand a situation</p>
<p><strong>legitimize </strong><em>– v. </em>to make something legal or acceptable</p>
<p><strong>stratify </strong><em>– v.</em> to arrange different part of something in separate parts of groups</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Tiny Plastic Particles in Our Bodies Harmful?  (2024/3/16) | 微塑料是否对人体有害？</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/are-tiny-plastic-particles-in-our-bodies-harmful.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A new study examines possible harm caused by microscopic pieces of plastic that end up inside people's bodies.<br/>
一项新的研究考察了最终进入人体的微小塑料碎片可能造成的危害。</p>
<p>These materials – known as microplastics and nanoplastics – can enter the body through the air or in food or drinks.<br/>
这些材料被称为微塑料和纳米塑料，它可以通过空气、食物或饮料进入人体。</p>
<p>Tiny plastic pieces have received widespread attention in the media. But so far, very little research has been done on how the substances affect human heart health.<br/>
微小的塑料制品受到了媒体的广泛关注。但到目前为止，关于这些物质如何影响人类心脏健康的研究很少。</p>
<p>One new study suggests the buildup of such plastics inside the body can increase the risk of a stroke, heart attack or death. But the researchers noted the evidence presented cannot prove a direct link between tiny plastic materials and heart problems.<br/>
一项新的研究表明，这种塑料在体内的堆积会增加中风、心脏病发作或死亡的风险。但研究人员指出，所提供的证据无法证明微小塑料材料与心脏问题之间的直接联系。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What did the study find?<br/>
该研究有何发现？</span></p>
<p>The study involved 257 people who had medical operations to clear blocked blood vessels in their necks. Italian researchers examined the fatty buildup the doctors removed from the carotid arteries, which supply blood and oxygen to the brain.<br/>
这项研究涉及257人，他们接受了清理颈部堵塞血管的医疗手术。意大利研究人员检查了医生从为大脑提供血液和氧气的颈动脉中清除的脂肪堆积物。</p>
<p>Using two methods, they found evidence of plastics – mostly nanoplastics that cannot be seen – in the artery plaque of 150 patients. No evidence of plastics was seen in 107 patients.<br/>
他们采用两种方法，在150名患者的动脉斑块中发现了塑料的证据，其中大部分是看不见的纳米塑料。在107名患者中没有发现塑料的迹象。</p>
<p>The team followed these people for three years. During that time, 30 individuals, or 20 percent of the group with plastics, had a heart attack, stroke, or died from any cause. These rates dropped to about eight percent among those with no evidence of plastics.<br/>
这个团队对这些人进行了为期三年的跟踪调查。在此期间，发现塑料的群体中有30人，占比20%，发生了心脏病、中风或死于各种原因。在那些没有塑料证据的群体中，这一比例降至8%左右。</p>
<p>Research results were recently published in a study in the New England Journal of Medicine.<br/>
研究结果最近发表在《新英格兰医学杂志》上的一项研究中。</p>
<p>The researchers also found more evidence of inflammation in individuals with tiny plastic bits in their blood. Inflammation is the body's reaction to injury and is thought to raise the risk of heart attacks and strokes.<br/>
研究人员还发现了血液中有微小塑料碎片的人出现炎症的更多证据。炎症是身体对损伤的反应，它被认为会增加心脏病发作和中风的风险。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are the problems with the study?<br/>
这项研究有什么问题？</span></p>
<p>The researchers admitted their study was very small. For example, it only looked at people with narrowed arteries who were already at risk for heart attacks and stroke.<br/>
研究人员承认他们的研究规模很小。例如，它只观察了动脉狭窄的人群，这些人已经存在心脏病发作和中风的风险。</p>
<p>And the patients with the plastics had more heart disease, diabetes and high cholesterol than those without plastics. They were also more likely to be men and more likely to be smokers. Both of those groups generally have higher rates of heart disease.<br/>
检出塑料制品的患者比没有检出塑料制品的患者更容易发生心脏病、糖尿病和高胆固醇。他们也更有可能是男性，更有可能是吸烟者。这两组人通常都有较高的心脏病发病率。</p>
<p>The researchers tried to account for these risk differences. But they noted they may have missed some important elements that could change the results. The team said because of these ongoing questions, this kind of study cannot prove the plastics caused the health problems.<br/>
研究人员试图解释这些风险差异。但他们指出，他们可能错过了一些可能改变结果的重要因素。该团队表示，由于这些持续存在的问题，这类研究无法证明塑料导致了健康问题。</p>
<p>Steve Nissen is a heart expert at the Cleveland Clinic in the state of Ohio who was not part of the study. He told the Associated Press he thinks the team's estimate that the risk of heart attack, stroke or death was four times greater seems too high.<br/>
史蒂夫·尼森是俄亥俄州克利夫兰诊所的心脏病专家，他没有参与这项研究。他告诉美联社，他认为该研究小组估算心脏病发作、中风或死亡的风险高出四倍，这似乎太高了。</p>
<p>"It would mean that these microplastics are the most important cause of coronary heart disease yet discovered. And I just don't think that's likely to be right," Nissen said.<br/>
尼森说：“这意味着这些微塑料是迄今为止发现的导致冠心病的最重要原因。我只是认为这不太可能是对的。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What is next for the researchers?<br/>
研究人员的下一步是什么？</span></p>
<p>Philip Landrigan of Boston College University told the AP that more research is needed on the issue. Landrigan, who wrote about the study in the Journal, said it is the first one suggesting a connection between microplastics and nanoplastics with disease in humans. Other scientists have found plastic bits in the lungs, liver, blood, placenta and breast milk.<br/>
波士顿学院大学的菲利普·兰德里根告诉美联社，需要对这个问题进行更多的研究。兰德里根在《华尔街日报》上撰文谈到了这项研究，他说这是第一个表明微塑料和纳米塑料与人类疾病之间存在联系的研究。其他科学家已经在肺、肝、血液、胎盘和母乳中发现了塑料碎片。</p>
<p>"It does not prove cause and effect, but it suggests cause and effect," Landrigan said. "And it needs urgently to be either replicated or disproven by other studies done by other investigators in other populations."<br/>
兰德里根说：“它不能证明因果关系，但它启发了因果关系。它迫切需要被其他研究人员在其他人群中进行的其它研究所重复或推翻。”</p>
<p>The Cleveland Clinic's Nissen added about the study, "It's a wake-up call that perhaps we need to take the problem of microplastics more seriously. As a cause for heart disease? Not proven. As a potential cause? Yes, maybe," Nissen said.<br/>
克利夫兰诊所的尼森在谈到这项研究时补充道，“这是一个警钟，也许我们需要更认真地对待微塑料问题。作为心脏病的病因？尚未被证实。作为潜在病因？是的，也许。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Wild Winter Sport of Skijoring  (2024/3/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/the-wild-winter-sport-of-skijoring.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>What do you get when you cross the sports of <strong>rodeo</strong> with skiing? An extreme winter sport called skijoring.</p>
<p>The competition involves riding horses that <strong>tow</strong> skiers by rope over jumps and around barriers. At the same time, competitors try to <strong>lance</strong> round targets with a baton, a special stick for the purpose.</p>
<p>Skijoring is a winter sport that celebrates the combination of rodeo and ski culture in the U.S. Mountain West.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A skijoring team competes in Leadville, Colo., on Saturday, March 2, 2024. Skijoring draws its name from the Norwegian word skikjoring, meaning ski driving. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-f1bc-08dc429d769e_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A skijoring team competes in Leadville, Colo., on Saturday, March 2, 2024. Skijoring draws its name from the Norwegian word skikjoring, meaning "ski driving." (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)</span></div>
<p>Horses — and sometimes dogs, snowmobiles and even cars — tow skiers by rope at speeds as high as 64 kilometers per hour. Skiers can go over jumps as high as 2.4 meters.</p>
<p>One of the most popular skijoring races in the country takes place in Leadville, Colorado. The event, called "The Granddaddy of 'em All," has been a tradition there since 1949.</p>
<p>"It's just the pure <strong>adrenaline</strong> that gets me to do it," said Nick Burri. He is one of the competitors and said teams get along with each other. "Getting these two different groups of people together with the riders and the skiers...we <strong>mesh</strong> pretty well."</p>
<p>Internet reports say skijoring takes its name from the Norwegian word skikjoring, which means "ski driving." It started as a way to get around in Scandinavia and became popular in Europe's Alps Mountains around 1900.</p>
<p>Today's sport is dangerous, and injuries are common among riders and skiers alike. One of the first riders in the Leadville race earlier this month fell off his horse and had to be helped off the track.</p>
<p>Burri did well in the competition although he was skiing with a separated shoulder that he suffered in a fall during a race two weeks earlier.</p>
<p>Savannah McCarthy has been a competitive skijorer since she was 12 years old. She said she experiences a nervous energy before she rides her horse for a race. But once she is speeding down the course, her world goes silent.</p>
<p>"I don't hear a thing when I'm running," she said. "When it's happening, you really don't have time to think about anything." McCarthy is a 24-year-old financial worker from Durango, Colorado. She has won the Leadville race nine times.</p>
<p>Loren Zhimanskova is head of Skijor USA, which helps organize races across the country. She said skijoring is becoming more popular because of social media. She hopes it will one day be an event in the Winter Olympics. Skijoring is especially popular in Poland and Switzerland, as well as in the U.S. states of Colorado, Wyoming and Montana.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the sport had about 350 teams of riders, skiers, and horses in the U.S., she said. Now, about 1,000 teams are competing, and the number of races has increased from about 15 a year to more than 30.</p>
<p>But getting the sport into the Olympics has proven difficult.</p>
<p>There is no official governing body. It has no clear set of rules. And there is no system that would permit riders to take part in the Winter Games. In addition, every course is different, and every race has its own special traditions.</p>
<p>Zhimanskova is pushing to include skijoring as a non-competitive demonstration sport. She said it could also be included in the <strong>torch</strong> <strong>relay</strong> at the 2034 Winter Olympics in Salt Lake City, Utah.</p>
<p>"Everyone loves snow...and then you add horses to that," Zhimanskova said. "I mean, all the elements that go into a skijoring event, in my opinion, are really feel-good elements," she added.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>rodeo </strong><em>— n. </em>a sport in the American West that involves events such as horse riding, bull riding and roping events</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tow </strong><em>— v. </em>to pull something that is attached by a rope or a hitch to the puller</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>lance </strong><em>— n.</em> to stick with a spear or long pointed piece of equipment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adrenaline </strong><em>— n. </em>a substance made by the body that causes excitement and strong emotions</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mesh </strong><em>— v. </em>to work well together</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>torch </strong><em>— n. </em>a light that is held by hand</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>relay </strong><em>— n. </em>a race or parade in which an object, especially a stick, is passed from one person taking part to another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Using 'Just' and 'Only'  (2024/3/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/using-just-and-only.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Mohammad.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>What is the difference between just and only?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Using 'Just' and 'Only'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2d6e-08dc442cb5c6_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Using 'Just' and 'Only'</span></div>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Mohammad. This is a good question.</p>
<p>In an earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/just-and-only/5408390.html" target="_blank">explained</a> how the two words, "just" and "only," seem to mean the same thing. For example:</p>
<p><em>She was <u>just</u> a baby when she came to America.</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>She was <u>only</u> a baby when she came to America.</em></p>
<p>In that article, we also explained how the two words have different meanings and when you should use one and not the other. The difference in usage is so small that you might not even notice at first. But it is very important.</p>
<p>So, let's look at more ways to use the two words today.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<p>Usage is the way in which a word or phrase is normally used.</p>
<p>The word "only" can be used in an undesirable situation. For example:</p>
<p><em>He <u>only</u> finished half his homework.</em></p>
<p><em><u>Only</u> two banks stay open after 4 p.m.</em></p>
<p><em>You're <u>only</u> coming on Saturday? I wish you could come earlier.</em></p>
<p>Its usage is also common when we are not happy about something:</p>
<p><em>It's <u>only</u> right that they get the same pay for the same work.</em></p>
<p><em>The noise is fine, <u>only</u> if it does not hurt my ear.</em></p>
<p>However, we use the word "just" when we want to make an <strong>emphasis</strong>, or a stronger statement. Let's compare the last two examples with these:</p>
<p><em>It's <u>just</u> not right that he gets more pay for the same work.</em></p>
<p><em>The noise hurts my ear. <u>Just</u> be quiet, please!</em></p>
<p>In spoken English, believe it or not, we also use "just" when we want to make something smaller or less important.</p>
<p>For example, when someone thinks the distance is too far, we might say:</p>
<p><em>Your friend lives <u>just</u> down the road.</em></p>
<p>If they do not have a lot of time, we might ask:</p>
<p><em>Can you wait <u>just</u> a minute?</em></p>
<p>And when someone appears to be busy, we might say:</p>
<p><em>Could I <u>just</u> ask you something?</em></p>
<p><em>I was <u>just</u> wondering, can we meet tomorrow?</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Mohammad.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's Ask a Teacher.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>emphasis</strong>—<em>n</em>. special importance, value, or attention</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Pi Day?  (2024/3/15) | 什么是圆周率日</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/what-is-pi-day.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Math lovers celebrate Pi Day on March 14, or 3/14. Around the world, many people even mark the day by eating a tasty piece of pie.<br/>
数学爱好者在3月14日庆祝圆周率日。在世界各地，许多人甚至通过吃一块美味的馅饼来纪念这一天。</p>
<p>For those who do not know, pi is a mathematical constant, a value that never changes. It expresses the ratio of a circle's circumference (the distance around the circle) to its diameter (the distance across the circle, passing through its center.)<br/>
对于那些不知道圆周率日的人来说，圆周率是一个数学常数，也就是一个定值。它表示圆的周长与其直径的比率。</p>
<p>The approximate value of this mathematical constant is 3.1415926535. But those are just the first 10 digits of pi. The numbers go on infinitely, or forever.<br/>
这个数学常数的近似值是3.1415926535。但这只是圆周率的前10位数字。这些数字是无限的，或者说是永无止境的。</p>
<p>Pi can calculate the circumference of a circle by measuring the diameter and multiplying that by the 3.14-plus number. The formula has been used in physics, astronomy, engineering and other fields, dating back thousands of years.<br/>
圆周率可用于计算圆的周长，即测量直径的长度并乘以3.14这个数字。该公式已被应用于物理学、天文学、工程学和其他领域，可以追溯到数千年前。</p>
<p>Long before computers, scientists such as Isaac Newton spent many hours calculating decimal places by hand. But today, researchers use computers to come up with trillions of digits for pi. But there is no end.<br/>
早在计算机出现之前，像牛顿这样的科学家就花了很多时间手工计算小数位数。但今天，研究人员使用计算机计算出数万亿位数的圆周率。但是没有尽头。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">What are some practical uses for Pi?<br/>
圆周率的一些实际用途</span></p>
<p>There are many uses for pi.<br/>
圆周率有很多用途。</p>
<p>The number helps calculate the size of paper rolls used in printers. And it helps decide the necessary size of a container that serves heating and air conditioning systems in buildings of different sizes.<br/>
这个数字有助于计算打印机中使用的纸卷的大小。它有助于确定不同尺寸建筑中供暖和空调系统所需容器的必要尺寸。</p>
<p>Scientists use the number to point an antenna toward a satellite and calculate the orbits and positions of planets and other space bodies.<br/>
科学家们用这个数字将天线指向卫星，以及计算行星和其他空间物体的轨道和位置。</p>
<p>Scientists with the American space agency NASA use pi to calculate when parachutes should open as a vehicle splashes down on Earth or lands on Mars.<br/>
美国宇航局的科学家使用圆周率来计算当飞行器溅落地球或降落火星时降落伞何时打开。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Pi Day<br/>
圓周率日</span></p>
<p>In 1706, British mathematician William Jones began using the Greek letter pi for the number 3.14… It is the first Greek letter in the words "periphery" and "perimeter." Both words have similar meanings as circumference.<br/>
1706年，英国数学家威廉·琼斯开始使用希腊字母π来表示3.14……这是单词periphery和perimeter中的第一个希腊字母。这两个词与周长的含义相似。</p>
<p>Pi Day itself dates back to the year 1988. That was when physicist Larry Shaw began celebrations at the Exploratorium, a science museum in San Francisco, California.<br/>
圆周率日自身可以追溯到1988年。当时物理学家拉里·肖在加州旧金山探索馆这家科学博物馆开始庆祝活动。</p>
<p>The so-called holiday did not gain national recognition until more than 20 years later. In 2009, the U.S. Congress declared every March 14 to be Pi Day as a way to bring more interest in math and science.<br/>
直到20多年后，这个所谓的节日才得到全美国的认可。2009年，美国国会宣布每年3月14日为圆周率日，以提高人们对数学和科学的兴趣。</p>
<p>The San Francisco museum that started the holiday organizes events, including a walk around a circular sign, called the Pi Shrine, 3.14 times. Of course, there is also plenty of pie to eat.<br/>
开创这一节日的旧金山博物馆会组织活动，包括绕着一个名为Pi Shrine的圆形标志散步3.14次。当然，这里也有很多馅饼可以吃。</p>
<p>Many Pi Day events take place at colleges in the United States. For example, Nova Southeastern University (NSU) in Florida holds the "Mental Math Bingo" game with free pizza pies.<br/>
许多圆周率日活动都在美国的大学举行。例如，佛罗里达州的新东南大学举办了免费披萨派的“心理数学宾果”游戏。</p>
<p>Jason Gershman oversees NSU's math department. He said, "Every year, Pi Day provides us with a way to celebrate math, have some fun and recognize how important math is in all our lives."<br/>
贾森·戈希曼负责新东南大学的数学部门。他说：“每年的圆周率日都为我们提供了一种庆祝数学、享受乐趣并认识到数学在我们生活中的重要性的途径。”</p>
<p>NASA has its yearly "Pi Day Challenge" online. The space agency offers games and puzzles, such as calculating the orbit of an asteroid or the distance a moon rover would need to travel each day to study a certain lunar area.<br/>
美国宇航局每年都会在网上举办“圆周率日挑战赛”。美国宇航局提供游戏和谜题，例如计算小行星的轨道或月球车研究某个月球区域每天需要行驶的距离。</p>
<p>If you still wonder why Pi Day is such an important day for math lovers, here are two more reasons: Albert Einstein, possibly the world's best-known scientist, was born on March 14, 1879. And famed physicist Stephen Hawking died on March 14, 2018, at age 76.<br/>
如果你仍然想知道为什么圆周率日对数学爱好者来说如此重要，还有两个原因：阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦这位可能是世界上最著名的科学家，出生于1879年3月14日。著名物理学家斯蒂芬·霍金于2018年3月14日去世，享年76岁。</p>
<p>Although pi is not a perfect number. Hawking once had this to say: "One of the basic rules of the universe is that nothing is perfect. Perfection simply doesn't exist. Without imperfection, neither you nor I would exist."<br/>
虽然圆周率不是一个完美的数字。霍金曾说过：“宇宙的一条基本规则是，没有什么是完美的。完美根本不存在。没有这些不完美，你和我就可能都不存在。”</p>
<p>And Happy Pi Day!<br/>
祝大家圆周率日快乐！</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Europe Approves AI Law  (2024/3/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/europe-approves-ai-law.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>European Union lawmakers gave final approval to the 27-nation group's artificial intelligence law Wednesday. The rules are expected to take effect later this year.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the European Parliament voted in favor of the Artificial Intelligence Act, five years after <strong>regulations</strong> were first proposed.</p>
<p>Major technology companies have generally supported the idea. But they want to make sure new AI requirements work in their favor. OpenAI chief Sam Altman suggested the maker of ChatGPT might pull out of Europe if it cannot <strong>comply</strong> with the AI Act. He later said his company had no plans to leave.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This illustration photograph taken on October 30, 2023, in Mulhouse, eastern France, shows figurines next to a screen displaying a logo of OpenAI. (Photo by SEBASTIEN BOZON / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9a9cc7d3-578f-4cd5-af6d-4c13bda4bc9c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This illustration photograph taken on October 30, 2023, in Mulhouse, eastern France, shows figurines next to a screen displaying a logo of OpenAI. (Photo by SEBASTIEN BOZON / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Here are some details about Europe's new AI rules:</p>
<p><strong>How does the AI Act work?</strong></p>
<p>Like many EU regulations, the AI Act started as <strong>consumer</strong> safety legislation. The EU took a "risk-based approach" to products or services that use artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<p>If an AI application is risky, then more rules cover it. Most AI systems are expected to be low risk, like content recommendation systems or <strong>filters </strong>that block spam, or unwanted email. Companies can choose to follow voluntary requirements and <strong>codes of conduct</strong>.</p>
<p>High-risk uses of AI include tools used in medical devices or important <strong>infrastructure</strong> like water or electrical networks. Those face additional requirements like using what the legislation calls high-quality data and providing clear information to users.</p>
<p>Some AI uses are banned because they are considered to present an unacceptable risk. Those include things like social scoring systems that are meant to govern how people behave. Some sorts of predictive policing and emotion recognition systems also are reportedly banned in schools and workplaces.</p>
<p>Other banned uses include ones that police use to <strong>scan</strong> faces in public places using AI-powered remote "<strong>biometric</strong> identification" systems. There is an exception for use in serious crimes like kidnapping or terrorism.</p>
<p><strong>What about generative AI?</strong></p>
<p>The law's early versions centered on AI systems that carry out limited tasks, like reviewing employment information and job applications. But general AI models, like OpenAI's ChatGPT, forced EU officials to add rules for generative AI models. AI chatbot systems that can produce lifelike responses, images and more are examples of generative AI models.</p>
<p>Developers of general purpose AI models will have to provide detailed descriptions of the writings, pictures, video and other data on the internet that was used to train the systems. They must also follow EU copyright law.</p>
<p>AI-generated pictures, video or audio of existing people, places or events must be labeled as <strong>artificially</strong> produced. These sorts of media are known as "deepfakes" because they appear to show real people doing or saying things that are not real.</p>
<p>There are reportedly extra rules for the biggest and most powerful AI models that carry "systemic risks." Those include OpenAI's GPT4 and Google's Gemini.</p>
<p><strong>What do Europe's rules mean?</strong></p>
<p>The EU first suggested AI regulations in 2019. Europe was quick to propose rules for the new and developing industry.</p>
<p>In the U.S., President Joe Biden signed an executive order on AI in October. The U.S. Congress is likely to propose legislation. Lawmakers in at least seven U.S. states are working on their own AI legislation. And international agreements are possible too.</p>
<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping has proposed his Global AI Governance Initiative for fair and safe use of AI. Other major countries, including Brazil and Japan, are developing rules, as well as the United Nations and Group of Seven industrialized nations.</p>
<p><strong>What happens next?</strong></p>
<p>The AI Act is expected to officially become law by May or June, after approval from EU member countries. Rules will start taking effect slowly. Countries will be required to ban unapproved AI systems six months after the law takes effect.</p>
<p>Rules for general purpose AI systems like chatbots will start going into effect in one year. By the middle of 2026, the complete set of regulations, including requirements for high-risk systems, will be in effect.</p>
<p>Each EU country will set up their own AI enforcement agency. Citizens can make a <strong>complaint</strong> if they think they have been the victim of a violation of the rules. And the EU will create an AI Office that will oversee the law for general purpose AI systems.</p>
<p>Violations of the AI Act could be punished with a fine of up to $38 million, or seven percent of a company's worldwide <strong>revenue</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>regulation </strong><em>— n. </em>a rule or a group of rules that control how an industry can carry out business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>comply </strong><em>— v. </em>to do what is requested to be done or what is required by rules or law</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>consumer </strong><em>— n. </em>a person or group that buys goods and services that are not for industrial purposes</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>filter </strong><em>— n. </em>something that permits only what is wanted through while blocking unwanted things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>codes of conduct </strong>–n. a set of rules that a group of people or businesses agrees to usually voluntarily</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>— n. </em>the structures and systems that are needed for modern life like roads, electricity lines, dams and many other things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scan </strong>–v. to use a camera to take a picture of a group of people to find a certain person</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>biometric </strong>–adj. related to taking measurements of the human body to confirm someone's identity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>artificial </strong><em>— adj. </em>made by people, not happening naturally; something that is not real</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>complaint </strong>–n. an official statement of dissatisfaction that is presented to a public official with the expectation that the problem will be dealt with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>revenue </strong><em>— n. </em>money collected by a business through sales, investment and other operations</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wildlife Workers Dress Up to Care for Orphaned Fox  (2024/3/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/wildlife-workers-dress-up-to-care-for-orphaned-fox.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In the eastern state of Virginia, employees of the Richmond Wildlife Center are doing their best to act like mother <strong>foxes</strong>. They started feeding and caring for a baby fox, called a kit, when the young animal became separated from its mother.</p>
<p>The Associated Press reported that a video recently appeared on the center's page on the social media service Facebook. In the video, Executive Director Melissa Stanley is shown wearing a red fox <strong>mask</strong> and equipment like rubber gloves. She feeds the young fox in the video. The kit sits on top of a <strong>stuffed</strong> <strong>animal</strong> that looks like a fox. It is supposed to look like her mother, Stanley said.</p>
<p>The Facebook post explained why employees were wearing the fox mask to feed the baby animal. It also said workers are avoiding making human sounds and are preventing the kit from seeing its human caregivers. The post said the <strong>orphan</strong> should not become too close to humans while it is being raised by them. The measures make it more likely that the kit could be returned to the wild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image taken from a video provided by the Richmond Wildlife Center, executive director and founder Melissa Stanley wears a fox mask as she feeds an orphaned red fox kit, March 10, 2024, in Richmond, Va. (Richmond Wildlife Center via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6c93a24f-0aa7-4f09-a076-d370bea43287_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image taken from a video provided by the Richmond Wildlife Center, executive director and founder Melissa Stanley wears a fox mask as she feeds an orphaned red fox kit, March 10, 2024, in Richmond, Va. (Richmond Wildlife Center via AP)</span></div>
<p>Stanley said a man brought the kit to the center on February 29. She said he found the animal on the street while walking his dog in Richmond.</p>
<p>Thinking she was a baby cat, the man turned her over to the Richmond Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (Richmond SPCA). The Richmond SPCA is a nonprofit organization that takes in cats and dogs without owners and finds them homes.</p>
<p>Wildlife center employees tried to find the kit's mother and their home, or den. They found the den, but they were told by officials that the foxes had been trapped and removed. Stanley said she thinks the fox kit either fell out of a trap or fell off the back of the trapper's truck.</p>
<p>Employees at the wildlife center have been taking turns feeding the kit every two to four hours. They all wear the fox mask while feeding her.</p>
<p>In addition to the large stuffed animal meant to look like the kit's mother, employees also put a smaller stuffed red fox in her space. She <strong>cuddles</strong> <strong>up</strong> to the smaller stuffed animal at the end of the video.</p>
<p>Stanley said, "The goal is to release the animals back into the wild." She added that the goal is not to just increase their chances of survival, but to raise them to <strong>recognize </strong>other animals of their kind. Another goal she said was that the animals should reproduce.</p>
<p>The center looked for other red fox kits of the same age and weight at other centers. Employees found three other kits in a center in northern Virginia.</p>
<p>The fox kit will be sent to the Animal Education and Rescue Organization in Virginia. That group plans to release the kits back into the wild together.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Denise Lavoie and Lea Skene reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fox </strong>– <em>n</em>. a wild animal of the dog family, with red-brown fur, a pointed face and a thick heavy tail</p>
<p><strong>mask </strong>– <em>n</em>. something that you wear over your face to hide it, or to frighten or entertain other people</p>
<p><strong>stuffed animal </strong><em>– n. </em>a toy in the shape of an animal, made of cloth and filled with a soft substance</p>
<p><strong>orphan </strong><em>– n. </em>a child whose parents are dead</p>
<p><strong>cuddle up </strong><em>– v.(phrasal) </em>to sit or lie very close to somebody/something</p>
<p><strong>recognize </strong><em>– v.</em> to know who somebody is or what something is when you see or hear them or it, because you have seen or heard them or it before</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Your Country’s National Dish?  (2024/3/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/what-is-your-country-s-national-dish.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Consider a time when you sat down to share a dish with family or friends. What was the dish? Is the dish special in your country or area?</p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will explore how to talk about foods. We will learn about the structures and words commonly used to talk about popular dishes.</p>
<p><strong>Ingredients </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c19d-08dc437fc2ab_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>Let's start with a comparison between cooking and grammar. Just as we have common <strong>ingredients</strong> when we cook – oil, salt, vegetables, meats, and so on – we also have common ingredients for sentences about food. These language ingredients include nouns, adjectives, and special kinds of <strong>phrases</strong>.</p>
<p>Just as cooking is about using food ingredients in special ways, food discussions are about using language ingredients in special ways.</p>
<p><strong>Nouns </strong></p>
<p>Our first ingredient is the noun. Nouns give us the name of a dish, or any food prepared in a special way. Nouns also give us names for all the spices and other materials that go into the dish.</p>
<p>But nouns alone cannot make a rich, complete sentence.</p>
<p>We need something else to add color, smells, and taste.</p>
<p>That is how we arrive at adjectives.</p>
<p>Adjectives are central to discussions about food. When we talk about any kind of dish, we describe it in terms of taste, color, smell, temperature, and so on.</p>
<p>In other words, adjectives are like spices that bring flavor to plain nouns.</p>
<p>There are many adjectives we use to describe dishes, but some common ones include: rich, spicy, sweet and fresh.</p>
<p><strong>Phrases </strong></p>
<p>So, we have nouns and adjectives. But we have one missing element. We need to express how ingredients go together to make up a dish.</p>
<p>One phrasal verb is especially useful in this regard: consist of.</p>
<p>We have the verb "consist" and the short word "of."</p>
<p>"Consist of" means to be formed, or made, of exact things.</p>
<p>So, you might say that pizza consists of flour, cheese, sauce, and vegetables.</p>
<p>Or you might say that kebab consists of meat and spices.</p>
<p>There are, of course, many other phrasal verbs you can use to describe the act of cooking. We have explored some of them in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/cooking-with-phrasal-verbs/4428624.html" target="_blank">previous Everyday Grammar lessons</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Example </strong></p>
<p>So far, we have covered a lot of territory - nouns, adjectives, and one phrasal verb. How might we use these ingredients?</p>
<p>Here is one possible example for how to describe any national dish:</p>
<p><em>[Noun] is the national dish of [noun]. It is a [adjective] dish that [phrasal verb] [noun], [noun], and [noun]. </em></p>
<p>How might we fill in the noun, adjective, and phrasal verb spots?</p>
<p>Let's use a traditionally popular dish in the United States as our example – apple pie. You may have heard the expression "As American as apple pie."</p>
<p>So, what could we say about apple pie if we used our example structure? Here is one possibility:</p>
<p><em>Apple pie is the national dish of the United States. It is a sweet dish that consists of apples, sugar, flour, and spices.</em></p>
<p>Of course, one could go on to add more details. You could say that apple pie also often includes a small amount of lemon juice or that apple pie is often served with ice cream on top.</p>
<p><strong>Call to action </strong></p>
<p>You have learned about one possible way to describe a popular American dish. Now we would like to hear from you. Can you write to us about a traditional dish in your country? Try to use the sentence structures that you have just learned about, but feel free to include more details.</p>
<p>Send us your piece of writing in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>In a future lesson, we will provide feedback on the writing that we receive.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ingredient</strong><em> – n. </em>one of the things that are used to make a food, product, etc.</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Insurance Group Rates Most Driver Assistance Systems ‘Poor’  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-insurance-group-rates-most-driver-assistance-systems-poor.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>An American <strong>insurance</strong> industry group has given most driver assistance systems "poor" ratings after a series of safety tests.</p>
<p>The Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (IIHS) carried out the tests. The group released a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iihs.org/news/detail/first-partial-driving-automation-safeguard-ratings-show-industry-has-work-to-do">report</a> this week describing its findings.</p>
<p>The tests involved 14 different driver assistance tools. Such tools offer partial driving <strong>automation</strong> as a way to improve safety and reduce accidents. The systems are equipped to assist drivers with things like staying inside road lines and automatically slowing or stopping the car when possible dangers are identified.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Tesla Model 3 vehicle drives on autopilot along the 405 highway in Westminster, California, U.S., March 16, 2022. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b708-08dc436a400c_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Tesla Model 3 vehicle drives on autopilot along the 405 highway in Westminster, California, U.S., March 16, 2022. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)</span></div>
<p>The IIHS is a nonprofit organization financed by America's insurance industry. The group carries out numerous crash tests each year as it seeks to persuade automakers to design safer vehicles. Automakers follow safety ratings issued by the group and often make changes to products based on them.</p>
<p>The IIHS noted there is a lack of effective tools to <strong>monitor</strong> drivers and provide warnings when they need to pay better attention or take immediate corrective action.</p>
<p>David Harkey is president of the IIHS. He told the Associated Press his group aims to set guidelines for manufacturers to make up for a lack of <strong>regulation</strong> over the systems by the U.S. National Highway Safety Administration.</p>
<p>Harkey noted that most current driver assist systems do not have effective measures "to prevent misuse and keep drivers from losing <strong>focus</strong> on what's happening on the road."</p>
<p>All automakers advise drivers using assistance tools not to fully depend on vehicle technologies to keep them safe. The companies say the tools are meant to improve, or enhance, overall safety, rather than take over certain driving duties.</p>
<p>The IIHS said it tested 14 different driver assist systems. Of those, 11 received an overall rating of "poor." Two other systems were rated "<strong>marginal</strong>," while one was considered "acceptable." Harkey said the 14 systems are among the highest quality technologies currently on the market.</p>
<p>The driver assist system used in the Lexus LS model earned the acceptable rating. The marginal declarations were given to systems in General Motors' GMC Sierra and Nissan's Ariya electric vehicle. Other systems from Nissan, Tesla, BMW, Ford, Genesis, Mercedes-Benz, and Volvo received ratings of "poor."</p>
<p>Harkey said the high-level of technology <strong>sophistication</strong> in today's driver assist systems provides a lot more automation possibilities. But these tools can cause drivers not to pay attention for longer periods, presenting new, dangerous risks. "That's why the focus is on how do we make sure that the driver remains focused on the driving...," he added.</p>
<p>The IIHS has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-many-drivers-treat-driving-assist-tools-as-fully-self-driving/6789001.html">warned</a> that manufacturers advertise their vehicles in a way that gives drivers the false idea that they are fully automated, or autonomous. "The one thing we do not want is for drivers to <strong>misinterpret</strong> what these things can or cannot do," Harkey said.</p>
<p>The IIHS is calling for automakers to build additional tools into their systems. These would be designed to observe whether or not a driver's eyes are directed at the road and whether their hands are on the wheel or ready to immediately take control.</p>
<p>The institute suggested the systems should have built-in tools that send warnings to drivers within 10 seconds if their eyes and hands are not in the right positions. At 20 seconds, the IIHS said the system should add another warning or start an automatic emergency process to slow down the vehicle.</p>
<p>Toyota, which makes Lexus vehicles, said it considers IIHS reports when it creates safety guidelines, while General Motors called the ratings important. Nissan said it will work with the institute on proposed changes.</p>
<p>Mercedes said it takes the findings seriously, while Hyundai Genesis said it was quickly improving its system, including plans to put a camera inside vehicles.</p>
<p>BMW said while it respects IIHS's efforts, it differs on the use of technology to monitor drivers inside the vehicle. Ford said its driver assist system monitors drivers and sends repeated warnings. While Ford said it disagrees with the institute's findings, it will consider the suggestions in future development.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>insurance </strong><em>– n. </em>an agreement in which you pay a company regularly, and it pays some of your costs if you have an accident or injury</p>
<p><strong>automate </strong><em>– v. </em>to control something using machines and not people</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>– v. </em>to watch closely</p>
<p><strong>regulation </strong><em>– n. </em>an official rule that controls how something is done</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>– n.</em> the person or thing that is getting the most attention</p>
<p><strong>marginal</strong><em> – adj. </em>small and not important</p>
<p><strong>sophisticated</strong><em> – adj. </em>very advanced in development</p>
<p><strong>misinterpret</strong><em> – v. </em>to understand something in the wrong way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Stone Tools Might Be Earliest Evidence of Human Ancestors in Europe  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/stone-tools-might-be-earliest-evidence-of-human-ancestors-in-europe.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say they have identified stone tools that might represent the oldest-known evidence of humans in Europe.</p>
<p>The recent research suggests that the human ancestors started settling Europe 1.4 million years ago. That is hundreds of thousands of years earlier than previously thought.</p>
<p>The stone tools were first discovered in the 1970s near the town of Korolevo, close to Ukraine's borders with Hungary and Romania. But the tools' age had remained unclear.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A view of the Korolevo quarry in western Ukraine, surrounded by archaeological sites, August 12, 2021. (Roman Garba/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fa7c2f72-937d-4a87-afc3-ba7a5c55e18a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A view of the Korolevo quarry in western Ukraine, surrounded by archaeological sites, August 12, 2021. (Roman Garba/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The place of the find is important for understanding how humans first spread into Europe. They moved into the area during warm periods, called interglacial periods. Those were times, in between Ice Ages, when huge amounts of ice covered Europe.</p>
<p>The scientists used a method for estimating the age that identifies the effects of <strong>cosmic rays </strong>on some kinds of minerals. The new method placed the age of the <strong>sediment</strong> layer containing the stone tools at around 1.4 million years.</p>
<p>The researchers believe that the maker of the tools was likely a human ancestor called Homo erectus. That early human <strong>species</strong> appeared around 2 million years ago and spread across Africa, Asia and Europe before disappearing perhaps 110,000 years ago.</p>
<p>"No bones were found at Korolevo, only stone tools. But the age suggests that Homo erectus was the only possible human species at the time. We know very little about our earliest ancestors. They used stone tools for <strong>butchery</strong> and probably used fire," said Roman Garba of the Czech Academy of Sciences. Garba was the lead writer of the research published in Nature.</p>
<p>Homo erectus was the first member of our evolutionary <strong>lineage</strong>. Homo erectus had body <strong>proportions</strong> like our species, Homo sapiens, though with a smaller brain.</p>
<p>The tools, made of volcanic rock, were made in a way that is called Oldowan. While simple, they represent the beginning of human technology.</p>
<p>Until now, the oldest-known evidence of humans in Europe was from about 1.2 million years ago from a place called Atapuerca in Spain.</p>
<p>The Korolevo findings suggest how the first humans might have moved into Europe. Homo erectus<strong> fossils</strong> from 1.8 million years ago are known from a place in the Caucasus Mountains in Georgia called Dmanisi. Garba said the evidence from Korolevo and Dmanisi suggests Homo erectus entered Europe from the east or southeast, moving along the Danube River.</p>
<p>It has been difficult to identify the age of places like Korolevo. The study dated the tools, left by their makers on a riverbed, by estimating when the layer holding the objects was buried under sediment.</p>
<p>Mads Knudsen of Aarhus University in Denmark described how scientists were able to date the prehistoric tools.</p>
<p>He said cosmic rays from outer space are always passing through the Earth's atmosphere. When they do, they create particles that are smaller than atoms, such as neutrons and muons. These particles are so small that they pass through all sorts of materials.</p>
<p>These particles react with minerals in rocks to produce radioactive nuclides, a class of atoms. The sediment was dated based on the <strong>ratio </strong>of two nuclides. This is possible because the two nuclides break down at different rates, through the process of radioactive decay.</p>
<p>Europe was later colonized by other human ancestor species including Homo heidelbergensis and Neanderthals. Scientists say Homo sapiens evolved in Africa about 300,000 years ago. They arrived in large numbers in Europe around 40,000 to 45,000 years ago.</p>
<p>The researchers suspect evidence of human occupation in Europe that is even older than Korolevo will be found.</p>
<p>"The question is not 'if' but 'when' we will find a site of similar or older age somewhere else in Ukraine, Romania, Bulgaria or Serbia," Garba said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cosmic rays </strong><em>– n.</em> particles of atomic or smaller size that pass into the Earth's atmosphere from space at extremely high energy levels</p>
<p><strong>sediment </strong><em>– n. </em>material (such as stones and sand) that sinks to the bottom of a body of water forming a layer that solidifies into rock over long periods of time</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>–n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young</p>
<p><strong>butchery </strong>–<em> n.</em> the job or act of preparing meat for eating</p>
<p><strong>lineage </strong><em>– n.</em> the people who were in someone's family in past times</p>
<p><strong>proportion </strong><em>– n.</em> the relationship between the size, shape, and position of the different parts of something</p>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as a bone or footprint) that is from a plant or animal that lived in ancient times</p>
<p><strong>ratio</strong> <em>–n.</em> a numerical relationship between two values</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Greek Grandmother Makes Scarves for Children in Need  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/greek-grandmother-makes-scarves-for-children-in-need.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In her small home in the capital of Greece, Athens, 93-year-old Ioanna Matsouka has <strong>knit</strong> thousands of brightly colored <strong>scarves </strong>for children in need from Greece to Bosnia to Ukraine. She has no plans to stop just yet.</p>
<p>"Until I die, I will be knitting," Matsouka told Reuters. Her knitting tools called needles made noises through her expert fingers, her nails painted red. "It brings me <strong>joy</strong> to share them," she said.</p>
<p>Since she took up knitting in the 1990s, Matsouka has easily made over 3,000 scarves, her daughters estimate.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ioanna Matsouka, 93, knits scarves in her house in Athens, Greece, March 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Karolina Tagaris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b19fcd92-bde9-41a5-bd04-1a392e8ad925_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ioanna Matsouka, 93, knits scarves in her house in Athens, Greece, March 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Karolina Tagaris)</span></div>
<p>By the door to her home, bags filled with her latest creations await their new owners. A knitted <strong>blanket</strong> is thrown over a large chair where she spends her days.</p>
<p>In the beginning, the scarves were gifted to friends. As the number of scarves grew, they were donated to children's homes across Greece. Then, through people she knew, they reached children in Bosnia and Ukraine. The latest 70 scarves went to a refugee camp near Athens this winter, via the United Nations refugee agency UNHCR.</p>
<p>"The fact that we give them away gives her strength," said her daughter Angeliki.</p>
<p>She recounted simple artwork and mail her mother received over the years: "Thank you, be well, keep going. You gave joy to children; you gave joy to people... That's her only <strong>reward</strong>: a letter, a few words."</p>
<p>Matsouka knits one scarf a day now. Her eyesight suffers and she sometimes has severe facial pain, a condition known as trigeminal neuralgia.</p>
<p>Angeliki says her mother is an example of strength and hope.</p>
<p>Matsouka wakes up every morning, drinks a glass of milk, puts on her jewelry and gets to work. She takes a break for lunch and a short sleep, then knits into the night.</p>
<p>She may have even found the secret to a long life in it, she says. "It's the happiness I get from giving," she said, sitting beside a big blue bag filled with the knitting materials.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Karolina Tagaris reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>knit </strong><em>– v. </em>to make (a piece of clothing) from yarn or thread by using long needles or a special machine</p>
<p><strong>scarf </strong><em>– n. </em>a long piece of cloth that is worn on your shoulders, around your neck, or over your head</p>
<p><strong>joy </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling of great happiness</p>
<p><strong>blanket </strong><em>– n</em>. a covering made of cloth that is used especially on a bed to keep you warm</p>
<p><strong>reward </strong><em>– n</em>. money or another kind of payment that is given or received for something that has been done or that is offered for something that might be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Filipino Man Makes Library in His Home  (2024/3/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/filipino-man-makes-library-in-his-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>"A good book is easy to find." That is the message on a sign at Hernando Guanlao's home in the Makati area of Manila, the capital of the Philippines.</p>
<p>Guanlao has turned his home into a free public library. Visitors can borrow the books inside for free.</p>
<p>Guanlao says he hopes his library will<strong> inspire</strong> people to read, especially the young. The 72-year-old told reporters that his library includes books that all students can enjoy – from young children in Kindergarten to older students in grade 12.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Hernando Guanlao, 72, sits in front of his home library in Makati, a metro area of Manila, Philippines, Feb. 7, 2024. (REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a80b-08dc3f8dc6b2_cx2_cy0_cw97_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Hernando Guanlao, 72, sits in front of his home library in Makati, a metro area of Manila, Philippines, Feb. 7, 2024. (REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez)</span></div>
<p>Guanlao says his library has books for readers of all interests. He spoke to reporters at his home, which is filled with thousands of available books.</p>
<p>He calls his library Reading Club 2000. It contains many different kinds of books, or genres.</p>
<p>Genre is a group of artistic, musical, or literary works that share a particular style, form, or content. Some genres in <strong>literature</strong> are poetry, non-fiction (or real stories), and fiction (or imaginary stories). Then there are "sub-genres" such as cookbooks, science fiction, and mystery, to name just a few.</p>
<p>Guanlao added, "There are also spiritual books for those who are looking for religious knowledge, hardbound and softbound books, autobiographies, and many different<strong> </strong>genres that one can enjoy, all for free."</p>
<p>He started his library more than 20 years ago when he set 50 books on the walkway in front of his home. Guanlao's collection has grown greatly over the years -- thanks to a continuous supply of books from donors.</p>
<p>Speaking of donors, he said, "They just leave boxes of books outside my house." He has also started donating books himself. He sends reading materials to public schools in far-away communities.</p>
<p>Guanlao's efforts come at a time when reading ability among students in the Philippines remains low. The Program for International Student Assessment reports that reading scores in the Philippines are among the lowest in the world. The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development runs that program.</p>
<p>Students in the Philippines are also facing learning delays in math and science.</p>
<p>Guanlao is firm about his goals: "My <strong>mission</strong> is to give away used and donated books to others at no cost," he said, "and to <strong>promote</strong> education through literature."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Adrian Portugal and Karen Lema reported this story for Reuters News Agency. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><strong><em>– v.</em></strong><strong> </strong><strong> </strong>to stimulate to greater or higher activity <strong>: </strong>make spirited</p>
<p><strong>literature </strong><strong><em>– n.</em></strong><strong> </strong>written works having excellence of form or expression and ideas of lasting and widespread interest</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><strong><em>– n. </em></strong>a preestablished and often self-imposed objective or purpose</p>
<p><strong>promote </strong><strong><em>– v.</em></strong><strong> </strong>to help (something) grow or develop<strong> </strong></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Agency Warns: Mass Coral Bleaching Expected in Near Future  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-agency-warns-mass-coral-bleaching-expected-in-near-future.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American agency that follows the risk of coral bleaching around the world says "the worst bleaching event in the history of the planet may come soon."</p>
<p>Those are the words of Derek Manzello, head of NOAA's Coral Reef Watch.</p>
<p>NOAA is the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A photo of threatened coral off the southern edge of Florida. (REUTERS/Maria Alejandra Cardona/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ad1c2456-02cd-438d-82bb-045e728f364a_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A photo of threatened coral off the southern edge of Florida. (REUTERS/Maria Alejandra Cardona/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Manzello said the "<strong>entirety</strong>" of the Southern Hemisphere is "probably going to bleach this year." The Southern Hemisphere is currently in summer and suffering from record-breaking water temperatures.</p>
<p>Experts say climate change and the El Nino weather pattern are to blame for the warmer water.</p>
<p><strong>Sensitive organisms</strong></p>
<p>Corals are small marine organisms that attach to mineral <strong>deposits</strong> in the ocean. Collections of the animals form ocean structures that support many kinds of sea life.</p>
<p>Bleaching is the term used by experts who see the once colorful coral turn white when water temperatures rise. It is a sign the animals are dying.</p>
<p>If corals die or go <strong>dormant</strong>, they can hurt fishing and tourism industries.</p>
<p>The last large coral bleaching event around the world took place from 2014 to 2017. At the time, the Great Barrier Reef off Australia lost nearly one-third of its coral. Overall, the world lost 15 percent of its coral.</p>
<p>Corals get their color from small plants called algae that live inside them. The high temperatures stress the coral and cause them to <strong>expel</strong> the algae. When that happens, the corals lose their color. The algae help the coral stay healthy and without it, the corals face increasing risk of disease.</p>
<p>Observers are concerned that 2024's bleaching will be even worse than the last time. Scientists reported the worst coral bleaching on record in the Caribbean late last year.</p>
<p>Manzello said there is coral bleaching "all over the place" in the Southern Hemisphere. He said all of the Great Barrier Reef is bleaching as are reefs in the territory of American Samoa.</p>
<p>The El Nino weather pattern always brings warmer ocean temperatures. However, the world just experienced one of the warmest 12-month periods on record. In 2023, temperatures were 1.5 degrees Celsius higher than during pre-industrial times. Scientists say a longer period of high temperatures could cause the deaths of 90 percent of the world's coral.</p>
<p>Manzello noted that scientists must look at coral in all three major oceans – Atlantic, Pacific and Indian – to call a bleaching event "global."</p>
<p>Scientists use sea surface temperature data and examine satellite imagery of reefs to measure for bleaching. Based on studies so far, Manzello said the world is "already there."</p>
<p>A similar study of Indian Ocean coral is continuing.</p>
<p>Joanne Manning is a spokesperson for the Australian Institute of Marine Science. Manning said the organization has documented extensive bleaching in the Keppels area and Capricorn-Bunker groups. She said the group's research continues.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>entirety </strong>–adj. everything, or the full amount</p>
<p><strong>deposit </strong>–n. a substance left behind, or created during a chemical reaction</p>
<p><strong>dormant </strong>–adj. not actively growing but still alive, such as when grass turns brown in the winter</p>
<p><strong>expel </strong>–v. to push something out</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Looks at How 15-year-olds Learn English  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/study-looks-at-how-15-year-olds-learn-english.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Today's English students have a lot of <strong>exposure</strong> to the language outside of the classroom. By using the internet, social media, and other <strong>digital</strong> technologies, they can watch videos, hear music, and play video games in English.</p>
<p>But teachers are not so sure that digital exposure results in better English-speaking abilities. That is the finding of a new study on how teenagers learn English. The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, or OECD, a group that studies economic activities in large economies, supported the study.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/a3fcacd5-en/1/3/8/index.html?itemId=/content/publication/a3fcacd5-en&amp;_csp_=699fa32b3d47245b9d0bc15535a1d6cf&amp;itemIGO=oecd&amp;itemContentType=book">study</a> is called "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/education/how-15-year-olds-learn-english_f30ed0a4-en">How 15-Year-Olds Learn English.</a>" It provides case studies of teaching teenagers English from five countries: Finland, Greece, Israel, the Netherlands and Portugal. The researchers gathered information by visiting schools and observing English lessons in each country. They also <strong>interviewed</strong> teachers, students and school administrators.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - ESL (English-as-a-second-language) teacher Xavier Chavez, standing, teaches a summer history class at Benson High School in Portland, Ore.,Wednesday, Aug. 6, 2008. (AP Photo/Don Ryan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/D453CE0D-CF25-4D78-912C-54154923EB59_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - ESL (English-as-a-second-language) teacher Xavier Chavez, standing, teaches a summer history class at Benson High School in Portland, Ore.,Wednesday, Aug. 6, 2008. (AP Photo/Don Ryan)</span></div>
<p>The study findings will be used to support the OECD's 2025 Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA), said Catalina Covacevich. She was one of the study's main researchers. PISA studies the school systems of about 90 countries by measuring the performance of 15-year-olds in reading, writing and math. In 2025, PISA will aim to measure 22 of those countries' English language skills for the first time.</p>
<p>"It's an <strong>obvious</strong> statement that English <strong>transcends</strong> classroom walls," Christa Rawkins told VOA. She was another one of the researchers for the study.</p>
<p>Teens spoke "about the ways they used English with people on those sorts of social networking sites and other media. But it was rarer that they were talking about sitting down to learn English via those <strong>platforms</strong>."</p>
<p>Some students in Greece said it is easier to search for English-language information on the internet because more of it is available. In the Netherlands, 15-year-olds described watching English YouTube videos. In a written opinion study, half of students in the Netherlands reported always using English when using digital tools.</p>
<p>Teachers however are unsure whether digital tools are improving students' English knowledge. While teachers said using English platforms might increase students' motivation to learn and help them get used to the language, the platforms "are not necessarily teaching them English," Rawkins said.</p>
<p>One teacher in Finland, for example, said students might get the false idea that they do not need to study English because of how often they use English outside of school.</p>
<p>"They think they know it better than I do because they use it in computer games and it's present in their lives all the time," the teacher said. "They think they don't have to listen to me in English classes, I feel that is a <strong>challenge</strong>.</p>
<p>Rawkins said there is a "slight disconnect" between the kind of English students are learning outside of school "and the kind of English they're being asked to learn and study in classrooms." Students might feel that "studying English at school is just about studying <strong>grammar</strong> whereas outside (of) school they can communicate and interact in the language," the report said.</p>
<p>A large part of OECD's work with PISA, the researchers said, is examining <strong>inequities</strong> in education. Rawkins said there can be large inequities that arise from the kinds of out-of-school exposure kids get to English. Kids from wealthy families are able to travel to English-speaking countries or attend summer camps where they can speak English to international friends, for example. Some students can pay for private lessons.</p>
<p>"Kids living in cities were more likely to be using English out and about in their daily lives compared to their counterparts in more rural areas," Rawkins added.</p>
<p>There has been a big change in how students are exposed to English outside of school. But within the classroom, things "hadn't really changed." The report noted how digital technologies are used within the classroom, but traditional teaching methods, like textbooks, were still used in every school observed.</p>
<p>Teachers in all five countries said their students struggled the most with writing and speaking English rather than in reading and listening. Researchers noted that students might feel a lack of self-confidence when it comes to speaking. They might also be less likely to speak and write English outside of school.</p>
<p>"Outside school they're doing a lot of reading and listening to English because that's what the majority of their exposure is, particularly when it comes to digital technologies," Rawkins said. "They're not doing so much speaking or writing."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exposure </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of experiencing or meeting something or someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>digital </strong>–adj. related to computers and computing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>interview </strong>–v. to talk to someone to get information and learn about something they know about</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>obvious </strong><em>— adj. </em>something everyone knows<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transcend </strong><em>— v. </em>to go beyond or above something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>platform </strong>–n. a service or network that distributes information or messages</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>challenge </strong>–n. something that is done that must be overcome or dealt with using effort</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grammar </strong>–n. the rules of language use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inequity </strong><em>— n.(social) </em>the state of being unequal or unbalanced especially when talking about how people feel about social relationships between groups<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Haiti's Leader to Resign amid Gang Violence  (2024/3/13) | 海地总理辞职</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/haiti-s-leader-to-resign-amid-gang-violence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Haitian Prime Minister Ariel Henry announced early Tuesday that he would resign once a transitional council is created. The move followed international pressure to save the country from violent criminal groups.<br/>
海地总理阿里埃尔·亨利周二早些时候宣布，一旦过渡委员会成立，他将辞职。此举是在国际社会施加压力，要求将该国从暴力犯罪集团手中拯救出来之后做出的。</p>
<p>Henry announced the decision hours after meeting with leaders of neighboring Caribbean nations and American Secretary of State Antony Blinken. The group met in Jamaica to discuss a solution to Haiti's crisis. They agreed to a joint proposal to establish a transitional council.<br/>
亨利在与加勒比邻国领导人和美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯会晤数小时后宣布了这一决定。该群体在牙买加举行会议，讨论海地危机的解决方案。他们同意了建立一个过渡委员会的联合提议。</p>
<p>"The government that I'm running cannot remain insensitive in front of this situation. There is no sacrifice that is too big for our country," Henry said in a videotaped statement. "The government I'm running will remove itself immediately after the installation of the council."<br/>
亨利在一份录像声明中说：“我所领导的政府在这种情况面前不能麻木不仁。对我们的国家来说，没有太大的牺牲。我所领导的政府将在委员会成立后立即解散。”</p>
<p>After the announcement, Haitians celebrated in the streets in the capital Port-au-Prince, dancing and playing music, Reuters news agency reported, based on videos posted on Haitian social media.<br/>
据路透社报道，根据海地社交媒体上发布的视频，该消息宣布后，海地人在首都太子港街头载歌载舞地庆祝。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Haiti under Henry<br/>
亨利统治下的海地</span></p>
<p>Henry took power in 2021 following the murder of President Jovenel Moise. Under his administration, armed criminal groups, called gangs, grew in wealth and power.<br/>
亨利于2021年在总统约维尼尔·莫伊兹被谋杀后掌权。在他的领导下，被称为帮派的武装犯罪集团的财富和权力不断增加。</p>
<p>In late February, Henry traveled to Kenya to secure its support for a United Nations-backed security mission to help Haitian police. However, the violence greatly increased in his absence. It led to the closing of the country's main international airports.<br/>
2月下旬，亨利前往肯尼亚，以确保其对联合国支持的一项帮助海地警察的安全任务的支持。然而，在他缺席期间，暴力事件大大增加。这导致该国主要国际机场关闭。</p>
<p>Armed gangs have burned police stations and raided two of the country's biggest prisons. The raids resulted in the release of more than 4,000 prisoners.<br/>
武装团伙烧毁了警察局，并突袭了该国两所最大的监狱。突袭行动导致了4000多名囚犯被释放。</p>
<p>Many Haitians have been killed and more than 15,000 are homeless after fleeing neighborhoods raided by gangs. Stores are running out of goods. Food and water are lacking. The main port in the capital city is closed, keeping supplies away.<br/>
许多海地人被杀害，还有15000多人在逃离被帮派袭击的社区后无家可归。商店里的商品眼看要销售一空。食物和水缺乏。首都的主要港口已经关闭，物资供应中断。</p>
<p>Henry arrived in Puerto Rico a week ago, after being barred from landing in the Dominican Republic, Haiti's neighbor. Dominican officials also closed the airspace to flights to and from Haiti.<br/>
亨利一周前抵达波多黎各，此前他被禁止在海地的邻国多米尼加共和国降落。多米尼加官员还对进出海地的航班关闭了领空。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">International force<br/>
国际力量</span></p>
<p>On Monday, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said the new council would be responsible for meeting the "immediate needs" of Haitians. They include the deployment of an international security mission to help police fight armed criminals.<br/>
周一，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示，新的委员会将负责满足海地人的“迫切需求”。其中包括部署一个国际安全特派团，帮助警察打击武装罪犯。</p>
<p>The U.S. would also provide an additional $100 million to this mission and $33 million in humanitarian aid, bringing the U.S. total promise to $300 million.<br/>
美国还将向这项任务额外提供1亿美元和3300万美元的人道主义援助，使美国的承诺总额达到3亿美元。</p>
<p>A U.N. spokesperson said that, as of Monday, less than $11 million had been provided to the U.N.'s account for the mission. No financial contributions have arrived since Haiti declared its state of emergency on March 3.<br/>
联合国发言人表示，截至周一，联合国负责该任务的账户收到的援助不足1100万美元。自3月3日海地宣布进入紧急状态以来，没有收到任何财政捐款。</p>
<p>As Haiti prepares for new leadership, some experts question the role of armed gangs that control 80 percent of Port-au-Prince.<br/>
在海地筹备新领导层之际，一些专家质疑控制太子港80%地区的武装组织的作用。</p>
<p>"Even if you have a different kind of government, the reality is that you need to talk to the gangs," said Robert Fatton, a Haitian politics expert at the University of Virginia.<br/>
弗吉尼亚大学海地政治专家罗伯特·法顿说：“即使有了一个不同类型的政府，现实是你需要与帮派对话。”</p>
<p>Fatton said officials will still have to deal with the armed groups and try to convince them to give up their weapons, "but what would be their concessions?"<br/>
法顿说，官员们仍将不得不与武装组织打交道，并试图说服他们放弃武器，“但他们会做出什么让步？”</p>
<p>The United Nations estimates over 362,000 people have been internally displaced in Haiti. The organization says thousands have been killed in the conflict overall, with widespread reports of rape, torture and kidnappings since 2021.<br/>
联合国估计，海地境内有362000多人流离失所。该机构表示，自2021年以来，已有数千人在冲突中丧生，同时有大量关于强奸、酷刑和绑架的报道。</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Shevchenko Garden: A Peaceful Oasis in Kharkiv  (2024/3/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/shevchenko-garden-a-peaceful-oasis-in-kharkiv.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/z/7773" target="_blank">Teach Us about Ukraine</a>" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>My name is Oksana Chelombitko. I teach at Chuhuiv Lyceum No. 1. This is my essay.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Taras Shevchenko Park is opposite the university in Kharkiv. (Adobe Stock Photo by Oleh Rode)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1ca4-08dc3c880932_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Taras Shevchenko Park is opposite the university in Kharkiv. (Adobe Stock Photo by Oleh Rode)</span></div>
<p>Shevchenko Garden, located in the heart of Kharkiv, is a significant public park named after the renowned Ukrainian poet Taras Shevchenko. Established in 1907, the garden has a rich history, beginning as a botanical garden showcasing Ukraine's diverse flora. Over the years, it has transformed into a beloved recreational space, hosting various events, art exhibitions and concerts, making it an integral part of Kharkiv's cultural scene.</p>
<p>In addition to its cultural significance, Shevchenko Garden plays a crucial role in preserving biodiversity. The park is home to a wide range of plant and animal species, some of which are rare and endangered. You can freely visit the modern and renovated Kharkiv Zoo, which is located in Shevchenko Garden. Efforts are made by the park's caretakers to maintain the ecological balance, ensuring the conservation of these species for future generations.</p>
<p>The garden's allure is not only in its natural beauty but also in its ability to bring people together. Families gather for picnics, children enjoy outdoor activities, and artists find inspiration amidst the serene surroundings. There are small, cozy cafes and ice cream stalls, restaurants, and coffee shops, a concert hall, and an opera house. Lots of people spend their time in this peaceful and tranquil place. Shevchenko Garden serves as a symbol of unity in Kharkiv, welcoming people from diverse backgrounds and fostering a sense of community. This is very important nowadays during the war; people in Kharkiv are courageous and resilient. They adore the city and make it better every single day.</p>
<p>Today, Shevchenko Garden stands as a testament to the city's cultural richness and the harmonious existence of nature and humanity. It continues to be a peaceful oasis where visitors can experience the beauty of nature and the spirit of Kharkiv in a peaceful setting.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the Writer</h2>
<p>Oksana Chelombitko was born and still lives in Chuhuiv, a city in eastern Ukraine. She graduated from Skovoroda Kharkiv National Pedagogical University and has worked as a teacher for 11 years. They have been learning online only since September 2022, and she misses her students in person. Despite the war in their country, they are working hard for a better future.</p>
<p><em>What do you think of this story? Let us know in the Comments.</em></p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pacific’s Gray Whale Found off Atlantic Coast  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/pacific-s-gray-whale-found-off-atlantic-coast.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have confirmed the presence of a gray whale off New England in North America recently.</p>
<p>The large sea animal disappeared from the Atlantic Ocean two centuries ago. The scientists are <strong>thrilled</strong> with the discovery but they say it shows the effects of climate change on sea life.</p>
<p>Researchers with the New England Aquarium in Boston found the gray whale on March 1. At the time, they were flying about 48 kilometers south of Nantucket, an island off the coast of Massachusetts in the Atlantic. The whale, which can weigh over 27,000 kilograms, usually lives in the northern Pacific Ocean.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo by Orla O'Brien shows a gray whale south of Nantucket, Massachusetts, on March 1, 2024. (Orla O'Brien/New England Aquarium via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4df06435-4a5a-48fe-9f23-5371a5704f55_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo by Orla O'Brien shows a gray whale south of Nantucket, Massachusetts, on March 1, 2024. (Orla O'Brien/New England Aquarium via AP)</span></div>
<p>The gray whale disappeared from the Atlantic Ocean by the 18th century. But there have been five observations of the animal in the Atlantic and Mediterranean waters in the last 15 years, the aquarium said in a statement. The whale found this month was likely the same animal observed off the coast of Florida late last year, the aquarium said.</p>
<p>The researchers who found the animal off Massachusetts said they were not sure at first. But after circling the area for 45 minutes, they were able to take photographs that confirmed it was a gray whale.</p>
<p>"I didn't want to say out loud what it was, because it seemed <strong>crazy</strong>," said Orla O'Brien. She is a research scientist with the Anderson Cabot Center for Ocean Life at the New England Aquarium.</p>
<p>Scientists said they were thrilled to see the animal, but its presence probably has to do with the warming of the planet. The Northwest Passage, which connects the Atlantic and Pacific oceans through the Arctic Ocean in Canada, has lacked ice in the summertime in recent years, they said.</p>
<p>That means gray whales can travel through the passage in the summer when normally they would have been blocked, the scientists said. O'Brien said the animal's arrival off New England serves "as a reminder of how quickly <strong>marine species</strong> respond to climate change, given the chance."</p>
<p>Gray whales were almost completely killed off by hunting during the years of <strong>commercial</strong> whaling. Today, the whales have recovered to the point that they are considered a species of "least concern" by the International Union for Conservation of Nature. The organization, however, considers the western population of whales that live off the coast of Asia to be endangered.</p>
<p>They can be identified by the lack of a part of a body often seen on other whales: a dorsal fin. Also, they can be identified by their <strong>blotchy</strong> appearance which is different from the humpback and minke whales seen off New England. Gray whales can also be identified by the unusual sounds they make.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Patrick Whittle reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>thrill </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling of great excitement or happiness</p>
<p><strong>crazy </strong><em>– adj. </em>very strange or unusual</p>
<p><strong>marine </strong><em>– adj. </em>of or relating to the sea or the plants and animals that live in the sea</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong><em>– adj. </em>concerned with earning money</p>
<p><strong>blotchy </strong><em>– n. </em>a usually dark-colored spot especially on the skin</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Grow Mini-organs in Cells from Pregnancy Fluid  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/scientists-grow-mini-organs-in-cells-from-pregnancy-fluid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health and Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>British researchers say they have grown small human organs using cells removed from fluid that protects developing fetuses.</p>
<p>These organs are known as mini-organs, or organoids. They are extremely small, simple structures. They could be used in testing of new medical treatments or to study the workings of full-size organs.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This microscope image provided by researchers in March 2024 shows a lung organoid created from cells collected from amniotic fluid. (Giuseppe Cal&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;224;, Paolo De Coppi, Mattia Gerli via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4d2a-08dc3eb3e96f_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This microscope image provided by researchers in March 2024 shows a lung organoid created from cells collected from amniotic fluid. (Giuseppe Cal<i>&amp;#</i>224;, Paolo De Coppi, Mattia Gerli via AP)</span></div>
<p>The University College London carried out the study. Researchers collected the cells from fluid removed from 12 pregnant women during routine medical examinations at Great Ormond Street Hospital in London.</p>
<p>The cells then were grown into organoids in a laboratory. The researchers said it was the first time such mini-organs had been produced from cells collected during an active pregnancy.</p>
<p>The scientists said they hope their method will lead to future methods for treating conditions present before birth.</p>
<p>Mattia Gerli of University College London was a lead writer of the study. He told the<em> </em>Associated Press (AP) that he and his team were "really excited" about how their research might result in important new treatment possibilities.</p>
<p>The findings were reported <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-024-02807-z">in a study</a> that recently appeared in the publication <em>Nature Medicine.</em></p>
<p>Scientists have so far produced organoids that look like some human organs, including the brain, kidney, lung, stomach and liver. Lab-grown mini-organs are generally used to study how organs work without the need to experiment on real ones.</p>
<p>The scientists looked for which tissues the stem cells came from and then identified cells from three organs: lungs, kidneys and intestines.</p>
<p>In the past, organoids could only be created from adult stem cells or tissues collected after an abortion. An abortion is a medical operation to end a pregnancy.</p>
<p>The current method does not violate rules that govern direct removal of stem cells from fetal tissue. The amniotic fluid method permits scientists to get cells from fetuses during the <strong>latter</strong> parts of pregnancy.</p>
<p>Governments around the world have different <strong>regulations</strong> covering abortions. In Britain, the legal limit for ending a pregnancy is generally 22 weeks after <strong>conception</strong>. This rule prevents British researchers from studying some parts of normal human development or diseases that are present past 22 weeks.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>In the United States, abortion restrictions differ by state. Most states ban the use of fetal tissue for research, said Alta Charo. She is a retired professor of law and bioethics at the University of Wisconsin at Madison. Charo was not part of the latest study.</p>
<p>Fetal tissue is <a class="wsw__a" href="https://grants.nih.gov/grants/policy/nihgps/html5/section_4/4.1.14_human_fetal_tissue_research.htm#:~:text=Human%20fetal%20tissue%20is%20defined,or%20induced%20abortion%20or%20stillbirth.">defined</a> by the National Institutes of Health as material coming from a dead human embryo or fetus. The tissue could come from a fetus that was aborted or did not survive because of medical problems with the pregnancy. The use of tissue from an abortion has long been <strong>controversial</strong>.</p>
<p>Charo said the new method does not raise the same <strong>ethical </strong>concerns. And taking amniotic fluid during a woman's pregnancy "does not appear to add any physical risks to either fetus or pregnant woman," Charo said in an email to the AP.</p>
<p>As part of the experiments, the researchers worked with scientists in Belgium to study the development of babies with a condition called congenital diaphragmatic hernia. This can result in organs such as the liver and intestines getting displaced into the chest. About 30 percent of fetuses with this disease die because the lungs cannot fully develop. If doctors could identify the condition before birth, they could operate on a fetus to fix it.</p>
<p>In the experiments, researchers grew lung organoids from the cells of fetuses with the hernia condition before and after treatment. When comparing those organoids to organoids from healthy fetuses, the team was able to use the lab method to identify the affected child's condition before birth.</p>
<p>The scientists said this ability to study working, pre-birth mini-organs is the first step toward establishing more detailed <strong>prognosis</strong> information and improving treatment methods.</p>
<p>And that's the Health and Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conception </strong><em>– n. </em>the moment when a woman or animal becomes pregnant</p>
<p><strong>controversial </strong><em>– adj. </em>causing a lot of disagreement or argument</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to what is right or wrong</p>
<p><strong>latter</strong> - <em>adj</em>. coming or happening near the end of a process, activity, series, life, etc</p>
<p><strong>regulation</strong> - <em>n</em>. an official rule or law that says how something should be done</p>
<p><strong>prognosis </strong><em>– n. </em>a judgement<em> </em>a doctor makes about a sick person's change of becoming healthy</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>War and Peace at the Oscars  (2024/3/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/war-and-peace-at-the-oscars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>American film <em>Oppenheimer</em> was the big winner at the Academy Awards Sunday in Los Angeles, California. The Academy honored the film about a creator of the atomic bomb with seven Oscars.</p>
<p>The televised event presented a usual mix of moods and messages. There was a reminder of the recent death in a Russian prison of opposition leader Alexei Navalny. Demonstrators called for a cease-fire in Gaza at a protest outside the Dolby Theatre where the event took place. And there was a bit of election-year politics from ceremony host Jimmy Kimmel.</p>
<p>But there was also joyful<strong> </strong>fun, as when actor Ryan Gosling performed <em>I'm</em> <em>Just Ken</em>, a nominated song from the film <em>Barbie</em>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Oppenheimer British film producer Emma Thomas (C) accepts the award for Best Picture onstage during the 96th Annual Academy Awards at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, California on March 10, 2024. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/bb27ae2e-5806-472f-ba71-e44ac495bcd1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">"Oppenheimer" British film producer Emma Thomas (C) accepts the award for Best Picture onstage during the 96th Annual Academy Awards at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, California on March 10, 2024. (Photo by Patrick T. Fallon / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The night, though, belonged not to <em>Barbie</em> but to its partner in the cultural event known as "Barbenheimer."</p>
<p><em>Oppenheimer's</em> seven wins include the top prize of best picture. Director Christopher Nolan also took home the Oscar for directing while the film's star Cillian Murphy received the best actor award. And <em>Oppenheimer's</em> Robert Downey Jr won the Oscar for best supporting actor. It is his first Academy Award.</p>
<p>Many of those wins were expected, but the Oscars did hold some surprises. The race for the best actress was considered very close this year. And, Emma Stone looked shocked when her name was called for her performance in the movie, <em>Poor Things</em>.</p>
<p>Stone won her first Oscar, also for best actress, in 2017 for <em>La La Land</em>.</p>
<p>Here are some more of the night's notable moments:</p>
<p>Jimmy Kimmel was hosting the Academy Awards for a fourth time. Late in the show he presented a social media post about the ceremony from former president Donald Trump.</p>
<p>"Thank you for watching," Kimmel said, adding, "isn't it past your jail time?"</p>
<p><strong>A call for peace In Ukraine...</strong></p>
<p><em>Associated Press</em> reporter Mstyslav Chernov, was one of the filmmakers accepting the best documentary Oscar for <em>20 Days in Mariupol</em>. He noted that it was the first Oscar in the history of his country, Ukraine. He said he was honored – but then added: "Probably I will be the first director on this stage to say I wish I'd never made this film." The film is an account of the early days of Russia's invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</p>
<p>Chernov called on Russia to end the war in Ukraine. "We can make sure that the history record is set straight ... and those who have given their lives, will never be forgotten," he said.</p>
<p><strong>And in Gaza</strong></p>
<p>Jonathan Glazer's <em>The Zone of Interest</em> takes place during World War II. It is about the family of a Nazi commandant living next to the Auschwitz death camp. But it was a current war that the writer-director spoke about when accepting his Oscar for best international film.</p>
<p>"Our film shows where dehumanization leads at its worst," Glazer said, before speaking about the conflict in Gaza. "Right now we stand here as men who <strong>refute</strong> their Jewishness and the Holocaust being hijacked by an occupation which has led to conflict for so many innocent people," he said. "Whether the victims of October the 7th in Israel or the ongoing attack on Gaza, all the victims of this dehumanization, how do we resist?"</p>
<p><strong>A sad reminder</strong></p>
<p>"If they decide to kill me, it means that we are incredibly strong." Those words from Navalny, the Russian opposition leader, began the memorial to industry members who died over the year. He was the subject of last year's winning documentary, <em>Navalny</em>. His wife stood on the Oscar stage that night and spoke directly to him: "Alexei, I am dreaming of the day when you will be free and our country will be free," Yulia Navalnaya said.</p>
<p><strong>Nolan's ‘incredible journey'</strong></p>
<p>Winning his first directing Oscar, the 53-year-old Nolan noted that <strong>cinema</strong> is just over 100 years old. "Imagine being there 100 years into painting or theater. We don't know where this <strong>incredible journey</strong> is going from here. But to know that you think that I'm a meaningful part of it means the world to me."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>refute </strong><em>— v. </em>to say that something is not true</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cinema </strong><em>— n. </em>the film industry</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>incredible </strong><em>— adj. </em> difficult or impossible to believe</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>journey </strong><em>— n. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Britain’s Princess Kate Apologizes for ‘Confusion’ over Official Photo  (2024/3/12) | 凯特王妃为P图造成混乱道歉</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/britain-s-princess-kate-apologizes-for-confusion-over-official-photo.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Kate, Britain's Princess of Wales, apologized Monday for "any confusion" caused by a photo released over the weekend. The official photo was the first image of the princess since she had a medical operation nearly two months ago.<br/>
英国威尔士王妃凯特周一为周末发布的一张照片造成的“任何混乱”道歉。这张官方照片是凯特王妃近两个月前接受医疗手术后的第一张照片。</p>
<p>Kensington Palace released the photograph on social media on Sunday. It showed the 42-year-old Kate looking healthy and sitting and smiling in a chair surrounded by her three children. The photo was credited to Kate's husband, Prince William, and was said to have been taken earlier in the week in Windsor.<br/>
肯辛顿宫周日在社交媒体上发布了这张照片。照片显示，42岁的凯特看起来很健康，她坐在椅子上面带微笑，身边环绕着她的三个孩子。这张照片被当成凯特王妃的丈夫威廉王子的作品，据说是本周早些时候在温莎城堡拍摄的。</p>
<p>In a message on X, Kate wrote, "Thank you for your kind wishes and continued support over the last two months." Her message also wished people a "Happy Mother's Day," as Britain celebrated the holiday on Sunday.<br/>
凯特在X网站上的一条消息中写道：“感谢你们过去两个月里的善意祝福和持续支持。”在英国周日庆祝母亲节之际，凯特还祝人们“母亲节快乐”。</p>
<p>But shortly after the photo was published, some royal observers online began raising questions about whether the picture had been changed in some ways with image editing tools.<br/>
但在照片发布后不久，网络上的一些王室观察人员开始质疑这张照片是否经过了图像编辑工具的某种修改。</p>
<p>
After close examination, several major news organizations withdrew the photo, saying it did in fact appear to have been edited in some way. Because of these changes, the picture did not meet the requirements set by those news organizations.<br/>
经过仔细检查，几家主要新闻机构撤回了这张照片，称其实际上似乎经过了某种编辑。由于这些改动，图片不符合这些新闻机构设定的要求。</p>
<p>After the questions about the image were raised, Kate issued another message on X. She wrote, "Like many amateur photographers, I do occasionally experiment with editing. I wanted to express my apologies for any confusion the family photograph we shared yesterday caused."<br/>
在人们对这张照片提出质疑后，凯特在X上发布了另一条消息。她写道：“和许多业余摄影师一样，我偶尔也会尝试修图。我想对我们昨天分享的全家福造成的任何混乱表示歉意。”</p>
<p>Among the news agencies withdrawing the photo were The Associated Press, Reuters, the French news agency AFP, Getty Images, and Britain's Press Association.<br/>
撤回这张照片的新闻机构包括美联社、路透社、法国法新社、盖蒂图片社和英国新闻协会。</p>
<p>Photo editors for Reuters said their examinations of the image showed the left arm of Kate's daughter, Princess Charlotte, did not seem to line up naturally with her body in the picture. This suggested that editing changes had been made to the photo.<br/>
路透社的图片编辑表示，他们对照片的检查显示，凯特王妃的女儿夏洛特公主的左臂似乎与照片中的身体对不上。这表明对照片进行了编辑更改。</p>
<p>Different news agencies have different policies regarding how much an image can be changed before being released. Both Reuters and the AP said the changes violated their editorial rules. Most news organizations generally only permit minor photo editing, such as cropping and making light and color changes.<br/>
各家新闻机构对图片在发布前可以有多大调整有着不同的政策。路透社和美联社都表示，这些调整违反了他们的编辑规则。大多数新闻机构通常只允许对照片进行小的编辑，如裁剪、调整光线和颜色。</p>
<p>The picture had already drawn widespread media attention online. This is because it was the first official image of Kate since she spent two weeks in the hospital after undergoing an abdominal operation in January. Her exact condition was not identified.<br/>
这张照片已经在网上引起了媒体的广泛关注。这是凯特一月份接受腹部手术并住院两周后的第一张官方照片。她的确切情况尚未确定。</p>
<p>Kate's office had said during her absence that she was recovering well and was not expected to return to her public duties until after Easter, which is March 31.<br/>
凯特办公室在她缺席期间表示，她恢复得很好，预计要到3月31日复活节后才能重返公职。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Data Suggests Jupiter’s Moon Europa Has Less Oxygen than Expected  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/new-data-suggests-jupiter-s-moon-europa-has-less-oxygen-than-expected.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests Jupiter's icy moon Europa produces much less oxygen than previously thought.</p>
<p>The study was based on data collected by the American space agency NASA's Juno spacecraft. Juno is an orbiter that has been studying Jupiter since July 2016.</p>
<p>The study involved Juno's instruments measuring levels of oxygen and hydrogen molecules coming from Europa's atmosphere. The data showed the icy moon produces about 1,000 tons of oxygen every 24 hours. NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/juno/nasas-juno-mission-measures-oxygen-production-at-europa/">said</a> that amount would be enough "to keep a million humans breathing for a day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image made available by NASA in 2014 shows Jupiter's icy moon Europa in a reprocessed color view, made from images captured by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/SETI Institute via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-cfbd-08dc3f79ca56_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image made available by NASA in 2014 shows Jupiter's icy moon Europa in a reprocessed color view, made from images captured by NASA's Galileo spacecraft in the late 1990s. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/SETI Institute via AP)</span></div>
<p>However, the space agency noted those oxygen level estimates were "<strong>substantially</strong> less" than those measured in earlier studies about the moon.</p>
<p>Europa is a little smaller than Earth's moon. But it is still one of the largest in our solar system. NASA observations have suggested an ocean exists beneath a thick layer of ice on Europa's surface. Scientists estimate the moon's ocean may contain twice the amount of water as Earth's oceans.</p>
<p>The new study is based on data Juno collected in 2022 during a particularly close flyby of Europa. The flyby is believed to have brought the spacecraft within 350 kilometers of the moon.</p>
<p>The research was led by teams from Princeton University in New Jersey and Maryland's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/">Southwest Research Institute</a>. The scientists estimated Europa is producing around 12 kilograms of oxygen per second. Earlier predictions suggested the moon was releasing up to 1,000 kilograms per second.</p>
<p>Since Europa is believed to have a large ocean under its surface, researchers in the past identified it <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/ocean-on-jupiter-moon-europa-may-have-supported-life/5481557.html">as a good candidate</a> to hold the right conditions to support some form of life. That data came mainly from telescope observations of oxygen levels existing in the moon's icy surface.</p>
<p>The new, lower oxygen estimates do not support the earlier observations. The team involved in the study said more research will be needed to confirm the latest findings.</p>
<p>Scott Bolton is a Juno investigator at the Southwest Research Institute and a co-writer of the study. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/press-release/juno-spacecraft-measures-oxygen-production-jupiter-s-moon-europa">said</a> in a statement that the team's new findings have a direct effect on the possibility that Europa could be <strong>habitable</strong>. While the oxygen amounts measured were much lower, the latest study gives scientists "a narrow range that could support habitability," Bolton said.</p>
<p>Princeton University researcher Jamey Szalay was the study's lead writer. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/press-release/juno-spacecraft-measures-oxygen-production-jupiter-s-moon-europa">said</a>, "The findings <strong>unambiguously</strong> demonstrate oxygen is continuously produced at the surface, just a good bit lower than we expected."</p>
<p>Szalay added that Juno's flyby of Europa marked the first time a spacecraft was able to directly measure the moon's atmosphere. "We couldn't wait to <strong>peek behind the curtain</strong> of its complex environment," he wrote to The Associated Press in an email.</p>
<p>The researchers said the new measurements can help scientists gain a better understanding of Europa and its environment, and "open the door for newer, more <strong>precise</strong> models."</p>
<p>Robert Ebert is a researcher at the Southwest Research Institute and a co-writer of the study. He said that even with the new results, he believes further investigations should take place to search for signs of life on Europa. "Water is important for the existence of life... Europa is a good place to search for water within our solar system."</p>
<p>NASA hopes to launch its Europa Clipper mission in October. This orbiter is designed to carry out close examinations of Europa. It will look for signs it might hold the right conditions to support life.</p>
<p>NASA says the orbiter plans to fly in orbit around Jupiter and "perform repeated close flybys of the ice moon."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, NASA, Nature Astronomy and the Southwest Research Institute. </em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>substantial </strong><em>– n. </em>large in amount</p>
<p><strong>habitable </strong><em>– adj. </em>able to support life</p>
<p><strong>unambiguous </strong><em>– n. </em>expressed in a very clear way</p>
<p><strong>peek behind the curtain </strong><em>– n. </em>get a look at something not normally seen</p>
<p><strong>precise</strong><em> – adj. </em>very clear or exact<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Garden Expert Tries New Fruits, Vegetables  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/garden-expert-tries-new-fruits-vegetables.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Jessica Damiano says crops like tomatoes, garlic, chives, basil, parsley, thyme, and sage have been permanent plants in her <strong>garden</strong> for ages. Damiano, a gardening expert who writes for The Associated Press, says every year, she experiments with new – or new to her – crops.</p>
<p>Many do not stay in her garden for long, like the Voyager tomatoes that lack taste or the goji berries she could not seem to eat. But others, like 8-ball zucchini, rainbow Swiss chard, and golden beets have earned permanent homes in her raised beds.</p>
<p>This year's new introductions are available in seed <strong>catalogs</strong> in the U.S.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co. shows Lila Lu Sang carrots, which are deep purple on the outside and bright orange on the inside. (Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co./rareseeds.com via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/673143a3-5d61-4aac-8711-ae45eb5d8372_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co. shows Lila Lu Sang carrots, which are deep purple on the outside and bright orange on the inside. (Baker Creek Heirloom Seed Co./rareseeds.com via AP)</span></div>
<p>Four small apple trees from Plants Nouveau called Blushing Delight, Golden Treat, Tangy Green, and Tasty Red, work well for people like Damiano who have limited garden space. The trees grow to 2.5 to 3 meters tall and just a meter wide. And they will even grow in containers. You can plant two different kinds for cross-<strong>pollination</strong> and fruit production.</p>
<p>Another crop, Love Gourmansun beefsteak tomatoes from Burpee, is available in two different kinds that each produce 28-gram, heart-shaped fruits. Choose between Red and a yellow-red fruit called Sunrise. They grow in similar ways and taste similar, but have different disease resistance.</p>
<p>Damiano said she tested another crop from Burpee called Prism Sweet Peppers last summer. She said the sweet, bell-shaped fruits grew well in her garden. The productive plants also added beauty to her garden, as the crop turned from light green to orange and then red as the fruit aged. The result was many different colors of fruits on the plants at any one time.</p>
<p>The crop Quick Snack cucumbers are the newest addition to PanAm Seed's Kitchen Minis collection. They are small enough to be grown in a hanging basket or even indoors since they do not require pollination. The small cucumbers are <strong>crisp</strong> and sweet.</p>
<p>The Pastel Duo baby turnip seed mix, introduced from Japan by Renee's Garden, grows small, round roots in colors like pink and white. Both colors have a <strong>mild</strong>, sweet taste and thin skin that does not need to be removed.</p>
<p>Damiano says her Genovese basil plants often get the disease downy mildew more often than not. She said she is looking forward to growing Noga Prospera Active DMR <strong>organic </strong>basil, produced by Genesis Seeds. The plants are sold as "highly resistant" to the disease. But they are also slow to flower, which she says is another problem she often deals with in the height of the summer's heat.</p>
<p>Finally, the crop Lila Lu Sang carrots offered by Baker Seeds are just about as eye-catching as vegetables can get. They have a deep purple color on the outside and a bright orange color on the inside. But they are more than what one sees: they contain the gains of both purple and orange carrots. They are sweet, tasty and full of nutrients.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong><em>– n. </em>an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>catalog </strong><em>– n. </em>a book containing a list of things that you can buy or use and often pictures</p>
<p><strong>pollinate </strong><em>– v.</em> to give (a plant) pollen from another plant of the same kind so that seeds will be produced</p>
<p><strong>crisp </strong><em>– adj.</em> pleasantly firm and making a sharp sound when chewed or crushed</p>
<p><strong>mild </strong><em>– adj. </em>not strong or harsh in taste</p>
<p><strong>organic </strong><em>– adj.</em> grown or made without the use of artificial chemicals</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France's 'Invader' Could Surprise Olympic Games Visitors  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/france-s-invader-could-surprise-olympic-games-visitors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>When visitors come to Paris for the Olympic Games starting in July, they will be entering the territory of France's most famous street artist: "Invader." It will be one invasion coming face-to-face with another.</p>
<p>Like Banksy, the British street artist he is sometimes compared to, Invader does not want his identity to be publicly known.</p>
<p>Sometimes working close to the edge of illegality, Invader comes, does his art, and disappears into the night. He leaves behind <strong>mosaics</strong> made mostly with small ceramic and glass <strong>tiles</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A mosaic by French artist Invader floats in the International Space Station in 2015. (Samantha Cristoforetti/ESA-NASA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8cd7e268-24be-4394-9b03-65b5e669f695_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A mosaic by French artist Invader floats in the International Space Station in 2015. (Samantha Cristoforetti/ESA-NASA via AP)</span></div>
<p>Many of the mosaics look like the aliens from the Space Invaders video game. Others are very complex <strong>portrayals</strong> of fruit or, in New York, of Lou Reed and Andy Warhol.</p>
<p>Some of his artworks come from popular culture, including Spiderman, Star Wars, Bugs Bunny, Ninja Turtles, pizza and others. Some artworks suggest deep research, including a portrait of guitarist Django Reinhardt facing the house where he lived, south of Paris in Samois-sur-Seine.</p>
<p>Since the first recorded mosaic of a blue Space Invader went up on a Paris street in 1998, numbered PA_01, Invader has taken over the world. There are now more than 4,000 of his mosaics in cities and towns on all continents except Antarctica.</p>
<p>London, Tokyo, Los Angeles and other cities were invaded in 1999; New York and Geneva and more in 2000; Hong Kong in 2001; Berlin, Bangkok, Melbourne. On and on.</p>
<p>The 4,000th mosaic was <strong>glued</strong> to a brick wall in Potosi, 4,000 meters up in the Bolivian Andes, in 2021. The European Space Agency installed Invader's Space2 mosaic aboard the International Space Station in 2015.</p>
<p>"‘Anytime, Anywhere' is the philosophy," Invader says on his website.</p>
<p>In Paris — by far his most invaded area — the artist's footprint is larger than ever as the Olympics draw closer.</p>
<p>A new public showing in a multi-story building has one of his works on its roof, visible via satellite on Google Maps. With a telescope, the show's visitors can also look across Paris to Invader's 1,500th mosaic in the city and surrounding areas.</p>
<p>Announced in February, PA_1500 is glued outside a chimney of the Pompidou Center. Unlike many of his other artworks, Invader got the center's permission to put the red-and-white Space Invader alien into place.</p>
<p>"It's a <strong>symbol</strong>. It's number 1,500. It's Paris," said Alexandre Aumis, the building's security director. He added, "It's got to be here."</p>
<p>Some of those who know Invader say they are expecting him to spring more surprises for the Olympics, perhaps installing new mosaics related to the Games.</p>
<p>Fabrice Bousteau is the <strong>editor</strong> of Beaux Arts Magazine. He said, "The invasion is the 15 million people who are going to arrive in Paris for the Olympic Games. It's a lot. Obviously, there will be Invader fans among them."</p>
<p>Bousteau, who also directed Invader's latest public showing, added, "So there will be this meeting between two cultures...He will doubtless invade the Games in a different way. I am almost certain."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Leicester reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mosaic<em> </em></strong><em>– n. </em> a kind of art made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material</p>
<p><strong>tile </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat piece of material that is used for covering walls, floors, etc.</p>
<p><strong>portrayal </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong> the act of showing someone or something especially in a painting</p>
<p><strong>glue </strong><em>-- v. </em>to make (something) stick to something else by using glue</p>
<p><strong>chimney<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the part of a building that sticks up above the roof</p>
<p><strong>symbol </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>an object that expresses or represents a particular idea</p>
<p><strong>editor </strong><em>-- n. </em> a person whose job is to edit something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dovbush Rocks: Secrets of the Stone Giants  (2024/3/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/dovbush-rocks-secrets-of-the-stone-giants.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>Hello everyone. My name is Natalia Lavryk. I am an English teacher from Ukraine. I would like to introduce you to my country—its beautiful nature and very hard-working and friendly people, who most of all want peace, freedom, and independence.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Dovbush rocks, a group of rocks, natural and man-made caves carved into stone. Photo taken on Oct. 22, 2020. (Adobe Stock Photo by Iryna_l)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5ed2-08dc3d5b737b_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Dovbush rocks, a group of rocks, natural and man-made caves carved into stone. Photo taken on Oct. 22, 2020. (Adobe Stock Photo by Iryna_l)</span></div>
<p>As the world watches Ukraine's fight for freedom, its soldiers have become a symbol of unbreakable resistance. For Ukrainians, nothing represents that spirit more than the giant stones in the Carpathian Mountains called Dovbush Rocks.</p>
<p>Located on the border of Ivano-Frankivsk and Lviv areas, Dovbush Rocks covers about 100 hectares. The website <a class="wsw__a" href="https://vidviday.ua/blog/en/dovbush-rocks-carpathian-mountains/">vidviday.ua</a> says the volcanic giant stones once rested at the bottom of the ancient sea. They are now surrounded by green forests. Named a national monument in 1981, they are seen as a "place of power" and are popular with visitors seeking a mystical experience.</p>
<p>The rocks are named after Oleksa Dovbush, a Robin Hood-like figure, who used them as a hideout in the 18th century. As a leader of a group of rebels, he fought against the oppressive forces that ruled the area. The rocky terrain, with its numerous caves and narrow passages, provided the perfect refuge for Dovbush and his followers.</p>
<p>Ancient storytellers said that Oleksa was killed by the husband of his former lover Dzvinka, who turned into a rock for her betrayal. And Oleksa's body was dismembered and spread throughout the mountains.</p>
<p><strong>Visiting Dovbush Rocks</strong></p>
<p>Last summer I visited this mysterious place with my students from the Lyceum of Otyniia, a school for students ages six to 17. The energy of this place is impossible to forget. We felt there was a special force that inspired us to do great things and build our inner strength.</p>
<p>The path through the cave is so narrow that, at times, it may seem that there is no way out. In some places, the distance between the rocks is very narrow, only 20 to 30 centimeters wide. In the caves between the rocks, it gets darker and you can hear the rustling of bats' wings and the echo of dripping water.</p>
<p>Above the cave is an unusual rock in the image of a lion. Visitors can climb on top of the lion to see the beautiful view of Prykarpattia and look for their hopes and dreams on a "wishing stone."</p>
<p>According to folk legend, the lion is there to guard Dovbush's buried treasure which no one has been able to find yet. It is said that after Dovbush's death, his fellow rebels hid gold taken from tavern keepers and merchants in the Odynets cave. The entry to the cave is covered by a rotating stone. One needs to say a magic word to turn the stone and open a passage to the cave. The person who knew that magic word died long ago. So the gold has been lying under the rock for more than a hundred years.</p>
<p>Another mysterious place is Devil's Gorge. Only 20 centimeters wide, the gorge is difficult to get through. People put a lot of effort into getting through this narrow gap because, as legend has it, they could be set free of sin.</p>
<p>For Ukrainians, Dovbush Rocks represents both the power of nature and the resilience of the human spirit. The rock formation inspires us to rethink our place in nature, and our culture and history. It is a beautiful place where everyone should experience all its magic for themselves.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Europe’s Digital Act Forces Tech Companies to Change  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/europe-s-digital-act-forces-tech-companies-to-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Europeans can now choose what online services, including <strong>browsers</strong> and search engines, to use for their mobile phones and computers. They can also choose where to download iPhone <strong>apps</strong> and how their personal online data is used.</p>
<p>They are part of changes required under the Digital Markets Act (DMA). The DMA is a set of European Union laws that six large technology companies had to start following recently. Those companies include Amazon, Apple, Microsoft, Google parent Alphabet, Facebook owner Meta, and TikTok owner ByteDance.</p>
<p>The DMA is the latest in a series of laws that Europe has passed as a world leader in controlling large tech companies. The companies have followed by changing long-held ways of doing business. For example, Apple will permit people to download smartphone apps outside of its App Store.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Google's first datacenter in Germany is pictured during its inauguration in Hanau near Frankfurt, Germany, Oct. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Probst, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/397c0153-2ef3-41fe-9ff6-b68ff64c19bb_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Google's first datacenter in Germany is pictured during its inauguration in Hanau near Frankfurt, Germany, Oct. 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Michael Probst, File)</span></div>
<p>Here's a look at how the Digital Markets Act will work:</p>
<p><strong>What companies have to follow the rules?</strong></p>
<p>Some 22 services, from operating systems to messenger apps and social media companies, fall under the DMA.</p>
<p>They include Google services like Maps, YouTube, the Chrome browser and the Android operating system. Others are the online store Amazon's Marketplace and Apple's Safari browser and operating system iOS.</p>
<p>Meta's social media and messaging sites Facebook, Instagram, and WhatsApp are included as well as Microsoft's operating system Windows and social media site LinkedIn.</p>
<p>The companies face the threat of large fines of up to 20 percent of their yearly worldwide income for repeated violations. That could amount to billions of dollars. And they also face the threat of a breakup for major violations.</p>
<p><strong>What effect will the rules have around the world?</strong></p>
<p>Zach Meyers is an assistant director at the Center for European Reform, a research organization. He said, "If it works, many Western countries will probably try to follow the DMA..."</p>
<p>Already, countries like Japan, Britain, Mexico, South Korea, Australia, Brazil, and India are writing their own versions of DMA-like rules. The aim is to prevent tech companies from having too much control over online markets.</p>
<p><strong>How will downloading apps change?</strong></p>
<p>In one of the biggest changes, Apple has said it will let European iPhone users download apps outside its App Store, which comes with its devices.</p>
<p>Apple has long opposed such a move. A large part of its income comes from the 30 percent charge it demands for payments made through iOS apps. Apple has warned that downloading apps outside of its store will come with added security risks.</p>
<p>Now, Apple is cutting those charges for developers in Europe that choose to stay with its payment-processing system. But Apple is adding a 55-cent fee for each iOS app downloaded through outside app stores. Critics say that will persuade existing free apps to not use outside stores.</p>
<p>Avery Gardiner is a director at the music company Spotify. She said those outside app stores will never grow because they will be missing many apps that would need to be there for people to want to use those stores.</p>
<p><strong>How will people get more choices online?</strong></p>
<p>Users of mobile devices will have more choices online.</p>
<p>They will not be forced to use certain services like Apple's Safari browser or Google search engine. Android users can choose which search engine to use, and iPhone users will get to choose which browser will be their main one. Microsoft, meanwhile, will stop forcing people to use its Edge browser.</p>
<p>Some Google search results will show up differently because the DMA bans companies from giving <strong>preference</strong> to their own services. So, for example, searches for hotels will now show a list of <strong>booking</strong> sites like Expedia.</p>
<p>Users can also stop companies from using their online data to target them with advertising.</p>
<p>The DMA also requires messaging systems to be able to work with each other.</p>
<p>Meta owns two messaging apps that fall under the rules. So it is expected to come up with a proposal on how Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp users can send messages, videos, and images to each other.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of software that you can download to a device such as a smartphone or tablet, for example to look up information or to play a game</p>
<p><strong>browser </strong><em>– n. </em>a computer program that lets you look at or read documents on the World Wide Web</p>
<p><strong>preference </strong><em>– n. </em>a greater interest in or desire for somebody/something than somebody/something else</p>
<p><strong>booking </strong><em>– n</em>. an arrangement to have something (such as a room) held for your use at a later time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Uncover ‘Secrets’ of African Sand Dune  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/researchers-uncover-secrets-of-african-sand-dune.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers have used radar and other technologies to study a large "star" sand <strong>dune</strong> in eastern Morocco. The team said it was able to capture detailed data on how these dunes form and develop.</p>
<p>A star dune is named after its shape because it can look like a star when seen from above. These structures are very large and have a hill, or peak, at the top. They have large masses, called arms, spreading out from the peak. Star dunes are shaped by wind and other conditions in the environment.</p>
<p>Star dunes are common in deserts and can be found in Africa, the Middle East, China and North America. But scientists say, although there are a lot of star dunes, the formations have not been studied very much so far.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A view of the Lala Lallia star dune of the Sahara Desert, in Erg Chebbi, Morocco, as seen in an undated handout image from 2008 and obtained by Reuters on March 1, 2024. (Charlie Bristow/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b857-08dc3d6095ab_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A view of the Lala Lallia star dune of the Sahara Desert, in Erg Chebbi, Morocco, as seen in an undated handout image from 2008 and obtained by Reuters on March 1, 2024. (Charlie Bristow/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The new study – believed to be the first of its kind – was led by two British researchers. It examines a large star dune in the Sahara Desert's Erg Chebbi sand sea in Morocco. The research results recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53485-3">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Scientific Reports</em>.</p>
<p>The scientists said the star dune rises 100 meters above surrounding dunes and is 700 meters wide. The structure contains an estimated five-and-a-half metric tons of sand.</p>
<p>The researchers used radar that can "see" underground to look at different elements within the star dune. The science instruments that were used are designed to map all layers within the dunes. They also used a method called <strong>luminescence</strong> dating to study the age of the dune. This method uses minerals in the sand to estimate when they last received sunlight in an attempt to guess the age of the dune.</p>
<p>Geoff Duller is a professor of geography and earth sciences at Britain's Aberystwyth University. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.aber.ac.uk/en/news/archive/2024/03/title-269226-en.html">said</a> in a statement the new technology had finally made it possible to study these large dunes. "It's only because of new technology that we can start to uncover their secrets," Duller said.</p>
<p>The researchers estimated the oldest parts of the base of the star dune are about 13,000 years old. And the dune is moving across the desert at a rate of about 50 centimeters a year. The team noted the star dune experienced the most growth during the past 1,000 years.</p>
<p>Star dunes make up just 10 percent of all dunes in Earth's deserts. They have also been observed on Mars and on Saturn's moon Titan.</p>
<p>Earth's largest star dunes are found in western China's Badain Jaran desert. Star dunes also are found in places including the Namib Sand Sea in Namibia, large sand seas in Algeria and Rub' al Khali in Saudi Arabia. In North America, Great Sand Dunes National Park in Colorado contains a series of them.</p>
<p>"I first encountered star dunes in Namibia 20 years ago," Duller told Reuters news agency. He added that he still has clear memories of being surprised at the size and beauty of the first sand dunes he saw. "I have a <strong>vivid</strong> memory of the long climb to the top, struggling up very loose sand in the heat of the day."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters, </em><em>Aberystwyth University </em><em>and Scientific Reports reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dune </strong><em>– n. </em>a hill of sand in a desert</p>
<p><strong>luminescence </strong><em>– n. </em>the giving out of light by a substance</p>
<p><strong>vivid </strong><em>– adj. </em>clear or strong</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Student-athletes Considered College Employees?  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/are-student-athletes-considered-college-employees.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Dartmouth College men's basketball team voted to join a labor organization, called a union, this week.</p>
<p>The move means that the student-athletes on the team could have the right to negotiate a working contract like other university employees.</p>
<p>In an election held by the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), the team members voted 13-2 to join Service Employees International Union Local 560. The same union also represents some workers at Dartmouth.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A student walks near the Alumni Gymnasium on the campus of Dartmouth College, Tuesday, March 5, 2024, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/dd226cf9-e035-4344-9bf4-8bdce29beaf2_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A student walks near the Alumni Gymnasium on the campus of Dartmouth College, Tuesday, March 5, 2024, in Hanover, N.H. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)</span></div>
<p>Cade Haskins and Romeo Myrthil are Dartmouth basketball players. The student-athletes said of the vote, "... we, as students, can also be both <strong>campus</strong> workers and union members. Dartmouth seems to be stuck in the past. It's time for the age of <strong>amateurism</strong> to end."</p>
<p>However, the school in Hanover, New Hampshire has already appealed the local NLRB decision. In a statement, Dartmouth said, "<strong>Classifying</strong> these students as employees simply because they play basketball is as <strong>unprecedented</strong> as it is inaccurate."</p>
<p>The school also warned the students that unionizing could get the team removed from athletic competition.</p>
<p>Both sides have until March 12 to file objections with the NLRB. The case could also end up in federal court, which would likely delay the outcome for some time.</p>
<p>The Dartmouth vote is the latest effort by student-athletes to unionize and gain money and other rights in exchange for many hours spent practicing and playing sports.</p>
<p>In 2015, a local NLRB blocked an attempt by students on the football team at Northwestern University in Illinois to form a union. But the decision did not directly answer the question of whether student-athletes are employees.</p>
<p><strong>Growth of college sports</strong></p>
<p>The history of college students playing sports for their school goes back over 100 years.</p>
<p>The National Collegiate Athletic Association, or NCAA, is the governing body for college sports. The organization has long said that its players are "student-athletes" who go to school mainly to study.</p>
<p>At first, students were not paid to play sports and were considered "amateurs." Gradually, student-athletes from large universities started receiving money for housing, food and <strong>tuition</strong>.</p>
<p>In recent years, American television networks have spent more money to broadcast college sports around the country and the world. The Big Ten, an athletic organization with college teams from the New York area to Los Angeles, reached an agreement in 2022 to broadcast its football and basketball games for $7 billion.</p>
<p>As college sports became popular, teams from large universities now regularly play in front of large crowds of up to 100,000 people. And some student-athletes have become even better known than professional athletes.</p>
<p>In 2021, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the NCAA could not prevent college athletes from getting paid by outside groups in return for the use of their name or image.</p>
<p>That opened the door for some college athletes to make lots of money. This year, one top student-athlete is Caitlin Clark, a basketball player at the University of Iowa. She set college scoring records and reportedly earns nearly $1 million a year for the use of her name and image.</p>
<p>The Dartmouth basketball players will never be famous enough to make that kind of money. One student-athlete said what he really wants from the union push is to get access to better healthcare so he can heal his basketball injuries.</p>
<p><strong>What about Dartmouth?</strong></p>
<p>Tony Clark is the head of the Major League Baseball Players Association. He said the vote gives the Dartmouth basketball players "a seat at the table and powerful voice."</p>
<p>One basketball coach whose team is very well known – Dan Hurley of the University of Connecticut – said some kind of union or players' organization is the future of college sports.</p>
<p>"These players are putting in <strong>incredible</strong> work days, work weeks for five, six months," he said. "I think there's so much there that's going to have to be settled."</p>
<p>A 2015 legal case suggested athletes like the basketball players can spend up to 40 hours per week involved in their sports activities, leaving little time for study or work.</p>
<p>Haskins said he loves playing basketball. But he has had serious injuries to his ankle, hip and shoulder while playing. "It is definitely a <strong>burden</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Union interest among younger workers is growing, says the Economic Policy Institute. Workers under 45 joined unions at <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.epi.org/publication/union-membership-data/" target="_blank">the highest rate in 2023</a>.</p>
<p>Myrthil said he will talk about the union with new students who are coming next year. "We'll introduce them to the idea and what it means," he said. "And then hopefully it gets passed on."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>campus </strong>– <em>n</em>. the grounds or land upon which a school is built</p>
<p><strong>amateurism </strong>– <em>adj</em>. participating in something, such as a sporting event, without being paid</p>
<p><strong>classify </strong>– <em>v</em>. to consider something as part of a group with other similar items</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not existing or having been done before</p>
<p><strong>tuition </strong>– <em>n</em>. the money paid to attend school</p>
<p><strong>incredible </strong>– <em>adj</em>. hard to believe, not believable</p>
<p><strong>burden </strong>– <em>n</em>. a heavy weight, used both literally and figuratively</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Dip Your Toes' or 'Take the Plunge'?  (2024/3/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/dip-your-toes-or-take-the-plunge.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about trying something new or something you are unsure about.</p>
<p>People can react differently to these kinds of situations. Some people may want to <u>jump right in feet first</u>. They may want to <u>take the plunge! </u></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Triathletes dive into The Seine river with the Eiffel Tower in the background during the men's 2023 World Triathlon Olympic Games Test Event in Paris. (Photo by Bertrand GUAY / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-116f-08dba014e0b4_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Triathletes dive into The Seine river with the Eiffel Tower in the background during the men's 2023 World Triathlon Olympic Games Test Event in Paris. (Photo by Bertrand GUAY / AFP)</span></div>
<p>And some people may want <u>to test the waters</u>. They may want to <u>dip their toes in </u>first.</p>
<p>Which kind of person are you? Well, imagine you are standing on the edge of a lake or swimming pool. You want to get into the water, but you don't know the water's temperature.</p>
<p>Do you jump right in? If you do, you may be more bold and adventurous.</p>
<p>Or do you want to dip a toe into the water before you decide? If so, you may be more <strong>cautious </strong>and careful.</p>
<p>If you dip your toes into something, you start doing it slowly and carefully. You are not sure if you will like it. You want to test the waters before beginning something, or before taking the plunge.</p>
<p>Testing the waters means you get a feel for something before committing to it. For example, if you want to move to a new city, you probably want to test the waters first by going there for a short stay.</p>
<p>Taking the plunge is the opposite of dipping your toes. When you take the plunge, you jump right into something. You do not wait or <strong>hesitate.</strong></p>
<p>We use the expression <u>dip your toes in </u>for many situations. You may want to try an activity briefly to find out if you like it first. It can also mean you start something very carefully before becoming involved in something that you are not experienced at.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear some of these expressions used in a non-water related situation.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, I'm going ballroom dancing this Saturday. Do you want to join me?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Ballroom dancing? I know nothing about ballroom dancing. </em></p>
<p><em>A: That's fine! This place I found is perfect for you. Before the dance starts, they give a free class to beginners.</em></p>
<p><em>B: Yeah, I don't know. Maybe I'll just go and watch. You know ... dip my toes in. I like to know what I'm getting into first.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Sure. But I promise you ... after the first 5 minutes you are going to want to jump in feet first!</em></p>
<p>That is all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>If you are new to VOA Learning English, there's no need to dip your toes in first. Just take the plunge! Visit our website to find more stories.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>careful about avoiding danger or risk</p>
<p><strong>hesitate </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to hold back in doubt or indecision</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russia, China Aim to Put a Nuclear Plant on the Moon  (2024/3/9) | 俄罗斯计划在月球建造核电站</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/russia-and-china-aim-to-put-a-nuclear-plant-on-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Russia and China are considering putting a nuclear power station on the moon in about 10 years.<br/>
俄罗斯和中国正在考虑在大约10年后将核电站送上月球。</p>
<p>The head of Russia's space agency Roscosmos, Yuri Borisov, made the statement recently. He added that such a project could support the building of moon settlements one day.<br/>
俄罗斯航天局局长尤里·鲍里索夫最近发表了上述声明。他补充说，这种项目有一天可以支持月球基地的建设。</p>
<p>Borisov said that Russia and China had been working on a moon program together. The former deputy defense minister explained that Russia was able to help with its expertise in "nuclear space energy."<br/>
鲍里索夫说，俄罗斯和中国一直在共同致力于月球计划。这位前国防部副部长解释说，俄罗斯能够利用其在“太空核能”方面的专业知识提供帮助。</p>
<p>"Today we are seriously considering a project - somewhere at the turn of 2033-2035 - to deliver and install a power unit on the lunar surface together with our Chinese colleagues," Borisov said.<br/>
鲍里索夫说：“今天，我们正在认真考虑一个项目——在2033至2035年左右——与中国同行一起在月球表面交付和安装发电机组。”</p>
<p>Solar panels would not be able to provide enough electricity to power future moon settlements, he said, while nuclear power could.<br/>
他说，太阳能电池板无法为未来的月球基地提供足够电力，而核电可以。</p>
<p>He said the possible plan should be done "without the presence of humans."<br/>
他说，这项可能的计划应该在“无人在场的情况下”完成。</p>
<p>Borisov also spoke about Russian plans to build a nuclear-powered spaceship to carry cargo. He said all the technical questions concerning the project had been solved, except for finding out how to cool the nuclear reactor.<br/>
鲍里索夫还谈到了俄罗斯建造核动力飞船运载货物的计划。他说，除了找出如何冷却核反应堆的办法之外，有关该项目的所有技术问题都已解决。</p>
<p>He said the ship would be a large "structure that would be able, thanks to a nuclear reactor and ... high-power turbines...to transport large cargoes from one orbit to another." He added that such a ship could collect objects for many other projects.<br/>
他说，这艘飞船将是一个大型“结构，由于有核反应堆和大功率涡轮机，将能够将大型货物从一个轨道运输到另一个轨道。”他补充说，这艘飞船可以为许多其他项目收集物体。</p>
<p>Russian officials have spoken before about plans to mine minerals on the moon. But the Russian space program has suffered a series of problems in recent years.<br/>
俄罗斯官员此前曾谈到在月球上开采矿产的计划。但近年来，俄罗斯的太空计划遇到了一系列问题。</p>
<p>Its first moon mission in 47 years failed last year after Russia's Luna-25 spacecraft lost control and crashed.<br/>
去年，在俄罗斯的月球-25号宇宙飞船失控坠毁后，其47年来的首次月球任务失败了。</p>
<p>Russian officials have said they will launch further lunar missions and then explore the possibility of a joint Russian-China crewed mission and even a lunar base.<br/>
俄罗斯官员表示，他们将进一步发动月球任务，然后探索俄中联合载人任务甚至月球基地的可能性。</p>
<p>Last month, China said it aimed to put the first Chinese astronaut on the moon before 2030.<br/>
中国上月表示计划在2030年前将首位中国宇航员送上月球。</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin last month said a warning by the United States that Russia planned to put nuclear weapons in space was false. Putin said the warning was part of a plan to force Russia into arms negotiations on the West's terms.<br/>
俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京上个月表示，美国警告俄罗斯计划在太空部署核武器是虚假的。普京表示，这一警告是迫使俄罗斯按照西方条件进行武器谈判计划的一部分。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>An Italian Shop in Rome Is Behind 17 Academy Awards  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/an-italian-shop-in-rome-is-behind-17-academy-awards.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In many movies, the clothing the actors wear is an important part of the story. In Rome, there is a workshop that has been a big part of Italian and international film history for 60 years.</p>
<p>Tirelli Costumes in Rome's Prati neighborhood is an <strong>atelier</strong>, a business that makes special clothing and costumes. It has earned the <strong>nickname</strong> the "Oscar tailor's shop" for its work in film costume design. An "Oscar" is another name for an award from the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.</p>
<p>Umberto Tirelli started the shop in November 1964. It has been behind 17 Academy Awards for best costume design. Most recently, its workers helped create the costumes for Ridley Scott's movie <em>Napoleon</em>. The film's costume designers were nominated for an Oscar that will be decided at the Academy Awards in Hollywood this weekend.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Amadeus dress by Milos Forman is displayed at the Tirelli Atelier in Rome, Tuesday, March 5, 2024. (AP Photo/Gregorio Borgia) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ad63-08dc3e0cba8e_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Amadeus dress by Milos Forman is displayed at the Tirelli Atelier in Rome, Tuesday, March 5, 2024. (AP Photo/Gregorio Borgia) </span></div>
<p>"Maybe it will win! Let's add another medal to the medal collection," the shop's current head, Dino Trappetti, told <em>The Associated Press</em>. "Of course, the Oscar is not won by the tailor's shop, the Oscar is won by the costume designer. But the tailor's shop has the <strong>merit</strong> and the honor of having participated to make it win."</p>
<p>The beginning of the atelier started with Tirelli's passion for collecting old clothes. He searched for clothing in houses of <strong>nobility</strong> and <strong>flea markets</strong> worldwide. He slowly built a collection that now has more than 15,000 real pieces of clothing that date from 1750 to 1980.</p>
<p>At the start, the shop had "a <strong>sewing</strong> machine, two cutters and two other <strong>seamstresses</strong>," Trappetti said.</p>
<p>Today, the headquarters of Tirelli Costumes has <strong>mannequins</strong> wearing some of the atelier's most famous creations: A pink flowered outfit that actor Tom Hulce wore as Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart in <em>Amadeus</em>, and the red outfit Michelle Pfeiffer wore in <em>The Age of Innocence</em>. The designers of each of those pieces of clothing won Oscars.</p>
<p>After the 1984 costume design Oscar for <em>Amadeus</em>, Tirelli could have accepted many international projects "because the market was immediately interested," Trappetti said. But Tirelli, who died in 1990, was not sure.</p>
<p>Trappetti remembered him saying: "I'm not going to America. If America wants, America will come looking for me."</p>
<p>Over 60 years, the tailor's shop has created more than 300,000 costumes that are now stored near Rome. Costume designers come for ideas and historical information. They also come for hand-cut, hand-sewn creations by the team of Tirelli workers.</p>
<p>"You can't make those costumes in a factory. In a factory you can make films with robots, futuristic or <strong>fantasy</strong>," Trappetti said. "But these things have to be made by hand."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>atelier </strong><em>— n. </em>a room or space where artists work; a small shop where skilled workers make things like clothing to order</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nickname </strong><em>— n. </em>an informal name for a person or something that is short and easy to use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nobility </strong><em>— n. </em>people who receive their position or rank from a king, queen or royal house</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>flea market </strong><em>— n. </em>an informal market that contains many sellers who informally gather in a place for a day to offer household objects and homemade art for sale</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sew </strong>–v. to make clothes our of cloth with thread</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>seamstress </strong><em>— n. </em>a woman who sews clothes as a job</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mannequin </strong><em>— n. </em>a form shaped like a human body that is used for making and showing clothes</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fantasy </strong>–n. a story or idea of pure imagination that is not based in reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Open Boat by Stephen Crane, Part Two  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/open-boat-stephen-crane-part-two-american-stories.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>
<em>We continue the story of "The Open Boat" by Stephen Crane. As we told you last week, the story is based on true events. In eighteen ninety-six, Crane was traveling to Cuba as a news reporter. On his way there, his ship sank in the Atlantic Ocean. Crane climbed into the last remaining lifeboat.</em></p>
<p><em>Three men got into the boat with him. They were the ship's captain, the cook and a sailor named Billie. For three days, the men steered the small boat through high waves along the coast of Florida. At last, they saw land. Here is Shep O'Neal with the final part of the story.</em></p>
<p>A long stretch of coast lay before the eyes of the men. Slowly, the land rose up out of the mountainous sea. The men could see a small house against the sky. To the south, they could see a lighthouse. Tide, wind and waves were pushing the lifeboat northward. The men thought someone on land would have seen the boat by now.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Open Boat Part Two" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0334B585-D474-47D2-A875-420BF2D17277_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Open Boat Part Two</span></div>
<p>"Well," said the captain, "I suppose we'll have to attempt to reach the shore ourselves. If we stay out here too long, none of us will have the strength left to swim after the boat sinks."</p>
<p>So Billie the sailor turned the boat straight for the shore.</p>
<p>"If we don't all get ashore," said the captain, "I suppose you fellows know where to send news of my death?"</p>
<p>The men then exchanged some information. There was a great deal of anger in them. They thought: "If I am going to be drowned, why, in the name of the seven mad gods who rule the sea, was I permitted to come this far and think about sand and trees?"</p>
<p>The waves grew stronger. They seemed always just about to break and roll over the little boat. The coast was still far away. The sailor said: "Boys, the boat won't live three minutes more, and we're too far out to swim. Shall I take her to sea again, captain?"</p>
<p>"Yes! Go ahead!" said the captain. The sailor turned the boat and took her safely out to sea again.</p>
<p>"It's funny those life-saving people haven't seen us," one of the men said.</p>
<p>"Maybe they think we're out here for sport! Maybe they think we're fishing. Maybe they think we're fools."</p>
<p>Once more, the sailor <strong>rowed</strong> the boat and then the reporter rowed. Suddenly, they saw a man walking along the shore.</p>
<p>The man stopped walking. He moved his hand in the air to wave at them. He saw them! Now he was running to the house.</p>
<p>The captain tied a cloth to a stick and waved it. Now there was another man on the shore. The two men waved their hands in the air, as if they were saying hello to the men in the boat.</p>
<p>Now, what was that moving on the shore? It was a bus – a hotel bus. A man stood on the steps of the bus and waved his coat over his head. The men in the boat wondered what he wanted to say. Was he attempting to tell them something? Should they wait for help? Should they go north? Should they go south?</p>
<p>The men waited and waited but nothing happened. The sun began to go down. It got dark and cold. They could no longer see anyone on the beach.</p>
<p>The sailor rowed, and then the reporter rowed, and then the sailor rowed again. They rowed and rowed through the long night. The land had disappeared but they could hear the low sound of the waves hitting the shore. This was surely a quiet night.</p>
<p>The cook finally spoke: "Billie, what kind of pie do you like best?"</p>
<p>"Pie," said the sailor and the reporter angrily. "Don't talk about those things!"</p>
<p>"Well," said the cook, "I was just thinking about ham sandwiches, and ..."</p>
<p>A night on the sea in an open boat is a long night. The sailor continued to row until his head fell forward and sleep overpowered him. Then he asked the reporter to row for a while. They exchanged places so the sailor could sleep in the bottom of the boat with the cook and the captain.</p>
<p>The reporter thought that he was the one man <strong>afloat</strong> on all the oceans in the world. The wind had a sad voice as it came over the waves.</p>
<p>Suddenly, there was a long, loud swishing sound behind the boat and a shining trail of silvery blue. It might have been made by a huge knife. Then there was another swish and another long flash of bluish light, this time alongside the boat. The reporter saw a huge fin speed like a shadow through the water, leaving a long glowing trail. The thing kept swimming near the boat. He noted its speed and power. The reporter wished the men would wake up. He did not want to be alone with the <strong>shark</strong>.</p>
<p>The reporter thought as he rowed. He was angry that they had come so close to land and yet might still die at sea. Then he remembered a poem that he had learned as a child. It was a poem about a soldier of the French Foreign Legion. The soldier lay dying in Algiers. Just before he died, he cried out: "I shall never see my own, my native land." And now, many years after he had learned this poem, the reporter for the first time understood the sadness of the dying soldier.</p>
<p>Hours passed. The reporter asked the sailor to take the oars so that he could rest. It seemed like only a brief period, but it was more than an hour later, when the sailor returned the oars to the reporter. They both knew that only they could keep the boat from sinking. And so they rowed, hour after hour, through the night.</p>
<p>When day came, the four men saw land again. But there were no people on the shore. A conference was held on the boat.</p>
<p>"Well," said the captain, "if no help is coming, we might better try to reach the shore right away. If we stay out here much longer, we will be too weak to do anything for ourselves at all."</p>
<p>The others agreed. They began to turn the boat toward the beach. The captain told them to be careful – that when the boat came near the beach, the waves would sink it. Then everyone should jump out of the boat and swim to the shore.</p>
<p>As the boat came closer to land, the waves got bigger and more violent. At last, a large wave climbed into the air and fell on the small boat with great force.</p>
<p>The boat turned over as the men jumped into the sea. The water was like ice. The reporter was tired. But he swam toward the beach. He looked for his friends.</p>
<p>He saw Billie, the sailor, in front of him, swimming strongly and quickly. The cook was near him. Behind, the captain held on to the overturned boat with his one good hand. Soon, the reporter could swim no longer. A current was carrying him back out to sea. He thought: "Am I going to drown? Can it be possible?"</p>
<p>But the current suddenly changed and he was able to swim toward the shore. The captain called to him to swim to the boat and hold on. The reporter started to swim toward the boat. Then he saw a man running along the shore. He was quickly taking off his shoes and clothes.</p>
<p>As the reporter got close to the boat, a large wave hit him and threw him into the air over the boat and far from it. When he tried to get up, he found that the water was not over his head, only half way up his body. But he was so tired that he could not stand up. Each wave threw him down, and the current kept pulling him back to sea.</p>
<p>Then he saw the man again, jumping into the water. The man pulled the cook to the shore. Then he ran back into the water for the captain. But the captain waved him away and sent him to the reporter. The man seized the reporter's hand and pulled him to the beach. Then the man pointed to the water and cried: "What's that?"</p>
<p>In the shallow water, face down, lay Billie, the sailor.</p>
<p>The reporter did not know all that happened after that. He fell on the sand as if dropped from a housetop. It seems that immediately the beach was filled with men with blankets, clothes and whiskey. Women brought hot coffee. The people welcomed the men from the sea to the land.</p>
<p>But a still and dripping shape was carried slowly up the beach. And the land's welcome for the sailor's body could only be its final resting place. When night came, the white waves moved in the moonlight. The wind brought the sound of the great sea's voice to the men on the shore.</p>
<p></p><p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>afloat</strong> - <em>adj</em>. floating on water</p>
<p><strong>shark</strong> - <em>n. </em>a large and often dangerous sea fish with very sharp teeth</p>
<p><strong>row </strong>- <em>v. </em>to move a boat through water using oars</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Yet'  (2024/3/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/yet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Al.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Hi, hello</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="'Yet'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8c17-08dc3d3702a9_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">'Yet'</span></div>
<p>My name is Al from Indonesia. I am still not sure how to use the word "yet" in a sentence, <strong>positive</strong> or <strong>negative</strong>.</p>
<p>Would you like to inform us more about that?</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Al.</p>
<p>We have talked about how to use the word "yet" in comparison to "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/already-or-yet-/6878196.html" target="_blank">already</a>" and "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/still-and-yet-/6818661.html" target="_blank">still</a>" in earlier <em>Ask a Teacher</em> articles. Now, let's talk about "yet" by itself.</p>
<p>"Yet" is almost always used as an adverb of time. It means from some time in the past until now. "Yet" is used in both positive and negative sentences.</p>
<p><strong>Yes-No Questions</strong></p>
<p>In spoken English, "yet" is often used in both yes or no questions. For example,</p>
<p><em>Have you heard from your boss <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p><em>Did you finish your homework <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p>We can ask these questions without "yet". Why use it then?</p>
<p>When we add "yet" to a question, we not only want to know if it happened, but we expect it to happen. And, we want it to happen.</p>
<p>We can use yet with negative questions, too. For example,</p>
<p><em>Have you not heard from your boss <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p><em>Have you not finished your homework <u>yet</u>?</em></p>
<p>Using a negative question expresses an even stronger expectation or desire, almost disbelief that something has not happened "yet!"</p>
<p><strong>Statements</strong></p>
<p>Most statements with "yet" are negative, especially in informal spoken language.</p>
<p><em>But you don't have to make a decision <u>yet</u>.</em></p>
<p><em>We are not there <u>yet</u>.</em></p>
<p>In these negative statements, "yet" expresses an expectation that it will happen at some point in the future.</p>
<p>We hope this explanation has helped you, Al.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>positive</strong>—<em>adj</em>. in grammar, a positive sentence does not have any negative words</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong>—<em>adj</em>. in grammar, a negative sentence shows that something cannot be the case, is not true or not happening</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Miami Beach Adding More Security Measures for Spring Break  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/miami-beach-adding-more-security-measures-for-spring-break.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American city of Miami Beach, Florida is a popular destination for travelers during school break periods in spring. But, in the last three years, the area has dealt with high levels of violent crime during spring break.</p>
<p>So, city officials are putting in place new security measures.</p>
<p>The measures include parking restrictions for non-<strong>residents</strong> and closings of outdoor restaurants on busy weekends. The city has warned visitors to expect curfews, personal property searches at the beach, early beach closures, road security checkpoints, and arrests for drug possession and violence.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Miami Beach park rangers watch over crowds Tuesday, Feb. 27, 2024, in Miami Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-715d-08dc3dfbb98b_cx0_cy10_cw99_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Miami Beach park rangers watch over crowds Tuesday, Feb. 27, 2024, in Miami Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Marta Lavandier)</span></div>
<p>Civil rights activists say the restrictions are an overreaction to large crowds of Black people. And, business owners in the city's famous South Beach neighborhood argue that the new measures will cause them financial loss during one of the busiest times of the year.</p>
<p>Miami Beach has ordered such measures before, so the restrictions are not unfamiliar to the area. But, this is the first time the rules have been established ahead of the season.</p>
<p>Steven Meiner is the mayor of Miami Beach. "The <strong>status quo</strong> and what we've seen in the last few years is just not acceptable," he said.</p>
<p>Meiner said spring break crowds get out of control even with a strong police presence. He said the island city can only hold so many people. And the amount of people has often gone beyond what is safe.</p>
<p>Local business owner, David Wallack, opposes the measures. He said the city has always been a place of celebration. And he argued that limits on the numbers of visitors will turn the city into a retirement community.</p>
<p>Wallack and others have proposed holding a music <strong>festival</strong> during the third week of spring break, the season's busiest time. Supporters say such an event would help prevent the gathering of mobs.</p>
<p>But, Meiner said the city has spent millions of dollars on musical performances and similar events in the past. He said such offerings did not prevent violence well. He said businesses suffer when violent crowds gather and force them to close. And, he said the people causing most of the problems are not spending money in the city anyway.</p>
<p>Some civil rights supporters, however, believe the restrictions are racist.</p>
<p>South Beach became popular among Black tourists about 20 years ago because of an event called Urban Beach Week. It takes place in late May during the Memorial Day holiday. Many locals have protested about violence and other crime connected to the event. Officials increased police presence during Memorial Day as a result.</p>
<p>Stephen Hunter Johnson is an attorney and member of Miami-Dade's Black Affairs Advisory Board. He said city officials are only cracking down so hard because many of the visitors are Black.</p>
<p>"Everybody loves this idea that they are free from the government <strong>intruding</strong> on them," Johnson said. "But amazingly, if the government intrudes on Black people, everyone's fine with it."</p>
<p>But Meiner rejects the idea that the city's actions have anything to do with race.</p>
<p>"I have a moral <strong>obligation</strong> to keep people safe, and right now, it is not safe," the mayor said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>one who lives in a place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>festival </strong><em>— n. </em>an often regularly occurring program of events or entertainment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>status quo </strong><em>— n. </em>the way things are now</p>
<p><strong>intrude </strong><em>— v. </em>to bring or force in unasked</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>— n. </em>something (as a promise or contract) that requires one to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boy Wounded in Gaza Travels to New York for a New Arm  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/boy-wounded-in-gaza-travels-to-new-york-for-a-new-arm.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Four-year-old Omar Abu Kuwaik is from the Gaza Strip, but in the last several weeks, he has spent time in Egypt, New York City, and Philadelphia before returning to Egypt.</p>
<p>Why did he travel so far from home?</p>
<p>He came for medical operations on his skin and to receive a <strong>prosthetic</strong> arm.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Omar Abu Kuwaik throws snow shortly after arriving from Gaza at the residence of the Global Medical Relief Fund as Khaolah Obahi of Rahma Worldwide looks on, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Peter K. Afriyie)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/29cfdf30-b88a-4fbb-8832-7c8191ea6a79_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Omar Abu Kuwaik throws snow shortly after arriving from Gaza at the residence of the Global Medical Relief Fund as Khaolah Obahi of Rahma Worldwide looks on, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Peter K. Afriyie)</span></div>
<p>He is one of the few Gazans to have made it out of the war <strong>zone</strong>. But his family was not so lucky.</p>
<p>Omar was wounded during an Israeli airstrike in December that also killed a number of his family members, including his parents and a sister.</p>
<p><strong>‘Anywhere is better'</strong></p>
<p>A <strong>charity</strong> group called the Global Medical Relief Fund found out about Omar and provided for his medical care in the U.S. Elissa Montanti started the organization. She has spent 25 years getting hundreds of children free medical care after they lost arms and legs to wars or disasters, including wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Montanti said she knew she would have to help the Gazan children when the conflict started between Hamas and Israel last October. But, she wondered, "How? How will I ever get these kids out when they can't even get out of Gaza?'"</p>
<p>Another group, Rahma Worldwide, a U.S.-based charity, learned about Omar's injuries. The group got him and his aunt into Egypt, provided them with new passports and airplane tickets to the United States in January.</p>
<p>Omar was getting only simple medical care in Gaza.</p>
<p>Adib Chouiki is vice president of Rahma Worldwide. Chouiki knew his group needed to get the boy to a place where he could get help.</p>
<p>"Our view was, anywhere is better for him than being in Gaza," Chouiki said.</p>
<p>The United Nations says there are many more men, women and children like Omar waiting for medical care. About 4,000 wounded people and their families – such as Omar's aunt – have been permitted to leave Gaza to get medical help. But the U.N. refugee agency says there are still 8,000 people on a medical waiting list.</p>
<p>Gaza's health ministry, which is controlled by the territory's Hamas rulers, said 30,000 people have been killed in Gaza, and 70,000 wounded. The ministry said about two-thirds of those killed have been women and children.</p>
<p><strong>To the United States</strong></p>
<p>Omar went with his aunt, Maha on a flight from Egypt to New York City. Maha left her husband and children behind in Gaza.</p>
<p>Along the way, Omar saw the airline pilots getting ready to start the flight and he said, "When I grow up, I want to be a pilot, so I can bring people places."</p>
<p>Once in the U.S., the Global Medical Relief Fund sent Omar to Shriners Children's Hospital in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, for treatment. He received pieces of new skin, called grafts, to repair the burns on his leg. Medical workers also fitted him for a prosthetic arm.</p>
<p>As he recovered, he learned how to use his new arm. He stayed in a home owned by the Global Medical Relief Fund in the Staten Island area of New York City.</p>
<p>His arm was cut off just below the elbow. As he received treatment, he could see his new arm. He looked forward to learning how to use it. One day, he reached out to touch it. "My arm is nice," he said.</p>
<p>Montanti said getting a prosthetic <strong>limb</strong> is important for children who have been wounded in a war. Even if they will never be the same, "The kids, they feel whole," she said, "<strong>Psychologically</strong>, it means so much."</p>
<p>The hospital in Philadelphia is currently treating two children who have been removed from Gaza. One is an American, who was trapped when the war started. Another child, a two-year-old boy, is supposed to come soon.</p>
<p>One day after Omar got his arm, he and his aunt got on a plane to return to Egypt. Maha said she was concerned about what would happen to Omar and the rest of her family when they arrived. Their relatives are living in tents.</p>
<p>After coming back to Egypt, Omar and his aunt's futures are unclear; they might remain in exile.</p>
<p>For Maha Abu Kuwaik and Omar, there might never be a home to return to.</p>
<p>She said she could not imagine going back to Gaza. "What would his life be? Where is his future?" she wondered.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>prosthetic </strong>–n. a device meant to take the place of a part of the body that is missing or injured</p>
<p><strong>zone </strong>–n. a place that is set apart and subject to special rules or restrictions</p>
<p><strong>charity </strong>–n. an organization that takes donations and usually uses that donations for a cause that is meant to help people</p>
<p><strong>limb </strong>–n. an arm or leg</p>
<p><strong>psychologically </strong>–adv. relating to the mind, how it works and how people think about things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Congo, Drilling Leads to Worry over Pollution  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/in-congo-drilling-leads-to-worry-over-pollution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Democratic Republic of Congo (D.R.C.) is looking to expand operations to dig, or <strong>drill</strong>, for oil. The central African country is known for its mineral riches. Currently, drilling is limited to just a small area along the Atlantic Ocean and out in the water. But that is expected to change if the government carries out its plan to sell 30 pieces of land for oil and gas exploration across the country.</p>
<p>Leaders say the plan will grow the economy. They say such growth is necessary for the poor people of Congo. But communities, rights groups, and environmentalist groups warn that expanded drilling will harm the environment and human health.</p>
<p>In the Moanda area of the D.R.C., locals say pollution has worsened since a French company began drilling there in 2000. They say spills and leaks from operations are destroying the soil. The work includes "flaring" --- the burning of natural gas near drilling sites. Locals report that the flaring is dirtying the air they breathe. Flaring is also wasteful as the energy goes unused.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Children sit inside a fishing boat outside a mangrove in Kimpozia village, one of the areas auctioned for oil drilling, in Moanda, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Monday, Dec. 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Mosa'ab Elshamy)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5881-08dc3c7e2147_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Children sit inside a fishing boat outside a mangrove in Kimpozia village, one of the areas auctioned for oil drilling, in Moanda, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Monday, Dec. 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Mosa'ab Elshamy)</span></div>
<p>And, critics say, the Congolese government does not supervise the oil drilling operations well enough.</p>
<p>The company, Perenco, says it follows accepted international measures in its <strong>extraction</strong> methods. It said its operation does not create health risks and that any pollution it causes is low-level. The company also said it offered to support a power plant that would make use of the natural gas and reduce flaring that way.</p>
<p>The government did not respond to questions about the proposed plant.</p>
<p>Congo's minister overseeing oil and gas, Didier Budimbu, said the government plans to protect the environment.</p>
<p>Natural areas in Congo, including the Congo Basin rainforest, capture large amounts of carbon dioxide – about 1.5 billion tons a year, or about 3 percent of what the world produces each year. More than 12 of the extraction areas for sale include land in government-protected wild areas.</p>
<p>The government said the 27 properties for sale hold an estimated 22 billion <strong>barrels </strong>of oil. Environmental groups say that selling more land to drill would have harmful effects in the D.R.C. and in other countries.</p>
<p>"Any new oil and gas project, anywhere in the world, is fueling the climate and nature crisis that we're in," said Mbong Akiy Fokwa Tsafak, program director for Greenpeace Africa. She said Perenco's operations have done nothing in respect to the poor and instead harm the environment and the lives of communities.</p>
<p>Environmentalists say Congo has a strong possibility to instead develop renewable energy.</p>
<p>Budimbu said now is not the time to move away from <strong>fossil fuels</strong> when the country still depends on them. He said the D.R.C. will move away from fossil fuel dependency over the long term.</p>
<p>Perenco has faced criticism for years. Local researchers, aid groups, and Congo's Senate have made multiple reports of pollution dating back more than ten years. Two organizations, Sherpa and Friends of the Earth France, opened a legal action against the company in 2022, accusing Perenco of polluting.</p>
<p>Adore Ngaka's lives in the village of Tshiende. Oil drills can be seen up the road from his home. Ngaka says they remind him every day of all that he has lost. The extraction processes have polluted the soil, hurt his crops, and forced the family to use all their savings to survive, he said.</p>
<p>He pointed to an ear of corn he grew. The 27-year-old farmer said the vegetable is about half the size of those that grew before the drilling began ten years ago.</p>
<p>He said, "It's bringing us to poverty."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Sam Mednick reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drill </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to get oil or water by digging through land or sea bed</p>
<p><strong>extract </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove or obtain a substance from something, for example by using an industrial or a chemical process</p>
<p><strong>barrel </strong><em>– n.</em> the contents of or the amount contained in a barrel; a unit of measurement in the oil industry equal to between 120 and 159 litres</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>– n.</em> fuel such as coal or oil that was formed over millions of years from parts of dead animals or plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Learn Indefinite Pronouns with 'Fast Car'  (2024/3/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/learn-indefinite-pronouns-with-fast-car.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dr. Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>On today's <em>Everyday Grammar,</em> we are going to look at things that are different from each other: in other words, contrasts.</p>
<p>Let's start:</p>
<p>At the 2024 Grammy awards, one performance got the attention of many different sorts of music fans. It was the country music singer Luke Combs singing with singer and songwriter Tracy Chapman.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-75a2-08dc3dd8ab34_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Together, they sang "Fast Car," a song that had helped Chapman win a Grammy Award in 1989 for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance. You can listen to the song <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.grammy.com/videos/tracy-chapman-luke-combs-fast-car-2024-grammys-performance-66th-annual-grammy-awards?streamUrl=https://nomad-content.grammy.com/pmc/2f/6d/c5/2f6dc584-337d-4a9e-8b03-916f21017e49/tra-apple-hls-acc/0312-cbsperf2-gmypgmbug-tp.m3u8&amp;title=Tracy%20Chapman%20and%20Luke%20Combs%20Perform%20%E2%80%9CFast%20Car%E2%80%9D%20%7C%202024%20GRAMMYs">on the Grammys website</a>.</p>
<p>The song won the Country Music Association Awards prize for Country Song of the Year in 2023. Chapman is the first Black songwriter to win this award. Luke Combs recorded the song in 2023. He invited Chapman to sing it with him at the Grammy awards show in February.</p>
<p><strong>The American Dream</strong></p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will look at some of the words in the song and explore how they tell the story of two people. The two tried to find the American Dream: good jobs, a nice home, and children.</p>
<p>We will especially learn about the meanings of some <strong>indefinite</strong> pronouns and how they can be used to make contrasts.</p>
<p>In the beginning of the song, Chapman sings about going someplace in a fast car:</p>
<p><em>You got a fast car<br/>
I want a ticket to anywhere<br/>
Maybe we make a deal<br/>
Maybe together we can get somewhere<br/>
Anyplace is better<br/>
Starting from zero got nothing to lose<br/>
Maybe we'll make something<br/>
But me myself I got nothing to prove</em></p>
<p><strong>Somewhere and anywhere</strong></p>
<p>In this part, we hear <strong>pairs</strong> of contrasting words. The first pair is "anywhere" and "somewhere." She says she wants a "ticket to anywhere," which means there is no exact place she wants to go. A similar word appears in the line, "Anyplace is better." Then, she says that together, she and her friend with the fast car "can get somewhere." "To get somewhere" means to succeed or reach a goal.</p>
<p><strong>Nothing and something</strong></p>
<p>The next pair of contrasting words is "nothing" and "something." The first expression is that she has "nothing to lose." That means she will not suffer if what she tries to do fails. Again, speaking of what the young <strong>couple</strong> can do together, she sings, "Maybe we'll make something." When we use "something" as an indefinite pronoun, it can mean a thing that is quite good, as in the expression:</p>
<p>That's really something!</p>
<p>Moving on to the next part of the song, we find the singer is working at a low-paying job and wants to escape.</p>
<p><em>You got a fast car<br/>
And I got a plan to get us out of here<br/>
I been working at the <strong>convenience</strong> store<br/>
Managed to save just a little bit of money<br/>
We won't have to drive too far<br/>
Just ‘cross the border and into the city<br/>
You and I can both get jobs<br/>
And finally see what it means to be living</em></p>
<p><strong>Dreams and reality</strong></p>
<p>Tracy Chapman has said she wrote the song about the lives of her parents. As a young couple, they struggled to create the kinds of lives they dreamed of. Listen for the words in the next part that contrast their dream with the reality of living in a shelter – a place for people without a home in which to live:</p>
<p><em>I know things will get better<br/>
You'll find work and I'll get promoted<br/>
We'll move out of the shelter<br/>
Buy a big house and live in the suburbs</em></p>
<p>Finally, we learn through Chapman's song that the young woman did not finish her education because she stayed home to take care of her sick father. The couple seems to continue to struggle in the last part of the song, but they have good memories of their younger years. Listen for the indefinite pronoun "someone" here. To "be someone" means to be an important person.</p>
<p><em>I remember we were driving driving in your car<br/>
The speed so fast I felt like I was drunk<br/>
City lights lay out before us<br/>
And your arm felt nice wrapped 'round my shoulder<br/>
And I had a feeling that I belonged<br/>
And I had a feeling I could be someone, be someone, be someone</em></p>
<p>Listening to Tracy Chapman's song, we find that indefinite pronouns can help express two ideas related to the American Dream: to "make something" and to "be someone."</p>
<p>How do you express your own dreams for the future? Email us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a> or write to us in the comments.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dr. Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>Official Music video for Tracy Chapman - "Fast Car" from 'Tracy Chapman' (1988)</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>indefinite</strong> – <em>adj.</em> (<em>grammar) </em>not limiting or specifying; not referring to a specific or previously identified person or thing</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>–n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>couple</strong> <em>– n.</em> two people who are married, living together, or in a romantic relationship</p>
<p><strong>convenience (store)</strong> – <em>n. </em>a small market with a limited choice of foods and everyday items</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Don’t Put Your Wet Phone in Bag of Rice  (2024/3/7) | 手机掉水里怎么办？</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/don-t-put-your-wet-phone-in-bag-of-rice.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Anyone with a mobile phone has likely dropped it in water or been caught in a rainstorm. And many seem to think that putting a wet phone in a bag of uncooked rice will rescue it.<br/>
人们都有可能会把手机掉进水里或者是淋了暴雨。许多人似乎认为，把弄湿的手机放进一袋米里能够挽救它。</p>
<p>However, Apple recently warned against doing just that. The technology company said it is a bad idea because small particles of rice can get into the phone and cause damage.<br/>
然而，苹果公司最近警告不要这样做。这家科技公司表示，这并非良策，因为碎米会进到手机里并造成损坏。</p>
<p>So what should you do instead?<br/>
那么你应该怎么做呢？</p>
<p>If the phone is dropped in water, dry it with a clean cloth, even a shirt will do. Turn the phone off if you can. Remove its SIM card. Remove the phone's cover. Remove the battery, if possible. And let everything dry at room temperature, perhaps with a fan running.<br/>
如果手机掉在水里，用干净的布擦干，用衣服擦也行。如果可以的话，关掉手机。取出SIM卡。卸下手机外壳。如果可能的话，取下电池。让所有东西在室温下干燥，也许可以打开风扇（加速空气流动）。</p>
<p>Since you cannot take an iPhone apart, Apple says to tap the phone against your hand with the connecting ports facing down so water can flow out.<br/>
苹果公司说，由于你不能拆开iPhone，用手轻轻拍打手机，连接端口朝下，这样水就可以流出。</p>
<p>Samsung, the biggest maker of Android phones, suggests using a cotton swab to get water out of the ports. Apple, however, advises against putting one inside iPhone openings.<br/>
最大的安卓手机制造商三星公司建议用棉签将水从端口中吸出。然而，苹果公司建议不要把棉签插入iPhone手机的端口。</p>
<p>If your phone is dropped in seawater, treated water, or a drink, Samsung advises to keep it in clean water for a few minutes. Doing that will remove any salt or substances that could hurt the phone.<br/>
如果你的手机掉在海水、经过处理的水或饮料中，三星公司建议把手机放在干净的水中泡几分钟。这样做可以去除任何有损手机的盐分或物质。</p>
<p>Both Apple and Samsung say to leave the phone out in an open area to dry. More importantly, do not use a hair dryer or put the phone in a freezer.<br/>
苹果和三星都表示要把手机放在开阔的地方晾干。更重要的是，不要用吹风机吹或将手机放在冰箱里。</p>
<p>Most newer phones are not waterproof but they are water-resistant. It means they can get wet for a short time.<br/>
大多数新手机都不防水，但是能抗水。这意味着它们可能会在短时间内浸湿。</p>
<p>Apple says its newest phones can survive 30 minutes in up to 6 meters of water. Samsung's phones can last for the same amount of time in about 5 meters. But Google advises that all phones lose some water resistance over time.<br/>
苹果公司表示，其最新款手机可以在6米深的水中坚持30分钟。三星的手机可以在大约5米的水中坚持相同的时间。但谷歌建议，随着时间的推移，所有手机都会失去一些抗水性能。</p>
<p>Another way to dry your phone is by using silica gel, a drying agent. Packs of silica gel are usually included with products including food and shoes to keep them dry. These packs can help dry your phone in a sealed container.<br/>
另一种干燥手机的方法是使用硅胶干燥剂。袋装硅胶通常放在食品和鞋子等产品里，以保持其干燥。这些袋装硅胶可以帮助你在密封容器中烘干手机。</p>
<p>The phone manufacturers say it is hard to know when phones are completely dry. But it will likely take a few days. Samsung says it is still a good idea to bring the phone in for service even if you can turn it back on again.<br/>
手机制造商表示，人们很难知道手机什么时候彻底干燥了。但这可能需要几天时间。三星公司表示，即使可以再次开机，最好还是将手机送去维修。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Virtual Fences for Cows Show Benefits  (2024/3/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/virtual-fences-for-cows-show-benefits.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>In the American state of Florida, <strong>rancher</strong> Jim Strickland can see his cows at any time, day or night. To do this, all he needs is his phone.</p>
<p>Strickland uses virtual fencing to watch and control the movements of his animals. The system, based on Global Positioning Satellite (GPS) technology, can help Strickland and researchers improve <strong>grazing</strong> lands, <strong>preserve</strong> wildlife and save time and labor for workers. It can also help improve animal health.</p>
<p>Strickland has been using the system for about six months. He told VOA Learning English he has already seen many good results with the new technology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Cattle wear Vence GPS tracking collars connected to a virtual fence system. (Courtesy photo Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e466-08dc3b075f76_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Cattle wear Vence GPS tracking collars connected to a virtual fence system. (Courtesy photo Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</span></div>
<p>"It has exceeded by far my expectations."</p>
<p><strong>How it works</strong></p>
<p>Virtual fencing uses radio signals to make an <strong>invisible</strong> fence. This means you cannot see the fence.</p>
<p>This keeps animals within, or outside of, certain areas. The signals come from nearby mobile phone towers. The signals can also come from base stations that can be moved using a small truck.</p>
<p>Each animal wears a <strong>collar</strong> around its neck. The collar has a radio signal receiver and a <strong>GPS</strong> device that shows the animal's location.</p>
<p>Ranchers train livestock to connect a sound with a small electric shock. When an animal gets close to a virtual fence, its collar makes a warning sound. If the animal moves even closer to the fence, it receives a shock. In this way, livestock quickly learn to stay away from the fence.</p>
<p>Ranchers can change the virtual fence boundaries quickly by using a phone App or computer. And livestock quickly learn the new boundaries.</p>
<p>Strickland and his coworkers can use their phones even while on horseback to move cattle from one area to another. All they need to do is change the virtual fence lines.</p>
<p>"And every 30 minutes, that line will move down; it will literally drive those cows down."</p>
<p><strong>Benefits of virtual fencing </strong></p>
<p>Physical fences take time, labor and money to build. It can be difficult to put them in areas such as rocky and hilly land, wet areas, or places with thick vegetation. Over time, fences need to be fixed or new ones need to be built.</p>
<p>When hurricane Ian hit Florida last year, it destroyed four houses and 45 kilometers of physical fence on the land where Strickland works. But the cell towers for the virtual fence system kept working.</p>
<p>Physical fences can also harm wild animals by making it difficult for them to move within and to areas they need for survival.</p>
<p>The Nature Conservancy (TNC) is a U.S-based environmental non-profit organization. It has partnered with cattle ranches in the states of Kansas, New Mexico and Colorado to research the effects of virtual fencing.</p>
<p>William Burnidge is Deputy Director of TNC's North America Regenerative Grazing Lands Strategy. He said that by changing fence boundaries, the systems prevent animals from eating too much vegetation within one area. This helps plants regenerate, or grow again.</p>
<p>He added that virtual fences could help protect rare plants and areas near rivers and streams. They could also support conservation of wild animals, improve the health of animals and help ranch workers have a better quality of life.</p>
<p>Strickland works with partners at Florida Conservation Group and the University of Florida. With virtual fences, they can carefully control grazing. This helps them research the effects of grazing patterns on the growth of young cows, birth rates, and even the effects on nesting birds.</p>
<p>They also plan to research how grazing can affect the release of carbon dioxide gas into the atmosphere. In Florida and other places, fields are sometimes burned to prepare them for future grazing. The burning releases carbon. Virtual fences may help reduce burning by better controlling where and how long cattle graze.</p>
<p>Both Strickland and Burnidge note that, unlike physical fences, livestock cannot not get injured by a virtual fence.</p>
<p>The GPS collars also let ranchers watch for animals that may be having problems. For example, if the system shows that a cow has not moved for many hours, it may be sick or injured.</p>
<p><strong>Other research and developing countries</strong></p>
<p>In the northwestern state of Oregon, researchers from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and Oregon State University studied how virtual fencing can prevent cows from grazing on recently burned land. Cattle can easily damage burned areas and the young plants that grow there.</p>
<p>The Oregon study showed that cows without virtual fence collars ate nearly 70 percent of the plants available to them in a burned area. However, cows with collars spent very little time in the burned area and ate less than three percent of the plants available to them.</p>
<p><strong>Reducing costs</strong></p>
<p>Although virtual fencing systems have benefits, they can be costly. A collar for just one animal can cost around $50 each year or more. And <strong>portable</strong> base stations cost $10,000 or more.</p>
<p>Researchers are looking for ways to lower costs and bring the technology to developing countries.</p>
<p>Last year, the Bezos Earth Fund awarded $9.9 million to Cornell University's College of Agriculture and Life Sciences to develop low-cost virtual fencing. The university plans to test new systems in Kenya, Mongolia, Argentina, Brazil and Colombia.</p>
<p>But in some areas, virtual fencing may not be the best solution, Burnidge said. When Burnidge visited Kenya, he saw many workers who closely follow and take care of livestock. Virtual fences could cause some of these workers to lose their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>Great interest in the new technology</strong></p>
<p>Still, Burnidge said, many people want to learn more about the technology. "The amount of interest in the ranching community, I've never seen anything comparable," he said.</p>
<p>And Strickland said they are already working on more ways virtual fencing can be used.</p>
<p>"Now we're seeing so many things. Once you start down the road of new technology, then it starts expanding . . . It's like, what can we do next?" he said.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rancher </strong><em>-n.</em> a person who owns or manages a large farm, especially one with animals such as cows, sheep, and goats</p>
<p><strong>graze </strong><em>-v.</em> the eating of grass or other plants in fields by animals</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong><em>-v.</em> to keep something safe for future use</p>
<p><strong>invisible </strong><em>-adj.</em> unable to be seen, not visible</p>
<p><strong>collar </strong><em>-n.</em> a ring worn around the neck of an animal</p>
<p><strong>GPS </strong><em>-n.</em> <em>(acronym </em><strong>Global Positioning Satellite</strong><em>) </em>a system for finding and tracking locations on earth using satellite technology</p>
<p><strong>portable </strong><em>-adj.</em> able to be moved or carried from one place to another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
