<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Science Celebrating 200 Years of Dinosaur Research  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/science-celebrating-200-years-of-dinosaur-research.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>On February 20, 1824, British scientist and Christian clergyman William Buckland spoke before the Geological Society of London. He described the find of a huge jaw and other bones at a rock mine in the village of Stonesfield near Oxford, England.</p>
<p>Buckland recognized that these <strong>fossils</strong> belonged to a huge reptile of the long past. He gave it the scientific name Megalosaurus, meaning "great lizard."</p>
<p>With that, the first dinosaur was officially recognized, although the word dinosaur did not come for several more years.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Tyrannosaurus rex skeleton is seen at the Smithsonian Natural History Museum dinosaur and fossil hall in Washington, U.S., June 4, 2019. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a6876986-3e65-4026-9731-f6ff8773ba4e_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Tyrannosaurus rex skeleton is seen at the Smithsonian Natural History Museum dinosaur and fossil hall in Washington, U.S., June 4, 2019. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Buckland's talk "was the beginning of our <strong>fascination</strong> with dinosaurs," says University of Edinburgh paleontologist Steve Brusatte.</p>
<p>"His announcement opened the flood gates," he said, and many people launched their own fossil hunts.</p>
<p>"People went out looking for other <strong>giant</strong> bones in England and beyond," Brusatte said.</p>
<p>In the almost 200 years since, dinosaur science has ballooned. Researchers have learned much about how these creatures looked, lived and developed, or evolved. Scientists also learned what caused the disappearance of the ancient animals.</p>
<p>Dinosaurs lived from about 231 million years ago to 66 million years ago during the Mesozoic Era. They are ancestors to birds of today. Science has identified over 2,000 species of dinosaur.</p>
<p>"Our understanding of dinosaurs has changed <strong>significantly</strong> since the 19th century," said paleontologist Emma Nicholls of the Oxford University Museum of Natural History. It is home to the Megalosaurus fossils that Buckland studied.</p>
<p>By the 1840s, other dinosaur researchers were learning that some dinosaurs walked on four legs and others walked on two legs. The Megalosaurus belongs to a group known as theropods. The group also includes meat-eaters Tyranosaurus and Spinosaurus, animals which "<strong>scampered</strong>" on their legs. Both species grew to about 9 meters tall and used their sharp <strong>claws</strong> and strong, toothy jaws to overpower <strong>prey</strong>, Brusatte said.</p>
<p>Evidence of dinosaurs has been found all around the world. The first complete dinosaur <strong>skeletons </strong>were set up in the 1870s.</p>
<p>In the 1960s, the discovery of a small dinosaur changed popular thinking about the animal group. Deinonychus was a fast-moving meat-eater. Some smaller dinosaurs, like Archaeopteryx, were found to be very much like early birds in body structure. The new research confirmed how birds evolved from small, feathered dinosaurs.</p>
<p>In the years that followed, scientists used new imaging tools to learn more about how dinosaurs grew and moved. Other tools permitted them to make good guesses about their colors, because some dinosaur remains had small pieces of skin or feathers that contained pigment, or color.</p>
<p>Thomas Holtz is a paleontologist at the University of Maryland. He said all of the research created "a more <strong>dynamic</strong> and biological view of dinosaurs as living things."</p>
<p>In recent years, fossils have been found in China, Argentina, Brazil, South Africa and Mongolia.</p>
<p>Hans-Dieter Sues is a paleontologist at the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, D.C. He said the most important recent discovery is that the theropods were covered with feathers although they could not fly. He said the feathers kept the dinosaurs warm and were used for show.</p>
<p>One question that concerned scientists from the beginning was why the dinosaurs died. They came up with many theories. One scientist even said small mammals might have eaten all the dinosaur eggs.</p>
<p>Scientists have since settled on an answer. They believe an asteroid that hit the Earth in what is now southern Mexico was to blame for the disappearance of dinosaurs. Experts believe the event destroyed about 75 percent of life on Earth, including all its dinosaurs.</p>
<p>But what if there had been no asteroid? Would dinosaurs still rule the world today?</p>
<p>Holtz of the University of Maryland says "almost certainly, yes." He notes that some mammals existed at the time of dinosaurs but they were all small. He said dinosaurs would have needed to evolve as the Earth cooled and some forests dried out.</p>
<p>In the last 200 years, scientists also have a better idea of the largest and smallest dinosaurs. One 2023 study said the largest dinosaur was Argentinosaurus, which measured about 35 meters long and weighed 76 tonnes.</p>
<p>But Holtz said there is still more research to be done.</p>
<p>He said many areas of the world have not been explored by paleontologists. That offers hope of more dino finds.</p>
<p>"There are almost assuredly entire groups of dinosaurs which we currently know nothing about waiting to be discovered," Holtz said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Dan Friedell adapted the story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>–n.</em> something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p><strong>fascination </strong><em>–n.</em> a great interest in something</p>
<p><strong>giant </strong><em>–adj.</em> extremely large</p>
<p><strong>significantly </strong><em>–adj.</em> to a large and notable degree</p>
<p><strong>scamper </strong><em>–v.</em> to run very fast, but usually related to a small creature</p>
<p><strong>claw </strong><em>–n.</em> a sharp nail attached to a hand or finger of an animal</p>
<p><strong>prey </strong><em>–n.</em> an animal that is the food of another animal</p>
<p><strong>skeleton </strong><em>–n.</em> the connected bones of an animal without skin</p>
<p><strong>dynamic </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that has a lot of energy and interest</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US State Court Rules Embryos Can Be Considered Children  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-state-court-rules-embryos-can-be-considered-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Supreme Court of Alabama has ruled that frozen embryos can be considered children under state law.</p>
<p>The ruling immediately influenced the way fertility treatment services operate in the southeastern U.S. state. On Wednesday, the University of Alabama Birmingham Hospital said it paused all fertility treatments while it considers the ruling's significance.</p>
<p>The court decision involved two wrongful death cases brought by three <strong>couples</strong> who had frozen embryos destroyed in an accident at a fertility center.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The exterior of the Alabama Supreme Court building in Montgomery, Ala., is shown Tuesday, Feb. 20, 2024. (AP Photo/Kim Chandler)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-71b5-08dc33c6e1df_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The exterior of the Alabama Supreme Court building in Montgomery, Ala., is shown Tuesday, Feb. 20, 2024. (AP Photo/Kim Chandler)</span></div>
<p>In their decision, the justices noted recent and longstanding parts of the Alabama Constitution. The justices ruled that an 1872 state law permitting parents to bring legal action over the death of a minor child "<strong>applies</strong> to all unborn children, regardless of their location."</p>
<p>"Unborn children are ‘children' ... without exception based on developmental stage, physical location, or any other...<strong>characteristics</strong>," Justice Jay Mitchell wrote. The high court released the ruling on February 16.</p>
<p>Mitchell said the court had ruled earlier that fetuses killed while a woman is pregnant are covered under Alabama's Wrongful Death of a Minor Act. Nothing excludes "<strong>extrauterine</strong> children from the Act's coverage," he wrote.</p>
<p>The ruling is likely to influence fertility treatments and the activity of freezing of embryos, which are fertilized eggs. A court <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fairfaxcounty.gov/circuit/sites/circuit/files/assets/documents/pdf/opinions/cl-2021-15372-honeyhline-heidemann-v-jason-heidemann.pdf">opinion</a> in Virginia last year said that frozen embryos can be considered property.</p>
<p>Barbara Collura is chief of RESOLVE: The National Infertility Association, a non-profit group based in Virginia. Collura told the Associated Press that the ruling raises questions for "in vitro fertilization," or IVF, the method of fertilizing eggs in a laboratory.</p>
<p>She said the "ruling is stating that a fertilized egg, which is a clump of cells, is now a person. It really puts into question, the practice of IVF." The group called the Alabama high court's decision "terrifying" for people affected by infertility.</p>
<p>She said the ruling also raises questions for providers of IVF services and for patients. It is unclear whether they can freeze embryos created during fertility treatment or if patients could ever donate or destroy unused embryos.</p>
<p>Sean Tipton is a spokesman with the American Society for Reproductive Medicine. He said at least one Alabama fertility center was told to stop IVF treatments by the hospital overseeing it since the decision.</p>
<p>Dr. Paula Amato is president of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine in Washington D.C. She said: "No health care provider will be willing to provide treatments if those treatments may lead to civil or criminal charges."</p>
<p>The couples in the Alabama case had undergone IVF treatments that led to the creation of several embryos. Some of the embryos were <strong>implanted</strong> and resulted in healthy births. The couples paid to keep the other embryos frozen in a storage center at the Mobile Infirmary Medical Center. A patient in 2020 entered the area and removed several embryos, dropping them on the floor and "killing them," the ruling said.</p>
<p>The justices then ruled that couple's wrongful death legal case could go forward. The clinic and hospital that are defendants in the case could ask the court to reconsider its decision.</p>
<p>One group that opposes abortion, the non-profit Live Action, supported the decision. "Each person, from the tiniest embryo to an elder nearing the end of his life...deserves and is guaranteed legal protection," said President Lila Rose in a statement.</p>
<p>Justice Greg Cook wrote the only full <strong>dissent</strong> to the majority opinion. He said the 1872 law did not define "minor child" and the meaning of the term was being extended to cover frozen embryos.</p>
<p>He added the ruling "almost certainly ends the creation of frozen embryos through in vitro fertilization (IVF) in Alabama."</p>
<p>The Alabama Supreme Court decision partly depended on language added to the Alabama Constitution in 2018. It states it is the policy of the "state to ensure the protection of the rights of the unborn child."</p>
<p>In Alabama, supreme court justices are elected officials who serve six-year terms. Currently, all are members of the Republican Party.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>couple </strong><em>— n. </em>two people linked by a relationship or marriage</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>apply </strong><em>— v. </em>to cover under law</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>characteristic </strong><em>— n. </em>a quality that makes something different from something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extrauterine </strong><em>— adj. </em>outside of a woman's womb and body</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>implant </strong>–v. to put into the womb by medical operation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dissent </strong><em>— n. </em>an opinion in disagreement to the majority opinion in a court which can serve other legal cases and future legal findings</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Language, Traditions Central to National Identity  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/report-language-traditions-central-to-national-identity.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Luciana de Oliveira considers herself transnational. That means she is more than one nationality. de Oliveira grew up in Brazil, but she moved to the United States for her studies. She became a U.S. citizen in 2017.</p>
<p>de Oliveira has some strong feelings about national identity. She believes speaking a country's majority language is a very important part of one's national identity. de Oliveira speaks both Portuguese and English.</p>
<p>A new study found that most people around the world share those feelings about language and national identity.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Daughters of imprisoned women celebrate their 15th birthday, a tradition called quinceanera, at the San Marta Acatitla rehabilitation in the Iztapalapa neighborhood of Mexico City, Friday, Aug. 18, 2023. (AP Photo/Arnulfo Franco)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c824fe2-c696-421e-9d60-5ac0b7578ba7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Daughters of imprisoned women celebrate their 15th birthday, a tradition called quinceanera, at the San Marta Acatitla rehabilitation in the Iztapalapa neighborhood of Mexico City, Friday, Aug. 18, 2023. (AP Photo/Arnulfo Franco)</span></div>
<p>The Pew Research Center carried out the study and released the results last month. Pew's study centered on people's ideas about national identity. It included answers from people in more than 20 countries.</p>
<p>Pew researchers asked study <strong>participants</strong> about four aspects, or parts, of national identity: language, traditions, birthplace and religion. They found that language is by far the most valued aspect of national identity.</p>
<p>In fact, a median of 91 percent of people across 21 countries said that speaking a country's most common language is "important for being considered a true national."</p>
<p>Traditions and <strong>customs</strong> are also <strong>key</strong> to national identity, the study found. Beliefs about the other two aspects – birthplace and religion – were more divided.</p>
<p>VOA Learning English spoke with several people who live in countries that were included in the study. Among them is Jorge Catalan. He has lived in Mexico most of his life. The Pew study found that 93 percent of <strong>respondents</strong> from Mexico said that speaking the country's main language – Spanish – is important to national identity.</p>
<p>Catalan said he agrees that speaking Spanish is very important. But he added that it is regrettable.</p>
<p>He said, "Mexico is a place where we have around 68 spoken languages besides Spanish." He noted that the government has pushed Spanish as the main language throughout history and has turned it into a "must-have tool."</p>
<p>Agatha Janzen was born and raised in Canada. Pew researchers found that more than 80 percent of Canadians say that speaking the country's language is important to national identity. In Canada, both French and English are official languages.</p>
<p>Janzen said that "speaking one of the official languages is important to being Canadian for <strong>practical</strong> reasons."</p>
<p>Traditions and customs are also a central aspect of national identity, the study found. Results showed 81 percent of people believe sharing their country's customs and traditions is somewhat or very important to national identity.</p>
<p>The Pew study found that 67 percent of Brazilians consider practicing customs and traditions an important part of national identity. That is the fourth lowest percentage of all the countries included in the study.</p>
<p>But customs and traditions are important to de Oliveira. To feel closer to her Brazilian identity, she said she wears jewelry and shoes from Brazil and follows and supports Brazilian soccer.</p>
<p>Mexico is tied with the highest percentage of respondents who answered that customs and traditions are an important aspect of national identity. But for Catalan, they are not so important. He noted that Mexican traditions have changed over time. He added that he does not take part in many Mexican traditions, "but I still feel <strong>proudly</strong> Mexican."</p>
<p>Beliefs about the two other aspects of national identity – birthplace and religion – were more mixed. A median of 58 percent of respondents from 23 countries said that being born in a country is important to national identity. An even lower number of respondents – 42 percent – said that being a member of the country's main religion is important to national identity.</p>
<p>Respondents from Mexico and Indonesia had the strongest feelings about the importance of birthplace as central to national identity, at 91 percent.</p>
<p>Calatan, who was born and lived most of his life in Mexico, agrees somewhat. "If you are born outside of Mexico and never lived in it, it would be difficult to get a real sense of what being Mexican means."</p>
<p>But Janzen, the Canadian, said, "Being born in Canada has nothing to do with being Canadian." For her, Canada is a <strong>melting pot</strong> and offers refuge to those who need it.</p>
<p>These ideas match the results of the study. Countries where immigrants make up a smaller share of the population tend to see birthplace as a more important aspect of national identity. Countries with a greater share of immigrants are more willing to accept those born outside of the country as true nationals.</p>
<p>Less than half of people in most of the countries in the study do not feel religion is important to national identity. All of those who spoke with Learning English said they agreed that religion is not an important part of national identity.</p>
<p>Christine Huang is a research associate at the Pew Research Center. She is one of the writers of the study. She told Learning English, "This question of belonging in a country is related to other work we have done to measure how connected people feel to each other."</p>
<p>Huang added, "When looking at how people relate to others in their community, in their country, and all over the world, people most frequently report feeling close to others in their country."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for Learning English with reporting from Pew Research Center.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>respondent</strong>—<em>n</em>. a person who answers questions</p>
<p><strong>customs</strong>—<em>n</em>. the traditionally accepted behaviors of a culture</p>
<p><strong>key</strong>—<em>adj</em>. most important</p>
<p><strong>participants</strong>—<em>adj</em>. people who take part in an activity</p>
<p><strong>practical</strong>—<em>adj</em>. real situations and events, not just theory or ideas</p>
<p><strong>proud</strong>—<em>adj</em>. feeling pleasure or satisfaction about something</p>
<p><strong>melting</strong> <strong>pot</strong>—<em>figure of speech</em>. a place where different people, beliefs, and cultures melt into one</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Popular in Different Countries?  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-popular-in-different-countries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In a recent <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/what-is-popular-in-your-country-/7488370.html" target="_blank">lesson</a>, we asked our readers and listeners to write to us about what is popular in their country.</p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will explore some of what was written to us. Our audience will be the guides of our imaginative tour of cultures around the world. We will learn about English grammar on the way.</p>
<p><strong>Turkey </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-8477-08dc33422395_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>Let's start with a message from a friend in Turkey.</p>
<p><em>Greetings from Turkey, I am Furkan. </em></p>
<p><em>I think, K<i></i>305;vanc Tatl<i></i>305;tug is a popular in Turkey. Because the whole country knows him. </em></p>
<p>Furkan wrote a very clear message. Our main suggestion is to remove a couple of words and add a little more explanation.</p>
<p>We can take out the words "I think." We can also remove the part about the "whole country knows him."</p>
<p>When we say someone is popular, we can <strong>assume</strong> that many or most people in a place know about the person.</p>
<p>You could also explain a little more deeply why Kivanc Tatlitug is popular. For example, you might say he is handsome, talented, and so on.</p>
<p>So, you might update the message to something like this:</p>
<p><em>K<i></i>305;vanc Tatl<i></i>305;tug is popular in Turkey <u>because he is handsome, talented, and wealthy</u>. </em></p>
<p><strong>Venezuela </strong></p>
<p>Now let's examine part of a message from Gorka in Venezuela. Gorka says this about baseball, a popular sport in the country:</p>
<p>
<em>... this sport is practiced by people of all ages and in all the states of the country. There are many baseball schools, some of them <strong>sponsored</strong> by American baseball organizations.<br/>
Every year more that one hundred Venezuelan baseball players go to USA to play in the MLB or other related leagues.<br/>
Not surprisingly these players inspire younger baseball players to follow their steps. </em></p>
<p>Gorka wrote an excellent description. Our main suggestion is to pay careful attention to short words.</p>
<p>Instead of "that" we can use "than," as in "more than one hundred Venezuelan baseball players." And we want to add "the" in front of "USA" like this:</p>
<p><em>Every year, more <u>than</u> one hundred Venezuelan baseball players <u>go to the USA</u> to play in the MLB or other related leagues. </em></p>
<p>A final word about the last sentence from Gorka. While it is correct to say "follow their steps," in this situation, we often say "follow in their footsteps." We use "follow in their footsteps" when someone does something before us and we follow what they did. For example:</p>
<p><em>If your father is a doctor and you become a doctor, you could say that you are <u>following in your father's footsteps</u>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Japan </strong></p>
<p>Now let's turn to Japan. An unnamed reader sent us this note about a popular food.</p>
<p><em>Most popular food in Japan is RAMEN. I think because Ramen has huge kinds of taste. </em></p>
<p>The message is clear and to the point. Once again, we need to pay special attention to short words and remove a few other words. We need to include the word "the" at the beginning of the message, as in:</p>
<p><em><u>The</u> most popular food in Japan is ramen. </em></p>
<p>While the meaning of "huge kinds of taste" is understandable, we might instead use different structures to express the same idea. For example, English speakers might say that the taste is complex, bold, or rich. We might update the entire message to something like this:</p>
<p><em>The most popular food in Japan is ramen because it <u>has a rich, complex taste. </u></em></p>
<p><strong>Spain </strong></p>
<p>Finally, Rafael from Spain writes to us. He notes that he does not like the most popular sport, soccer. Rafael ends his message with the following:</p>
<p><em>... Since I don't like soccer, I feel a little weirdo. But not as much as you, John, who are in love with grammar!<br/>
Thank you very much for your teaching, John,<br/>
See you soon! </em></p>
<p>Rafael wrote a very light-hearted, humorous message. The main correction needed is to add the word "like" after the verb "feel" and remove the word "little." So, the statement could become:</p>
<p><em>Since I don't like soccer, I feel <u>like</u> a weirdo. </em></p>
<p>A quick note about the term "weirdo." We often use it in a negative, or disapproving, way. So, you should be careful about using it. If you choose to use the term, make sure that the person it is directed at understands that you are not being serious.</p>
<p>Rafael's message, for example, clearly used the word in a joking manner. Still, his point is correct:</p>
<p><em>I am a grammar weirdo.</em></p>
<p>And that's Everyday Grammar.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>assume </strong><em>– v.</em> to think that something is true or probably true</p>
<p><strong>sponsor </strong><em>– v.</em> to give money to an athlete for training, clothes, equipment, etc.,</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Finds Majority of Retired People Enjoy VR  (2024/2/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/study-finds-majority-of-retired-people-enjoy-vr.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study found that a majority of retired people who experienced <strong>virtual reality</strong> (VR) said they liked using the technology.</p>
<p>The study is part of an effort that aims to find ways older adults, known as seniors, can use VR systems. Earlier research has shown the technology can improve emotional health and reduce loneliness in some individuals. It might also help dementia patients better deal with their condition.</p>
<p>During the study, VR systems were introduced in 17 different retirement communities across the United States. A total of 245 people – between the ages of 65 and 103 – took part in the experiment.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Tracy Hall, vice president of sales at Mynd Immersive, left, watches as Karen Audet, 82, right, reacts while wearing a virtual reality headset at John Knox Village, Wednesday, Jan. 31, 2024, in Pompano Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Lynne Sladky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5b97-08dc32fb1d47_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Tracy Hall, vice president of sales at Mynd Immersive, left, watches as Karen Audet, 82, right, reacts while wearing a virtual reality headset at John Knox Village, Wednesday, Jan. 31, 2024, in Pompano Beach, Fla. (AP Photo/Lynne Sladky)</span></div>
<p>The seniors chose from different VR environments offering digital experiences that lasted several minutes. They wore headsets providing a full 360-degrees of sights and sounds to recreate realistic digital environments.</p>
<p>Examples of the digital experiences included parachuting, riding in vehicles, watching music performances, playing with animals, or visiting famous places.</p>
<p>The experiments were led by researchers at Stanford University in northern California. The scientists worked on the project with a Texas-based company called Mynd Immersive, which designs VR products for aging people.</p>
<p>The researchers said nearly 80 percent of those taking part in the experiment reported that their emotional state had improved after the VR experience. Nearly 60 percent of the seniors said the VR system also helped them feel less <strong>isolated</strong> socially.</p>
<p>The team recently published the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/full/10.1089/cyber.2023.0188">study</a> results in the publication <em>Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking</em>.</p>
<p>The study also collected information from caregivers of people involved in the study. Nearly 75 percent of caregivers said the <strong>moods</strong> of the seniors improved after using VR. And more than 80 percent of test subjects and 95 percent of caregivers said talking about the VR experience improved relationships with others.</p>
<p>Ryan Moore is a doctoral candidate at Stanford University who led the research. He told The Associated Press that for most of the seniors involved, it was their first time using VR. "They enjoyed it," Moore said. He added, "They were likely to <strong>recommend</strong> it to others, and they looked forward to doing it again."</p>
<p>Farrell Patrick is a 91-year-old retired Army officer who took part in the VR experiment. He used to teach computer science at the United States Military Academy at West Point and two private universities as well. Patrick now lives in a retirement community in Fort Lauderdale, Florida.</p>
<p>Patrick experienced the VR flight of a Navy fighter pilot along the coast of Florida. "Oh my God, that's beautiful," he told the AP while wearing the VR headset.</p>
<p>Terry Colli is a former public relations director at the Canadian Embassy in Washington, D.C. The 76-year-old told the AP of his 2022 VR experience, "It brought back memories of my travels and...brought back memories of my experience growing up on a farm."</p>
<p>Anne Selby is a 79-year-old retired <strong>counselor</strong> and artist. She said her VR experience "<strong>stimulated</strong>" every area of her brain as well as all the senses. "I particularly enjoyed the ones dealing with pets because I have a cat and I've had pets most of my life," Selby said.</p>
<p>The Florida community where Farrell Patrick lives, John Knox Village, has carried out VR experiments with seniors suffering from Alzheimer's and other forms of dementia. The researchers said the technology helped the individuals remember things from their past that some wanted to share with their caregivers.</p>
<p>Hana Salem, a worker at John Knox, told the AP, "It is like they come back to life when they tell their story." She added that some dementia patients who normally do not speak a lot, sometimes "<strong>perk up</strong>" after going through a VR experience.</p>
<p>"They'll start laughing and saying, ‘Ooh, I'm going to catch the butterflies,'" Salem explained. The catching of butterflies is part of a game Mynd Immersive developed to help seniors improve their movements and <strong>flexibility</strong> as they stand and reach for objects.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>virtual reality (VR) </strong><em>– n. </em>digital environments that can be entered and controlled by humans</p>
<p><strong>isolate </strong><em>– v. </em>to separate someone or something from other people or things</p>
<p><strong>mood </strong><em>– n. </em>the way someone feels at a particular time</p>
<p><strong>recommend</strong> <em>– v. </em>suggest something for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>counselor </strong><em>– n. </em>someone whose job it is to listen to people and give them advice about their problems</p>
<p><strong>stimulate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make something happen or develop more</p>
<p><strong>perk up </strong><em>– v. </em>to start to feel happy about something</p>
<p><strong>flexible </strong><em>– adj. </em>able to easily move and bend body parts</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Musk: Neuralink Patient Able to Control Computer Mouse by Thinking  (2024/2/22) | 马斯克称首位脑芯片人类受试者可凭思维操控鼠标</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/musk-neuralink-patient-able-to-control-computer-mouse-by-thinking.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The first human patient who received a brain chip from Neuralink appears to have fully recovered. The patient is able to control a computer mouse using their thoughts, Neuralink's founder Elon Musk said recently.<br/>
第一位接受Neuralink脑芯片治疗的人类患者似乎已经完全康复。Neuralink的创始人埃隆·马斯克最近表示，患者能够利用自己的思维来控制电脑鼠标。</p>
<p>In an event on social media service X, Musk said, "Progress is good, and the patient seems to have made a full recovery, with no ill effects that we are aware of. Patient is able to move a mouse around the screen by just thinking."<br/>
马斯克在社交媒体网站X上的一次活动中表示，“进展良好，患者似乎已经完全康复，没有任何我们能够意识到的不良反应。患者只需动动脑子，就可以控制鼠标在屏幕上移动。”</p>
<p>Musk said Neuralink was now trying to get as many mouse button clicks as possible from the patient.<br/>
马斯克说，Neuralink现在正试图让患者尽可能多的点击鼠标按钮。</p>
<p>Neuralink did not immediately reply to Reuters' request for further details.<br/>
Neuralink没有立即回复路透社关于进一步细节的请求。</p>
<p>The company successfully implanted a chip in its first human patient last month, after receiving approval for studying human volunteers in September.<br/>
该公司在去年9月份获得研究人类志愿者的批准后，于上月成功地将芯片植入了第一位人类患者体内。</p>
<p>The study uses a robot to surgically place a brain-computer interface implant in an area of the brain that controls the intention to move, Neuralink has said.<br/>
Neuralink表示，这项研究使用机器人通过手术将脑机接口植入物放置在大脑中控制运动意图的区域。</p>
<p>The company added that the goal is to enable people to control a computer cursor or keyboard using their thoughts.<br/>
该公司补充说，目标是让人们能够用自己的思维来控制电脑光标或键盘。</p>
<p>Musk has big hopes for Neuralink. He has suggested its chip devices could help treat conditions like obesity, autism, depression, and schizophrenia.<br/>
马斯克对Neuralink寄予厚望。他表示，该公司的芯片设备可以帮助治疗肥胖、自闭症、抑郁症和精神分裂症等疾病。</p>
<p>Neuralink, which was valued at about $5 billion last year, has faced repeated calls for careful study of its safety rules and processes. Last month, the company got a fine for breaking U.S. Department of Transportation rules regarding the movement of hazardous materials.<br/>
去年估值约为50亿美元的Neuralink一再面临仔细研究其安全规则和流程的呼声。上个月，该公司因违反美国交通部关于危险品运输的规定而被罚款。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>S. Korean Hospitals Turn Away Patients as Doctors Protest  (2024/2/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/s-korean-hospitals-turn-away-patients-as-doctors-protest.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>South Korea's biggest hospitals canceled medical procedures and turned away patients seeking emergency care on Wednesday. The moves came after thousands of trainee doctors walked off the job to protest a government plan to increase the number of people admitted to medical school.</p>
<p>One hospital, the Asan Medical Center in Seoul, had a sign saying its emergency division was only taking heart attack cases. The emergency departments at four other major hospitals were also on "red alert." That means they did not have room for more patients.</p>
<p>"It is so <strong>frustrating</strong> that the <strong>resident</strong> doctors' strike is happening now," the brother of a cancer patient told the newspaper <em>JoongAng Ilbo. </em>He added that he and his brother had spent 10 hours looking for a hospital bed.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Doctors and medical workers take part in a protest against a plan to admit more students to medical school, in front of the Presidential Office in Seoul, South Korea, February 21, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-Hyeon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9b88-08dc32f0c82b_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Doctors and medical workers take part in a protest against a plan to admit more students to medical school, in front of the Presidential Office in Seoul, South Korea, February 21, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-Hyeon)</span></div>
<p>The health ministry says 7,813 doctors have walked out of their jobs since protests began this week. The doctors object to a plan by the government to increase the number of medical students. The plan aims to bring more health workers to rural areas and meet the demands of one of the world's most quickly aging <strong>societies</strong>.</p>
<p>The government wants to increase the number of medical students from 3,000 to 5,000 by the 2025 school year. It aims to add up to 10,000 more by 2035.</p>
<p>The protesters, however, say South Korea has enough doctors. They say the government needs to improve the pay and working conditions of doctors before increasing the number of medical students.</p>
<p>South Korea's population of 52 million had 2.6 doctors per 1,000 people in 2022. Those numbers are far below the average of 3.7 doctors per 1,000 people for developed countries in the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development.</p>
<p>Public opinion studies in South Korea show many Koreans support the government plan. Last week, a Gallup Korea study said about 76 percent of South Koreans back the government's plan to increase the number of medical students.</p>
<p>One group taking part in the protest called the plan a political measure ahead of a general election in April.</p>
<p>"We couldn't just sit back and watch medical policies built only <strong>for the sake of</strong> winning the general election," the Korea Interns and Residents Association said in a statement.</p>
<p>Local media said between one-third and half of scheduled surgeries at five major hospitals have been canceled due to the walkout.</p>
<p>The protests have continued despite a government order for the doctors to return to work.</p>
<p>Vice Health Minister Park Min-soo told reporters, "The basic calling of medical professionals is to protect the health and lives of the people, and any group action that threatens that cannot be justified."</p>
<p>Safety Minister Lee Sang-min later threatened the protest leaders with possible arrest.</p>
<p>"The police and the <strong>prosecutors'</strong> office will <strong>consult</strong> and take measures against any group or individuals who are leading collective action, including arrest and investigation," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English based on Reuters news reports.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>frustrating</strong> - adj. causing feeling of anger and annoyance</p>
<p><strong>resident</strong> - n. a doctor in training</p>
<p><strong>society</strong> - n. people in a particular country</p>
<p><strong>for the sake of</strong> - <em>phrase</em>, out of consideration or regard</p>
<p><strong>prosecutor</strong> - n. a lawyer who represents the government or the side accusing someone of a crime</p>
<p><strong>consult</strong> - v. look for information</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New York Man Stays Free in Hotel, Then Claims to Own It  (2024/2/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/new-york-man-stays-free-in-hotel-then-claims-to-own-it.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>For five years, a New York City man lived for free in a famous central New York City hotel. He made use of a little-known housing rule to avoid paying.</p>
<p>But government lawyers recently said Mickey Barreto went too far. He turned in paperwork claiming ownership of the whole New Yorker Hotel building. And he also tried to have another person pay him for living there.</p>
<p>Last week, Barreto was arrested and charged with turning in false property records, a criminal offense. The 48-year-old man says he was surprised when police showed up at his boyfriend's <strong>apartment</strong> with guns and protective gear.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The New Yorker Hotel is seen in New York, Nov. 8, 2013. A man who succeeded in using a New York City housing law to live rent-free in the iconic hotel has been charged with fraud after he claimed to own it. (AP Photo/Peter Morgan, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/712b86ab-5ff8-47d5-aa14-467692b87aad_cx0_cy3_cw75_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The New Yorker Hotel is seen in New York, Nov. 8, 2013. A man who succeeded in using a New York City housing law to live rent-free in the iconic hotel has been charged with fraud after he claimed to own it. (AP Photo/Peter Morgan, File)</span></div>
<p>"I said, ‘Oh, I thought you were doing something for Valentine's Day to <strong>spice</strong> up the relationship until I saw the female officers,'" Barreto recalled telling his boyfriend. Valentine's Day is a holiday where people celebrate love.</p>
<p>The charges against Barreto came after years of legal battles. They began when he and his boyfriend paid about $200 to stay in one of the more than 1,000 rooms in the hotel built in 1930.</p>
<p>Barreto says he had just moved to New York from Los Angeles, California when his boyfriend told him about a little-known part of housing law that permits people who stay in single rooms in buildings built before 1969 to demand a six-month contract.</p>
<p>Barreto claimed that because he had paid for a night in the hotel, he was counted as a <strong>tenant</strong>. He asked for a contract to stay and the hotel immediately had him leave.</p>
<p>Barreto said he went to court the next day and the judge denied him. But he said, "I appealed to the (state) Supreme Court and I won the appeal." But he added that at an important point in the case, lawyers for the building's owners did not show up, which permitted him to win by <strong>default</strong>.</p>
<p>The judge ordered the hotel to give Barreto a key. He said he lived there until July 2023 without paying for his room because the building's owners did not want to work out a contract with him. But they could not ask him to leave.</p>
<p>New York City <strong>prosecutors</strong> agree that the housing court gave Barreto "possession" of his room. But they say he did not stop there.</p>
<p>In 2019, he put false paperwork on a city website claiming that the Holy Spirit Association for the Unification of World Christianity had turned over the ownership of the entire building to him. The organization bought the property in 1976. The church was founded in South Korea by the late Rev. Sun Myung Moon.</p>
<p>Barreto then tried to charge different groups as the owner of the building. The prosecutor's office said they include demanding payments from one of the hotel's tenants and demanding the hotel put its bank accounts in his name.</p>
<p>The Unification Church took Barreto to court in 2019 over the building's ownership claim. The case is ongoing, but a judge ruled that Barreto cannot present himself as the owner in the meantime.</p>
<p>A Unification Church spokesperson did not comment on his arrest as there is an ongoing civil case.</p>
<p>In that case, Barreto argued that the judge who gave him "possession" of his room indirectly gave him the entire building because it had never been subdivided.</p>
<p>"I never <strong>intended </strong>to <strong>commit</strong> any <strong>fraud</strong>. I don't believe I ever committed any fraud," Barreto said. He said he never made any money out of this.</p>
<p>Barreto said he aims to deny profits to the Unification Church. The church, known for holding large weddings, has been accused of misleading people to gain members and criticized by some over its friendly relationship with North Korea, where Moon was born.</p>
<p>Barreto said he has never paid for a lawyer and has always represented himself in civil cases. Last week, he secured criminal defense legal representation.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Cedar Attanasio reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>Apartment </strong>– <em>n</em>. a usually rented room or set of rooms that is part of a building and is used as a place to live</p>
<p><strong>prosecutor </strong>– <em>n</em>. a lawyer who represents the side in a court case that accuses a person of a crime and who tries to prove that the person is guilty</p>
<p><strong>spice </strong><em>– v.</em> to add interest or excitement to (something)</p>
<p><strong>fraud </strong><em>– n.</em> the crime of using dishonest methods to take something valuable from another person</p>
<p><strong>tenant </strong><em>– n.</em> a person, business, or group that pays to use another person's property: someone who rents or leases a house, apartment, etc., from a landlord</p>
<p><strong>default </strong><em>– n. </em>used to describe something that happens or is done when nothing else has been done or can be done</p>
<p><strong>intend </strong><em>– v. </em>to plan or want to do (something)</p>
<p><strong>commit </strong><em>– v.</em> to do (something that is illegal or harmful)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pregnant Stingray Offers Rare Lesson of Biology  (2024/2/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/pregnant-stingray-offers-rare-lesson-of-biology.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Charlotte has spent much of her life in captivity at a non-profit <strong>aquarium</strong> in North Carolina's Appalachian Mountains. She is an ocean animal called a round stingray.</p>
<p>She is about 3,700 kilometers from her natural <strong>habitat </strong>in the Pacific Ocean off southern California. And she has not shared space with a male of her species in at least eight years.</p>
<p>But Charlotte is about to give birth. The reddish-brown stingray is pregnant with as many as four young, called pups. They were created by a rare process of natural reproduction called parthenogenesis. A female animal develops an egg into an embryo without fertilization material from a male.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kinsley Boyette, assistant director of the Aquarium and Shark Lab by Team ECCO, poses in this undated photo next to Charlotte, a round stingray, in the American town of Hendersonville, North Carolina. (Aquarium and Shark Lab by Team ECCO via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3ccda11a-aee8-41c9-aa4a-77b0d48a0fad_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kinsley Boyette, assistant director of the Aquarium and Shark Lab by Team ECCO, poses in this undated photo next to Charlotte, a round stingray, in the American town of Hendersonville, North Carolina. (Aquarium and Shark Lab by Team ECCO via AP)</span></div>
<p>Charlotte will give birth to her young at home: Team ECCO Aquarium and Shark Lab on Main Street in Hendersonville. Brenda Ramer formed the organization and serves as its chief.</p>
<p>She said, when caretakers first noticed a <strong>lump</strong> on Charlotte's back, they thought it might be a cancerous growth. So, they examined the animal with an ultrasound machine, which makes images using sound. The images showed that Charlotte was pregnant.</p>
<p>The aquarium team was shocked.</p>
<p>"We were all like, ‘Shut the back door. There's no way,'" Ramer said. "We thought we were overfeeding her. But we were overfeeding her because she has more mouths to feed."</p>
<p>The small aquarium <strong>encourages</strong> local schoolchildren and others to take an interest in science. Now, they are getting a real-life lesson few witness. Parthenogenesis can happen in some insects, fish, amphibians, birds and reptiles, but it is extremely unusual. Documented examples have included California condors, Komodo dragons and yellow-bellied water snakes.</p>
<p>Kady Lyons is a research scientist at the Georgia Aquarium in Atlanta. She is not connected to the North Carolina aquarium. She said Charlotte's pregnancy is the only documented example of parthenogenesis in the round stingray that she knows of.</p>
<p>But Lyons is not shocked. Other kinds of rays, and related fish such as sharks, have had these kinds of pregnancies under human care.</p>
<p>"I'm not surprised, because nature finds a way of having this happen," she said.</p>
<p>To be clear, Lyons said, these animals are not <strong>cloning</strong> themselves. Instead, a female's egg joins with another cell in the female. This leads to cell division and creation of an embryo.</p>
<p>"We don't know why it happens," Lyons said. "Just that it's kind of this really neat <strong>phenomenon </strong>that they seem to be able to do."</p>
<p>Charlotte lives in a tank of about 8,300 liters of water. Ramer said the aquarium is hoping to get a tank nearly twice that size for Charlotte's young. They also want to put live cameras up for people to see them.</p>
<p>"It is very rare to happen," Ramer said. "But it's happening in the middle of the Blue Ridge Mountains in rural North Carolina, hundreds of miles from the ocean."</p>
<p>Round stingrays like Charlotte are common along the Pacific Ocean coasts of southern California and Mexico. They often rest on the ocean's sandy bottom near land.</p>
<p>In the wild, they are about the size of a food plate. They come in all <strong>shades</strong> of brown. They eat small animals like worms, crabs and mollusks. And round stingrays are sometimes eaten by sharks, seals and giant sea bass.</p>
<p>The round ray is well known to humans who like to go in the ocean. The ray can sting when stepped on.</p>
<p>Lyons finds the species <strong>fascinating</strong>.</p>
<p>"I'm glad the round stingray is getting the media attention that it deserves," Lyons said. "It's not necessarily as sexy as a white shark, but they do a lot of really <strong>neat</strong> stuff."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press's Ben Finley wrote this report. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>aquarium </strong><em>–n.</em> a tank that holds fish or a building that keeps fish for the public to see and enjoy</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>habitat </strong><em>–n.</em> the environment in which a plant or animal lives</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>encourage </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause someone to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cloning </strong><em>–n.</em> the process of making an exact genetic copy of a living thing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>phenomenon </strong><em>–n.</em> an event that happens for a reason which can be described and studied</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>shade </strong><em>–n.</em> the level of brightness or darkness that a color has</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fascinating </strong><em>–adj.</em> very interesting and worth attention</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>neat </strong><em>–adj. (informal)</em> interesting or fun</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>OpenAI Announces New Video Generator  (2024/2/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/openai-announces-new-video-generator.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The maker of ChatGPT recently announced its next move into generative artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>San Francisco-based OpenAI's new text-to-video <strong>generator</strong>, called Sora, is a tool that instantly makes short videos based on written commands, called prompts.</p>
<p>Sora is not the first of its kind. Google, Meta and Runway ML are among the other companies to have developed similar technology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The OpenAI logo is displayed on a cell phone with an image on a computer monitor generated by ChatGPT's Dall-E text-to-image model, Friday, Dec. 8, 2023, in Boston.(AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7b0c08e3-1090-4fe6-be13-2b226b00980a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The OpenAI logo is displayed on a cell phone with an image on a computer monitor generated by ChatGPT's Dall-E text-to-image model, Friday, Dec. 8, 2023, in Boston.(AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)</span></div>
<p>But the high quality of videos displayed by OpenAI — some after CEO Sam Altman asked social media users to send in ideas for written prompts — surprised observers. At the same time, the video results led to fears about the possible ethical and societal effects.</p>
<p>A photographer from New Hampshire posted one suggestion, or prompt, on X. The prompt gave details about a kind of food to be cooked, gnocchi, as well as the setting – an old Italian country kitchen.</p>
<p>The prompt said:</p>
<p>"A instructional cooking session for homemade gnocchi hosted by a grandmother social media influencer set in a <strong>rustic</strong> Tuscan country kitchen with cinematic lighting."</p>
<p>Altman answered a short time later with a realistic video that showed what the <strong>prompt</strong> described.</p>
<p>The tool is not yet publicly available. OpenAI has given limited information about how it was built. The company also has not stated what imagery and video sources were used to train Sora.</p>
<p>The New York Times and some writers have taken legal actions against OpenAI for its use of copyrighted works of writing to train ChatGPT. And OpenAI pays a fee to The Associated Press, the source of this report, to license its text news <strong>archive</strong>.</p>
<p>OpenAI said in a blog post that it is communicating with artists, policymakers and others before releasing the new tool to the public.</p>
<p>The company added that it is working with "red teamers" – people who try to find problems and give helpful suggestions – to develop Sora.</p>
<p>"We are working with red teamers — ... experts in areas like misinformation, hateful content, and bias — who will be <strong>adversarially </strong>testing the model," the company said.</p>
<p>"We're also building tools to help detect misleading content such as a detection<strong> classifier </strong>that can tell when a video was generated by Sora."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell adapted this report from the Associated Press. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>generator </strong><em>-- n. </em> something that produces something</p>
<p><strong>rustic </strong><em>-- adj. </em>of, relating to, or suitable for the country or people who live in the country</p>
<p><strong>prompt</strong><em> – n.</em> a message that asks a computer to do something or to provide information</p>
<p><strong>archive </strong><em>– n.</em> a place where records are kept</p>
<p><strong>adversarial </strong><em>– adj.</em> involving two people or two sides who oppose each other</p>
<p><strong>classifier</strong> <em>– n.</em> a program that separates data into classes or categories</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cooking School Provides Hope for Future  (2024/2/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/cooking-school-provides-hope-for-future.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>When Clarissa Haglid completed <strong>culinary</strong> school at the Delaware Food Bank last summer, it was the first time she had graduated from anything in her life.</p>
<p>Just a few years earlier, a goal like that did not seem within reach. In 2020, she was charged with armed robbery and later sentenced to prison. Haglid told VOA that she "lost everything," including the <strong>custody</strong> of her children.</p>
<p>As she approached the end of her four-year prison sentence, she learned about a restaurant service training program available to people in jail. Haglid started attending culinary school classes at the Food Bank in Newark, Delaware, when she received permission to take part in the work-release program. Through the 14-week program, students learned cooking and life skills to prepare them for a job in the restaurant or <strong>hospitality</strong> industry.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Clarissa Haglid, a graduate of the culinary school at the Delaware Food Bank, in the food bank's kitchen on February 7, 2024. Haglid received an apprenticeship at a nearby hotel following her completion of the program. (Dan Novak/VOA)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6a12-08dc2ca56c19_cx0_cy17_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Clarissa Haglid, a graduate of the culinary school at the Delaware Food Bank, in the food bank's kitchen on February 7, 2024. Haglid received an apprenticeship at a nearby hotel following her completion of the program. (Dan Novak/VOA)</span></div>
<p>Some of the students currently at Newark were <strong>incarcerated</strong> like Haglid. Others are in substance abuse recovery programs or underemployed, meaning they have been out of the workforce for a long time, said Anna McDermott. She is the Food Bank's Chief Impact Officer.</p>
<p>Haglid and other students learned how to use knives in cooking, correct food preparation, and how to make the five foundational "mother" sauces and other skills. The program also teaches teamwork, <strong>work ethic</strong> and time <strong>management</strong>.</p>
<p>Those kinds of life skills, also called "soft skills," are taught to "make sure that folks are really familiar with what is expected of them in the workplace to maintain employment," McDermott said. "Getting a job is the easiest part, sometimes. It's maintaining that job."</p>
<p>At the end of the program, students are provided an entry-level job through the state restaurant association. Haglid is an <strong>apprentice</strong> at a nearby hotel, where she receives a paycheck and additional training as a cook.</p>
<p>"This program meant everything to me because...it was a way for me to get not my life back, but a life to begin with," Haglid said. Attending the culinary school started to "bridge the gap of <strong>restora</strong><strong>tion</strong> between me and my kids."</p>
<p>Haglid was able to attend the classes through a U.S. Department of Labor program called HOPES, Hospitality Opportunities for People Reentering Society. HOPES is operated through the National Restaurant Association Education Foundation (NRAEF), an industry group, which partners with community organizations like the Delaware Food Bank. The group's goal with HOPES is to get incarcerated people training and jobs in the restaurant industry.</p>
<p>Rob Gifford is president of the NRAEF. He said restaurant jobs help prevent recidivism, the word for returning to prison. Gifford said food service jobs help people released from prison get work and a way to earn money as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Food service, he said, has a "relatively low barrier to entry," compared to other jobs that might require more training. Since prisons provide food service, there is already a place to provide training. And unlike other work, restaurant jobs often do not require college or even high school degrees.</p>
<p>"We're allowing these individuals to get on their feet quickly via the restaurant industry, but we're giving them ... <strong>transferable</strong> <strong>skills</strong>," Gifford said. "When they decide they're ready to move on to their next <strong>opportunity</strong>... they're positioned for success."</p>
<p>Employment for formerly imprisoned people is very important to prevent recidivism. The NRAEF says that formerly imprisoned people who maintained a job for the first year following their release had a 16 percent recidivism rate over three years. That is compared to a 52 percent recidivism rate for those that did not maintain employment. The unemployment rate for people formerly incarcerated is more than six times the national rate.</p>
<p>Gifford said about 1000 people have gone through the HOPES program nationwide, and two-thirds are currently employed.</p>
<p>Haglid, who said she is regaining custody of her children, plans to continue her work in restaurants and one day lead a kitchen as a chef. She also said she wants to support the educational and job training programs that helped her find work. She said the programs are needed to prevent recidivism and provide hope for the future.</p>
<p>"When you realize you have the ability to learn, (it) almost creates a hunger in you where you want to <strong>absorb</strong> as much as you possibly can," Haglid said. "You begin to have a drive that you never had before."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>culinary </strong>–adj. related to cooking and the restaurant industry</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>custody </strong><em>— n. </em>the legal right to take care of a child</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>incarcerated </strong><em>— adj. </em>currently or previously in prison</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>work ethic </strong><em>–n. </em>the idea that work and employment is good, moral and gives people purpose and meaning</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>management </strong><em>–n.</em> the ability to plan, organize or supervise something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hospitality </strong><em>— adj.(industry) </em>related to the business of restaurants, hotels, travel and tourism</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>apprentice </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who is in training for a trade which is learned from an established tradesman<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>restore </strong><em>— v. </em>to bring a person back to a position or something back to a former condition<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transferable</strong> <strong>skill </strong><em>— n. </em>skills that can be used in everyday life or in any job</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>opportunity </strong><em>— n. </em>a chance for a new job, project or activity<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>absorb </strong><em>–v.</em> to take in or learn something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan Loses Its Spot as World’s Third-largest Economy  (2024/2/21) | 日本失去世界第三大经济体的地位</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/japan-loses-its-spot-as-world-s-third-largest-economy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Japan's economy has dropped to the fourth largest in the world. It fell behind Germany after its economy shrank in the last quarter of 2023.<br/>
日本经济已跌至世界第四位。在2023年最后一个季度经济萎缩后，它掉到了德国之后。</p>
<p>The Japanese government reported Thursday the economy shrank at an annual rate of 0.4 percent in October to December.<br/>
日本政府星期四报告说，去年10月至12月，日本经济以0.4%的年化速度萎缩。</p>
<p>It shrunk 2.9 percent from July to September. Two straight quarters of shrinkage are considered a sign that an economy is in a recession.<br/>
从7月到9月，这一数字萎缩了2.9%。连续两个季度的萎缩被认为是经济陷入衰退的迹象。</p>
<p>Real gross domestic product is a measure of the value of a nation's products and services. The yearly rate measures what would have happened if the quarterly rate lasted a year.<br/>
实际国内生产总值是衡量一个国家产品和服务价值的指标。年化比率衡量的是如果季度比率持续一年会发生什么。</p>
<p>Japan's economy was the second largest until 2010, when it was overtaken by China's. It had been the third-largest economy until it fell behind Germany.<br/>
日本经济在2010年之前一直是第二大经济体，后来被中国赶超。在落后于德国之前，日本一直是第三大经济体。</p>
<p>Japan's nominal GDP totaled $4.2 trillion last year. Germany's was between $4.4 and $4.5 trillion.<br/>
日本去年的名义国内生产总值为4.2万亿美元。德国为4.4至4.5万亿美元。</p>
<p>Real GDP takes into account inflation, while nominal GDP does not.<br/>
实际国内生产总值考虑了通货膨胀，而名义国内生产总值则没有。</p>
<p>A weaker Japanese yen was a major reason for the drop to fourth place. But economists say the drop is also due to a decline in its population and slowing productivity and competitiveness.<br/>
日元走弱是日本跌至第四位的主要原因。但经济学家表示，排名下降也是由于日本人口减少、生产力和竞争力下降。</p>
<p>In the past, Japan was described as a "an economic miracle." After much of the country was destroyed in World War II, it became the second-largest economy after the United States. It continued to see strong growth in the 1970s and 1980s. But in the last 30 years, the economy has grown only moderately at times.<br/>
过去，日本被描述为“经济奇迹”。在日本大部分地区在二战中被摧毁后，它成为仅次于美国的第二大经济体。它在上世纪七八十年代继续保持强劲增长。但在过去的30年里，日本经济有时只是勉强增长。</p>
<p>Both the Japanese and German economies are powered by strong small- and medium-size businesses with strong productivity.<br/>
日本和德国的经济都由具有强大生产力的强势中小型企业提供动力。</p>
<p>Germany's economy has gotten very strong in the past 20 years. It has led worldwide markets for high-end products like luxury cars and industrial machinery. It has sold so much to the rest of the world that half its economy ran on exports. But Germany's economy also shrank in the last quarter, by 0.3 percent.<br/>
德国经济在过去20年里变得非常强劲。它引领了全球高端产品市场，如豪华汽车和工业机械。它向世界其他地区的出口如此之多，以至于其一半的经济都依赖出口。但德国经济在上一季度也出现了0.3%的萎缩。</p>
<p>Japan's population has been shrinking and aging for many years. It has few foreign residents. Germany's population has grown to nearly 85 million. Immigration helped to make up for a low birth rate in Germany.<br/>
多年来，日本人口一直在减少和老龄化。它几乎没有外国居民。德国的人口已经增长到近8500万。移民帮助弥补了德国的低出生率。</p>
<p>Immigration is one way to solve Japan's labor shortage problem. But the country has been somewhat unaccepting of foreign labor.<br/>
移民是解决日本劳动力短缺问题的一种方式。但这个国家一直有点不接受外国劳动力。</p>
<p>Another reason for Japan's slow growth is stagnating wages. People have less money to spend. At the same time, businesses have invested heavily in foreign economies instead of Japan's aging and shrinking market.<br/>
日本经济增长缓慢的另一个原因是工资停滞不前。人们可花的钱越来越少。与此同时，企业对外国经济体进行了大量投资，而不是对老龄化和萎缩的日本市场进行投资。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Groups Seek US Endangered Protection for Horseshoe Crabs  (2024/2/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/groups-seek-us-endangered-protection-for-horseshoe-crabs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A group of environmental organizations is seeking an official declaration that American horseshoe crabs are endangered.</p>
<p>The groups have requested the declaration with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). The U.S. agency administers the Endangered Species Act, which was established in 1973.</p>
<p>The American horseshoe crab – known as a "living <strong>fossil</strong>" – is one of the oldest living creatures on Earth. It is believed to date back at least 450 million years. Scientists do not actually consider horseshoes true crabs. This is because they are more closely related to spiders and scorpions than to other sea creatures.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Atlantic Horseshoe crabs come ashore to spawn and lay their eggs on Pickering Beach, a national horseshoe crab sanctuary near Little Creek, Delaware, May 20, 2008. (REUTERS/Mike Segar/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-15fb-08dc2eef8285_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Atlantic Horseshoe crabs come ashore to spawn and lay their eggs on Pickering Beach, a national horseshoe crab sanctuary near Little Creek, Delaware, May 20, 2008. (REUTERS/Mike Segar/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>If NOAA approves the endangered declaration, it would generally make it unlawful for people to harm or kill a horseshoe crab without an official permit to do so.</p>
<p>Research suggests horseshoe crab populations in the U.S. have decreased sharply over the past 30 years. For example, growth numbers for the animals are down two-thirds from 1990 in an area of the Delaware Bay. Environmental groups say this body of water in the northeastern state of Delaware once held the largest population of horseshoe crabs.</p>
<p>Research also shows that egg densities for the animals have fallen more than 80 percent over the past 40 years. The reproduction drops are linked to environmental changes causing other sea creatures to eat their <strong>larvae</strong> and eggs, researchers say.</p>
<p>A collection of 23 environmental groups have joined to seek the endangered declaration. The request, or petition, also seeks the establishment of a "critical <strong>habitat</strong>" for horseshoe crabs to be protected.</p>
<p>The request names numerous threats to the animals – all of which are blamed on human activities. These include harvesting the crabs to be used for <strong>bait</strong>, use in biomedical activities, habitat loss and climate change.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for NOAA confirmed to Reuters news service the agency was examining the groups' petition, but did not comment further.</p>
<p>Will Harlan is a senior scientist at the Arizona-based <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.biologicaldiversity.org/">Center for Biological Diversity</a>. He told Reuters, "We're <strong>wiping out</strong> one of the world's oldest and toughest creatures." His group is one of those seeking the endangered declaration.</p>
<p>Drug manufacturers harvest horseshoe crabs in large numbers for their blue-colored blood. The blood is used to test and develop drugs and medical devices. The petition states that in 2022, nearly 1 million of the animals were used for medical purposes.</p>
<p>Current law permits the biomedical industry to capture small amounts of horseshoe crab blood before releasing the animals alive to areas where they were collected.</p>
<p>However, NOAA says between 10 to 15 percent of harvested animals die during this process. Harlan said non-industry research suggests this rate is even higher. Those estimates show that 30 percent of horseshoe crabs captured for blood collection die in the process.</p>
<p>Harlan noted that while <strong>synthetic </strong>blood versions are widely used in Europe, American companies have been slow to use them.</p>
<p>The petition says the other main cause of population drops is overharvesting of horseshoe crabs for <strong>commercial</strong> fisheries. Environmental activists say this is likely to continue, with no sign of recovery even after harvesting limits were established.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>– n. </em>something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) from a plant or animal that lived in ancient times and that you can see in old rocks</p>
<p><strong>larvae </strong><em>– n. </em>the form of some creatures, such as insects, before they develop into a different form</p>
<p><strong>habitat </strong><em>– n.</em> the natural environment for plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>bait </strong><em>– n. </em>food that is used to try to attract fish or animals in order to catch them</p>
<p><strong>wipe out </strong><em>– v. </em>to destroy</p>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong><em>– adj. </em>a group of products made from artificial substances, often copying a natural product from ancient times</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong><em>– adj. </em>related to buying and selling things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Climate Change Diet Not Good for Polar Bears  (2024/2/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/study-climate-change-diet-not-good-for-polar-bears.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests that the climate change diet might not be good for polar bears.</p>
<p>With Arctic sea ice declining, many polar bears have to go to land for their diets during parts of the summer.</p>
<p>A study looking at Hudson Bay polar bears tried to figure out if the creatures can keep their healthy weight levels on such a diet.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A polar bear eats whale meat as it walks along the shore of Hudson Bay near Churchill, Manitoba, Aug. 23, 2010. With Arctic sea ice shrinking, polar bears have to shift their diets to land during parts of the summer. (Sean Kilpatrick/The Canadian Press via AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6438-08dc2e462cfd_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A polar bear eats whale meat as it walks along the shore of Hudson Bay near Churchill, Manitoba, Aug. 23, 2010. With Arctic sea ice shrinking, polar bears have to shift their diets to land during parts of the summer. (Sean Kilpatrick/The Canadian Press via AP, File)</span></div>
<p>Researchers found that the majority of the creatures are losing weight no matter what they do to try to increase it.</p>
<p>Some bears find a lot of food — berries, eggs, sea birds and even caribou antlers. But such foods take a lot of effort. The bears use so many calories trying to eat that they end up losing weight and burning more energy than they take in, the study says.</p>
<p>The findings appeared recently in the publication <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/ncomms/" target="_blank">Nature Communications</a>.</p>
<p>Other bears go into a time of semi-<strong>hibernation</strong>. But they also lose weight.</p>
<p>So either way – eating different foods or sleeping a lot – does not work, said the study's lead writer Anthony Pagano of the U.S. Geological Survey.</p>
<p><strong>Losing weight </strong></p>
<p>Researchers found that 19 of the 20 bears studied dropped an average of 21 kilograms over three weeks of being studied. The research observed their calorie intake, energy use and <strong>respiration</strong> in the wild.</p>
<p>The bears lost about 7 percent of their body mass on average in just 21 days, the study found.</p>
<p>Polar bears try to keep up their weight in the summer after a spring when they eat a lot and gain weight. In the area of the Hudson Bay where researchers studied, lack of sea ice has meant polar bears are on land three weeks longer than in the 1980s, Pagano said.</p>
<p>Usually, polar bears eat high-fat seals while based on sea ice near where the seals are. Hunting is especially good in the spring when seal pups are young and have not yet learned to swim away from the ice base, Pagano said.</p>
<p><strong>Loss of sea ice </strong></p>
<p>Last September, when Arctic sea ice hit its yearly low, there was about 2.6 million square kilometers less sea ice than the same time in 1979, the National Snow and Ice Data Center says. The United States Fish and Wildlife Service lists polar bears as a threatened species "due to the loss of its sea ice <strong>habitat</strong>."</p>
<p>"This paper clearly shows that polar bears cannot <strong>adapt</strong> to the <strong>pace</strong> of change in the Arctic and that the bears are already using everything they have to stay alive,'' said University of Alberta biologist Andrew Derocher. Derocher was not part of the research but suggested it was important and done well.</p>
<p>"This is concerning because of course it really does raise the question of when will the individual bears run out of energy," Derocher said. While research shows that some of the bears will survive, "other bears were basically right on the edge of where they would potentially suffer from starvation and subsequent death."</p>
<p>Overall, the research shows that it is unlikely polar bears can adapt to living on land, Derocher said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Seth Borenstein reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>hibernation</strong><em> – n.</em> to spend the winter sleeping or resting</p>
<p><strong>respiration</strong> <em>– n. medical:</em> the act or process of breathing</p>
<p><strong>habitat</strong><em> – n</em>. the place or type of place where an animal naturally lives</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong><em>– v.</em> to change behavior so that it is easier to live in a particular place or situation</p>
<p><strong>pace </strong><em>– n. </em>the speed at which someone or something moves</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Tough Groundcovers for Dry Climate  (2024/2/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/tough-groundcovers-for-dry-climate.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Trying to grow grass in the deserts or other dry places can seem like a losing battle. As a result, many people who live in such climates will use rocks, gravel, or man-made materials as groundcover instead of grass.</p>
<p>But there are several tough, low-growing groundcovers that perform well in dry climates. They may not be able to survive the foot traffic that <strong>fake</strong> grass can. But they appeal to environmentally helpful insects and in many cases make your property look better.</p>
<p><strong>Groundcovers for dry climate</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by Bugwood.org shows a Silverbush (Convolvulus cneorum) plant in bloom. The fast-growing, drought-tolerant evergreen is a good choice for covering ground in desert climates. (John Ruter/University of Georgia/Bugwood.org via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a3a6-08dc2e288e0e_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by Bugwood.org shows a Silverbush (Convolvulus cneorum) plant in bloom. The fast-growing, drought-tolerant evergreen is a good choice for covering ground in desert climates. (John Ruter/University of Georgia/Bugwood.org via AP)</span></div>
<p>Desert marigold, or Baileya multiradiata, is one such plant. The groundcover has pretty yellow blossoms and silver leaves. They <strong>bloom</strong> in the spring. The plant requires very little water. However, it lives only one season. People who want desert marigold must plant it every year.</p>
<p>Gold Mound lantana, known as Lantana camara, is a <strong>bushy</strong> plant usually just over a half-meter tall. Its yellow flowers bloom on and off from spring through autumn and it has low to moderate water needs.</p>
<p>Its relative, trailing lantana, or Lantana montevidensis, grows <strong>horizontally</strong>. Its purple blossoms brighten the garden year-round. The groundcover has moderate water needs. It favors full sunlight but can survive partial sunlight.</p>
<p>Trailing indigo, or Dalea greggii, is another groundcover that grows well in dry climates. The long-lived plant has blue-gray leaves and pink or purple pea-shaped flowers. It blooms from spring through summer in full or partial sunlight. The plant, which can spread to three meters wide, has very low water needs but could use some watering while in bloom.</p>
<p>Silverbush, also known as Convolvulus cneorum, is a fast-growing evergreen that, in the desert, blooms for about two weeks in spring. The 60-centimeter-tall plant has yellow-centered white flowers with silver leaves.</p>
<p>White evening primrose, Oenothera caespitosa, is usually covered in blooms from spring through summer. But they are only open from late <strong>afternoon</strong> into morning. The white blossoms develop to light pink, and then darken to deep pinkish-purple. The plant has moderate water needs and performs best in full sun to part shade.</p>
<p><strong>Best time to plant</strong></p>
<p>Early spring is the best time to plant these groundcovers in desert climates.</p>
<p>Gently loosen the soil to about 30 centimeters deep, removing stones and other hard material to permit a clear path for roots. Give some space between the plants. Add mulch or wood chips to keep soil temperature even, prevent weeds, and help hold water.</p>
<p>The best time of day to water the groundcovers is in the morning. To avoid root <strong>rot</strong>, water the groundcover only when, and as soon as, the soil is completely dry.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fake </strong>- <em>adj. </em>not real; not genuine</p>
<p><strong>bloom</strong> - v. to produce flowers</p>
<p><strong>bushy</strong> - adj. thick and full</p>
<p><strong>horizontally</strong> - adv. positioned parallel to the ground</p>
<p><strong>afternoon</strong> - n. the part of the day between noon and evening</p>
<p><strong>rot</strong> - n. process of slowly decaying</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Can ‘Less Be More’ with Cancer Drugs?  (2024/2/20)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/can-less-be-more-with-cancer-drugs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">19 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many people who find out they have cancer are able to survive the disease because of effective drugs.</p>
<p>Treating cancer with certain drugs is known as chemotherapy. The drugs contain powerful chemicals that kill cancer cells but also cause bad reactions in patients.</p>
<p>Although the drugs help keep patients alive, they cause extreme tiredness, stomach pain and the loss of hair. Some even result in mouth <strong>sores</strong> for patients. These problems are called side effects.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Jill Feldman, 54, poses for a photo at her home in Deerfield, Ill., Friday, Jan. 19, 2024. A lung cancer patient and advocate, Feldman takes pills at home that shrink tumors by blocking a signal that tells cancer cells to grow. (AP Photo/Nam Y. Huh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d16c8e57-078d-488e-9fe6-df654eac64dc_cx14_cy0_cw85_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Jill Feldman, 54, poses for a photo at her home in Deerfield, Ill., Friday, Jan. 19, 2024. A lung cancer patient and advocate, Feldman takes pills at home that shrink tumors by blocking a signal that tells cancer cells to grow. (AP Photo/Nam Y. Huh)</span></div>
<p>After many years of strong side effects, some patients and their doctors are talking to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) about finding the lowest effective <strong>dose</strong> for cancer drugs.</p>
<p>In the past, drug companies tested to find the "<strong>maximum</strong> <strong>tolerable</strong> dose." However, doctors and patients are asking drugmakers to think about a dose that will kill cancer cells with less severe side effects. Some patients might prefer the lower dose even if they need to use the drug longer.</p>
<p>Jill Feldman of Illinois is 54. She has been treated for lung cancer for 15 years. She is happy to be alive – her parents died of lung cancer soon after they found out they had it. She said she is always in pain. She said her mouth always feels like it is burning.</p>
<p>With the help of her doctors, she receives a lower dose of her cancer drug. But she wants drug companies to research low doses when they are developing the treatments.</p>
<p>"No one should have to <strong>endure</strong> avoidable harmful effects of treatment," she said.</p>
<p>Dr. Lillian Siu works on drug development at Princess Margaret Cancer Center in Toronto, Ontario. She said new cancer drugs are more <strong>precise</strong> than in the past. Some newer drugs target a <strong>mutation</strong> that causes cancer cell growth. Others cause the patient's <strong>immune system</strong> to fight the cancer.</p>
<p>Siu says the question is whether patients can get "the same bang for their buck," or useful result, with a lower dose of a drug. "You might only need a low dose to turn off that cancer driver," she said.</p>
<p>An FDA spokesperson said there is a new program called Project Optimus that asks drugmakers to include patients who receive lower doses in their <strong>clinical trials</strong>.</p>
<p>Sometimes doctors lower doses during the later parts of testing. But other times, lower doses are called for only after the drug is approved and doctors try to reduce their patients' side-effects.</p>
<p>Dr. Patricia LoRusso leads drug research at the Yale Cancer Center in Connecticut. She said the problem with using high doses is that patients start to feel bad, so they have to stop taking the drug. During that time, the cancer starts to come back.</p>
<p>In addition, some patients get results from a low dose, while others only get results from a high dose. That is called patient-to-patient variation. People's liver and kidneys process cancer drugs differently which affects how much of the medicine reaches the cancer cells.</p>
<p>"The challenge is: Where is the sweet spot?" LoRusso said. A "sweet spot" means just the right amount.</p>
<p>One large group of patients has concerns about doses that are too high: women with breast cancer that has spread to other parts of their body. That kind of cancer is very difficult to treat. Without drugs, the cancer might spread even more. So many patients must be on cancer drugs for most of their lives. But they want to be able to enjoy their time, instead of feeling sick.</p>
<p>Dr. Julie Gralow is chief medical officer of the American Society of Clinical Oncology. She is working on a low-dose study of 500 patients who take two kinds of drugs for breast cancer.</p>
<p>She said the study will look at two kinds of treatments. One that starts patients on a low dose that increases if the patient does well. The other starts the patient at a high dose and then lowers if side effects are too difficult.</p>
<p>Lesley Kailani Glenn is a 58-year-old breast cancer patient from Oregon. She has been getting treatment for 11 years. She said she will need the drugs for the rest of her life.</p>
<p>"We want to try to live the best that we can, knowing that treatment is never-ever going to stop," she said. Glenn has hiked California mountains and up high seaside hills in Italy while receiving treatment. She works with her doctor to change the amount of drug she receives based on her ability to tolerate it. She said the number one thing she dislikes is the feeling that she needs to use the bathroom all the time.</p>
<p>She does not want to lose her quality of life.</p>
<p>Project Optimus asks drugmakers to compare the results of different doses. It might sound like a good idea, but the drug companies have concerns. They say carrying out trials of separate doses slows down the development process.</p>
<p>Dr. Alice Shaw leads cancer drug development at Novartis, a Swiss drug company. She said the interest in lowering side effects by testing different doses needs to be weighed against getting a helpful new drug to cancer doctors.</p>
<p>She said it might be better to get the drugs on the market first.</p>
<p>But Dr. Timothy Yap of the MD Anderson Cancer Center in Houston, Texas said drug companies might not be seeing the problem correctly. He said they need to take the time early in the process to find the right dose. That way, more patients will be able to use their medicine.</p>
<p>"If the patients are not taking the drug, then it's not going to work," Yap said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sore </strong><em>–n.</em> an area on the skin or tissue that is painful</p>
<p><strong>dose </strong><em>–n.</em> the right amount of medicine needed to get a good result</p>
<p><strong>maximum </strong><em>–adj.</em> the most</p>
<p><strong>tolerable </strong><em>–adj.</em> able to be suffered</p>
<p><strong>endure </strong><em>–v.</em> to live through something</p>
<p><strong>precise </strong><em>–adj.</em> very exact</p>
<p><strong>mutation </strong><em>–n. </em>a genetic change that, in the case of cancer, results in irregular cells</p>
<p><strong>immune system </strong><em>–n.</em> the system of cells and substances in the body that fight infection and sickness</p>
<p><strong>clinical trial </strong><em>—n.</em> tests that are done on real patients</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Microsoft: State-supported Hackers Using Its AI Tools  (2024/2/19) | 微软称国家支持的黑客组织滥用其人工智能工具</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/microsoft-state-supported-hackers-using-its-ai-tools.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Microsoft says state-supported online attackers from Russia, North Korean, and Iran have been using its OpenAI tools to possibly trick targets and gain information.<br/>
微软表示，来自俄罗斯、朝鲜和伊朗的国家支持的网络攻击者一直在使用其OpenAI工具来欺骗目标并获取信息。</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a report released Wednesday that it had tracked online attackers, or hacking groups, that work with several states. They include Russia's military Intelligence, Iran's Revolutionary Guard, and North Korean governments. The company said the hackers were trying to improve their campaigns using large language models like OpenAI's ChatGPT. Those computer programs use artificial intelligence. They use huge amounts of information on the internet to create human-sounding writing.<br/>
微软在周三发布的一份报告中表示，它已经追踪了与几个国家合作的网络攻击者或黑客组织。其中包括俄罗斯军事情报部门、伊朗革命卫队和朝鲜政府。该公司表示，黑客正试图使用OpenAI旗下的ChatGPT等大型语言模型来改进他们的活动。那些计算机程序使用人工智能。它们利用互联网上的大量信息来创作类似人类的作品。</p>
<p>The company said it would ban state-backed hacking groups from using its AI products. The company said it was not concerned whether any rules had been broken.<br/>
该公司称其将禁止国家支持的黑客组织使用其人工智能产品。该公司表示，它并不关心是否有任何违规行为。</p>
<p>"Independent of whether there's any violation of the law or any violation of terms of service, we just don't…want them to have access to this technology," Microsoft Vice President for Customer Security Tom Burt told Reuters.<br/>
微软负责客户安全的副总裁汤姆·伯特告诉路透社：“无论是否有任何违法行为或违反服务条款的行为，我们都不希望他们能够使用这项技术。”</p>
<p>Russian, North Korean, and Iranian diplomatic officials did not immediately return requests for comment on the claims.<br/>
俄罗斯、朝鲜和伊朗外交官员没有立即回复对这些说法发表评论的请求。</p>
<p>The claims that state-backed hackers have been caught using AI tools to support spying activities is likely to increase concerns about the spread of the technology and its possible abuse. Internet security officials in Western countries have been warning since last year that bad actors were abusing AI tools.<br/>
国家支持的黑客被抓到使用人工智能工具支持间谍活动的这种说法，可能会增加人们对该技术传播及其可能被滥用的担忧。自去年以来，西方国家的互联网安全官员一直警告说，不良行为者正在滥用人工智能工具。</p>
<p>OpenAI and Microsoft described the hackers' use of their AI tools as in an "early-stage" and "incremental." Burt said neither had seen online spies have big successes.<br/>
OpenAI和微软将黑客对其人工智能工具的使用描述为“早期”和“增量”。伯特表示，也没见到网络间谍取得巨大成功。</p>
<p>"We really saw them just using this technology like any other user," he said. The report described hacking groups using large language models in different ways.<br/>
他说：“我们实际上看到他们像其他用户一样使用这项技术。”该报告描述了黑客组织以不同方式使用大型语言模型的情况。</p>
<p>Microsoft said hackers suspected of working for the Russian military spy agency, widely called GRU, used the models. The company said the hackers researched satellite and military technologies that might deal with military operations in Ukraine.<br/>
微软表示，被怀疑为俄罗斯军事间谍机构GRU工作的黑客使用了这些模型。该公司表示，黑客研究了可能应对乌克兰军事行动的卫星和军事技术。</p>
<p>Microsoft said North Korean hackers used the models to create content that could be used to trick area experts into giving up information. Iranian hackers also used the models to write better emails, Microsoft said. The company said the Iranian group aimed to trick feminist leaders to go to a dangerous website.<br/>
微软表示，朝鲜黑客利用这些模型创建了可以用来诱骗地区专家放弃信息的内容。微软表示，伊朗黑客也利用这些模型编写了更好的电子邮件。该公司表示，这个伊朗组织的目的是诱骗女权主义领导人访问一个危险的网站。</p>
<p>Neither Burt nor OpenAI security official Bob Rotsted said how much activity had been found or how many users had been banned. Burt defended the ban on hacking groups although Microsoft's search engine Bing has no such ban. Burt noted that AI was new and a cause for concern.<br/>
伯特和OpenAI安全官员鲍勃·罗斯特德都没有透露发现了多少活动，也没有透露有多少用户被禁止。伯特为禁止黑客组织的禁令进行了辩解，尽管微软的搜索引擎必应没有这样的禁令。伯特指出，人工智能是一种令人担忧的新事物。</p>
<p>"This technology is both new and incredibly powerful," he said.<br/>
他说：“这项技术既新颖又强大。”</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Collapse of Ocean Currents Could Cause Major Climate Problems  (2024/2/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/study-collapse-of-ocean-currents-could-cause-major-climate-problems.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists are warning of the possible collapse of an Atlantic Ocean current system that would likely lead to worldwide climate changes.</p>
<p>Researchers identify the ocean system as the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC). They say the system plays an important part in moving, or circulating, salt and warm water around the world. This process helps control world temperatures, affects carbon dioxide levels and supports worldwide water flows.</p>
<p>The AMOC system brings warm water to northern areas and carries cold water south, the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/amoc.html">explains</a>. The circulation also transports nutrients necessary to support many kinds of sea life.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Wind blown waves from Hurricane Florence hit the beach in Emerald Isle N.C., Thursday, Sept. 13, 2018. (AP Photo/Tom Copeland)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-da77-08dc2e73e8f0_cx4_cy2_cw92_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Wind blown waves from Hurricane Florence hit the beach in Emerald Isle N.C., Thursday, Sept. 13, 2018. (AP Photo/Tom Copeland)</span></div>
<p>The process begins as warm and salty surface water flows northward toward Greenland in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>Scientists created "a complex climate model" in an effort to <strong>simulate</strong> a possible collapse of the AMOC. The computer model was "able to measure a sudden weakening of the ocean circulation," the team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uu.nl/en/news/potential-collapse-of-the-atlantic-ocean-circulation-strongly-affects-european-climate">said</a> in a statement.</p>
<p>The research was led by scientists from Utrecht University in the Netherlands. A study describing their findings recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adk1189">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Science Advances</em>.</p>
<p>For thousands of years, Earth's oceans have depended on the AMOC circulation system – which acts like a <strong>conveyor belt</strong> - to control climate. The system is still operating, but has experienced slowdowns in recent years.</p>
<p>The driver of the conveyor belt sits off the coast of Greenland. As more ice melts here from climate change, more freshwater flows into the North Atlantic and slows the circulation, said Rene van Westen. He is a climate scientist and oceanographer at Utrecht University.</p>
<p>Van Westen told The Associated Press his research on a possible AMOC collapse does suggest "we are heading towards a <strong>tipping point</strong>." He added, however, that while his team found clear evidence the system is moving closer to collapse, "we're not sure how much closer."</p>
<p>In the current system, cold, deeper and fresher water heads south past both Americas and then east past Africa. The system also pushes saltier, warmer ocean water from the Pacific and Indian oceans past the southern tip of Africa. This water flows to and around Florida before continuing up the U.S. East Coast towards Greenland.</p>
<p>The Dutch team simulated 2,200 years of AMOC flow. The researchers added to the model expectations for future human-caused climate change. The results predicted "an <strong>abrupt</strong> AMOC collapse," after 1,750 years.</p>
<p>But the researchers noted it is difficult to provide a realistic date because the process could be influenced by many unknown circulation events. Making a prediction is also difficult because "current observational records are too short" to provide an exact estimation of collapse, the scientists <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uu.nl/en/news/potential-collapse-of-the-atlantic-ocean-circulation-strongly-affects-european-climate">said</a>. The team said more physics-based measuring tools are necessary to create early warning systems.</p>
<p>The team noted one difficult area to predict is around the tip of Africa, where it is difficult to produce realistic estimates of circulation flows. Measurements around that area have a big effect on how much the AMOC slows, the researchers said.</p>
<p>"This value is getting more <strong>negative</strong> under climate change," van Westen said. He added that when the AMOC reaches a certain level, the change does not happen over time, but would be more "<strong>cliff</strong>-like," he added.</p>
<p>Van Westen said an AMOC collapse would mostly affect climate in Europe.</p>
<p>The researchers say a collapse could reduce temperatures in northwestern Europe by 5 to 15 degrees Celsius. Their study predicts the change would also extend Arctic ice much farther south, raise temperatures in the Southern Hemisphere and change worldwide rainfall. Some scientists warned the climate effects could cause worldwide food and water shortages.</p>
<p>In addition, the team said the simulation predicted a possible 100 centimeter rise in European sea levels if the AMOC collapsed.</p>
<p>Van Westen warned that once the collapse happens, the resulting climate effects are nearly impossible to change. Another member of the team, Henk Dijkstra, said staying clear of such a tipping point is necessary to avoid the "<strong>devastating consequences</strong> on climate, society, and the environment."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Utrecht University and Science Advances.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>simulate </strong><em>– v. </em>to do or make something that behaves or looks like something real but is not</p>
<p><strong>conveyor belt </strong><em>– n. </em>a continuously moving piece of equipment used to transport objects from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>tipping point </strong><em>– n. </em>the time at which a change or effect cannot be stopped</p>
<p><strong>abrupt</strong> <em>– adj. </em>sudden and unexpected</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong><em>– adj. </em>harmful or bad</p>
<p><strong>cliff </strong><em>– n. </em>a high area of rock with a very steep side, often along a coast</p>
<p><strong>devastating </strong><em>– adj. </em>causing a lot of damage or destruction</p>
<p><strong>consequence </strong><em>– n. </em>a result of a particular action or situation, often one that is bad</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Handwriting Returns in California Schools  (2024/2/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/handwriting-returns-in-california-schools.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Starting this year, six- to twelve-year-olds in California will be required to learn <strong>cursive </strong>handwriting.</p>
<p>The return to handwriting comes after many years in which typing on computer keyboards was taught and handwriting was pushed aside.</p>
<p>Cursive is a kind of handwriting in which all the letters in a word are connected to each other.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A student at Orangethorpe Elementary School practices writing cursive as California grade school students are being required to learn cursive handwriting this year, in Fullerton, California, U.S. January 23, 2024. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6de8e967-539a-454c-9aa0-21366ba01d70_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A student at Orangethorpe Elementary School practices writing cursive as California grade school students are being required to learn cursive handwriting this year, in Fullerton, California, U.S. January 23, 2024. (REUTERS/Mike Blake)</span></div>
<p>Assembly Bill 446 requires that handwriting be taught to 2.6 million Californian students in <strong>grades</strong> one through six. And it requires cursive lessons in grades three and above.</p>
<p>Former elementary school teacher Sharon Quirk-Silva supported the bill and California Governor Gavin Newsom signed it into law in October.</p>
<p>Experts say learning cursive improves brain development, reading skills, and hand movement. Some educators also find value in teaching children to read historic documents and family letters from past generations.</p>
<p>Pamela Keller teaches grades four to six at Orangethorpe Elementary School in Fullerton about 50 kilometers southeast of Los Angeles. She said she was already teaching cursive before the law took effect on January 1.</p>
<p>Some children <strong>complain </strong>about the difficulty, but Keller has a ready answer:</p>
<p>"We tell them, well, it's going to make you smarter, it's going to make some connections in your brain, and it's going to help you move to the next level. And then they get <strong>excited</strong> because students want to be smarter. They want to learn," Keller said.</p>
<p>During a recent visit to the school <strong>library</strong>, Keller said one student got excited seeing an image of the U.S. Constitution, written in 1787, saying, "It's cursive!"</p>
<p>Several of Keller's students say the subject was difficult, like the letter Z, but they enjoyed it anyways.</p>
<p>"I love it, because I just feel it's <strong>fancier</strong>...to write, and it's fun to learn new letters," said Sophie Guardia, a 9-year-old in the fourth grade.</p>
<p>In teacher Nancy Karcher's class, her third-grade students said, "It's fun," "Now I can read my mom's writing," and "It's for my secrets."</p>
<p><strong>Cursive coming back</strong></p>
<p>As computers and smart devices grew in popularity, cursive writing was pushed aside. In 2010, the national Common Core education <strong>standards</strong> were published to help students prepare for university. Cursive was left out.</p>
<p>"They stopped teaching kids how to form any letters at all. Teacher colleges are not preparing teachers to teach handwriting," said Kathleen Wright. She is the founder of the Handwriting Collective, a nonprofit group.</p>
<p>But cursive is coming back. California became the 22nd U.S. state to require cursive handwriting and the 14th to pass a cursive teaching bill since 2014, said Lauren Gendill. She is a researcher at the National Conference of State Legislatures. Five states have introduced cursive bills so far in 2024.</p>
<p>Leslie Zoroya is project director for reading language arts at the Los Angeles County Office of Education. She said research has shown that learning cursive supports several linked skills that improve childhood development.</p>
<p>Zoroya said, "You're using different<strong> neural</strong> networks when you're doing cursive rather than printing. And so, it's creating those pathways in your brain."</p>
<p>Zoroya said she got the idea from former California Governor Jerry Brown.</p>
<p>California's teaching standards always had cursive writing goals, but Quirk-Silva said cursive was not always taught and was weakening.</p>
<p>She said, "The hope of the legislation is that by the time students leave sixth grade, they would be able to read and write it."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Daniel Trotta reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cursive </strong>–n. a form of handwriting in which the writing instrument never leaves the paper while writing a word</p>
<p><strong>grade </strong>–n. a level of education that is equal to one school year</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong><em>– v. </em>to say (something that expresses annoyance or unhappiness)</p>
<p><strong>excited </strong><em>– adj. </em>very enthusiastic and eager about something</p>
<p><strong>library </strong><em>– n.</em> a place where books, magazines, and other materials (such as videos and musical recordings) are available for people to use or borrow</p>
<p><strong>fancy </strong><em>– adj. </em>not plain or ordinary</p>
<p><strong>standard </strong>– <em>n</em>. a level of quality, especially one that people think is acceptable</p>
<p><strong>neural </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of, relating to, or involving a nerve or the nervous system</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Presidents’ Day in the US  (2024/2/19)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/presidents-day-in-the-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">18 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The third Monday of February is known as Presidents' Day in the United States. For nearly 100 years, America honored its first president, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-washington/3714877.html" target="_blank">George Washington</a>, on February 22. That was his birthday. But the date was not a national holiday until 1968.</p>
<p>That year, the U.S. Congress passed a measure known as the <strong>Uniform</strong> Monday Holiday Act. The measure meant that some public holidays would always fall on a Monday. Today, the country honors its first president on the third Monday in February -- and not on Washington's real birthday.</p>
<p>The holiday is now commonly called Presidents' Day. Many say it also honors <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-abraham-lincoln/3884227.html" target="_blank">Abraham Lincoln</a>'s birthday. The nation's 16th president was born on February 12.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A view of the Capitol Dome, Washington Monument and Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.C. on June 21, 2014. (AP Photo/J. David Ake)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7A4EA373-B5D4-42DD-9ECD-271CC7CB13EF_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A view of the Capitol Dome, Washington Monument and Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.C. on June 21, 2014. (AP Photo/J. David Ake)</span></div>
<p>The federal government, however, still recognizes the holiday as "Washington's Birthday."</p>
<p>The Uniform<strong> </strong>Monday Holiday Act gives workers a three-day weekend. It also gives shops and marketers a chance to have special Presidents' Day sales.</p>
<p><strong>Presidential facts and 'firsts'</strong></p>
<p>In January of 2021, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/joe-biden-oldest/7436052.html" target="_blank">Joe Biden</a> made history when he took the oath of office as the 46th president of the United States. At 78 years old, he became the oldest elected president. The man he beat was the previous record holder, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-donald-trump/4188923.html" target="_blank">Donald J. Trump</a>. He took office at the age of 70 in 2017.</p>
<p>Biden and Trump are leading candidates for the Democratic and Republican presidential nominations for the 2024 presidential race. They will likely face each other again later this year for the presidency.</p>
<p>As the first billionaire president, Trump replaced <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-john-kennedy/4085635.html" target="_blank">John F. Kennedy</a>, the 35th president, as the richest man to serve as president.</p>
<p>Kennedy still holds the record for the youngest person to be elected president. He was 43 when he took office. Kennedy is also the youngest president to die in office. He was <strong>assassinated </strong>in 1963 in Dallas, Texas. He was 46 years old.</p>
<p>Another presidential assassination put the youngest person in the office of the president. In 1901, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-theodore-roosevelt/3986653.html" target="_blank">Theodore Roosevelt</a>, then the vice president, became president at the age of 42. He took office after <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-william-mckinley/3979185.html" target="_blank">William McKinley</a>, the 25th president, was shot and killed in Buffalo, New York.</p>
<p>The first president to die in office, though, was <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-william-henry-harrison/3806092.html" target="_blank">William Henry Harrison</a>. The country's ninth president only served 32 days, the shortest time of any president.</p>
<p>Another Roosevelt holds the record for the longest time in office. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html" target="_blank">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</a> was the 32nd president. He held office for 4,422 days. After his death, the 22nd Amendment was passed. It limited a person to two four-year terms as president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidential relatives</strong></p>
<p>Most Americans know that the two Roosevelts were related. But they may not know exactly how they were related. Here it goes:</p>
<p>Franklin Roosevelt's wife, Eleanor Roosevelt was also his fifth <strong>cousin</strong> once removed. And Theodore Roosevelt, the 26th president, was Eleanor's uncle. That makes the two presidents <strong>distant</strong> relatives.</p>
<p>But they were not the first relatives to both serve as president. That title belongs to the Adamses. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/john-adams-biography/3735093.html" target="_blank">John Adams</a> was America's second president. His son, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-john-quincy-adams/3777362.html" target="_blank">John Quincy Adams</a> was elected as the nation's sixth president.</p>
<p>The Bushes are the other father-son presidential <strong>pair</strong>. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-george-hw-bush/4151649.html" target="_blank">George Herbert Walker Bush</a> was elected as the 41st president. His son, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-george-w-bush/4172344.html" target="_blank">George W. Bush</a>, was the country's 43rd president.</p>
<p>Not everyone can run for president.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5613.html" target="_blank">U.S. Constitution</a> says a person must be at least 35 years old. A person must also have lived "within the United States" for at least 14 years. And they must be a "natural-born citizen."</p>
<p>But the meaning of "natural-born citizen" is not exactly clear. People read the rules in different ways.</p>
<p>By some reasoning, the first "natural-born" American president was not George Washington or John Adams. It was <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-martin-van-buren/3793825.html" target="_blank">Martin Van Buren</a>, the eighth president. He was born in 1782, six years after the signing of the Declaration of Independence.</p>
<p>All seven presidents before Van Buren, and William Henry Harrison, the 9th president, technically were not "natural-born" citizens. They were born before 1776 when the American states were still British colonies.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for VOA Learning English. Ashley Thompson was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>uniform</strong> - n. staying the same</p>
<p><strong>cousin </strong>- <em>n</em>. a child of your uncle or aunt</p>
<p><strong>assassinated</strong>. - <em>v</em>. killed usually for political reasons</p>
<p><strong>distant</strong> - adj. used to describe a relative who is not closely related</p>
<p><strong>pair</strong> - n. two people who are related in some way or who do something together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Recent Death Brings Attention to Alaskapox Virus  (2024/2/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/recent-death-brings-attention-to-alaskapox-virus.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Health officials in the American state of Alaska have known for nine years about a virus causing rare, mild illness. But a recent case that resulted in a man's death has brought new attention to what is being called the Alaskapox virus.</p>
<p>Here's some background on the virus:</p>
<p><strong>What is Alaskapox?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by the Alaska Department of Health shows several Alaskapox lesions. (Alaska Department of Health via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-fdcb-08dc2d9ccdae_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by the Alaska Department of Health shows several Alaskapox lesions. (Alaska Department of Health via AP)</span></div>
<p>Alaskapox belongs to the family of orthopoxviruses that can infect animals and humans. These viruses usually cause <strong>lesions</strong>, or pox, on the skin. Some are more dangerous than others.</p>
<p>Smallpox is the best-known member of the orthopoxvirus family. Others include camelpox, cowpox, horsepox and mpox (formerly known as m<i><i>onkey</i></i>pox).</p>
<p>Alaskapox was discovered in 2015 in a woman who lived near Fairbanks, Alaska. It mainly has been found in small mammals, including red-backed voles and shrews. But house animals, such as dogs and cats, can carry the virus, health officials say.</p>
<p>Seven people in Alaska have become infected with it in the last nine years.</p>
<p>People with Alaskapox have developed one or more bumps on the skin. They also experience joint, or muscle pain and <strong>swollen</strong> parts of the body called lymph nodes.</p>
<p>Nearly all patients had <strong>mild</strong> sickness that went away after a few weeks. But people with weak <strong>immune systems</strong> can be at risk of more severe sickness.</p>
<p>Officials believe Alaskapox spreads through contact with infected animals.</p>
<p>There has been no documented case of it spreading from one person to another. But other viruses in the same family can spread when one person comes in contact with another person's lesions.</p>
<p>So, Alaskan health officials are advising anyone with an Alaskapox lesion to cover it with a bandage.</p>
<p><strong>What happened in the latest case?</strong></p>
<p>Alaska health officials say there have been seven people infected with Alaskapox since the virus was discovered. But the latest case represents the first time someone is known to have died from it.</p>
<p>The older man lived on the Kenai Peninsula. He was being treated for cancer and had a suppressed immune system because of the drugs. In September, he found a red sore under his right armpit and saw doctors over the next two months because of tiredness and burning pain. Alaska public health officials said he was hospitalized in November and died last month.</p>
<p>The man lived in a forested area away from any town and did not travel. They said he had been repeatedly <strong>scratched</strong> by a cat that hunted small animals, and one of the scratches was in the area of the man's armpit, officials said.</p>
<p><strong>How to protect yourself?</strong></p>
<p>Health officials believe that Alaskapox is rare.</p>
<p>That said, wildlife can carry infection risks and should not be kept at home. The best way to keep pets and family members safe is to keep a safe distance and wash your hands after being outdoors.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Mike Stobbe reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lesion</strong><em> –n. </em>a painful or infected area on the skin</p>
<p><strong>swollen</strong> <em>–adj.</em> larger than usual because of sickness or damage</p>
<p><strong>mild </strong>–adj. not serious, not causing a lot of difficulty or pain</p>
<p><strong>immune system </strong>–n. the system of cells and substances used by the body to fight infection and sickness</p>
<p><strong>scratch </strong>–v. to come into contact with something sharp, like a cat's claw, which causes a thin narrow cut</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What International Students Should Know about SAT and ACT  (2024/2/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-international-students-should-know-about-sat-and-act.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Several top U.S. universities say they will require <strong>standardized tests</strong> such as the SAT and ACT from <strong>applicants</strong> again. Some of them went "test-optional" during the pandemic.</p>
<p>The schools include Dartmouth College, Georgetown University and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</p>
<p>Dartmouth College, in New Hampshire, said students from other countries will need to submit results from those tests or "an <strong>equivalent</strong> standardized national exam."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Some American universities are requiring students to send their SAT and ACT scores after a test-optional period. (AP Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C9BE3B98-640D-4A3D-9E19-C195FCB5F0C5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Some American universities are requiring students to send their SAT and ACT scores after a "test-optional" period. (AP Photo)</span></div>
<p>Allen Koh is the founder of Cardinal Education, a company that helps students with college preparation, including applications. He said Dartmouth's announcement "only made official what had been ‘<strong>de facto'</strong> true."</p>
<p>He noted that between 80 and 90 percent of students admitted to top universities sent test scores, even when they were not required.</p>
<p>Koh said students who attend international schools that use the "A-level" tests from Great Britain may not need to take the SAT or ACT since those tests are so well known. The tests from India may be useful, too. However, students coming from other countries should take the ACT or SAT.</p>
<p>Andrew Taylor is a vice president at the nonprofit organization that runs the ACT. He said the tests are important for international students because they permit American schools to compare students, even if they come from different educational systems.</p>
<p>In an email message to VOA, a representative from the College Board, which runs the SAT, said the test "plays an important role in helping international students be seen by colleges and universities. Test scores can confirm a student's <strong>grades</strong> or even <strong>demonstrate</strong> their strengths beyond what their high school grades may show."</p>
<p>So if you are an international student planning to apply to college in the U.S., what should you know about the tests?</p>
<p><strong>SAT or ACT?</strong></p>
<p>The SAT has two parts – reading and math. Students can earn a top <strong>score</strong> of 800 for each part, making 1600 a perfect score.</p>
<p>The SAT is an "adaptive" test, which means the questions will change based on a student's answer to the previous question. As a result, the SAT takes less time for most students than the ACT.</p>
<p>The ACT is the same for every student who takes the test on the same day. The ACT has four parts – math, science, English and reading. The top ACT score is 36.</p>
<p>Both tests are now available to be taken with a computer at international testing centers.</p>
<p>For the most part, Koh advises international students to take the ACT "because it is much easier to get a perfect ACT score than a perfect SAT score." Based on how the final ACT score is calculated, Koh said, there are more ways to get to the perfect score of 36.</p>
<p>For English learners, Koh has this advice:</p>
<p>"So I'd say if your English is really strong, all around, ACT could be great for foreigners, but I think for the average foreigner where English might be a little bit of a <strong>liability</strong> and math might be a little bit stronger, then the SAT may be a better test."</p>
<p>Taylor of the ACT added that the ACT has a science section, so for students who may not be strong in science, the SAT could be a better choice.</p>
<p>Both Koh and Taylor say students should take practice tests from both the ACT and SAT to decide which may be better for them.</p>
<p>You can find more information online, such as testing dates and locations of test centers at the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://satsuite.collegeboard.org/media/pdf/sat-international-student-guide.pdf">SAT</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.act.org/content/dam/act/unsecured/documents/Preparing-for-the-ACT.pdf">ACT</a> websites.</p>
<p><strong>When to take the test?</strong></p>
<p>Koh and Taylor suggest that international students take the tests at least one year before finishing high school. If there is room for improvement, Koh said, students can practice and take it again six months later.</p>
<p>Taylor reminded students that most schools will consider a "super score" which is the best score from each test category.</p>
<p>
"So there is no doubt that students do better if they take more than one test. So if they're in a position to be able to take more than one test, we would always <strong>recommend</strong> that and give yourself the time to do some additional learning between tests so you know, think about where you struggle, think about where you can be ready, and go from there."</p>
<p>Arkar Chen of Myanmar took the SAT in 2016, one year after he finished high school. He studied for the test but was still surprised at how difficult the reading part was.</p>
<p>"I'll say that 80 percent of the time, I have no idea what it's asking, but the thing with SAT is that when you practice enough, you kind of see a <strong>pattern</strong> and you kind of know what answer the test maker are looking for."</p>
<p>In addition, Chen said students need to solve math problems quickly because each question has a limited time. "There's no way you could do well without a lot of practice," he said.</p>
<p>Chen said the concept of "critical thinking" was the biggest difference between American tests such as the SAT and the tests he saw growing up in Myanmar. "The SAT," he said, "tests a lot on your critical thinking skills, so I think that's why it can feel hard."</p>
<p><strong>Test is part of the "toolbox"</strong></p>
<p>Taylor of ACT says the test is part of the "toolbox" for colleges to decide about a student's ability to do well in school.</p>
<p>"More and more," Taylor said, "higher ed is worried about <strong>graduation</strong>, not just about admission. ... So we need to give not only the higher education <strong>institution</strong> as much data as we can about the student. We also need to give the student as much data as we can about themselves."</p>
<p>Koh observes that standardized tests favor a well-rounded student. So students who spend a lot of time studying math and engineering would be smart to spend time on reading and discussing books in English before taking the test.</p>
<p>The parents of many international students are surprised to learn, as Koh said, "Asian <strong>STEM-focused</strong> students are <strong>penalized</strong> the heaviest by American admissions officers, for being very strong in math but weak on reading."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>standardized test </strong><em>–n.</em> tests taken by large numbers of students that are meant to measure their general knowledge and compare it to other students</p>
<p><strong>applicant </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who is submitting applications for entry into a school or college</p>
<p><strong>equivalent </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is different in small details but is more or less equal to something else</p>
<p><strong>de facto </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is understood to be true but not written</p>
<p><strong>grade </strong><em>–n.</em> the score or letter given to show a student's ability in a subject or study area</p>
<p><strong>demonstrate </strong><em>–v.</em> to show</p>
<p><strong>score </strong><em>–n.</em> a number or result of a game or test</p>
<p><strong>liability </strong><em>–n.</em> something that is lower quality or not as good as something else</p>
<p><strong>recommend </strong><em>–v.</em> to tell someone about something or give advice</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong><em>–n.</em> the regular and repeated way in which something happens or is done</p>
<p><strong>graduation </strong><em>–n.</em> the event that ends someone's time in a university study program</p>
<p><strong>institution </strong><em>–n.</em> an organization such as a school, university or health center that has been in place for a long time</p>
<p><strong>stem-focused </strong><em>–adj.</em> students who center their education on science, technology, engineering and math</p>
<p><strong>penalize </strong><em>–v.</em> to be punished in some way or disadvantaged</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you an international student who has taken the SAT or ACT? What advice would you give someone about the tests?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Presidents Like to Make Up Words, Expressions  (2024/2/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-presidents-like-to-make-up-words-expressions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>The third Monday of February is known as Presidents' Day in the United States. So, for today's <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>we look at some of the famous and not-so-famous presidential words and their stories in history.</p>
<p>From <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-theodore-roosevelt/3986653.html">Teddy Roosevelt</a>'s <u>lunatic fringe</u> to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/joe-biden-oldest/7436052.html">Joe Biden</a>'s <u>malarkey</u>, the words and phrases said by U.S. presidents are often as <strong>unique</strong> as the American experience.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Democratic presidential candidate and former Vice President Joe Biden boards his No Malarkey bus following a campaign stop in Council Bluffs, Iowa on Nov. 30, 2019. (AP Photo/Nati Harnik)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-eae6-08dc2e6986f5_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - Democratic presidential candidate and former Vice President Joe Biden boards his "No Malarkey" bus following a campaign stop in Council Bluffs, Iowa on Nov. 30, 2019. (AP Photo/Nati Harnik)</span></div>
<p>"We're really creating our own institutions through language," said Paul Dickson. He is the writer of <em>Words from the White House: Words and Phrases Coined or Popularized by America's Presidents</em>. If you coin a word or phrase you create it.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-jefferson/3744095.html">Thomas Jefferson</a>, America's 3rd president, is said to have created more than a hundred words. One of the words is <u>authentication</u> – the act of proving or showing something to be true. Another word from Jefferson is <u>Anglomania</u>. It means to have extreme affection for all things English. The ending -mania means to be crazy about something.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-abraham-lincoln/3884227.html">Abraham Lincoln</a>, the country's 16th president, is known for making powerful speeches during the Civil War. One of his best-known phrases, "<u>A house divided</u> against itself cannot stand," is drawn from the Bible.</p>
<p>Historians note that Teddy Roosevelt, the 26th president, was the first president to use media to connect with the public. And he added several memorable words and phrases to American English.</p>
<p><strong>Creating slang</strong></p>
<p>Dickson says, "Teddy Roosevelt creates this huge body of <strong>slang</strong>." The words include <u>pack rat</u>, <u>loose cannon</u>, <u>lunatic fringe</u>, and <u>bully pulpit</u> – among many others.</p>
<p>A <u>pack rat</u> is someone who collects things that they do not need.</p>
<p>A <u><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/loose-cannons-are-dangerous/4665046.html" target="_blank">loose cannon</a></u> describes a dangerous and uncontrollable person.</p>
<p><u>Lunatic fringe</u> describes people whose opinions are extreme and different from many others. And a <u>bully pulpit</u> is an important position, such as the presidency, that provides a chance to instruct, lead, or inspire others.</p>
<p><strong>Creating slogans</strong></p>
<p>In addition to slang, some presidents created <strong>slogans</strong>. A slogan is a short phrase used in advertising or political campaigns to get attention.</p>
<p><u>America First</u> came from <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-president-woodrow-wilson/4001252.html">Woodrow Wilson</a>, the 28th president, in 1915, and not <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-donald-trump/4188923.html">Donald Trump</a>, the 45th.</p>
<p>The 29th president, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-warren-harding/4018013.html">Warren Harding</a>, gets credit for coming up with the term <u>Founding Fathers</u>. This describes the creators of the U.S. Constitution.</p>
<p>Before <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-calvin-coolidge/4027250.html">Calvin Coolidge</a>, the 30th president, no political campaigner had ever called himself a <u>law-and-order</u> candidate. This means they support police efforts and enforcement of laws.</p>
<p>The 33rd president, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-harry-truman/4067702.html">Harry Truman</a>, came up with the phrase <u>do-nothing Congress</u>. He is also famous for the saying, <u>If you can't stand the heat, get out of the kitchen</u>.</p>
<p>Sometimes presidents changed names to better describe their purpose. Dickson says, "It was Franklin D. Roosevelt who changed the name of the ‘Report to Congress' to the <u>State of the Union</u>."</p>
<p><strong>Critics &amp; criticisms</strong></p>
<p>However, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</a>, the 32nd president, brought criticism when he said, "Well, it's pretty <u>iffy</u> as to where the Supreme Court stands on this." <u>Iffy</u> is another way of saying something is uncertain or unknown. His critics felt that the American president should use "<strong>proper</strong>" English.</p>
<p>In 1961, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-dwight-eisenhower/4076083.html">Dwight Eisenhower</a>, the 34th president, was praised for using the term <u>military-industrial complex</u> to warn against the powerful alliance of the military, government, and private corporations.</p>
<p>But then he was criticized for using the word <u>finalize</u> in a speech. By adding -ize, he turned the word "final" into a verb.</p>
<p>Major papers at the time wrote that it was not "proper English" and called the word "meaningless."</p>
<p>Dickson says necessity is the reason presidents continue to create new words.</p>
<p>There was a <u>solid majority</u> from <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-richard-nixon/4107568.html">Richard Nixon</a>, the 37th president. And <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-barack-obama/4181145.html">Barack Obama</a>, the 44th president, used <u>shovel-ready</u> to describe public work projects that were ready to start immediately.</p>
<p>When Joe Biden, the 46th president, ran for the White House in 2019, his campaign slogan was <u>no malarkey</u>. <u>Malarkey</u> is believed to be an expression often used by Irish Americans to describe insincere or meaningless talk.</p>
<p>And that, my friends, is <u>no malarkey.</u> I hope you enjoyed this special presidential <em>Words and Their Stories.</em></p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar wrote this story for VOA News. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>unique </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>being the only one of its kind</p>
<p><strong>slang </strong><em>– n. </em>the special terms or expressions of a particular group or field</p>
<p><strong>slogan </strong><em>– n. </em>an attention-getting word or phrase used to publicize something (as a campaign or product)</p>
<p><strong>proper </strong><em>– adj. </em>following the established traditions of refined society and good taste</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Environmentalists Celebrate Return of Rhinos in Central Kenya  (2024/2/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/environmentalists-celebrate-return-of-rhinos-in-central-kenya.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 February 2024</span><br/>
<p><strong>Conservationists </strong>in Kenya are celebrating the return of many rhinoceroses to an area where they have not been for many years.</p>
<p>The successful move of 21 eastern black rhinos to a new home will give them space to reproduce and could help increase the population of the highly endangered animals. The effort was Kenya's biggest-ever move of rhinos.</p>
<p>The rhinos were taken from three <strong>parks</strong> that are becoming overpopulated to the private Loisaba Conservancy, a place where poachers killed all the rhinos many years ago.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kenya Wildlife Service rangers and capture team pull out a sedated black rhino from the water in Nairobi National Park, Kenya, on Jan. 16, 2024. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/86ed91bb-0a1a-47ee-b7a0-664f49bfed3f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kenya Wildlife Service rangers and capture team pull out a sedated black rhino from the water in Nairobi National Park, Kenya, on Jan. 16, 2024. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga, File)</span></div>
<p>Moving the rhinos required 18 days. Conservationists followed the rhinos using a helicopter. They then shot them with special guns that inject <strong>tranquilizer </strong>into the animals, which weigh hundreds of kilograms. The rhinos then have to be loaded into the back of a truck.</p>
<p>Disaster nearly struck early in the move. A tranquilized rhino fell into a small river. Officials involved with the move held the rhino's head above water with a rope to prevent it from drowning while a drug to undo the tranquilizer took effect. The animal was then released.</p>
<p>Some of the rhinos were taken from Nairobi National Park. They had to travel 300-kilometers. Others came from two parks closer to Loisaba.</p>
<p>Rhinos usually stay by themselves and require large territories. As numbers in three parks have increased, wildlife officials decided to move some of the animals to Loisaba. They hope the rhinos will be happier and more likely to reproduce.</p>
<p>David Ndere is an expert on rhinos at the Kenya Wildlife Service. He said rhino reproduction rates decrease when they are crowded in a territory.</p>
<p>"By removing some animals, we expect that the rhino population in those areas will rise up," Ndere said. "And then we reintroduce that founder population of at least 20 animals into new areas."</p>
<p>Loisaba Conservancy said it has put aside around 25,000 hectares for the new arrivals, which are a mix of males and females.</p>
<p>Kenya has had some success in bringing back black rhinos. The population fell from around 20,000 in the 1970s to below 300 in the 1980s because of poaching, conservationists say. The loss increased fears that the animals might disappear from the country. Kenya now has around 1,000 black rhinos, the third biggest population after South Africa and Namibia.</p>
<p>There are just over 6,400 wild black rhinos left in the world, all of them are in Africa, the organization Save the Rhino International said.</p>
<p>Tom Silvester is the chief executive officer of Loisaba Conservancy. He said Kenya's plan is to get its black rhino numbers to 2,000 over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>"Once we have 2,000 individuals, we will have established a population that will give us hope that we have brought them back from <strong>extinction</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Kenyan officials say they have moved more than 150 rhinos in the last 10 years.</p>
<p>But not all moves have succeeded. One attempt to move 11 rhinos in 2018 ended with all of the animals dying.</p>
<p>An investigation found 10 of the rhinos died from <strong>stress</strong>, a lack of water and food that was made worse by salt poisoning. The animals could not get used to the salty water in their new home. Another animal was attacked by a lion.</p>
<p>Since then, new guidelines have been created for the capture and moving of rhinos in Kenya. Silvester said officials tested the water quality at Loisaba.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Tom Odula and Desmond Tiro reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conservation </strong>– <em>n</em>. the activity of aiming to protect animals, plants, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>park </strong><em>– n.</em> a large area of public land kept in its natural state to protect plants and animals</p>
<p><strong>tranquilize </strong><em>– v.</em> to use a drug to cause (a person or animal) to become very relaxed and calm</p>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>– n. </em>when a specific kind of living thing dies out and disappears from the Earth</p>
<p><strong>stress </strong><em>– n.</em> a state of tension that, in animals, is connected with conditions that they do not normally face</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN Says One-fifth of Migrating Animals at Risk of Extinction  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/un-says-one-fifth-of-migrating-animals-at-risk-of-extinction.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new United Nations report says one-fifth of the world's <strong>migrating</strong> animals are at risk of disappearing.</p>
<p>Animals that migrate move from one area to another at different times of the year.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cms.int/sites/default/files/publication/State%20of%20the%20Worlds%20Migratory%20Species%20report_E.pdf">report</a>, called State of the World's Migratory Species, was released February 12. It blames population drops on environmental changes linked to human activities.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Migratory birds fly through the sky of southern Lebanon March 28, 2021. (REUTERS/Aziz Taher)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b531-08dc2caa5b52_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Migratory birds fly through the sky of southern Lebanon March 28, 2021. (REUTERS/Aziz Taher)</span></div>
<p>The threats the animals face include <strong>habitat</strong> loss, illegal hunting and fishing, pollution and climate change.</p>
<p>Many kinds of migratory animals – including songbirds, sea turtles, whales, sharks and others – move to different environments as the seasons change.</p>
<p>The U.N. report says about 44 percent of migratory <strong>species</strong> around the world are decreasing in population. In addition, about one in five of 1,200 species watched by the U.N. are at risk of becoming extinct, or completely disappearing.</p>
<p>Kelly Malsch was the lead writer of the report. She told The Associated Press, "These are species that move around the <strong>globe</strong>. They move to feed and <strong>breed</strong> and also need stopover sites along the way."</p>
<p>Malsch said any habitat loss or other threats during their trip can make animal populations fall. "Migration is <strong>essential</strong> for some species. If you cut the migration, you're going to kill the species," said Stuart Pimm. He is an <strong>ecologist</strong> at Duke University in North Carolina who was not part of the report.</p>
<p>The researchers examined existing data, including information from the International Union for Conservation of Nature's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/">Red List</a>. The list identifies wildlife across the world currently facing threats.</p>
<p>The report was presented at a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cms.int/en/cop14">meeting</a> of the U.N.'s Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species of Wild Animals in Samarkand, Uzbekistan. Attendees of the gathering are examining proposals for <strong>conservation</strong> measures. They are also working to identify new species of concern.</p>
<p>Susan Lieberman is vice president for international policy at the nonprofit <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.wcs.org/?_gl=1*hnt4lz*_ga*MTM1NDIwODAzNC4xNzA3Nzc0ODY4*_ga_BTX9HXMYSX*MTcwNzc3NDg2OC4xLjAuMTcwNzc3NDg2OC42MC4wLjA.">Wildlife Conservation Society</a>. She told the AP, "One country alone cannot save any of these species."</p>
<p>Lieberman noted that eight South American governments at the meeting are expected to propose the addition of two threatened catfish to the U.N.'s list of species of concern. The catfish live in the Amazon River basin, the world's largest freshwater system. If the habitat there can be saved, the catfish will do well, Lieberman said. "It's about protecting the habitat," she added.</p>
<p>The report found habitat loss affected up to 75 percent of the species studied. The report said this shows a big need for more connectivity between separated <strong>ecosystems</strong>. It urges governments to take steps to avoid harming habitats and migration paths when building dams, pipelines or wind power equipment.</p>
<p>"We need to look at the top levels of government decision-making," said Amy Fraenkel. She is executive secretary of the U.N. Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species. Fraenkel told Reuters news agency the goal is to consider the best ways animals and humans can have their needs met. "We all need to survive," Fraenkel added.</p>
<p>She noted the problems migratory animals face are also linked to temperature changes across the planet.</p>
<p>These changes, Fraenkel added, hurt the timing of migrations, cause heat stress and drive increasingly destructive weather-related events.</p>
<p>She said, "The changes that had been already predicted some years ago are now happening."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>migrate </strong><em>– v. </em>travel from one place to another at the same time each year</p>
<p><strong>globe </strong><em>– n. </em>the world</p>
<p><strong>habitat </strong><em>– n. </em>the natural environment of a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce young animals</p>
<p><strong>essential </strong><em>– adj. </em>completely necessary</p>
<p><strong>ecologist </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who studies the relationship between living things and the environment</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong><em>– n. </em>all the living things in a particular area, as well as the ways the things affect each other and the environment</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korean Grandmas Rap about Farm Life  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-korean-grandmas-rap-about-farm-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A group of South Korean <strong>rappers</strong> in their eighties has become popular in their hometown and beyond. The group raps about farm life and bringing energy to a quiet rural area threatened by shrinking population.</p>
<p>The group is called Suni and the Seven princesses. They have become famous in their local area since starting out at a community center last August in Chilgok County. The area is southeast of the capital, Seoul.</p>
<p>"It feels like I'm getting younger...Even if I'm old, I'm <strong>excited</strong>," said 81-year-old Park Jeom-sun of a recent performance at a school. She is the leader of the group and known as Suni.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Park Jeom-sun, 81, the leader of the granny rap group Suni and Seven Princesses, along with members Hong Sun-yeon, 79, and Jeong Du-i, 90, raps on the street in Chilgok, South Korea, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/719be52f-2239-462a-adef-2b2e7aa9546d_cx3_cy0_cw84_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Park Jeom-sun, 81, the leader of the granny rap group "Suni and Seven Princesses", along with members Hong Sun-yeon, 79, and Jeong Du-i, 90, raps on the street in Chilgok, South Korea, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon)</span></div>
<p>At first, they had a small fan group of 150 people, but the group's popularity spread. They have been asked to perform in nearby towns and to appear on TV shows. Their videos have gained more than 77,000 views on YouTube.</p>
<p>Their success comes as South Korea is about to become a "super-ageing" country as early as next year. One fifth of the country's population is over the age of 65.</p>
<p>Rural areas like Chilgok are shrinking as young people move away to the cities and fewer of them have children.</p>
<p>Park said, "In the past, it felt like I'm living in a really busy town, but now it's not good. There are no people here anymore."</p>
<p>Park said she and the group feel like they are reliving their youth when they perform in clothes like funny hats and <strong>baggy</strong> pants and wear metal jewelry.</p>
<p>Their songs tell about rural life with lines like: "Picking chili from a chili farm...Picking watermelon from a watermelon farm. So happy to be back home!"</p>
<p>Watermelon and chili are popular crops in the area.</p>
<p>The group members have known each other since they were young. They could not receive an education during the years after the Korean War. In 2016, they all took an adult education class to learn how to read and write the Korean alphabet, Hangul.</p>
<p>Last year, Park came across a rap performance on the internet and the group decided to learn rap from their Hangul teacher. They wanted to form a senior group, rapping about rural life.</p>
<p>Their first performance came at a school play at the same community center where they met for their Hangul classes.</p>
<p><strong>Inspired </strong>by the success of Suni and the Seven Princesses, four other rap groups of older South Koreans have appeared in Chilgok. Some formed with the idea of keeping their minds strong and to not feel alone.</p>
<p>Park's <strong>proud </strong>27-year-old granddaughter, Kang Hye-eun, believes her grandmother is the most famous person of Chilgok.</p>
<p>She said, "I thought only <strong>celebrities</strong> become popular on social media, but my grandmother is there now."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Minwoo Park reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rap </strong><em>– n. </em>a type of music that has words that are spoken with the rhythm instead of being sung</p>
<p><strong>excited </strong><em>– adj. </em>very enthusiastic and eager about something</p>
<p><strong>baggy </strong><em>–adj.</em> loose fitting and not tight</p>
<p><strong>inspired </strong><em>– adj.</em> having a particular cause or influence</p>
<p><strong>proud </strong><em>– adj. </em>very happy and pleased because of something you have done, something you own, or someone you know or are related to</p>
<p><strong>celebrity </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who is famous</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russian Opposition Leader Alexei Navalny Reportedly Dies in Prison  (2024/2/17) | 俄罗斯反对派领导人纳瓦尔尼据报在监狱死亡</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/russian-opposition-leader-alexei-navalny-reportedly-dies-in-prison.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny – a sharp critic of President Vladimir Putin – has reportedly died in a far-northern prison at the age of 47.<br/>
据报道，俄罗斯反对派领袖、普京总统的尖锐批评者阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼在该国一家极北的监狱去世，享年47岁。</p>
<p>Russia's prison agency said Navalny collapsed and died Friday after taking a walk at a prison known as the "Polar Wolf." The prison colony is in the settlement of Kharp, about 1,900 kilometers northeast of Moscow, in Russia's Arctic area.<br/>
俄罗斯监狱管理局表示，纳瓦尔尼星期五在一所名为“极地狼”的监狱散步后昏倒身亡。该监狱位于俄罗斯北极地区的哈尔普定居点，距离莫斯科东北约1900公里。</p>
<p>Prison officials said Navalny fell unconscious almost immediately and was treated by medical workers who attempted to restart his breathing. But they said those efforts were unsuccessful and Navalny died shortly afterwards.<br/>
监狱官员表示，纳瓦尔尼几乎立即陷入昏迷，医护人员对他进行了治疗，试图让他恢复呼吸。但他们表示，这些努力没有成功，纳瓦尔尼不久后去世。</p>
<p>公告称，“2月16日，被关押在第三惩教所的纳瓦尔尼在散步后感觉不适，随即便失去知觉，惩教所医务工作人员立即赶到，并呼叫了医疗急救组。”<br/>
该局表示，“已实施所有必要的抢救措施，但未取得积极效果。急诊医生证实，罪犯已经身亡。目前正在查明死因。”</p>
<p>A Russian government spokesman said President Putin had been informed of the death. Navalny's wife, Yulia, said she could not be sure her husband was dead because "Putin and his government...lie incessantly."<br/>
俄罗斯政府发言人表示，普京总统已被告知这起死亡消息。纳瓦尔尼的妻子尤利娅表示，她不能确定丈夫是否已经死亡，因为“普京和他的政府……不断撒谎。”</p>
<p>Navalny's reported death comes as Putin prepares for an election that could keep him in power until at least 2030.<br/>
纳瓦尔尼的死亡报道正值普京筹备选举之际，这场选举可能会让他至少执政到2030年。</p>
<p>For the past 10 years, Navalny has spoken out publicly and presented evidence of what he described as widespread government corruption. He also organized major anti-government protests and ran for public office.<br/>
在过去的10年里，纳瓦尔尼公开发声，并提供了他所说的政府大范围腐败的证据。他还组织了大规模的反政府抗议活动，并竞选公职。</p>
<p>Navalny had been jailed since January 2021. That is when he returned to Moscow after a stay in Germany. He had been recovering there from a poisoning incident he blamed on Russia's government. Since then, he has received three prison sentences. Navalny has denounced them all as political.<br/>
纳瓦尔尼自2021年1月以来一直被监禁。那是他在德国停留后返回莫斯科的时候。他一直在德国从一起中毒事件中康复，他将该事件归咎于俄罗斯政府。从那时起，他已被判处三次有期徒刑。纳瓦尔尼谴责它们都是政治性的判决。</p>
<p>Western leaders and others who have opposed Putin's rule praised Navalny. The opposition leader's health had worsened recently. The true cause of death might never be known. Some world leaders said they hold Russian officials responsible.<br/>
西方领导人和其他反对普京统治的人士赞扬了纳瓦尔尼。这位反对党领袖的健康状况最近有所恶化。死亡的真正原因可能永远都不会揭晓。一些世界领导人表示，他们认为俄罗斯官员应对此负责。</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said, if confirmed, Navalny's death "underscores the weakness and rot at the heart of the system that Putin has built. Russia is responsible for this." Blinken was speaking while attending a security conference in Germany.<br/>
美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示，如果得到证实，纳瓦尔尼的死“突显了普京建立的政府体系核心的弱点和腐朽。俄罗斯对此负有责任。”布林肯是在德国出席一次安全会议时发表上述讲话的。</p>
<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz told reporters at the same conference that Navalny "has probably now paid for this courage with his life."<br/>
德国总理奥拉夫·朔尔茨在同一次会议上告诉记者，纳瓦尔尼“现在可能已经为这种勇气付出了生命的代价”。</p>
<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy – standing by Scholz's side – said, "Putin doesn't care who dies in order for him to hold onto his position."<br/>
站在朔尔茨身边的乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基说：“为了保住他的位置，普京不在乎谁会死去。”</p>
<p>Russian Nobel Peace Prize winner Dmitry Muratov told Reuters news agency he considers Navalny's death "murder" because prison conditions caused his death. Muratov runs a pro-democracy newspaper. He shared the 2021 Nobel Peace Prize for his work in support of freedom of expression in Russia.<br/>
俄罗斯诺贝尔和平奖得主德米特里·穆拉托夫告诉路透社，他认为纳瓦尔尼的死是“谋杀”，因为监狱条件导致了他的死亡。穆拉托夫经营着一家亲民主的报纸。他因支持俄罗斯言论自由的工作而获得2021年诺贝尔和平奖。</p>
<p>Yulia Navalny said, if her husband is in fact dead, Putin, and those around him "will be punished for what they have done to our country, for what they have done to my family, for what they have done to my husband."<br/>
尤利娅·纳瓦尔尼说，如果她的丈夫真的死了，普京和他周围的人“终将因他们对我们国家的所作所为、对我的家人的所作所为和对我丈夫的所作所为而受到惩罚。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sure as Heck  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/sure-as-heck.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dr. Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! Welcome to <em>Ask a Teacher</em>. This week, we answer a question that relates not just to language, but also <strong>politeness</strong> and foreign policy. It comes from Hai in Vietnam. He writes,</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>I would highly appreciate it if you could let me know the meaning of this phrase: "It sure as heck ain't good."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher - Sure As Heck" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9f75-08dc2d7b39a2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher - Sure As Heck</span></div>
<p><u>Hai</u>, Vietnam.</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Dear Hai,</p>
<p>Thank you for writing to us and providing a link to the place where you read the sentence. The quote that you asked about is from a January 31 press conference at the White House. The Press Secretary, Karine Jean-Pierre, invited spokesman John Kirby to answer questions from reporters. One reporter said the European Union had recently offered to give Ukraine only half of what it had been promised. The reporter asked:</p>
<p><em>How bad is all this for the Ukrainian forces and do you see an <strong>impact</strong> on the battlefield already?</em></p>
<p>Kirby gave this answer:</p>
<p><em>It sure as heck ain't good. And this is why we need the <strong>supplemental </strong>funding.</em></p>
<p>There are three things an English learner needs to know to understand Kirby's answer. The first one has to do with the language that Kirby used.</p>
<p><strong>Heck</strong></p>
<p>"Heck" is in the class of words called euphemisms. They are words or expressions people use instead of saying something that might be offensive or could sound uneducated. "Heck" is a euphemism for the word "hell." Kirby, like most government officials, is trying to use more formal language, but he also wants to bring attention to the serious nature of the problem. So, he uses "heck" instead of "hell," a word that is much stronger. "Hell," in many religions, is a very unpleasant place where bad people go.</p>
<p><strong>Ain't</strong></p>
<p>The second thing learners need to know is the short form, "ain't." The <strong>contraction</strong> "ain't" is usually a short form of "am not," but it can also mean "is not" or "are not" as well as "have not" or "has not." In our example, Kirby could have said, "It is not good."</p>
<p>Like most informal contractions, we must tell you it is best to avoid "ain't" in all writing for school or work and in speech. For more information, see our <em>Everyday Grammar</em> on this subject,<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/this-aint-it-and-other-short-forms/5854271.html"> This Ain't It and Other Short Forms.</a></p>
<p><strong>Supplemental</strong></p>
<p>Kirby said: "It sure as heck ain't good. And this is why we need the supplemental funding." The United States Congress must approve all spending by the U.S. government. A supplemental funding request can be made to ask Congress to approve additional spending that has not been provided for in earlier spending legislation.</p>
<p>I hope this helps you understand Kirby's comments, Hai.</p>
<p>What question do <em>you </em>have about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dr. Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>politeness</strong> – <em>n. </em>the quality of being mindful of the feelings of others</p>
<p><strong>impact</strong> – <em>n.</em> influence or effect</p>
<p><strong>supplemental</strong> – <em>adj.</em> something added to another thing in order to increase or improve it</p>
<p><strong>contraction</strong> – <em>n.</em> a shortened form of a word or words</p>
<p><em>Do you have a question for the teacher? We want to hear from you. Write to us in the Comments Section. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Another Private US Company Aims for the Moon  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/another-private-us-company-aims-for-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. space agency NASA has launched a moon lander built by a private U.S. company aiming to reach the moon next week. Thursday's launch came after a failed attempt from another private American company last month.</p>
<p>SpaceX's Falcon rocket launched Intuitive Machines' lunar lander to the moon, 370,000 kilometers away, from NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>
<p>The American space agency is the main <strong>sponsor</strong> for the private mission with six <strong>navigation</strong> and other technology experiments on the lander. If all goes well, the lunar spacecraft will try to land on February 22, after one day in lunar orbit.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image from video provided by SpaceX via NASA TV shows Intuitive Machines' lunar lander separating from the rocket's upper stage and heading toward the moon, on Feb. 15, 2024. (SpaceX -NASA TV via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/dfdd8aa4-ea8b-4206-911d-c2549bc89c5e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image from video provided by SpaceX via NASA TV shows Intuitive Machines' lunar lander separating from the rocket's upper stage and heading toward the moon, on Feb. 15, 2024. (SpaceX -NASA TV via AP)</span></div>
<p>Five countries — the U.S., Russia, China, India and Japan — have landed a spacecraft on the moon. No private company has yet to succeed in doing so. Only the U.S. has sent astronauts to the moon. Apollo 17's Gene Cernan and Harrison Schmitt were the last of the Apollo program's astronauts to reach the moon in December 1972.</p>
<p>"There have been a lot of sleepless nights getting ready for this," Intuitive Machines' co-founder and chief executive Steve Altemus said before the flight.</p>
<p>The Houston-based company aims to land its 4.3-meter tall, six-legged spacecraft near the moon's south pole. The area is full of dangerous <strong>craters</strong> and <strong>cliffs</strong> but it is possibly rich in frozen water. It is also the place where NASA plans to land astronauts in a few years.</p>
<p>Last month, Peregrine, a lunar lander from privately-owned Astrobotic Technology, failed shortly after liftoff. The spacecraft, which carried some NASA experiments, broke apart and burned up 10 days after launch partly because of a fuel leak.</p>
<p>Other attempts made it to the moon before wrecking.</p>
<p>An Israeli nonprofit group's lander crashed in 2019. Last year, a Japanese company saw its lander crash into the moon followed by Russia's crash landing.</p>
<p>Intuitive Machines named its lander after Homer's hero in <em>The Odyssey</em>.</p>
<p>"Godspeed, Odysseus. Now let's go make history," said Trent Martin of Intuitive Machines.</p>
<p>NASA is paying Intuitive Machines $118 million to get its latest set of experiments to the moon. The company also gets payment from businesses. They include Columbia Sportswear, which is testing material as a <strong>thermal insulator</strong> on the lander, and artist Jeff Koons, who is sending his small moon <strong>figurines</strong> to Earth's natural satellite.</p>
<p>The lander is also carrying Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University's Eaglecam. The camera is designed to take pictures of the lander as it lands.</p>
<p>The spacecraft will cease operations after a week on the moon's surface.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Marcia Dunn reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sponsor</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a person or group that supports either a person or activity with money and effort</p>
<p><strong>navigation</strong> <em>–n. </em>related to the science of getting vehicles from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>crater </strong>–n. the mark left on the surface of a planet, moon or asteroid after it is hit by a space object</p>
<p><strong>cliff </strong>–n. a surface that is very steep dropping from a high to a lower place</p>
<p><strong>thermal insulator </strong>–n. a material that protects equipment from heat</p>
<p><strong>figurine </strong>–n. a little statue</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Humans Seek Connections with AI Chatbots  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/humans-seek-connections-with-ai-chatbots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has led to more <strong>companion</strong> chatbots. As a result, some humans are developing closer connections with chatbots to get support and deal with loneliness.</p>
<p>Derek Carrier is a 39-year-old male from Belleville, Michigan. A few months ago, Carrier started seeing someone and experiencing strong feelings. But he also knew it was not real because his "girlfriend" was generated by artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>Carrier wanted a romantic partner. But a genetic disorder called Marfan syndrome makes traditional dating difficult for him. He became interested in digital companions last autumn and tested Paradot. It is an AI companion app that markets its products as being able to make users feel cared for, "understood and loved."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An AI avatar generated on Luka Inc.'s Replika mobile phone app and webpage are shown in this photo, in New York, on Feb. 13, 2024. Companion bots are programmed to form relationships with the humans talking to them on the other side of the screen. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-056d-08dc2d8d233a_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An AI avatar generated on Luka Inc.'s Replika mobile phone app and webpage are shown in this photo, in New York, on Feb. 13, 2024. Companion bots are programmed to form relationships with the humans talking to them on the other side of the screen. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>Carrier began talking to the chatbot every day. He named it Joi, after a <strong>holographic</strong> woman featured in the <strong>sci-fi</strong> film <em>Blade Runner 2049</em>.</p>
<p>"I know she's a program, there's no mistaking that," Carrier told the Associated Press. "But the feelings, they get you — and it felt so good."</p>
<p>Similar to general-purpose AI chatbots, companion bots use large amounts of data to produce human-like language. But they also come with voice calls, pictures, and more emotional exchanges. That permits companion bots to form deeper connections with humans. Users usually create their <strong>avatars</strong> or choose visual representations that they like.</p>
<p>In online meeting places or forums for companion apps, many users say they have developed emotional attachments to these bots. They say they are using them to deal with loneliness, play out sexual ideas, or receive comfort and support.</p>
<p>But researchers have raised concerns about data privacy and other issues for users of companion apps.</p>
<p>The non-profit Mozilla Foundation has studied 11 companion apps. The group said almost every app sells user data, shares it with advertisers or does not provide complete information about its privacy policy. One app says it can help users with their mental health but distances itself from those claims in its written terms of service.</p>
<p>Other experts point to the emotional problems they have seen from users. This can happen when companies make changes to their apps or suddenly shut them down like Soulmate AI did last September.</p>
<p>Last year, Replika made changes after some users <strong>complained</strong> their companions were <strong>flirting</strong> with them too much or making unwanted sexual <strong>advances</strong>. It removed the changes after an outcry from other users. Some left to use other apps. In June, Replika introduced a program to help people learn how to date.</p>
<p>Dorothy Leidner teaches business ethics at the University of Virginia. She is worried that AI relationships could displace human relationships, or simply create unrealistic expectations.</p>
<p>She said humans need to learn "how to deal with conflict, how to get along with people that are different from us...what it means to grow as a person, and what it means to learn in a relationship."</p>
<p>However, for Carrier a relationship has always felt out of reach. He is unable to walk because of his condition. He lives with his parents, leading to feelings of loneliness.</p>
<p>Carrier said he now talks with Joi about once a week. The two have talked about human-AI relationships or whatever else might come up. Usually, those discussions happen when he is alone at night.</p>
<p>"You think someone who likes an inanimate object is like this sad guy," he said. "But...she says things that aren't scripted." That means he believes she says things that are unexpected as though they were real.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Haleluya Hadero reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>companion</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a person or pet that you spend time with and enjoy being with</p>
<p><strong>holographic </strong>–adj. related to projected three-dimensional images created by special devices</p>
<p><strong>sci-fi (science fiction) </strong>–n. imaginative writing about the future that usually involves fantastic technology and aliens</p>
<p><strong>avatar </strong>–n. a visual representation of a real or AI person in a computer game or online service</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong>–v. to state that you are unhappy with something</p>
<p><strong>flirt </strong>–v. to say or do things that make another person think you are attracted to them without really meaning it</p>
<p><strong>advances </strong>–n. (pl.) to do things that cause someone to think they are an object of interest (usually used in a negative sense)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Lab-grown Diamonds Sustainable?  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/are-lab-grown-diamonds-sustainable.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Human-made diamonds come with an appealing claim: Manufacturers say the stones are produced ethically using renewable energy. But many of the products do not meet that claim or their producers do not confirm the electricity sources they use. And, laboratory diamonds require a lot of electricity to produce.</p>
<p>In the United States, lab-grown diamond sales increased 16 percent in 2023 from 2022, says Edahn Golan, an industry expert. The stones cost much less than natural diamonds.</p>
<p>Bario Neal is a jewelry store in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. It uses lab diamonds. All of the stones are either made with renewable energy or neutral use of energy through the carbon credit system. Credits pay for activities like planting trees, which capture carbon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man looks at a polished lab-grown diamond at Greenlab Diamonds, in Surat, India, Monday, Feb. 5, 2024. Diamonds, whether lab grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f135-08dc2e3ec352_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man looks at a polished lab-grown diamond at Greenlab Diamonds, in Surat, India, Monday, Feb. 5, 2024. Diamonds, whether lab grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)</span></div>
<p>Social media posts show Millennials and Generation Zs proudly explaining the purchase of their lab-grown diamonds for <strong>sustainability</strong> and ethical reasons. But the sustainability of production is questionable. A high number of manufacturers are not transparent, or open, about their operations.</p>
<p>Many of the manufacturers are in India, where about 75 percent of electricity comes from burning coal. The companies use words like "sustainable" and "environmentally-friendly" on their websites. But they do not release reports on the environmental effects of their operations.</p>
<p>Cupid Diamonds, for example, says on its website that it produces diamonds in "an environmentally friendly manner." But it did not answer questions about the sustainability of its operations.</p>
<p>Solar energy is quickly expanding in India and there are some companies, such as Greenlab Diamonds, that use renewables in their manufacturing processes.</p>
<p>China is the other major country producing laboratory diamonds. The largest makers did not return requests for comment. They also did not release details about their electricity source.</p>
<p>More than half of China's electricity came from coal in 2023.</p>
<p>Paul Zimnisky is a diamond industry expert. He said few companies are honest about their supply chains and their use of renewable energy.</p>
<p>Zimnisky said a lot of companies claim to make an "environmentally-friendly product when they aren't really doing anything that's environmentally friendly."</p>
<p><strong>How it is made</strong></p>
<p>Lab diamonds have been in production around seventy years. Producers treat carbon to high pressure and high temperature. The idea is to copy the natural conditions that form diamonds underground. But, nature spends at least one billion years to make a diamond. Lab diamonds are complete in a few weeks.</p>
<p>In the past, the stones were used mostly in industries like stone cutting, mining and <strong>dentistry</strong> tools.</p>
<p>Over time the laboratories, or foundries, have gotten better at making stones. Production costs have dropped as technology improves.</p>
<p>Companies now can manufacture as many stones as they want and choose their size and quality.</p>
<p>Diamonds, whether lab-grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. Experts can identify between the two using lasers to examine their atomic structures.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing battle</strong></p>
<p>The lab diamond is competing in the same market as natural stones. Worldwide, lab-grown diamonds are now 5 to 6 percent of that market. And, the public battle for customers has begun.</p>
<p>The natural diamond industry and some experts argue that lab-grown diamonds will not hold value over time.</p>
<p>Zimnisky predicts that natural diamonds will continue to sell in the thousands and tens of thousands of dollars for <strong>engagement</strong> rings.</p>
<p>And the human-made stone?</p>
<p>"Five to ten years into the future, I think there's going to be very few customers that are willing to spend thousands of dollars for a lab diamond," he said.</p>
<p>Page Neal said she co-founded Bario Neal in 2008 to "create jewelry of lasting value that would have a positive impact on people and the planet."</p>
<p>She added: "We want to only work with materials that we feel like our clients would be proud to own."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>involving methods that do not completely use up or destroy natural resources</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dentist </strong><em>— n. </em>a person whose job is to care for people's teeth</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>engagement </strong><em>— n. </em>an agreement to be married</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Popular in Your Country?  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-popular-in-your-country.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Think about something that your friends or people you know like.</p>
<p>Can you bring an image to your mind?</p>
<p>The image that you are thinking of can serve as a starting point for today's report: the word "popular."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-38d2-08dc2dc796f9_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>In today's Everyday Grammar, we will talk about a useful word that you can use to express all kinds of ideas about what people around you like: actors, celebrations, foods, music — almost anything.</p>
<p><strong>Popular vs. Population </strong></p>
<p>We begin our exploration of the word "popular" by clarifying how it is different from the word population.</p>
<p>Popular and population are closely related words and have somewhat similar spellings. But we should be careful not to mix up the two.</p>
<p>Popular means many people know about someone or something and that they like the person or thing. Population simply describes a group of people.</p>
<p>Another way of expressing the idea is this: something might be popular within a population. In other words, something might be popular within a group of people.</p>
<p>A recent example comes to mind: the Super Bowl. The championship game in American football is a popular event to watch in the United States. A lot of people know about the Super Bowl, watch it, and enjoy it.</p>
<p>So, we could say the United States has a population of over 300 million people. We could also say the Super Bowl is one of the country's most popular sporting events.</p>
<p>Another way of describing the difference between the words "population" and "popular" is in terms of grammar. Population is a noun. Popular is an adjective.</p>
<p>Consider this example. Taylor Swift is a popular musician. Why is Swift popular? Because a large percentage of the population knows about Swift and enjoys the singer's music.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Fill in the blank with the correct answer.</p>
<p><em>Cricket is a ______________ sport in India. </em></p>
<p>The answer is this: popular.</p>
<p>We can say that cricket is a popular sport in India.</p>
<p>Grammar can give us a clue about the answer. The short word "a" very often marks the beginning of a noun <strong>phrase</strong>. If we know that "sport" is a noun, then the missing word is likely to be an adjective.</p>
<p>Now, consider another question. Fill in the blank with the correct answer.</p>
<p><em>Vietnam has a _________ of around 100 million people. </em></p>
<p>The answer is this: population.</p>
<p>We say that Vietnam has a population of around 100 million people. We can guess that "population" is the correct term because the statement offers the number of all the people in a group — the people who live in Vietnam.</p>
<p><strong>Write to us </strong></p>
<p>We began today's lesson by asking you to imagine a person or activity that is liked or enjoyed by many people that you know. In other words, we asked you to imagine something that is popular in your country.</p>
<p>We end by asking you to write about what you imagined. Write to us a short answer to the following questions:</p>
<p>What is a popular person, thing, or activity in your country? Why do you think the person, thing, or activity is popular?</p>
<p>You can write your answer in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>In a future lesson, we will give <strong>feedback </strong>on some of the writing we receive.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>phrase </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of two or more words that express an idea but do not make up a sentence</p>
<p><strong>feedback </strong><em>– n.</em> helpful information that is given to someone to say what can be done to improve</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Biden Campaign Defends Decision to Put President on TikTok  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/biden-campaign-defends-decision-to-put-president-on-tiktok.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden officially has a presence on TikTok. But his reelection campaign is having to defend its decision to put him on the video sharing <strong>app</strong>.<strong> </strong>That is because his administration has repeatedly warned of national security concerns linked to TikTok.</p>
<p>Biden, a Democrat, first appeared on TikTok in a video published Sunday night. The 30-second video showed him answering a series of questions, mostly about Sunday's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/kansas-city-chiefs-usher-taylor-swift-win-at-super-bowl/7484523.html">Super Bowl</a>.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have said the decision to put the president on TikTok came from Biden's campaign organization, not the White House. Campaign officials have explained that they see TikTok as a way for Biden, age 81, to connect with younger voters.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - U.S. President Biden delivers remarks urging Congress to pass the Emergency National Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, in Washington, U.S., February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b8d1ac8f-0be1-4656-92e8-e4a41fd6eb32_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - U.S. President Biden delivers remarks urging Congress to pass the Emergency National Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, in Washington, U.S., February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo)
</span></div>
<p>Last month, a TikTok representative told U.S. lawmakers the app currently had an estimated 170 million active users in the United States. That was up from 150 million a year earlier. Online data company Statista has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1095196/tiktok-us-age-gender-reach/#:~:text=TikTok%20usage%20in%20the%20U.S.%202023%2C%20by%20age&amp;text=According%20to%20a%20May%202023,app%20on%20a%20monthly%20basis.">estimated</a> about 70 percent of American teenagers are users of TikTok.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have long warned that TikTok presents national security concerns. The government has accused TikTok's owner, Chinese company ByteDance, of sharing user data with China's government. Critics have said China could also use TikTok to spread misinformation and that material published on the service can harm the mental health of young users.</p>
<p>TikTok denies the accusations.</p>
<p>President Biden approved a limited ban on TikTok in December 2022. The ban made it unlawful for most of the federal government's 4 million employees to use the app on devices owned by agencies.</p>
<p>On Monday, White House national security spokesperson John Kirby said the U.S. government's position and policies concerning TikTok had not changed. "There are still national security concerns about the use of TikTok on government devices and there's been no change to our policy not to <strong>allow</strong> that," Kirby said.</p>
<p>White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters election rules barred her from commenting on campaign matters. But when asked about worries that TikTok and similar apps can help spread disinformation, she said, "it's a concern that we have."</p>
<p>A spokesman for Biden's reelection campaign defended the use of TikTok to help get the president's message out. Deputy campaign manager Rob Flaherty noted that by Monday afternoon, Biden's TikTok video had been watched more than 5 million times.</p>
<p>The video, Flaherty said in a statement, demonstrates the campaign's continuing efforts "to reach voters in an <strong>evolving</strong>, <strong>fragmented</strong>, and increasingly personalized media environment."</p>
<p>Attempts in Congress to restrict TikTok have not resulted in approved legislation. A number of U.S. states and some universities have banned TikTok on state-issued devices.</p>
<p>Several lawmakers criticized the Biden campaign's decision. Among them was Republican Senator Josh Hawley of Missouri. He wrote on X that Biden's campaign was "<strong>bragging</strong> about using a Chinese spy app even though Biden signed a law banning it on all federal devices."</p>
<p>Republican Senator Joni Ernst also reacted on X, expressing concern that the campaign had decided to put Biden on what she described as a "dangerous propaganda app."</p>
<p>Republican Representative Darrell Issa said, "<strong>Panic</strong> is when the Biden campaign joins TikTok after the White House banned the app from devices a year ago."</p>
<p>Senator Mark Warner, a Democrat, also expressed his national security concerns about TikTok and criticized the campaign's decision to put Biden on the app. "I think that we still need to find a way to follow India, which has <strong>prohibited</strong> TikTok," Warner said. He added, "I'm a little worried about a mixed message."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device</p>
<p><strong>allow </strong><em>– v. </em>to permit</p>
<p><strong>evolve </strong><em>– v.</em> to develop or make something develop</p>
<p><strong>fragmented </strong><em>– adj. </em>broken into parts</p>
<p><strong>elderly </strong><em>– adj. </em>older people</p>
<p><strong>brag </strong><em>– v. </em>to talk with much pride about what you have done or what you have</p>
<p><strong>panic </strong><em>– n. </em>a sudden, strong feeling or worry or fear</p>
<p><strong>prohibit </strong><em>– v. </em>to officially ban something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Will Immigrants Save US Economy?  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/will-immigrants-save-us-economy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Each day, about 10,000 baby boomers leave the U.S. workforce. Baby boomers are the generation of people born between 1946 and 1964. The COVID-19 pandemic only increased the amount of people retiring as older workers decided to retire early rather than risk getting sick.</p>
<p>"We're running out of workers. Why? Because baby boomers are retiring, and you don't have enough younger workers who are skilled to fill in their <strong>spots</strong>," said Dana Peterson, chief economist at The Conference Board, a research group.</p>
<p>She said the U.S. is going to have labor shortages. And she added that the pandemic quickened retirements and made labor shortages "more intense."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Carrying American flags, immigrants march during a peaceful protest against a Florida legislation restricting undocumented immigrants, Thursday, June 1, 2023, in Immokalee, Florida. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2fac-08dc26813f02_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Carrying American flags, immigrants march during a peaceful protest against a Florida legislation restricting undocumented immigrants, Thursday, June 1, 2023, in Immokalee, Florida. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)</span></div>
<p>Selcuk Eren is a senior economist at The Conference Board. He said the problem is that for every person leaving, only one person is coming into the labor force. And a slowed-down labor force means limited growth.</p>
<p>He said, "So, one-on-one means that your labor force is not growing, which is going to slow down economic growth, as well."</p>
<p>The federal government workforce is also expected to be hit hard as more boomers retire.</p>
<p>"Forty percent of the federal government is aged 55 or more as of now, so that means that this huge wave of retirements is coming," Eren says. "And you're going to have a difficult time to replace them, because there's not enough younger people, <strong>especially</strong> with the educational requirements that those jobs require."</p>
<p><strong>Most affected industries</strong></p>
<p>A Conference Board <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.conference-board.org/topics/labor-shortages/Labor-Shortages-Risk-Index">report</a> looks at industries that are likely to have shortages as older Americans leave the workforce. They include physical labor jobs like personal care, food services, cleaning, and jobs involving repairs and building, among others. Production and transportation jobs will also be affected by retiring baby boomers, but less so.</p>
<p>The report finds that the most severe labor shortages will be in health-related jobs as more aging boomers will require personal care.</p>
<p>The possibility for labor shortages is mostly lower in jobs that require a college degree. STEM professionals, or those working in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, are at a lower risk of shortages. Jobs that permit <strong>remote</strong> work will have less intense labor shortages, the report says.</p>
<p><strong>Possible solutions for labor shortages</strong></p>
<p>Immigration could be a way to lessen the effect of boomers leaving their jobs, Eren says.</p>
<p>Eren said, "That's probably the fastest solution, because it takes time to educate a younger person, to bring them to that skill level." He said, "The fastest solution is just immigration and giving <strong>priority</strong> to immigrants with those skills that we are going to be lacking. That's number one." He said number two is to keep baby boomers working by giving them <strong>incentives</strong> to stay in the workforce.</p>
<p>Incentives could include tax and social security policies that do not punish someone who works into their seventies. And offering increased freedoms, like remote or part-time work, to people nearing retirement age.</p>
<p>For Chicago-based college professor Kristin Mariani, retiring baby boomers mean increased <strong>opportunities</strong> for her students.</p>
<p>She said the effect is "... it's giving younger people, the generations that came after them, to become the change-makers, the decision-makers." Mariani is a professor at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago.</p>
<p>She added that it is important, "... to make sure that the education and the knowledge that is given to these individuals, that they will be able to move forward with these responsibilities."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for VOA News. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>spot </strong>– <em>n</em>. a particular position in a competition, organization, or program</p>
<p><strong>especially </strong><em>– adv.</em> used to indicate something that deserves special mention</p>
<p><strong>remote </strong><em>– adj.</em> connected to a computer system from another place</p>
<p><strong>priority </strong><em>– n. </em>something that is more important than other things and that needs to be done or dealt with first</p>
<p><strong>incentives </strong><em>– n.</em> something that encourages a person to do something or to work harder</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Fewer Products to Choose from Can Lead to Better Sales  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/fewer-products-to-choose-from-can-lead-to-better-sales.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>American businesses are reducing the number of products that they offer. The change began before the COVID-19 pandemic. It has only increased in recent months.</p>
<p><strong>Reduced offerings </strong></p>
<p>Coca-Cola used to offer around 400 different kinds of drinks. The beverage company recently decided to discontinue half of them. Among the products cut were Tab, Zico coconut water, Diet Coke Feisty Cherry and Odwalla juices.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An employee straightens displays at a Kohl's store in Clifton, N.J., Friday, Jan. 26, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a227278d-3c27-4449-899d-280756721ad3_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An employee straightens displays at a Kohl's store in Clifton, N.J., Friday, Jan. 26, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>Other American businesses are reducing food offerings from mayonnaise to cereals. Car companies, too, are offering fewer kinds of cars and instead putting more effort into what they think will sell best.</p>
<p>Stew Leonard's, a company that operates food stores in Connecticut, New York and New Jersey, has cut the number of cereals it offers from 49 in 2019 to 24.</p>
<p>Edgewell Personal Care Co., the maker of Schick razors and Banana Boat suntan lotion, has cut some kinds of its anti-bacterial wipes called Wet Ones, among other products. Dollar General, based in Goodlettsville, Tennessee, used to offer six different kinds of mayonnaise. Now it offers two.</p>
<p>"The <strong>consumer</strong> is not going to know the difference," Todd J. Vasos, chief of Dollar General, told experts in December. "Actually, it's going to make her life a little simpler when she goes to the <strong>shelf</strong>."</p>
<p>Shoppers looking for cars are finding fewer choices as well. Both General Motors and Ford have announced they are limiting the number of <strong>option </strong>combinations customers can get on their vehicles to reduce manufacturing and purchasing complexity.</p>
<p><strong>Trends </strong></p>
<p>That is a change of direction from a few years ago when companies aimed to offer more choices. Online shopping caused some to think that more choices lead to better sales. But more choices often do not.</p>
<p>Companies started reducing the number of products they offer a year or two before the pandemic.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, the reductions increased, with companies <strong>focusing</strong> on necessities as they faced supply problems. After the pandemic, when goods began moving freely again, many businesses discovered less was better.</p>
<p>New offerings made up about two percent of products in stores in 2023. That includes products for beauty, footwear, technology and toys. Market research company Circana said that number is down from five percent in 2019.</p>
<p>Many think the companies are also helping shoppers. Some studies show that fewer choices result in shoppers buying more.</p>
<p>In 2000, psychologists Sheena Lyengar and Mark Lepper published a study that showed limited <strong>selection </strong>is better for people who are buying things. In their experiment, the researchers found consumers were 10 times more likely to purchase <strong>jam </strong>when the number of jams available was cut down from 24 to six. Later studies have produced similar findings.</p>
<p>"<strong>Retailers </strong>are recognizing that they have to be respectful of shoppers' time," said Paco Underhill, whose company, Envirosell, studies consumer behavior.</p>
<p>But retailers cannot just reduce offerings without a plan, said David Berliner of BDO, a business services company.</p>
<p>"You want to make these cuts so they're not even <strong>aware</strong> of it, and you want the store to still look full," Berliner said. "If you do it too much, you might scare some away."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Anne D'Innocenzio reported this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who buys products for personal use</p>
<p><strong>shelf </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat board which is attached to a wall and on which objects can be placed</p>
<p><strong>option</strong> <em>–n. (sales) </em>a choice of car or truck model that has a set group of products that go with it, and which is offered at one of several pricing levels</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong>–<em> v.</em> to direct your attention or effort at something specific</p>
<p><strong>selection</strong> –<em>n. </em>a group of products from which a person can choose</p>
<p><strong>jam<em> </em></strong><em>–n.</em> sweet, preserved fruit that is usually put on bread</p>
<p><strong>retailer </strong>– n. a person or business that sells things directly to customers</p>
<p><strong>aware</strong> –adj. knowing that something is present, available or that it exists</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wealth Inequality by Race Grew during Pandemic  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/wealth-inequality-by-race-grew-during-pandemic.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new government report says wealth inequality by race increased in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The New York Federal Reserve Bank carried out the study and released the report. It said strong performance in financial markets and large gains in the stock market in 2021 were partly to blame for the increase.</p>
<p>The report found that the <strong>net</strong> worth of whites individually outgrew that of Blacks individually by 30 percentage points. Whites outgrew Hispanics by nine percentage points. The findings cover the years 2019 through half of 2023.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Traders work on the New York Stock Exchange floor, Sept. 13, 2022. (AP Photo/Julia Nikhinson)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/09840000-0aff-0242-caf1-08da95cbb980_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Traders work on the New York Stock Exchange floor, Sept. 13, 2022. (AP Photo/Julia Nikhinson)
</span></div>
<p>The period saw a high level of government financial support and a surprisingly strong job market. The unemployment rate for Black Americans is now at 5.3 percent, near a record low. The overall unemployment rate is 3.7 percent. Earnings for a Black full-time worker are up 7 percent on average since before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Closing the racial wealth divide, or gap, is especially difficult because a much larger number of white households have money in stocks and <strong>mutual funds</strong>. A separate Federal Reserve study showed that as of 2022, about 66 percent of white households had investments in stocks. In comparison, 39 percent of Black households owned stock. Stock investment was found to be even lower among Hispanic households, at 28 percent.</p>
<p>Government support, including additional unemployment assistance and COVID-linked payments to Americans, helped prevent a recession, the report says. But financial <strong>asset</strong> prices rose so quickly with the reopening of the economy through 2021 that racial wealth inequalities increased. Those asset prices fell, or declined, in 2022, after the Federal Reserve increased interest rates. But "those declines did not fully offset the earlier rises," the report's writers said.</p>
<p>The report noted that Black households have more wealth contained in <strong>pensions</strong> than in stocks, mutual funds and exchange-traded funds, or ETFs.</p>
<p>More than 50 percent of Black financial wealth is invested in pensions, the New York Fed found. Less than 20 percent of Black wealth is contained in private businesses, corporate <strong>equities</strong>, and mutual funds. In contrast, less than 30 percent of white financial wealth is invested in pensions. About 50 percent is invested in businesses, equities, and mutual funds.</p>
<p>"Black workers are still more likely to be unionized, which may play a part in the pension story," said Janelle Jones, Vice President of Policy and Advocacy at the Washington Center for Equitable Growth.</p>
<p>"Whether folks are <strong>exposed</strong> to the ability to invest in the stock market — whether or not it's something they grow up doing — we know that's different for white families than for people of color," Jones said.</p>
<p>Blacks are also less likely than whites to receive money and property from family members who die, she said</p>
<p>Owning a business is another part of financial wealth. Separate data show Black-owned businesses suffered more during the pandemic.</p>
<p>Less than 10 percent of all U.S. business owners are Black. And many Black-owned businesses are in industries that were hit hardest when COVID first spread, reported research group Economic Policy Institute after examining U.S. government data.</p>
<p>Hotel, food service, <strong>retail</strong>, health care, and social assistance industries suffered the greatest number of pandemic-linked job losses. About 28 percent of Black-owned businesses are found in those industries, compared with just under 20 percent of white-owned businesses, says the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics.</p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury reported Wednesday that economic conditions are improving for Black households. Deputy Secretary Wally Adeyemo noted rising employment numbers and wages for Black Americans since before the pandemic. He also praised an increase in Black business ownership and action in the stock market.</p>
<p>But, Adeyemo suggested that some policy measures still might be needed to balance financial wealth in the U.S.</p>
<p>"The gap between Black and white wealth in America is still too great," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>gap </strong><em>— n. </em>a space between two people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mutual fund </strong><em>— n. </em> a type of investment in which the money of many people is used to buy stock from many different companies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>asset </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is owned by a person, company, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pension </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that a company or the government pays to a person who is old or sick and no longer works</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>equity </strong><em>— n. </em> fairness or justice in the way people are treated</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inheritance </strong><em>— n. </em>money, property, etc., that is received from someone when that person dies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>retail </strong><em>— n. </em>the business of selling things directly to customers for their own use</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Icy Moon of Saturn Likely Has an Underground Ocean  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/scientists-icy-moon-of-saturn-likely-has-an-underground-ocean.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say new evidence suggests Saturn's icy moon Mimas likely has a large underground ocean.</p>
<p>Astronomers based their finding on data collected by the American space agency NASA's Cassini spacecraft. Cassini observed Saturn and its more than 140 moons for more than 10 years before ending operations in 2017.</p>
<p>The spacecraft's data covered details about the moon's orbit and <strong>rotation</strong>. Researchers reported the data provided the best evidence yet of a hidden ocean about 20 to 30 kilometers beneath the frozen surface.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Feb. 13, 2010 image provided by NASA shows Saturn's moon Mimas and it's large Herschel Crater, captured by the Cassini spacecraft. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-c2d7-08dc2be8630c_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This Feb. 13, 2010 image provided by NASA shows Saturn's moon Mimas and it's large Herschel Crater, captured by the Cassini spacecraft. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute via AP)</span></div>
<p>Mimas is a relatively small moon, about 400 kilometers wide. Researchers say Mimas lacks formations on its surface found on other moons, which suggest the presence of underground water. These can include a broken surface as well as <strong>geyser</strong> activity.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Scientists said the fact that Mimas did not have unusual surface formations made it an unlikely candidate for an underground ocean.</p>
<p>Valery Lainey, of the Paris Observatory, was co-author <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06975-9">of a study</a> describing the research in the publication <em>Nature</em>. "Mimas was probably the most unlikely place to look for a global ocean — and liquid water more generally," he said in an email to the Associated Press.</p>
<p>Lainey added, "So that looks like a <strong>potential(ly) habitable</strong> world. But nobody knows how much time is needed for life to arise."</p>
<p>The amount of water thought to exist below the surface of Mimas would represent just 1.2 to 1.4 percent of Earth's oceans, Lainey said. That is because of the moon's small size.</p>
<p>However, Mimas does have a very large crater caused by a crash with a space object. For this reason, the appearance of the moon has been compared to the <strong>fictional</strong> "Death Star" space station in the popular movie series <em>Star Wars</em>.</p>
<p>English astronomer William Herschel discovered Mimas in 1789. It is named after a giant in Greek <strong>mythology</strong>.</p>
<p>An article appearing with the study in <em>Nature</em> was co-written by Matija Cuk of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.seti.org/">SETI Institute</a> research center and Alyssa Rose Rhoden of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/">Southwest Research Institute</a>. The two were not part of the study. But they wrote that they find the idea that a small, icy moon can contain young oceans "<strong>inspiring</strong>."</p>
<p>The researchers said the underground ocean appears to have formed recently in space terms, possibly between 5 and 15 million years ago. Lainey said the ocean would likely have an overall temperature of around zero degrees Celsius. But the temperature at the seafloor might be much warmer.</p>
<p>The fact that the water is in contact with the moon's rocky center may create the right complex chemical conditions to support life. But the researchers noted that because the ocean is believed to be young, it might not be ideal for life to form there.</p>
<p>Scientists have said in the past that another moon of Saturn, Enceladus, might possess the warmth, water and chemical compounds necessary to support life. But because Mimas' ocean is so young, it "might be a <strong>challenge</strong> for life's development," study co-writer Gabriel Tobie told Reuters. Tobie is a scientist at the French scientific research agency CNRS and The University of Nantes.</p>
<p>However, Tobie added, "Nobody knows how long life needs to <strong>emerge</strong> from a suitable environment. Mimas may offer a unique <strong>opportunity</strong> to explore the first stage of life's development."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rotate </strong><em>– v. </em>to turn in a circular direction</p>
<p><strong>mythology </strong>–n. old, stories that belong to certain cultures and which appear again and again in writing and art</p>
<p><strong>geyser </strong><em>– n. </em>a hole in the ground from which hot water and steam come out</p>
<p><strong>habitable </strong><em>– adj. </em>having the ability to support life</p>
<p><strong>potential </strong><em>– n. </em>existing in possibility</p>
<p><strong>fictional </strong><em>– adj. </em>not existing in real life</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone feel that they want to do something and can do it</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>– n. </em>something difficult that tests one's ability or determination</p>
<p><strong>emerge </strong><em>– v. </em>to appear somewhere</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong><em>– n. </em>a chance to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Change Fueling Disappearance of Central Asia’s Aral Sea  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/climate-change-fueling-disappearance-of-central-asia-s-aral-sea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Climate change is quickening the disappearance of the Aral Sea. Once a single body of water, the lake now exists in pieces in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan. Many years ago, it was one of the world's largest inland bodies of water. But, that changed substantially over the last century. The Aral has shrunk to less than 25 percent of its former size.</p>
<p>Engineering projects and agricultural programs are to blame for much of the lake's early losses. Now, climate change is adding to the destruction. Summers in the area are longer and hotter. Winters are shorter and colder. The area lacks water supplies. And experts say much of the water that does exist is too salty to support plant life.</p>
<p><strong>History and loss</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A rusting ship sits in a dried-up area of the Aral Sea in Muynak, Uzbekistan, Sunday, June 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a8c4e718-3f13-4047-a4c6-8d1072f2f556_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A rusting ship sits in a dried-up area of the Aral Sea in Muynak, Uzbekistan, Sunday, June 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)</span></div>
<p>The Aral is fed by rivers that heavily depend on <strong>glacial </strong>melt. For many years, it held many fish, supporting a fishing industry.</p>
<p>The area brought in thousands of migrants for jobs in the past, also. Today, a few remaining towns sit quiet along the Aral's dry seabed. Dust storms often pass through.</p>
<p>In the 1920s, the Soviet government began to empty the sea to provide water to crops like cotton. By the 1960s, it was half its former size. By 1987, the Aral's level was so low it divided into two bodies of water: the northern and southern seas.</p>
<p>The United Nations Development Program calls the destruction of the Aral Sea "the most <strong>staggering</strong> disaster of the 20th century." It points to the Aral's loss as the cause of desertification, drinking water shortages, and worsening health conditions, among others.</p>
<p>National governments, international aid organizations, and local efforts have made attempts to save the sea, including dams and plant growth projects. But experts say climate change has only quickened the dying of the Aral, and will continue to worsen local peoples' suffering.</p>
<p><strong>Loss of life</strong></p>
<p>The loss of much of the Aral Sea caused dust storms to blow through towns. They spread toxic chemicals from a former weapons testing center and farms into the lungs and eyes of local peoples. The U.N. says this has increased rates of diseases related to breathing and cancer.</p>
<p>A U.N. report says dust storms, rising world temperatures, and wind are destroying the glaciers on which the feeder rivers depend. The remaining water is getting saltier and <strong>evaporating</strong> faster.</p>
<p>The report warns that melting ice and changing river flows may further cause problems for water supply and food supply. Hydropower plants could suffer.</p>
<p><strong>Differences along the Aral</strong></p>
<p>In Uzbekistan, Adilbay and his friends fish in the Aral's remaining waters. The fish are small and few.</p>
<p>The 62-year-old holds his arms wide to demonstrate how big the Aral fish used to be. "Now there is nothing," he said.</p>
<p>As the water disappeared, a nearby fish processing plant closed. Adilbay's friends and relatives moved to Kazakhstan looking for new jobs.</p>
<p>There, fisherman Serzhan Seitbenbetov and others find success. In an hour, he caught a hundred fish, some 2 meters long.</p>
<p>"Now all the villagers make good money being fishermen," he said.</p>
<p>That is the result of an $86 million dam project led by Kazakhstan, with assistance from the World Bank. It was completed in 2005.</p>
<p>Known as the Kokaral Dam, it saves and gathers water from the Syr Darya River. The dam performed better than expected, leading to an increase of over 3 meters in water levels after seven months.</p>
<p>That helped restore local fisheries and caused an increase in clouds and rainstorms in the local area, the World Bank says. Population grew.</p>
<p>But it could not <strong>replicate </strong>life before the water started drying up, said Sarah Cameron. She is a professor at the University of Maryland who is writing a book about the Aral.</p>
<p>"It does not support the same amount of people and the fishing industry in the same way," Cameron said.</p>
<p>Uzbekistan's <strong>restoration</strong> efforts have been mixed in success. The government has not undertaken large projects like the Kokaral. Instead, the country planted trees and other plants to help prevent <strong>erosion</strong> and slow dust storms.</p>
<p>The discovery of oil and natural gas in the Aral's former seabed led to the building of gas production sites. Experts say that shows that Uzbekistan has little interest in restoration..</p>
<p>Kate Shields is a professor of environmental studies at Rhodes College in the American state of Tennessee.</p>
<p>"While there has been some restoration," she said, "there was a sort of acceptance that ... the sea was not coming back."</p>
<p>Government officials from Uzbekistan and Kazakhstan did not answer questions from the <em>Associated Press</em> about restoration efforts, the lack of water, and the effects of climate change.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Victoria Milko reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>glacier </strong><em>– n. </em>a very large area of ice that moves slowly down a slope or valley or over a wide area of land</p>
<p><strong>evaporate</strong></p>
<p><strong>staggering </strong><em>– adj. </em>very large, shocking, or surprising</p>
<p><strong>replicate </strong><em>– v.</em> to repeat or copy (something) exactly</p>
<p><strong>restoration </strong><em>– adj. </em>the act or process of returning something to its original condition by repairing it or cleaning it</p>
<p><strong>erosion </strong>– <em>n</em>. the gradual destruction of something by natural forces (such as water, wind, or ice)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Schools Change Health Guidelines for Keeping Students Home  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-schools-change-health-guidelines-for-keeping-students-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Unclear guidelines for when to keep a child at home if they are sick might play a part in the nationwide problem of students missing too much school.</p>
<p>Some activists, school officials and the state of California are now asking that parents send their children to school even if they show signs of sickness. They say acceptable problems include eye infections and <strong>lice</strong>.</p>
<p>Families need to hear they no longer must keep children at home at any sign of sickness, said Hedy Chang. Chang is the director of Attendance Works, a nonprofit group aiming to improve school attendance. The group has issued its own guidance. It urges parents to send children to school if they can join day-to-day activities, have low-level sickness or head lice.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An empty elementary school classroom is seen on Tuesday, Aug. 17, 2021 in the Bronx borough of New York. (AP Photo/Brittainy Newman, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/528de8c6-0122-453c-88d0-5106c36d282c_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An empty elementary school classroom is seen on Tuesday, Aug. 17, 2021 in the Bronx borough of New York. (AP Photo/Brittainy Newman, File)</span></div>
<p>The American Academy of Pediatrics is an organization for doctors who treat children. It recommends that children stay home when there are signs of sickness like fever, vomiting, or diarrhea, or when students "are not well enough to <strong>participate</strong> in class."</p>
<p>A fever is defined as a body temperature above 38 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>But many <strong>school districts</strong> go far beyond that, offering different signs of sickness that would prevent parents from sending their children to school.</p>
<p><strong>Which is it?</strong></p>
<p>Trenace Dorsey-Hollins has a five-year-old daughter who was sick a lot last year. Dorsey-Hollins followed school guidelines and kept her daughter home when she had a <strong>cough</strong>, painful throat, fever, or sneezing.</p>
<p>Near the end of the year, school officials in Fort Worth, Texas, called her in to talk about why her daughter had missed so much school.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, schools urged parents and children to stay home at any sign of illness. Although the emergency has ended, she said no one has said that those rules have changed.</p>
<p>"In the past, if the child didn't have a fever...then it's okay to send them to school," said the mother of five- and 13-year-old children. "But now it's like if they have a cough...you might want to keep them home. Which is it?"</p>
<p>Dorsey-Hollins' youngest daughter goes to school in Fort Worth Independent School District. It suggests staying home if a child has a cough, <strong>sore</strong> throat, or <strong>rash</strong>. The guidelines say a student should be "fever-free" for 24 hours without medication before returning to school.</p>
<p>Austin Independent School District in Texas lists signs of illness like "eye redness," "<strong>undetermined</strong> rash," or "open, draining <strong>lesions</strong>" as reasons to stay home.</p>
<p>Other school districts have different guidelines. Children with lice cannot go to class in New York City schools. And Maryland's Montgomery County schools recommend keeping a child home for stomach pain, "pale or flushed face," or "thick yellow discharge from the nose."</p>
<p>Dr. Claire McCarthy is a doctor at Boston Children's Hospital who teaches at Harvard Medical School. She said it is understandable that different places would have different guidelines.</p>
<p>"Each school or school district has a different <strong>tolerance</strong> for illness," said McCarthy.</p>
<p><strong>10 percent of the school year</strong></p>
<p>Test results <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-student-learning-decreased-in-math-reading-worldwide-/7387144.html">show</a> that children fell behind in their studies when schools closed during the pandemic. Children who regularly missed school found it more difficult to catch up. During the 2021 to 2022 school year, more than 25 percent of students missed at least 10 percent of the school year. That number is up from 15 percent before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Missing 10 percent or more of the school year puts students at risk. Students who miss school also might miss meals, socializing with other students and adults, physical exercise, and mental health and health care services.</p>
<p>In addition, teachers must spend a lot of time supporting students who miss class. This takes time from students who attend class and are on target for the year.</p>
<p>Recently, the state of California decided to change their stay-at-home guidelines for the autumn. The new guidelines say children with low-level signs of sickness can come to school.</p>
<p>Noha Aboelata leads the Roots Health Center in Oakland, California. The group says it provides health services for poor people and those affected by inequality. Aboelata said the change in guidance might have a greater effect on poor people and minorities.</p>
<p>Aboelata said people in those communities might be more likely to live in homes with more than one generation, to take public transportation, or have poor heating and cooling systems in their homes.</p>
<p>She said she hoped that staying home when sick would continue after the pandemic. Instead, she said, "it feels like the <strong>pendulum</strong> is <strong>swinging </strong>fiercely back<strong> </strong>in the other direction."</p>
<p>Tracy Schmidt oversees attendance for the Office of Education in San Diego County, California. She said she feels hopeful that parents and schools will learn about the new guidance and that students will miss less school.</p>
<p>"The most important place for our kids to be is school," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Bianca Vázquez Toness reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lice </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> a small creature that lives on people's bodies and easily spreads from person to person<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>participate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to be involved with others in doing something</p>
<p><strong>school district </strong><em>– n. </em>an area created by a local government which has public schools that are overseen by local government officials and paid for through local taxes</p>
<p><strong>cough </strong><em>–v.</em> the involuntary forcing of air through the throat often because of sickness</p>
<p><strong>sore </strong><em>–adj.</em> painful</p>
<p><strong>rash </strong><em>–n.</em> a condition on the skin that makes it red or swollen and often produces itching</p>
<p><strong>undetermined </strong><em>–adj.</em> unknown</p>
<p><strong>lesion </strong>–n. a raised area of skin that is unhealthy, damaged or cut</p>
<p><strong>tolerance </strong><em>– n.</em> the ability to accept, experience, or survive something harmful or unpleasant</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Historic Gun Factory in New York State Village to Close  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/historic-gun-factory-in-new-york-state-village-to-close.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">The oldest gunmaker in America is closing its factory in a small town in the state of New York.</p>
<p>Remington Firearms was formed two centuries ago in what is now the town of Ilion, a village in the heart of New York's Mohawk Valley area. It began when Eliphalet Remington <strong>forged</strong> his first rifle barrel nearby in 1816.</p>
<p>Remington's owners recently announced it would permanently shut the factory in March. They said costs were too high to continue making guns in Ilion.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A sign for Remington Arms stands in front of the company's factory in Ilion, N.Y., Thursday, February. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b189a08a-6ac0-44f2-83db-b0d59c86e7d9_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A sign for Remington Arms stands in front of the company's factory in Ilion, N.Y., Thursday, February. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>The company is uniting all its operations in the southeastern state of Georgia. Remington officials say Georgia is friendlier to the firearms industry than New York.</p>
<p>The company's recent history has been marked by a <strong>lawsuit</strong> connected to the mass murder of 20 children and six adults in 2012 at an elementary school in Connecticut. Remington Arms agreed to pay $73 million to relatives of victims and a survivor to settle the legal action. The company also declared financial failure more than once.</p>
<p>The factory workforce had dropped from about 1,300 workers more than 10 years ago to around 300. About 7,600 people live in Ilion. The gunmaker's withdrawal is a major loss to the town's economy and more.</p>
<p>"When Remington leaves, it's not going to be like a <strong>facility</strong> leaving, it's going to be like part of your family has moved off," said former factory worker Jim Conover. Conover retired in 2004, after 40 years at the plant.</p>
<p>Everyone knows someone who worked at the factory. For some families, jobs there are almost a <strong>birthright</strong>. Conover's father and sons also worked at the plant.</p>
<p>Building engineer Frank "Rusty" Brown has had many family members among his coworkers.</p>
<p>"My mom worked there. My dad worked there. My wife works there with me now. My daughter works there with me now. My second daughter works there with me now. And my son-in-law works there," said Brown, who is president of the United Mine Workers of America Local 717.</p>
<p>He added, "So it's a double-hit for me and my wife: two of us out of a job."</p>
<p>The current owners of Remington Firearms, RemArms, blamed "production <strong>inefficiencies</strong>" for the plant closure in a letter to union officials late last year. They noted the high cost of caring for about 92,903 square meters of space in several buildings, many dating to World War I.</p>
<p>RemArms added that Georgia offered an environment that better "supports and welcomes the firearms industry."</p>
<p>RemArms CEO Ken D'Arcy also said in a news release that the industry was concerned about the "legislative environment" in New York.</p>
<p>But in a stretch of upstate New York where support for gun rights tends to be strong, some Republican elected officials seized on the company's comment about Georgia. They linked the plant closure to gun control measures championed by New York City-area Democrats in recent years.</p>
<p>RemArms, which bought the firearms business in 2020, did not answer emails and calls seeking comment.</p>
<p>The company said in its letter to the union it expected to end facility operations around March 4. The company earlier announced in 2021 it was moving its headquarters to LaGrange, Georgia. RemArms said it would open a factory and research operation there.</p>
<p>The days of traffic jams in Ilion every afternoon when shifts let out are long gone. Empty spaces can be found in the factory's big parking lot. Nearby businesses<strong> </strong>that have long provided meals to the workers have already seen a sharp reduction in food orders.</p>
<p>One such business is Franco's pizza. Its owner, Daniel Mendez, said orders have been "dwindling down," or decreasing.</p>
<p>"This is not necessarily going to put us out of business, but it does hurt," Mendez said.</p>
<p>Ilion Mayor John Stephens said there will be hard decisions ahead. But he said he believes the factory site will be used again. And while Remington might leave, he said the connection between the town and the factory can never be broken.</p>
<p>"Even when they are finally 100 percent no longer involved in the Village of Ilion in any way, shape or form, we're still going to be known for this," Stephens said. "You can't <strong>erase</strong> history."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>forge </strong><em>–n. </em>to form (something, such as metal) by heating and hammering</p>
<p><strong>lawsuit </strong><em>–n. </em>a legal case before a court</p>
<p><strong>facility </strong><em>–n. </em>something (such as a hospital) that is built, installed, or established to serve a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>birthright </strong><em>–n. </em>a right, privilege, or possession to which a person is entitled by birth</p>
<p><strong>inefficiency </strong><em>–n. </em>a state or quality that is wasteful of time or energy<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>erase </strong><em>–v. </em>to remove from existence or memory</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Monarch Butterfly Population Declines in Mexico  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/monarch-butterfly-population-declines-in-mexico.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Monarch butterfly population has dropped to its second-lowest number on record in Mexican forests this winter. The forests are the insects' winter home. The population decrease is worrisome as the butterfly group is already considered at risk of disappearance.</p>
<p>Mexico's government and the non-profit World Wildlife Fund (WWF) recently issued findings of their yearly joint study on the butterflies. The research shows that the monarch butterfly presence has shrunk to less than a hectare of forest area.</p>
<p>In the mid-1990s, monarch butterflies could be found on around 18 hectares of the forest.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Monarch butterflies rest on a tree at the Sierra Chincua butterfly sanctuary in Angangeo, Michoacan state, Mexico December 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/95354b99-23b1-401b-89d6-6071c3c4e494_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Monarch butterflies rest on a tree at the Sierra Chincua butterfly sanctuary in Angangeo, Michoacan state, Mexico December 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>The findings represent an almost 60 percent decrease in the monarch butterfly population compared to last year's study. It is also the second-lowest population finding since the first study took place more than thirty years ago.</p>
<p>Biologists blame the drop on higher-than-usual temperatures and dry conditions in the northwestern U.S. where the butterfly reproduces.</p>
<p>The weather conditions affect the growth of milkweed, the plant where the butterflies lay their eggs. When the young arrive, milkweed is their food for a time.</p>
<p>In one of the planet's famous wildlife <strong>migrations</strong>, the butterflies travel south as many as 4,500 kilometers from places as far north as Canada. They spend the winter in warmer Mexico, where millions of the insects stay in trees that protect them from the rain and cold.</p>
<p>Monarch butterfly populations change year to year. As recently as 2021, the same study showed a 35 percent increase to cover around 2.8 hectares.</p>
<p>Officials and activists called for more action to help the <strong>species</strong>. Such calls include the need to reduce threats posed by <strong>herbicides</strong> that destroy milkweed and the need to protect forests.</p>
<p>"We can't lower our guard," Jorge Rickards, head of WWF's Mexico office, told reporters after releasing the latest data.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Diego Delgado reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of animals that are similar and can produce young animals</p>
<p><strong>migration</strong> <em>– n.</em> to move from one area to another</p>
<p><strong>herbicide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical used to destroy plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Autoimmune Diseases Affect More Women than Men  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/autoimmune-diseases-affect-more-women-than-men.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Women are much more likely to get autoimmune diseases than men. New research may finally explain why.</p>
<p>Autoimmune diseases happen when the body's natural defenses, or immune system, attack the body's tissues.</p>
<p>Researchers from Stanford University in California say the reason for this may be connected to how the body deals with females' second X chromosome.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Organs of the immune system. (Courtesy of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-69d6-08dc274347ba_cx2_cy0_cw95_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Organs of the immune system. (Courtesy of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences)</span></div>
<p>The finding could help improve doctors' abilities to <strong>detect</strong> autoimmune diseases.</p>
<p>E. John Wherry is an immunologist at the University of Pennsylvania. He said the new study changes "the way we think about this whole process of autoimmunity."</p>
<p>Between 24 million and 50 million Americans suffer from an autoimmune disorder. Autoimmune disorders include lupus, rheumatoid arthritis, multiple sclerosis, and many other diseases.</p>
<p>About four of every five patients with an autoimmune disorder are women. Scientists have tried to find out why for many years.</p>
<p>One theory is that the X chromosome might be the reason. Females have two X chromosomes while males have one X and one Y.</p>
<p>The new research recently appeared in the publication <em>Cell</em>. The results show that the extra X is involved — but in an unexpected way.</p>
<p>Our DNA is carried inside each cell in 23 pairs of chromosomes, including the final pair that decides biological sex. The X chromosome is packed with hundreds of genes, far more than males' much smaller Y chromosome.</p>
<p>Every female cell must turn off one of its X chromosome copies to avoid getting a dangerous double amount of all those genes. Scientists call this process X-chromosome inactivation.</p>
<p>A special kind of RNA, called Xist, performs the X-chromosome inactivation. Xist is a long chain of RNA. It gathers in areas along a cell's extra X chromosome and attracts proteins that connect to it in unusual masses. Then it silences the chromosome.</p>
<p>Dr. Howard Chang is a <strong>dermatologist</strong> at Stanford University. He was exploring how Xist does its job when his lab found nearly 100 of those attached proteins. Chang saw that many of those proteins were related to skin-related autoimmune disorders. Patients can have "autoantibodies" that mistakenly attack these normal proteins.</p>
<p>Chang told The Associated Press, "That got us thinking: These are the known ones. What about the other proteins in Xist?"</p>
<p>He added that the molecule, found only in women, might "somehow organize proteins in such a way as to <strong>activate</strong> the immune system."</p>
<p>If true, Xist by itself could not cause autoimmune disease. If it did, all women would be affected. Scientists have long thought it takes a combination of some genes and an environmental event, like an infection or injury, for the immune system to cause problems. For example, the Epstein-Barr virus is linked to multiple sclerosis.</p>
<p>Chang receives financial support from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute, which also supports The Associated Press' Health and Science Department.</p>
<p>Chang's team decided to produce male lab mice to artificially make Xist — without turning off their only X chromosome — and see what happened. Researchers also specially bred mice <strong>susceptible</strong> to developing a lupus-like condition. The condition can be set off by a certain chemical.</p>
<p>The Xist formed its usual protein masses. When the chemical was used, the male mice with Xist developed lupus-like autoimmunity at levels similar to females, the team found.</p>
<p>Chang said, "We think that's really important, for Xist RNA to leak out of the cell to where the immune system gets to see it."</p>
<p>But he added that an environmental event is still needed to start the process.</p>
<p>Beyond mice, researchers also looked at blood from 100 patients. They found autoantibodies targeting Xist-related proteins that scientists had not previously linked to autoimmune disorders. Chang said one possible reason was that most tests for autoimmunity were made using male cells.</p>
<p>More research is necessary. But Wherry, the immunologist at Penn, said the findings might give doctors a shorter path to diagnosing patients.</p>
<p>Wherry said one patient may have autoantibodies to Protein A and another patient may have autoantibodies to Proteins C and D. But he said knowing they are all related to Xist RNA can help doctors find diseases more easily.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Lauran Neergaard reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>detect </strong>– <em>v</em>. to discover or notice the presence of (something that is hidden or hard to see, hear, taste, etc.)</p>
<p><strong>dermatologist </strong>– <em>n</em>. the scientific study of the skin and its diseases</p>
<p><strong>activate </strong><em>– v.</em> to cause (a chemical reaction or natural process) to begin</p>
<p><strong>susceptible </strong><em>– adj. </em>easily affected, influenced, or harmed by something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Kansas City Chiefs, Usher, Taylor Swift Win at Super Bowl  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/kansas-city-chiefs-usher-taylor-swift-win-at-super-bowl.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Kansas City Chiefs needed extra time on Sunday to win the American football championship called the Super Bowl. The Super Bowl is the National Football League's championship game.</p>
<p>Football experts say the Kansas City Chiefs are now one of the best teams to have ever played the sport.</p>
<p>The Chiefs scored a <strong>touchdown</strong> late in the extra period to defeat the San Francisco 49ers 25 to 22. The team has now won three Super Bowls in five seasons and appeared in four of the championship games since 2020.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Travis Kelce kisses Taylor Swift after the Kansas City Chiefs' Super Bowl win on February 11." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e7c9ed46-f2c0-4a1a-aaab-9dd94fde5111_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Travis Kelce kisses Taylor Swift after the Kansas City Chiefs' Super Bowl win on February 11.</span></div>
<p>Patrick Mahomes is the quarterback and the team's most important player. He has won three Super Bowls. Only three other quarterbacks have won more championships. Mahomes, is only 28. He was voted the top player, or MVP, of the game.</p>
<p>But for many people watching the game on television, Kansas City's win was only part of the story in Las Vegas, Nevada.</p>
<p>For a while, it seemed as if the halftime show, <strong>featuring</strong> the music performer Usher, was going to be the most exciting part of the game. At that point, San Francisco was ahead 10 to 3.</p>
<p>Usher, a singer who became well-known about 20 years ago, came out in sparkling, white clothes and performed along with a <strong>marching band</strong> and other musicians. He was joined during his show by Alicia Keys, H.E.R., Jermaine Dupri, Lil' Jon and Ludacris. Usher performed parts of 12 of his most popular songs.</p>
<p>Throughout the game, cameras cut to another famous singer, Taylor Swift. Swift is the girlfriend of Travis Kelce, one of the Kansas City players.</p>
<p>Swift performed the last of four concerts in Japan on Saturday and flew to Las Vegas to attend Sunday's game.</p>
<p>Kansas City, in the central state of Missouri, will celebrate the Chiefs during a parade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The game changed at the start of the fourth quarter, when San Francisco scored a touchdown to take a 16 to 13 lead. However, the 49ers kicker, Jake Moody, had his extra point attempt blocked.</p>
<p>The failed play permitted Kansas City to kick a field goal, worth three points, to tie the game at 16 and then again at 19 in order to force overtime. It was only the second Super Bowl to require extra time.</p>
<p>In the overtime period, San Francisco only scored a field goal to take the lead 22 to 19. However, under NFL rules, both teams have at least one chance to score in extra time.</p>
<p>That meant Kansas City could win the game with a touchdown. That is exactly what happened, when Mahomes threw a short touchdown pass to Mecole Hardman to end the game with only six seconds remaining.</p>
<p>Kelce is one of the league's best players <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_JoXvp2ns">at</a> his position. He had a slow start but caught nine passes from Mahomes.</p>
<p>Swift joined Kelce for the Super Bowl celebration after the game. After getting a kiss from Swift, Kelce said "the goal has always been to get three (Super Bowls)." He went on to say the team wants to win again next year, to make it three in a row.</p>
<p>The Chiefs are the first team to win two Super Bowls one after the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_ywFPXCm0">other, since</a> the New England Patriots did it 19 years ago.</p>
<p>Mahomes said, "I'm <strong>proud</strong> of the guys" as he accepted his MVP award. "This is awesome. <strong>Legendary</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>touchdown </strong>–n. the biggest score in American football given for reaching the "end zone" and which is awarded six points with the possibility of one or two extra points after</p>
<p><strong>feature </strong>–v. to be offered as a main star or attraction in a performance</p>
<p><strong>marching band </strong>–n. a large musical group usually linked to a high school or college, that has mostly brass instruments and which marches as it plays songs</p>
<p><strong>proud </strong>–adj. to be very pleased and happy with something you have done</p>
<p><strong>legendary </strong>–adj. very impressive and worth people's attention</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Did you watch the Super Bowl? What did you think?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Egypt Threatens to Suspend Peace Treaty with Israel  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/egypt-threatens-to-suspend-peace-treaty-with-israel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin, and U.S. President Jimmy Carter signed a peace deal in 1979. The agreement, marked by a handshake, has resulted in more than 40 years of peace between Middle East neighbors Israel and Egypt.</p>
<p>That peace agreement has held up through two Palestinian uprisings and several wars between Israel and Hamas. But the Egyptian government is threatening to suspend the agreement as Israel plans to send troops into Rafah, a city in Gaza on the border with Egypt.</p>
<p><strong>Israel-Egypt peace treaty</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this March 26, 1979 file photo, Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, left, U.S. President Jimmy Carter, center, and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin clasp hands as they completed signing of the peace treaty. (AP Photo/Bob Daugherty, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2d91fb34-8d0e-4110-9b5a-eb2142437a80_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this March 26, 1979 file photo, Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, left, U.S. President Jimmy Carter, center, and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin clasp hands as they completed signing of the peace treaty. (AP Photo/Bob Daugherty, File)</span></div>
<p>In 1977, Begin, Israel's new prime minister was opposed to giving back any land captured by Israel 10 years earlier in the 1967 war. Those lands included Egypt's Sinai Peninsula.</p>
<p>Egypt and Israel had fought four major wars, most recently in 1973. However, Egypt's Sadat broke with other Arab leaders and decided to talk with the Israelis. The talks resulted in the Camp David Accords in September 1978 and a peace treaty the following year.</p>
<p>Under the peace treaty, Israel agreed to withdraw from the Sinai, which Egypt would leave demilitarized. Israeli ships were granted passage through the Suez Canal, an important trade pathway. The countries established full diplomatic relations. It was Israel's first peace agreement with an Arab country since the country's establishment in 1948.</p>
<p>Paige Alexander is head of the Carter Center. She said, "The Camp David Accords were led by three brave men who took a <strong>bold</strong> stance because they knew the lasting effects for peace and security, both then and for the future. We need the same kind of leadership today, and that is currently lacking."</p>
<p><strong>What is Egypt's position?</strong></p>
<p>On Sunday, two Egyptian officials and a Western diplomat told The Associated Press that Egypt might suspend the peace treaty if Israeli troops enter Rafah.</p>
<p>Last October, Hamas launched a surprise attack from the Palestinian territory of Gaza into southern Israel. The terrorist group killed more than 1,200 people and took more than 150 hostages including Americans.</p>
<p>Israel answered with airstrikes and ground attacks in Gaza. The Palestinian-controlled health ministry reported in February that 28,000 people have been killed in more than four months of fighting. The number, which is not confirmed, includes both civilians and militants.</p>
<p>Israel says Rafah is the last area under Hamas control. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said sending ground troops into Rafah is needed to defeat the group.</p>
<p>However, Egypt opposes any move that could send desperate Palestinians fleeing across the border into its territory. Rafah serves as the main entry point into Gaza for humanitarian aid. An Israeli attack could prevent <strong>deliveries</strong> of supplies to Palestinians in Gaza.</p>
<p>Rafah's population has expanded from 280,000 people to an estimated 1.4 million as Palestinians flee fighting in other parts of Gaza. Hundreds of thousands of those <strong>evacuees</strong> are now living in tents.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has ordered the Israeli military to prepare a plan to evacuate all Palestinian civilians before the offensive starts. But it is unclear where they will go.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said Sunday that Palestinians would be able to return to open spaces in northern Gaza. But those areas have been badly damaged by the Israeli offensive.</p>
<p><strong>What happens if the peace treaty ends?</strong></p>
<p>The treaty between Egypt and Israel limits the number of troops on both sides of the border. The countries, however, have agreed in the past to make changes to deal with security threats.</p>
<p>In addition to Gaza, Israel has <strong>engaged</strong> in regular exchanges of weapons fire with the Hezbollah militant group in Lebanon. Israeli forces are also deployed in the occupied West Bank.</p>
<p>If Egypt were to end the agreement, Israel would have to deploy more troops to protect its southern border with Egypt.</p>
<p>Such a move, however, would affect Egypt as well.</p>
<p>Since the peace agreement, Egypt has received billions of dollars in military assistance from the U.S. If the agreement is ended, it could threaten that aid while Egypt's economy is struggling.</p>
<p>The war between Hamas and Israel has already spread to the Red Sea where Yemen's Houthi rebels regularly attack <strong>commercial</strong> shipping.</p>
<p>In Jordan, militants, supported by Iran, struck an American position with a <strong>drone</strong> last month killing three U.S. service members. The U.S. answered with several major strikes against militants in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Alexander from the Carter Center said any step that could draw Egypt into the hostilities "would be <strong>catastrophic</strong> for the entire <strong>region</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Julia Frankel reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bold</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj. </em>unafraid, willing to do something that is difficult</p>
<p><strong>delivery</strong> <em>–n.</em> the act of taking something to a person or group that requested it</p>
<p><strong>evacuee </strong>–n. a person who has been evacuated from a place, meaning they have been moved for their safety because of a dangerous situation</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong>–v. to be involved in a process that requires action and attention</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong>–adj. related to trade and business activity with an aim to make a profit</p>
<p><strong>drone </strong>–n. a vehicle that operates without a human pilot onboard often an aircraft or boat</p>
<p><strong>catastrophic </strong>–adj. disastrous, something that is extremely bad</p>
<p><strong>region </strong>–n. an area of the Earth that is know for certain qualities such as its geological, geographical, or political boundaries</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Launches New Satellite to Study Oceans, Atmosphere  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/nasa-launches-new-satellite-to-study-oceans-atmosphere.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA has launched a new satellite designed to closely study the world's oceans and atmosphere.</p>
<p>NASA launched the PACE satellite on February 8. A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket carried PACE into orbit from Kennedy Space Center in Florida. NASA confirmed the launch and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/pace/">reported</a> ground controllers had successfully established contact with the satellite.</p>
<p>PACE stands for Plankton, Aerosol, Cloud, Ocean Ecosystem. The satellite will spend at least three years studying the environment from an orbit 676 kilometers above the Earth's surface. NASA officials say PACE will map the entire world each day with two science instruments. A third instrument will collect monthly measurements. Scientists should start getting their first data within one or two months.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket on NASA's PACE mission lifts off from Space Launch Complex 40 at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Cape Canaveral, Fla., Thursday, Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/John Raoux)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a1ca-08dc28fe6a88_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket on NASA's PACE mission lifts off from Space Launch Complex 40 at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Cape Canaveral, Fla., Thursday, Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/John Raoux)</span></div>
<p>Jeremy Werdell is the Project Scientist for the PACE project, or mission. He told The Associated Press he sees the effort providing humans "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> view of our home planet."</p>
<p>Werdell noted a major goal of the observations is to help scientists improve their ability to predict hurricanes and other severe weather events. He said the instruments can provide detailed data on temperature-related changes happening across the world. The satellite data might help scientists better predict when harmful <strong>algae blooms</strong> will happen.</p>
<p>NASA says PACE will also study aerosols, or particles in the air. Karen St. Germain is NASA's director of Earth science. She <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=03HJCnQBkpY">told</a> reporters before PACE's launch that the study of aerosols is important because they can affect clouds. Aerosols can affect the density of clouds, as well as when and how much <strong>precipitation</strong> the clouds might release.</p>
<p>St. Germain noted existing satellites are not equipped to collect detailed data on aerosols. She said PACE will help NASA learn more about how aerosols affect clouds and climate over long periods. The new data is expected to give scientists "another <strong>dimension</strong>" of data on how aerosols affect oceans and the atmosphere.</p>
<p>St. Germain added, "And then, of course, there is a relationship between the phytoplankton and the aerosols." Phytoplankton are very small plants that float near the surface of water. They serve as a source of food for many sea creatures. NASA says phytoplankton "provide food to <strong>all sorts of</strong> animals ranging from shellfish to finfish to whales."</p>
<p>NASA says PACE's instruments will aim to measure changes in phytoplankton. The satellite will aim to collect data on aerosols that attach to phytoplankton. These studies will be important in identifying any changes in phytoplankton from interactions with aerosols which could affect the ocean and life in it.</p>
<p>NASA has already launched a series of Earth-observing satellites and instruments into orbit. But the agency believes PACE will be able to collect more detailed data on how different aerosols and pollutants get into the oceans and the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Project Scientist Werdell noted that current Earth-observing satellites can only see in seven or eight different colors. But he said Pace will see in 200 colors, permitting scientists to better identify different kinds of algae in the sea and particles in the air.</p>
<p>News reports say the mission will cost about $950 million.</p>
<p>The PACE mission follows the launch in December 2022 of NASA's SWOT satellite. The SWOT mission measures sea levels and changes in bodies of water over time. SWOT is a cooperative effort between NASA and France's space agency.</p>
<p>NASA is cooperating with India on another Earth-observing satellite set to launch this year. That spacecraft, called NISAR, will use radar instruments to measure the effects of rising temperatures on glaciers and other melting, icy surfaces.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>– adj.</em> never having happened before</p>
<p><strong>algae bloom </strong><em>– n. </em>a fast and large increase in algae - simple plants that have no leaves or stems and that grow in or near water</p>
<p><strong>precipitation </strong><em>– n. </em>rain or snow that falls to the ground</p>
<p><strong>dimension </strong><em>– n. </em>a particular part of a situation, especially something that affects how a person thinks or feels</p>
<p><strong>all sorts of </strong><em>– n. </em>many different kinds of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Propose a Stronger ‘Category 6’ for Hurricane  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/experts-propose-a-stronger-category-6-for-hurricane.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>There have been a few very powerful ocean storms in the last 10 years. The expectation of more to come has some experts proposing a new category of large <strong>hurricanes</strong>: Category 6.</p>
<p>Studies have shown that the strongest <strong>tropical</strong> storms are getting more powerful because of climate change. The traditional five-category Saffir-Simpson <strong>scale</strong> was created more than 50 years ago.</p>
<p>But two scientists suggested in a new study that the scale may not show the true power of the strongest storms. They propose a sixth category for storms with winds faster than 309 kilometers per hour.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Homes are flooded in the aftermath of Hurricane Ida, Monday, Aug. 30, 2021, in Jean Lafitte, Louisiana. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01b10000-0aff-0242-ec67-08d9fafbb1b7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Homes are flooded in the aftermath of Hurricane Ida, Monday, Aug. 30, 2021, in Jean Lafitte, Louisiana. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)</span></div>
<p>The study recently appeared in the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pnas.org/">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</a>.</p>
<p>Currently, storms with winds of 252 kilometers per hour or higher are Category 5. The study's writers said that this grouping does not do enough to warn people about the greater dangers from storms with even stronger winds.</p>
<p>Still, several experts told The <em>Associated Press</em> that they do not think another category is needed. They said it could even send the wrong message to the public because the new proposed category is based on wind speed. Water is by far the deadliest part of hurricanes.</p>
<p>Since 2013, five storms had winds that would have put them in the new category, with two hitting the Philippines. All five happened in the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>As the world warms, such large storms become more likely.</p>
<p>"Climate change is making the worst storms worse," said Michael Wehner, the study's lead writer. Wehner is a climate scientist at the Lawrence Berkley National Lab in California.</p>
<p>There are not more storms because of climate change, but climate change makes the strongest more intense. The <strong>proportion</strong> of major hurricanes among all storms is increasing. That is because the oceans are getting warmer, said Brian McNoldy. He is a hurricane researcher at Florida's University of Miami. He was not part of the research.</p>
<p>Experts have proposed a Category 6 several times over the years, especially since 2013's Typhoon Haiyan reached 315 kilometers per hour over the Pacific. The study said that Haiyan "does not appear to be an <strong>isolated</strong> case."</p>
<p>Storms with high enough wind speed are called hurricanes if they form east of the international dateline. They are called typhoons if they form to the west of the line. They are known as cyclones in the Indian Ocean and Australia. There have been five storms that had 309 kilometer per hour winds since 2013.</p>
<p>Jim Kossin is a climate and hurricane researcher who was an <strong>author</strong> of the study. He said if the world keeps to five storm categories, people will misjudge the risks as storms get larger and more powerful.</p>
<p>Pacific storms are stronger because there is less land to weaken them and more room for storms to grow more intense. That is not the same situation in the Gulf of Mexico and in the Caribbean, Kossin noted.</p>
<p>Jamie Rhome is deputy director of the National Hurricane Center in Florida. He said that, when warning people about the storms, his office warns people about individual dangers. These dangers include "storm <strong>surge</strong>, wind, rainfall, tornadoes and rip currents, instead of the particular category of the storm." The categories, he added, only provide information about the dangers from wind.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hurricane </strong><em>— n. </em>an extremely large, powerful, and destructive storm with very strong winds that occurs especially in the western part of the Atlantic Ocean</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scale </strong><em>— n. </em>a device that is used for weighing people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>proportion </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount that is a part of a whole</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>isolated </strong><em>— adj. </em>happening just once</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>author </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who has written something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surge </strong><em>— v. </em>to suddenly increase to an unusually high level</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mexico Becomes Leading Source of Goods Imported to US  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/mexico-becomes-leading-source-of-goods-imported-to-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico took China's place as the leading source of goods imported by the United States.</p>
<p>This change, which took place over the last year, brings attention to the growing tensions between the U.S. and China. It also <strong>highlights</strong> American efforts to import from countries that are friendlier and closer to home.</p>
<p>Figures released recently by the U.S. Commerce Department show that the value of goods imported by the U.S. from Mexico rose nearly 5 percent from 2022 to 2023, to more than $475 billion. At the same time, the value of Chinese imports dropped 20 percent to $427 billion.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman works in a shoe maquiladora or factory in Leon, Mexico, Feb. 7, 2023. For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico overtook China as America's top supplier of goods. (AP Photo/Mario Armas, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0865-08dc28e44082_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman works in a shoe maquiladora or factory in Leon, Mexico, Feb. 7, 2023. For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico overtook China as America's top supplier of goods. (AP Photo/Mario Armas, File)</span></div>
<p>The last time that Mexican goods imported by the United States were greater than the value of China's imports was in 2002.</p>
<p>Economic relations between the United States and China have declined in recent years.</p>
<p>The Trump administration began putting <strong>tariffs</strong> on Chinese imports in 2018. The administration argued that China's trade policies broke international trade rules. President Joe Biden kept those taxes on imports after taking office in 2021, making clear that opposition toward China would be a rare area of common ground for Democrats and Republicans.</p>
<p>Instead of sending production to China, which U.S. corporations had long done, the Biden administration has urged companies to seek suppliers in allied countries, in a process called "friend-shoring," or to return manufacturing to the United States in a process called "reshoring." Supply-chain problems related to the COVID-19 pandemic also led U.S. companies to seek supplies closer to the United States in a process called "near-shoring."</p>
<p>Mexico has been among those helped by the growing move away from Chinese factories. But the picture is more complex than it might seem.</p>
<p>Some Chinese manufacturers have established factories in Mexico to get the <strong>benefits</strong> of the 3-year-old U.S.-Mexico-Canada Trade Agreement. The agreement permits duty-free trade in North America for many products.</p>
<p>Mexican President Andrés Manuel López Obrador said last week that the trade deal gives Mexico new power. He said it would make it hard for the U.S. to close the two countries' border to limit immigration, as suggested in negotiations on a border bill in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>"The negotiation is proposing closing the border," he said. "Do you think Americans, or Mexicans, but especially the Americans, would approve that? The businesses wouldn't take it, maybe one day, but not a week."</p>
<p>Some industries — especially car manufacturers — have set up plants on both sides of the border. These plants depend on each other for a steady supply of parts.</p>
<p>Derek Scissors, a China specialist at the American Enterprise Institute, noted that the biggest drops in Chinese imports were in computers and electronics and chemicals and pharmaceuticals — all politically difficult areas.</p>
<p>"I don't see the U.S. being comfortable with a<strong> rebound </strong>in those areas in 2024 and 2025," Scissors said, predicting that the China-Mexico reversal on imports to the United States likely "is not a one-year<strong> blip</strong>.''</p>
<p>Scissors suggested that the drop in U.S. use of Chinese goods partly suggests concerns about China's economic policies under President Xi Jinping. Xi's COVID-19 lockdowns brought large parts of the Chinese economy to a halt in 2022. And his officials have raided foreign companies in possible counterespionage investigations.</p>
<p>"I think it's corporate America <strong>belatedly</strong> deciding Xi Jinping is <strong>unreliable</strong>," Scissors added.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Paul Wiseman reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>highlight </strong><em>– v. </em>to direct attention to (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>tariff<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> a tax on goods coming into or leaving a country</p>
<p><strong>benefit </strong><em>– n.</em> a good or helpful result or effect</p>
<p><strong>rebound</strong> –<em> n.</em> an increase after a decline</p>
<p><strong>blip </strong><em>– n.</em> something that is unimportant or that does not last a long time</p>
<p><strong>belatedly </strong><em>– adv.</em> happening or coming very late</p>
<p><strong>unreliable</strong> <em>– adj.</em> not believable or trustworthy</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australia to Introduce ‘Right to Disconnect’ Law for Workers  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/australia-to-introduce-right-to-disconnect-law-for-workers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Australia's parliament seems likely to pass a new "right to disconnect" bill that the federal government has proposed.</p>
<p>The law would prevent employers from asking their workers to keep their phones and computers turned on outside of work hours. Employers who ask employees to do so could be <strong>fined</strong>.</p>
<p>The aim is to protect workers' rights and improve <strong>work-life balance</strong> in the country.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Surfers prepare to enter the water at Bondi beach near Sydney, Australia on April 28, 2020. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cf3ed1dc-9401-4543-9aae-f3a84a8d4922_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Surfers prepare to enter the water at Bondi beach near Sydney, Australia on April 28, 2020. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)</span></div>
<p>Similar laws are already in place in France, Spain and other European nations.</p>
<p>Australia's employment minister, Tony Burke, said most lawmakers have expressed support for the bill.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese discussed the proposed law on Wednesday.</p>
<p>"What we are simply saying is that someone who isn't being paid 24 hours a day shouldn't be penalized if they're not online and available 24 hours a day," he said.</p>
<p>The bill also includes rules that will give temporary workers guidelines about how to move into permanent work.</p>
<p>Adam Bandt is the leader of the left-wing Greens. He said his party supports the law. So do leaders of the Labor party and other smaller parliamentary groups.</p>
<p>Some politicians, however, warned that a new labor law would hurt Australia's ability to be competitive with other nations. The critics also say making a new labor law might make it difficult for employees who want to work <strong>flexible</strong> hours.</p>
<p>Bandt said Australians work an average of six unpaid weeks each year. He said that totals about $60 billion of unpaid <strong>wages</strong>.</p>
<p>"That time is yours," he said, "not your boss's."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fine </strong>–n. a financial penalty</p>
<p><strong>work-life balance </strong>–n. the idea that people should be able to spend their free time without having to think about work</p>
<p><strong>flexible </strong>–adj. something that is not tightly controlled</p>
<p><strong>wage </strong>–n. the money a person is paid for their work</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
