<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>New COVID-19 Variant Expands Internationally  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/new-covid-19-variant-expands-internationally.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>International health officials are closely following a new version of COVID-19 as it spreads to more countries.</p>
<p>The version, or variant, is called BA.2.86. Officials from the World Health Organization (WHO) say it has already been identified in several countries, including the United States, Switzerland, South Africa, Israel, Denmark and Britain.</p>
<p>WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus recently spoke to reporters about the latest COVID-19 developments. He said the new COVID-19 variants show that the virus remains a health threat around the world.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, a student at the University of Pennsylvania's Perelman School of Medicine in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania demonstrates a viral RNA extraction on December 16, 2021. (REUTERS/Hannah Beier)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a292-08dba9a08485_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, a student at the University of Pennsylvania's Perelman School of Medicine in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania demonstrates a viral RNA extraction on December 16, 2021. (REUTERS/Hannah Beier)</span></div>
<p>Tedros noted the latest data show that COVID-19 infections and hospitalizations are decreasing. But he added that the agency had seen "increasing reports of hospitalizations, ICU admissions and deaths in some countries." ICU is a short form for the term intensive care unit, part of a hospital that cares for very sick patients.</p>
<p>Maria Van Kerkhove is with the WHO's Health Emergencies Program. She said that, as of last week, only about 10 cases of the BA.2.86 variant had been found worldwide. But Van Kerkhove added that health officials are worried because the variant appears to have more than 30 genetic <strong>mutations</strong>.</p>
<p>She said the WHO is currently trying to closely follow the movements of the latest virus variants. The efforts include taking wastewater <strong>samples</strong> from different cities to follow where COVID-19 is spreading. In addition, such methods can help officials learn how fast current variants are spreading and how severe they are. "Governments cannot <strong>drop the ball</strong>," Van Kerkhove said.</p>
<p>Health officials say BA.2.86 broke off from the Omicron variant, which has been spreading in the U.S. at least since last year. It was first discovered in Denmark on July 24.</p>
<p>Some international scientists have said that while it is important to keep following BA.2.86, the variant was unlikely to cause a new, harmful wave of infections. This is because much of the population has built up defenses against COVID-19 because of vaccinations or previous infection.</p>
<p><strong>Testing new vaccines</strong></p>
<p>Scientists are currently testing how effective newly created COVID-19 vaccines will work against BA.2.86. Van Kerkhove noted that in the past, vaccines have been better at preventing severe sickness and death than blocking re-infections. U.S. health officials said earlier this month the latest COVID-19 vaccines are set to be released sometime in September.</p>
<p>The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) completed a risk report on the new variant last week. The report said BA.2.86 may be capable of causing infection in vaccinated people and those who had COVID-19 before. But officials noted there is so far no evidence that the new variant is causing more severe sickness than earlier ones.</p>
<p>The WHO said COVID-19 testing has dropped by 90 percent worldwide from the highest point of the pandemic. Testing rates have also fallen sharply in the U.S., and genetic <strong>sequencing</strong> is down by around 90 percent, said Dr. Ashish Jha. He served as the White House COVID-19 Response Coordinator until June 2023.</p>
<p>Jha said data from hospital stays, emergency room visits, deaths, wastewater testing and sequencing efforts had given health officials improved information about current virus spread.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and the Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mutate </strong><em>– v. </em>to cause a gene to change and create an unusual characteristic in a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of something that gives you information about the thing it was taken from</p>
<p><strong>drop the ball </strong><em>– idiom</em> to make a mistake, especially by not taking action or dealing with something that should have planned for</p>
<p><strong>sequence </strong><em>– v. </em>to combine things in a particular order, or discover the order in which they are expressed</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>West Virginia University to Cut Languages, Creative Programs  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/west-virginia-university-to-cut-languages-creative-programs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>School leaders at West Virginia University recently proposed cutting almost 10 percent of the university's study programs and over 100 educators because of a $45 million budget deficit.</p>
<p>Included in the cuts were study programs, known as majors, in world languages, art history, jazz performance, creative writing, and degrees in math and education.</p>
<p>The languages include Chinese, French, German, Russian and Spanish. In addition, professors leading programs in <strong>linguistics </strong>and TESOL could be cut.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="West Virginia University students lead a protest against cuts to programs in world languages, creative writing and more amid a $45 million budget deficit outside Stewart Hall in Morgantown, W.Va., on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Leah Willingham)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c8e5aca3-3485-4dcf-bdb7-8abf9ca4cd6c_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">West Virginia University students lead a protest against cuts to programs in world languages, creative writing and more amid a $45 million budget deficit outside Stewart Hall in Morgantown, W.Va., on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Leah Willingham)</span></div>
<p><strong>‘Emotions are high'</strong></p>
<p>The university's Office of the Provost considered "several key <strong>metrics</strong>" to reduce or eliminate majors. The metrics included: the number of students interested in the majors, the <strong>ratio</strong> of students to professors in the program, the amount of money the programs bring to the school, and the future research plans each program had.</p>
<p>WVU released its plan in early August. The school permitted the affected programs to appeal the university's decision. The cuts resulted in a large protest on August 21.</p>
<p>The provost, one of the university's top leaders, is Maryanne Reed. At a meeting during the protests, she called the time "incredibly <strong>stressful</strong>," and noted, "emotions are very high right now."</p>
<p>The university's final plan will be announced in the middle of September.</p>
<p><strong>Appeal results</strong></p>
<p>The World Languages department appealed WVU's proposal on August 25, asking the university to reconsider part of its plan.</p>
<p>Lisa Di Bartolomeo is one of the professors in the department. She also attended the university as a student.</p>
<p>Before the appeal, she told VOA that cutting foreign language instruction would hurt students from West Virginia when they look for jobs. She said it would hurt their career earnings and hurt elementary and high school-aged children in West Virginia who depend on language teachers trained at WVU.</p>
<p>"The best and the brightest students don't see a future for themselves in West Virginia."</p>
<p>On August 29, WVU said it planned to follow through with much of its proposal. It is likely to cut all language majors but continue some teaching in both Spanish and Chinese. The university said it is important to continue with those languages because Spanish is in "high demand" and Chinese is a "critical need."</p>
<p>Reed said the university will remove a foreign language study requirement for students seeking Bachelor of Arts degrees. The university said it will work to support students who are interested in "<strong>immersive</strong> (language) experiences" through study abroad programs.</p>
<p><strong>Poor planning?</strong></p>
<p>Those who run the school are concerned about the state's decreasing population and the decreasing number of college-aged students. West Virginia is the only state in the U.S. with a population that is lower today than it was in 1950.</p>
<p>WVU has about 27,000 students. About 25,000 are at its main campus in Morgantown. That number is 10 percent lower than it was in 2015. That means the school takes in less money from students and taxpayers.</p>
<p>The population loss is one reason for the university's financial problems. New student housing and new academic buildings meant for a growing number of students are empty today.</p>
<p>E. Gordon Gee, the university president, said the cuts are needed so WVU can be "a competitive university on the national stage." He said the school is not taking its reduction proposal lightly. University leaders say study programs and professors are not all that are being cut.</p>
<p><strong>International students affected</strong></p>
<p>Among the 27,000 students at WVU, there are about 1,000 international students. Some of them are studying in the programs that might be <strong>eliminated</strong>. All of them will be permitted to finish their degrees. But no new students will come into the eliminated programs. That process is called a "teach out."</p>
<p>VOA Learning English spoke with two international students who are worried about their study programs: Jose Ramirez is a music and higher education graduate student from Colombia. Winda Melati is a higher education <strong>graduate</strong> student from Indonesia.</p>
<p>Ramirez also is a graduate of WVU's world languages program: he studied German.</p>
<p>He said the plan to take away most language teaching is "sad," and he wondered if the university no longer sees language learning as important.</p>
<p>Ramirez said:</p>
<p>"And it's also showing... like kind of the mentality of a lot of English speakers is that they don't need to learn another language because everybody (else) will learn English."</p>
<p>Melati said she is concerned for herself and other students who are in the U.S. on F-1, or student visas. Some, she noted, planned to stay at WVU to continue teaching or studying after completing their degrees. Now they may have to change their plans because of the cuts.</p>
<p>Melati and Ramirez both expressed concern about the programs and the value of their degrees if they are cut. Melati asked: "How can I be proud of (my work) if I graduate from a program that is no longer there?"</p>
<p>Ramirez said he feels lucky that he was able to study at WVU, but he feels sad that future students will not get the same instruction he did. They worry international students will not come to WVU after learning of the cuts.</p>
<p>But, Henry Oliver of the university's global affairs office believes the university will still appeal to international students.</p>
<p>"WVU has a really long-standing history and appeal for international students. And to be honest, I don't expect that to change."</p>
<p>He noted that popular WVU programs are safe. He listed most science, technology, engineering, math and business study programs. "These programs are still things that remain very strong at WVU and will continue to be strong," Oliver said.</p>
<p><strong>A compromise ahead?</strong></p>
<p>Many who are protesting the reductions say they would have liked to see the university do more to talk with professors, students, employees and West Virginians before announcing the cuts.</p>
<p>Both Di Bartolomeo and Ramirez are afraid there was not enough input from students, parents and graduates.</p>
<p>And Ramirez said, even with the appeal process, he believes most decisions have already been made.</p>
<p>"I would like to be wrong, but I think that everything is ... they are just seeing the numbers and the numbers are not making it."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell reported this story for Learning English with additional reporting from the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>linguistics </strong><em>–n.</em> the study of how languages work</p>
<p><strong>metric </strong><em>–n.</em> a tool for measuring something, especially something's value<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>ratio </strong><em>–n.</em> the relationship that exists between two values which can be expressed as two numbers</p>
<p><strong>stressful </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing worry or fear</p>
<p><strong>immersive </strong><em>–adj.</em> a method involving being completely surrounded by a language in an effort to learn it</p>
<p><strong>eliminated</strong><em>—adj.</em> having been removed or ended</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong><em>–adj</em>. having already graduated from undergraduate schooling</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Explore from Your 'Armchair'  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/explore-from-your-armchair.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a piece of <strong>furniture</strong> used for sitting. As the name suggests, an armchair has extensions for resting your arms. So, armchairs are more <strong>comfortable</strong> than other chairs. In fact, they are so comfortable that people sit in them for hours.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pictured here is an traditional style armchair in front of some bookshelves." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-936e-08dbaa5c816c_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pictured here is an traditional style armchair in front of some bookshelves.</span></div>
<p>Besides being a kind of furniture, Americans use the word "armchair" in front of other words. They do this to describe different sorts of people and the experiences they might or might not have.</p>
<p>For example, some experiences can be called <strong>vicarious</strong>. If you live vicariously, you experience things through other people. You do not actually do the thing you are interested in yourself. Rather, you enjoy the activity by watching or reading about what others do.</p>
<p><u>Armchair detectives</u> are not real detectives investigating crimes. An armchair detective enjoys reading detective novels or watching true crime shows. Armchair detectives may even try to solve a crime. But all their efforts are done from the safety and comfort<strong> </strong>of their homes.</p>
<p>Living vicariously through others can be a wonderful chance to escape. Let's say you do not have the time or money to travel. But you still want to experience the pleasure of traveling. You can read about places that you would like to visit. You can watch travel <strong>documentaries</strong> about them too. And you can do these things from the comfort<strong> </strong>of your own home. So, you could call yourself an <u>armchair traveler. </u></p>
<p>If you enjoy watching and reading about people who do dangerous activities -- such as climbing Mount Everest or free diving into the depths of the ocean -- you might be an <u>armchair adventurer</u>.</p>
<p>However, we also use "armchair" to describe another sort of person. If someone does not have responsibility for a job but talks about it from a distance, we can use the word "armchair" to describe them. Also, if someone is not an expert in a subject, but gives advice anyway, we could use the word "armchair."</p>
<p>For example, an armchair <u><strong>strategist</strong></u> gives strategies that are more <strong>theoretical</strong> than <strong>practical</strong>. This means they are talking about a problem but are not actually involved in solving it.</p>
<p>In the same way, an <u>armchair general</u> gives advice on going into battle ... from a safe distance. Armchair generals are not involved in a real battle.</p>
<p>In the U.S., a favorite term comes from American football. <u>Armchair quarterbacks</u> comment on a football game from the comfort of their own chair. They criticize and insult the players who actually play the game while they themselves have never played it.</p>
<p>But the use of the term "armchair quarterback" goes far beyond the world of sports. So, you could hear the term used to describe anyone who does not do an activity or have responsibility but still makes sharp comments or criticizes others who work at the job every day.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>furniture </strong>–n. things found in the room of a home or business such as chairs, tables, sofas, and shelves</p>
<p><strong>comfortable </strong>–adj. causing a feeling of ease and enjoyment and not pain</p>
<p><strong>vicarious </strong>–adj. something that is not felt by oneself but through others</p>
<p><strong>documentary </strong>–n. a kind of movie that tells a real story and that does not use actors but real people</p>
<p><strong>strategist </strong>–n. a person who is skilled at making detailed plans to reach goals that extend over a long period of time</p>
<p><strong>theoretical </strong>–adj. having to do with the theory of how something should work rather than how people know something works</p>
<p><strong>practical </strong>–adj. having to do with reality rather than what is possible in the future or imaginary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Woodrow Wilson: Idealist  (2023/9/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-president-woodrow-wilson.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Woodrow Wilson. He served two terms, from 1913 to 1921, and led the United States through the first World War.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Woodrow Wilson" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/92cf1972-5ba1-4b76-a2d3-807f2f365994_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Woodrow Wilson</span></div>
<p>Wilson might have seemed an unlikely war president. He was a university professor before he entered politics.</p>
<p>And, when the conflict began in Europe in 1914, Wilson strongly rejected the idea of the U.S. getting involved. He even campaigned for his second term on the slogan "He kept us out of the war."</p>
<p>But Wilson's idealism eventually made him believe the U.S. must enter the conflict. He famously said, "The world must be safe for democracy."</p>
<p>He spent the last months of his presidency fighting to create a league of nations that would prevent future wars.</p>
<p>Wilson did not succeed in that effort. But the effects of his presidency are still seen today in both the domestic and foreign affairs of the United States.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Woodrow Wilson was born in the state of Virginia in 1856 and grew up in the South.</p>
<p>Wilson's father was a Protestant Christian minister who supported the views of the Confederacy during the Civil War.</p>
<p>Wilson's mother had been born in England but raised in the United States. She was reportedly warm and loving, especially to her husband and four children.</p>
<p>Wilson's early life was marked by poor health and a passion for learning. His education included tutoring by Confederate soldiers, classes with his father, a year at Davidson College, a bachelor's degree from the school now called Princeton, one year of law school, and a doctoral degree in history and political science from the University of Johns Hopkins.</p>
<p>He remains, so far, the only president with a Ph.D.</p>
<p>Wilson's academic interests were in government, and how it could be most effective. Even as a young man, he supported the idea of a strong executive, either a prime minister or a president.</p>
<p>He wrote a number of books, including a biography of George Washington, and a history of the United States. He also taught popular classes at several colleges, including Bryn Mawr in Pennsylvania, Wesleyan in Connecticut, and Princeton in New Jersey.</p>
<p>In time, Wilson became the president of Princeton. He made major reforms to the school until some faculty and alumni resisted his efforts.</p>
<p>Wilson had always been interested in political power. The Democratic Party in New Jersey became interested in Wilson when they were looking for a candidate with an honest public image.</p>
<p>In truth, party officials believed he would be a weak leader whom they could influence. Wilson surprised them by winning the seat as New Jersey governor easily, and then rejecting their efforts to control him.</p>
<p>He went on to pass major reform legislation in New Jersey that reduced corruption and protected the rights of workers. His actions drew the attention of Democratic Party leaders seeking a candidate for president in 1912.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: first term</strong></p>
<p>Voters did not overwhelmingly choose Wilson in 1912. Although he did well in the Electoral College, he earned only a little more than 40 percent of the popular vote. Other votes were mostly divided between two former presidents, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-theodore-roosevelt/3986653.html" target="_blank">Theodore Roosevelt</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americans-presidents-william-taft/3997949.html" target="_blank">William Taft</a>.</p>
<p>Yet Wilson quickly <strong>asserted</strong> authority over Congress and pushed through a number of laws aimed at dramatic reform.</p>
<p>Historian Kendrick Clements at the University of South Carolina <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/wilson/domestic-affairs">says</a> Wilson had a strongly progressive vision.</p>
<p>He was interested in "expanding economic <strong>opportunity</strong> for people at the bottom of society and <strong>eliminating</strong> special <strong>privileges</strong> enjoyed by the richest and most powerful members of society."</p>
<p>One of Wilson's most important acts was to create a new federal agency called the Federal Reserve Board. It still <strong>regulates</strong> American banks, credit, and money supply. He also created the Federal Trade Commission to ensure fair business practices, and the Department of Labor to protect workers' rights.</p>
<p>And he supported laws to reduce working hours for railroad employees, bar child labor, and offer government loans to farmers.</p>
<p>But even during Wilson's busy lawmaking, the threat of world war demanded his attention. Wilson had declared that the U.S. would remain neutral in the growing conflict between the Allied and Central Powers.</p>
<p>One of his reasons was that people in the U.S. were immigrants from the countries that were at war. Wilson did not want the conflict to divide Americans.</p>
<p>However, he permitted international trade, including with Britain and France. As a result, many believed the U.S. was favoring those countries.</p>
<p>In 1915, a German submarine sank a British ship called the Lusitania and killed more than 100 Americans on board.</p>
<p>Wilson protested several times to Germany about the sinking. He warned that the U.S. would not accept another such aggression. But two years later, Germany attacked U.S. <strong>commercial</strong> ships. It also invited Mexico to enter into an alliance against the United States.</p>
<p>At the beginning of Wilson's second term in office, he asked Congress to declare war on Germany.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency: second term</strong></p>
<p>The U.S. entered World War I on the side of the Allied Powers. The additional support came at an important time. American soldiers were able to help resist German troops in France.</p>
<p>In time, Germany asked for an <strong>armistice </strong>– an agreement to stop fighting.</p>
<p>Following the war, Wilson had a grand vision for how to gain lasting peace in Europe. In a speech known as "<a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/wilson-outlines-the-fourteen-points">Fourteen Points</a>," he proposed that the countries that had won the war not punish Germany.</p>
<p>Wilson also wanted European colonies to rule themselves, and other areas be given immediate independence.</p>
<p>Most importantly, Wilson suggested a League of Nations that would guarantee the member countries' independence and safety.</p>
<p>But few world leaders agreed with his plan completely.</p>
<p>Even in the U.S., many Republican lawmakers in Congress resisted Wilson's idea for a League of Nations. Some strongly objected to any treaty that would limit the country's independence. Others did not want the country to be involved in world issues at all.So Wilson began a trip across the U.S. to raise public support for the League of Nations. He traveled more than 15,000 kilometers in 22 days and gave 29 speeches.</p>
<p>Wilson's doctors warned him that the trip was hard on his health. But Wilson was firm about pressuring Senate Republicans to adopt the agreement.</p>
<p>Finally, he collapsed from <strong>exhaustion</strong>. Shortly after, he suffered a major stroke. Although he recovered somewhat, he remained partly <strong>paralyzed</strong>. He rarely appeared in public again.Instead, Wilson communicated to Congress through his wife. When Republicans changed the treaty to deal with their concerns, Wilson told his supporters to reject it.</p>
<p>In the end, the U.S. never did join the League of Nations.</p>
<p>When a new president, Warren Harding, was sworn-in in 1921, Edith and Woodrow Wilson retired to a house in Washington, D.C. Three years later, the former president died quietly there, finally at peace.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Caty Weaver was the editor. </em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>assert </strong>— <em>v. </em>to demand that other people accept or respect (something)</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>— <em>n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>eliminate</strong> — <em>v. </em>to remove; to get rid of</p>
<p><strong>privilege</strong> - <em>n. </em>a right or benefit that is given to some people and not to others</p>
<p><strong>regulate</strong> -<em> v. </em>to make rules or laws that control (something)</p>
<p><strong>commercial</strong> - <em>adj. </em>related to or used in the buying and selling of goods and services</p>
<p><strong>armistice</strong> -<em> n. </em>an agreement to stop fighting a war</p>
<p><strong>exhaustion</strong> -<em> n.</em> the state of being extremely tired</p>
<p><strong>paralyzed</strong> - <em>adj. </em>unable to move or feel all or part of the body</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Abandoned Village Is a Reminder of Fast-changing UAE  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/abandoned-village-is-a-reminder-of-fast-changing-uae.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>About an hour's drive from the tall buildings of Dubai is an empty village in the sands of the United Arab Emirates. It stands as a <strong>reminder</strong> of how fast the Middle Eastern country is changing.</p>
<p>Built in the 1970s, the village of al-Ghuraifa was left empty twenty years later. Oil wealth has turned the UAE, home to the cities of Dubai and Abu Dhabi, into an international center of commerce and <strong>tourism</strong>.</p>
<p>In recent years, the empty village near the town of al-Madam in the Sharjah emirate has become more popular with visitors.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A house's entrance gate is buried under the sand at the Bedouin village of al-Ghuraifabout 100 km, 62 miles, southeast of Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/31efa6d1-767b-4fb3-9828-2e3bf75bda2c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A house's entrance gate is buried under the sand at the Bedouin village of al-Ghuraifabout 100 km, 62 miles, southeast of Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, Sunday, July 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)</span></div>
<p>The village, made up of two rows of homes and a religious center, "can teach us a lot of the modern history of the UAE," said Ahmad Sukkar of the University of Sharjah. Sukkar is part of a team studying the area.</p>
<p>Al-Ghuraifa was built as part of a public housing project after the 1971 establishment of the United Arab Emirates, a group of seven sheikhdoms. The discovery of oil 13 years earlier was just starting to reshape the country.</p>
<p>The village housed around 100 members of the al-Ketbi tribe, Sukkar said. They were one of several Bedouin groups that until then had led a semi-<strong>nomadic</strong> existence. They raised animals, traveled among the desert <strong>oases</strong> and visited Dubai and Abu Dhabi when they were small towns.</p>
<p>The modern cement houses were built with local details to ease the change to settled life. The inside walls were brightly colored, and some had <strong>mosaics</strong>. The homes also had spaces where village leaders could gather locals for meetings. One house had special paper known as wallpaper showing a land with green plants and trees - a big difference from the sandy environment outside.</p>
<p>It is unclear what exactly caused people to leave just twenty years after the homes were built. Some say that they were driven away by evil spirits. But Sukkar says it is more likely that people left to seek a better life in the UAE's fast-growing cities.</p>
<p>The village had limited electricity and water, and was often hit by sandstorms. Families would have also had to deal with long traveling times across the desert to reach government jobs and schools in Dubai.</p>
<p>Now, the desert is slowly taking back the village. Sand has blown into the homes. Only the religious center, or mosque, remains as it was, thanks to regular cleaning by workers from nearby al-Madam.</p>
<p>Some <strong>descendants</strong> of the camel-mounted Bedouin who once traveled the desert sands still live in the Emirates' rural areas. However, many now live in cities with tall buildings, large shopping centers, and modern roads.</p>
<p>Foreign nationals make up the majority of the UAE's population, and some have taken an interest in its history. It is also a place for them to record music videos and social media posts. On a recent day, groups of visitors walked through the abandoned village.</p>
<p>"I wonder why they left," said Nitin Panchal, an Indian living in the UAE. "Could it be a <strong>genie</strong>," could it be "black magic?" Panchal asked. "We'll never know."</p>
<p>The local government recently installed fencing along with a security gate, waste containers and a parking lot. Officials made the changes because past visitors had caused damage to the village.</p>
<p>The new measures have taken some of the mystery from the village.</p>
<p>Danny Booth is from the Isle of Man, a British Crown Dependency in the Irish Sea. He said he had decided to "come and have a look before things start to change here."</p>
<p>"Sometimes these places are better left<strong> undisturbed</strong>, as they lose their <strong>charm</strong> when they become crowded," he said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Nick El Hajj reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>reminder</strong><em> -- n. </em>something that causes you to remember or to think about something</p>
<p><strong>tourism </strong><em>-- n. </em>the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>nomadic </strong>– adj. describes a member of a group of people who move from place to place</p>
<p><strong>oasis</strong> – n. an area in a desert where there is water and plants</p>
<p><strong>mosaic </strong>– n. a decoration on a surface made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material that then hardens to make pictures or patterns</p>
<p><strong>descendant </strong>– n. someone who is related to a person or group of people who lived in the past</p>
<p><strong>genie</strong> – n. a magic spirit that looks like a person and often lives in a lamp or bottle</p>
<p><strong>undisturbed </strong><em>-- adj. </em>not changed or touched by anyone or anything</p>
<p><strong>charm </strong><em>-- n. </em>an attractive quality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Cities Answer Some Emergency Calls with Mental Health Teams  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-cities-use-mental-health-teams-for-emergency-calls.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Clear Creek County in Colorado is one of the latest places to begin using mental health teams to answer some emergency 911 calls.<br/>
<br/>
Mental health response teams are not new. Many large cities put such teams in place after the killing of George Floyd during his arrest by police in Minneapolis in 2020.<br/>
</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - WellPower clinician Jane Lemaux loads supplies into a STAR van in Denver on Oct. 20, 2022. The STAR program uses clinicians and EMTs or paramedics to respond to nonviolent mental health crises, instead of police. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-eff8-08dba98a290d_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - WellPower clinician Jane Lemaux loads supplies into a STAR van in Denver on Oct. 20, 2022. The STAR program uses clinicians and EMTs or paramedics to respond to nonviolent mental health crises, instead of police. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)</span></div>
Some people believe mental health response teams might be more successful in answering some emergency 911 calls than police. The job of a mental health worker is to help people who have emotional problems or mental sickness. The job of the police is to enforce laws. They are not trained to treat mental health conditions.<br/>
<br/>
In Clear Creek County, the case of Christian Glass received a lot of attention. News reports said Glass called the 911 emergency phone number when his car got <strong>stuck</strong> on the roadside. Police answered the call, but Glass refused to get out of his car.<br/>
<br/>
Later, the police broke the car window. Glass threatened them with a small knife. He was then shot and killed by police. The lawyer for Glass's parents said he was having a mental health crisis. He believed that <strong>supernatural</strong> beings meant to harm him.<br/>
<br/>
After legal action, Clear Creak County agreed to pay $19 million as a result of the case and two officers face criminal charges.<p></p>
<p>New York City officials said mental health response teams resolve half of their calls by talking to people or taking them to social services or community health centers. However, the Associated Press (AP) reported that workers for the city's mental health crisis program, called B-HEARD, have had difficulty dealing with the number of calls and cases. The program answered about two percent of the 171,000 calls throughout the city in 2022.<br/>
<br/>
Carleigh Sailon was a mental health response team supervisor who used to work in a program in Denver, Colorado. She said mental health teams aim to meet the needs of the community and send the right experts to solve the problems.<br/>
<br/>
Mental health teams may also have more time to spend in response to an emergency call than police. That could be a reason that mental health response teams might be more successful than police in answering some 911 calls.<br/>
<br/>
For example, a mental health team responded to a 911 call about a homeless man in Denver, Colorado. The team spent three hours helping the man get a form of identification, food, and medications. They also took him to a shelter designed to house homeless people. Police might spend 10 to 90 minutes on a call.<br/>
<br/>
This would not be long enough to help a homeless person.<br/>
<br/>
At least 14 of America's 20 biggest cities are using mental health teams to answer some emergency 911 calls. New York City, Los Angeles; Houston, Texas; and Columbus, Ohio, spent almost $125 million on their programs. Smaller cities are also starting to use the teams.<br/>
<br/>
The AP reports that federal government information is incomplete on how effective mental health response teams are. But a recent study of a mental health response program in Denver from Stanford University suggested they have good results. The 2022 study found that, in some Denver neighborhoods where the programs were in place, few small crimes were reported while violent crimes remained unchanged.<br/>
<br/>
At a conference discussing mental health teams in Washington, D.C. this spring, officials from several cities discussed using mental health response teams. They said they faced difficulties in finding enough trained mental health workers, training workers at 911 call centers and sending unarmed civilians into situations that could be dangerous.<br/>
<br/>
However, an official for New York's B-HEARD program believes the effort is important.<br/>
<br/>
Laquisha Grant is with the New York Mayor's Office of Community Mental Health. She said, "We really think that every single B-HEARD response is just a better way that we, the city, are providing care to people."<br/>
<br/>
I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
<br/>
<em>Gena Bennett adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English with the addition of other sources.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>stuck</strong> –adj. unable to move; trapped in a spot or place</p>
<p><strong>supernatural</strong> –n. unable to be explained by science or laws; seeming to come from something beyond this world</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cheer vs. Applause  (2023/9/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/cheer-vs-applause.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "cheers" and "applause."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA Learning English,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6e7a-08dba9a1a624_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I am Sina from Iran. I have been learning English with your app for two years. I have a question:</p>
<p>What is the difference between "cheers" and "applause?"</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for writing to us, Sina.</p>
<p>These two words can mean to express approval or excitement, but the way that these feelings are expressed is a little different.</p>
<p>Cheering uses your voice, and applauding uses your hands to clap and make a sound. But let's look a little closer at each.</p>
<p><em>"I live for the applause-plause, live for the applause-plause, live for the-</em></p>
<p><em>Way that you cheer and<strong> scream</strong> for me</em></p>
<p><em>The applause, applause, applause..." </em></p>
<p>"Applause" is a noun that has two meanings. The first meaning is the approval or excitement marked by clapping hands together. The second meaning is the show of approval through<strong> praise</strong> or vocalizing.</p>
<p>Lady Gaga sang that she lives for the applause of her fans.</p>
<p>"Applaud" is the verb form and also has two meanings. When you applaud something, you are showing your approval or excitement by clapping your hands together. The verb can either take a direct object or not.</p>
<p><em>The crowd applauded the dancers during the show.</em></p>
<p><em>The <strong>audience</strong> applauded after the musical performance.</em></p>
<p>The second meaning of "applaud" is to praise or say that you like or agree with something that a person has done.</p>
<p><em>My professor applauded my work this year.</em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "cheer."</p>
<p>Much like "applaud," "cheer" as a verb means to show approval or excitement by vocalizing or shouting.</p>
<p><em>Parents cheered on their children at the soccer game.</em></p>
<p>To "cheer" also means to perform the act of cheerleading. Cheerleaders are people who lead the crowds at sporting events through cheering and applauding the teams. They encourage their team to win.</p>
<p><em>Kirstin cheered in school for the basketball team.</em></p>
<p>As a verb, "cheer" also means to be cheerful or to make glad or happy. We often use this verb with the preposition "up" in the command, "Cheer up!"</p>
<p><em>You look so unhappy, cheer up!</em></p>
<p><em>He cheered his girlfriend up with flowers.</em></p>
<p>Cheer is also a noun, and its meanings are closely related to the verb form.</p>
<p>"Cheer" is a shout of approval or excitement.</p>
<p><em>The cheers of the crowd grew louder as the football team started winning.</em></p>
<p>"Cheer" is the sport or activity of cheerleading.</p>
<p><em>There are different kinds of shoes needed in cheer depending on what position you are in.</em></p>
<p>"Cheer" also has other meanings as a noun, such as a mood or feeling, gladness or joy, or encouragement.</p>
<p><em>Holidays are a time for good cheer and making memories with family.</em></p>
<p>And we often say "cheers" before eating or drinking at a party or social gathering.</p>
<p><em>Cheers to the happy couple on their wedding day.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Sina.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scream </strong><em>– v.</em> to shout or cry out</p>
<p><strong>praise </strong><em>– n. </em>spoken or written words about the good qualities of someone or something: an expression of approval for someone or something</p>
<p><strong>audience </strong>– <em>n</em>. people who gather to watch a performance</p>
<p><em>Do you have a question for the teacher? We want to hear from you. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Activists Campaign against Rich Lifestyles  (2023/9/1) | 环保人士抨击富豪生活方式</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/climate-activists-campaign-against-rich-lifestyles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Climate activists have spray painted a boat, blocked private planes from taking off and covered holes in golf courses over the summer.<br/>
今年夏天，气候活动人士向一艘船泼油漆，阻止私人飞机起飞，并填平了高尔夫球场的球洞。</p>
<p>These actions are part of a campaign against the lifestyles of very rich people who, the activists say, release a lot of carbon pollution into the atmosphere.<br/>
这些行动是反对超级富豪生活方式运动的一部分，活动人士称这些人向大气中释放了大量碳污染。</p>
<p>As flooding, storms, and wildfires take place around the world, climate activists have also turned to new measures to call attention to these bad weather events. Some activists glued themselves to a road in Germany. Others threw soup on a Vincent van Gogh painting in Britain. They caused delays in sporting events including a Formula One Grand Prix racecar competition and the Tour de France bicycle race.<br/>
随着洪水、风暴和野火在世界各地发生，气候活动家也转向了新的措施，以引起人们对这些恶劣天气事件的关注。一些激进分子把自己粘在德国的一条路上。有人在英国向文森特·梵高的画作泼汤。他们导致了包括一级方程式大奖赛和环法自行车赛在内的体育赛事延误。</p>
<p>Now, they are turning their attention to rich people after targeting oil and gas companies and businesses that invest in fossil fuels.<br/>
他们在瞄准石油和天然气公司以及投资化石燃料的企业后，现在又将注意力转向了富豪。</p>
<p>"We do not point the finger at the people but at their lifestyle, the injustice it represents," said Karen Killeen. She was protesting in Ibiza, Spain, a popular summer place for the wealthy.<br/>
克伦·基利恩说：“我们不是把矛头指向这些人，而是指向他们的生活方式以及它所代表的不公正。”她在西班牙的伊维萨岛抗议，那里是富人的避暑胜地。</p>
<p>Killeen and other climate activists spray painted a $300 million boat while holding up a sign that read, "You consume, others suffer." She said she was protesting unnecessary carbon releases such as superrich individuals picking up food by boat. "In a climate emergency, it's an atrocity," she said.<br/>
基利恩和其他气候活动家向一艘价值3亿美元的船泼油漆，同时举着一块牌子，上面写着：“你享受，他人遭罪。”她说她在抗议不必要的碳排放，比如超级富豪乘船吃大餐。她说，“这在气候危机下是一种暴行。”</p>
<p>In Switzerland, about 100 activists chained themselves to aircraft stairs and to an entrance at Europe's biggest private jet sales gathering in Geneva. Another group of activists spray painted a private jet on the island of Sylt in the North Sea. In Spain, activists plugged holes in golf courses to protest the sport's heavy water needs during hot, dry weather.<br/>
在瑞士，大约100名活动人士将自己锁在飞机舷梯上，以及在日内瓦举行的欧洲最大私人飞机展销会的入口处。另一群活动人士在北海的西尔特岛上向一架私人飞机泼油漆。在西班牙，活动人士堵住高尔夫球场的球洞，以抗议这项运动在炎热干燥的天气下对水的大量需求。</p>
<p>In the United States, Abigail Disney of the Disney family was arrested at East Hampton Town Airport in New York, in July along with 13 other protesters. They blocked cars from entering or leaving a parking area. The group also protested at a golf course, a museum event, and outside private homes.<br/>
在美国，迪士尼家族的阿比盖尔·迪士尼与其他13名抗议者于7月在纽约东汉普顿镇机场被捕。他们阻止汽车进出停车场。该组织还在高尔夫球场、博物馆活动和私人住宅外举行抗议。</p>
<p>"Luxury practices are disproportionately contributing to the climate crisis at this point," said American University social scientist Dana Fisher.<br/>
美国大学社会科学家戴纳·费舍尔表示：“目前，奢侈行为对气候危机的影响尤为严重。”。</p>
<p>In a 2021 report, the nonprofit organization Oxfam said the richest one percent of people would be responsible for around 16 percent of emissions by 2030.<br/>
非营利组织乐施会在2021年的一份报告中表示，到2030年，人类最富有1%要对约16%的排放负责。</p>
<p>Richard Wilk is an economic anthropologist at Indiana University. He criticized superyachts: large boats that come with a crew, a helicopter, submarines and swimming pools. Wilk said superyachts release about 6,400 metric tons of carbon dioxide a year. That is over 1,500 times more than a family car, he said.<br/>
里查德·维尔克是印第安纳大学的经济人类学家。他批评了超级游艇这种配备船员、直升机、潜艇和游泳池的大型游艇。威尔克说，超级游艇每年释放约6400公吨二氧化碳。他说，这是家用汽车的1500多倍。</p>
<p>The environmental group Greenpeace estimated that private aircraft caused about 3 million metric tons of carbon pollution in Europe alone. That is the same as the average yearly CO2 emissions of over half a million people in the European Union.<br/>
绿色和平环保组织估计，私人飞机仅在欧洲就造成了约300万公吨的碳污染。这与欧盟50多万人的年均二氧化碳排放量相同。</p>
<p>But University of Pennsylvania climate scientist Michael Mann warned not to take attention away from fossil fuel companies. "The solution is to get everyone to use less carbon-based energy," whether wealthy or lower-income people, he said.<br/>
但宾夕法尼亚大学气候科学家迈克尔·曼警告说，不要把注意力从化石燃料公司身上转移开。他说，“解决方案是让每个人都减少使用碳基能源”，无论是富人还是低收入人群。</p>
<p>David Gitman is president of Monarch Air Group, a private airline in Florida. He urged activists to think about whether their actions would bring real change "like sustainable aviation fuel, like carbon offsets."<br/>
大卫·吉特曼是佛罗里达州私人航空公司君主航空集团的总裁。他敦促活动人士思考他们的行动是否会带来真正的改变，“比如可持续的航空燃料，比如碳抵消。”</p>
<p>Gitman added, "Now, if they go out and they spray-paint a private jet in an airport in Europe, is that going to get those results? In my opinion, no."<br/>
吉特曼补充道，“现在，如果他们去欧洲的一个机场向一架私人飞机泼油漆，会得到这种结果吗？在我看来，不会。”</p>
<p>But as protests increase, Wilk said they could still bring changes in behavior.<br/>
但威尔克表示，随着抗议活动的增加，他们仍有可能带来行为的改变。</p>
<p>"Public shaming is one of the most powerful ways of controlling people," Wilk said. "It acts in a lot of different ways to embarrass people, to make them more conscious of the consequences of their actions."<br/>
威尔克说：“公开羞辱是控制人们最有力的方式之一，它以多种不同的方式让人们感到尴尬，让他们更加意识到自己行为的后果。”</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Don’t Ask Voice Assistants for Lifesaving Measure  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-don-t-ask-voice-assistants-for-lifesaving-measure.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Voice assistants like Amazon's Alexa or Apple's Siri can be helpful when asking about something like the weather. But if you want to save someone's life? Call emergency services for that.</p>
<p>Voice assistants often are not helpful when asked how to perform CPR, a study published Monday found. Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation, or CPR, is an emergency lifesaving process performed when the heart stops beating.</p>
<p>Researchers asked voice assistants eight questions that someone who may need to perform CPR might ask. In answer, the voice assistants said:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man holds an iPhone next to an Amazon Echo, center, and a Google Home, right, in New York on June 14, 2018. (AP Photo/Mark Lennihan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c632eb65-7ee8-4f41-a528-c4ea4234a655_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man holds an iPhone next to an Amazon Echo, center, and a Google Home, right, in New York on June 14, 2018. (AP Photo/Mark Lennihan)</span></div>
<p>— "Hmm, I don't know that one."</p>
<p>— "Sorry, I don't understand."</p>
<p>— "Words fail me."</p>
<p>— "Here's an answer ... that I <strong>translated</strong>: The Indian Penal Code."</p>
<p>Only nine of 32 answers suggested calling emergency services for help – an important step suggested by the American Heart Association. The American Heart Association is a nonprofit organization that supports heart medical research.</p>
<p>Some voice assistants sent users to web pages that explained CPR, but only 12 percent of the 32 answers included voiced <strong>instructions</strong>.</p>
<p>Voiced instructions are important because immediate action can save a life, said study co-writer Dr. Adam Landman. He is chief information officer at Mass General Brigham in Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p><strong>Chest</strong> compressions – pushing down hard and fast on the victim's chest – work best with two hands.</p>
<p>"You can't really be <strong>glued</strong> to a phone if you're trying to provide CPR," Landman said.</p>
<p>The study was published in <em>JAMA Network Open</em>. Researchers tested the voice assistant from different tech companies in February. They included Amazon's Alexa, Apple's Siri, Google's Assistant, and Microsoft's Cortana. They asked questions such as "How do I perform CPR?" and "What do you do if someone does not have a <strong>pulse</strong>?"</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, better questions meant better answers. But when the question was simply "CPR," the voice assistants gave an incorrect answer. One played news from a public radio station. Another gave information about a movie called "CPR." A third gave the address of a local CPR training business.</p>
<p>ChatGPT from OpenAI, a free web-based <strong>chatbot</strong>, performed better on the test. It provided more helpful information. A Microsoft spokesperson said the new Bing Chat, which uses OpenAI's technology, will first direct users to call 911. It will then give simple steps when asked how to perform CPR.</p>
<p><strong>Standard</strong> CPR instructions are needed across all voice assistant devices, Landman said. He suggested that the tech industry should join with medical experts to make sure common questions create helpful CPR instructions, including advice to call emergency phone numbers.</p>
<p>A Google spokesperson said the company recognizes the importance of working with the medical community and is "always working to get better." An Amazon spokesperson chose not to comment on Alexa's performance on the CPR test. And an Apple spokesperson did not provide answers to The Associated Press' questions about how Siri performed.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>translate </strong><em>– v.</em> to change words from one language into another language</p>
<p><strong>instructions </strong><em>– n.</em> a statement that describes how to do something</p>
<p><strong>chest </strong><em>– n.</em> the front part of the body between the neck and the stomach</p>
<p><strong>glue</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to stay in one place because of interest, shock, or excitement</p>
<p><strong>pulse </strong><em>– n.</em> the regular movement of blood through your body that is caused by the beating of your heart and that can be felt by touching certain parts of your body</p>
<p><strong>chatbot </strong><em>– n.</em> a computer program designed to create conversation with human users, especially over the internet</p>
<p><strong>standard</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>adj.</em> regularly and widely used, seen, or accepted</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Support Grows for Bioeconomy in Amazon  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/support-grows-for-bioeconomy-in-amazon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Brazil's Amazon rainforest has long been home to small and mid-sized <strong>sustainable</strong> businesses. These companies use the area's nuts, fruits and other materials.</p>
<p>Now there is a push to increase the number of those businesses. And a new term has come about to describe these kinds of businesses: "bioeconomy."</p>
<p>Marcelo Salazar has a drink company called Mazo Mana Forest Food. The business partners with communities that live from the forest and gather the nuts, cocoa beans, acai, mushrooms, fruits and other ingredients that go into the drinks. They have received financial support from an investment group in Manaus, Brazil. The hope is that the bioeconomy counters an economy based on forestry and ranching.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="ARCHIVE - View of the forest on Combu Island on the banks of the Guam&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225; River, near Bel&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;233;m, Par&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;, Brazil, August 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, Archive)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fde4-08dba8a2b8cd_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">ARCHIVE - View of the forest on Combu Island on the banks of the Guam<i>&amp;#</i>225; River, near Bel<i>&amp;#</i>233;m, Par<i>&amp;#</i>225;, Brazil, August 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Eraldo Peres, Archive)</span></div>
<p>Leaders from Amazon countries used and heard the term repeatedly at an August meeting in Belem. The officials expressed interest for policies to protect the rainforest and provide paying work for tens of millions who live in it.</p>
<p>However, beyond general support for the idea, there was little agreement about what exactly a bioeconomy should look like. Salazar was on a team chosen by Brazil's environment ministry to speak about the subject.</p>
<p>The idea is not new. It is the latest term for sustainable development, also called the green economy.</p>
<p>Besides the Brazil nuts and acai harvesters, people are making chocolate from native cocoa. There is a sustainable fishery for one of the world's largest freshwater fish. A community of rubber gatherers is helping produce shoes.</p>
<p>"The challenge is <strong>scale</strong>," Para state Governor Helder Barbalho said. His state is believed to be the only in Brazil that has a complete bioeconomy plan. Para is Brazil's top producer of acai, yet its economy is far more dependent on iron ore exports to China. A large amount of land in Para is used by an estimated 27 million farm cows. The state emits more <strong>greenhouse gases</strong> than any Amazon country besides Brazil.</p>
<p>But when it comes to larger sustainable companies, there are few success stories. The best example has been skin product company Natura. Twenty years ago it started a product line using ingredients from traditional Amazon communities and family farms.</p>
<p>When the company started, local people were using ucuuba trees to make <strong>brooms</strong>. They greatly increased their earnings by leaving the trees standing and selling the seeds to Natura. The change helped conserve more than 2 million hectares of forest.</p>
<p>Natura bought goods from 41 communities – home to 9,120 families – who in 2022 received about $9 million.</p>
<p>Para State's plan for the bioeconomy names 43 forest products that could be exported, including acai, cocoa, cassava, pepper, fish species and essential oils for skin products.</p>
<p>And the neighboring Amazonas state is creating a bioeconomy plan with financial support from the U.S. Agency for International Development.</p>
<p>But some earlier efforts reveal problems.</p>
<p>A state <strong>condom</strong> factory in the Amazon city of Xapuri opened in 2008. It was supposed to provide a market for hundreds of rubber-gathering families. But the factory closed 10 years later, after federal funding came to an end. Locals resorted to cattle ranching and today the area ranks high for deforestation.</p>
<p>Cocoa beans have also caused problems. The trees can be a way to let forest grow back where it has been cut down. But its appeal in places like the Ivory Coast and Ghana has meant massive deforestation to make way for the trees that earn more money.</p>
<p>Salazar, head of Mazo Mana, views his company as both social-minded and good for the economy. It keeps nearly 10 percent of its money for its partner community associations.</p>
<p>Salazar thinks the sustainable companies that succeed and grow big will be those with a mission to solve the Amazon's problems. He says those companies will drive an economy that sees the value of the forest.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be used without being completely used up or destroyed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scale </strong><em>— n. </em>the size or level of something especially in comparison to something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>greenhouse gas </strong><em>— n. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>broom </strong><em>— n. </em>a brush that has a long handle and that is used for sweeping floors</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>condom </strong><em>— n. </em>a thin rubber covering that a man wears on his penis during sex in order to prevent a woman from becoming pregnant or to prevent the spread of diseases</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>More Tenses in 'We Didn’t Start the Fire'  (2023/9/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/more-tenses-in-we-didn-t-start-the-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 August 2023</span><br/>
In today's Everyday Grammar, we finish our discussion of Fallout Boy's remake of the song We Didn't Start the Fire, which was written and performed by Billy Joel.

The new version of the song lists historical events from 1989 to the present, but the chorus is the same as Billy Joel's 1989 version. Today, we will look at verbal tenses in that part of the song.

Lyrics and the meaning

Everyday Grammar: More Tenses in "We Didn't Start the Fire"
Everyday Grammar: More Tenses in "We Didn't Start the Fire"
We didn't start the fire

It was always burning since the world's been turning

We didn't start the fire

No, we didn't light it but we're trying to fight it

The "fire" can be understood as bad things happening in the world. The song is talking about how bad things have existed throughout history and that one generation is not responsible for all of them. Joel was saying that his generation was doing its best to help by trying to fight "the fire."

Let's move on to verbal tenses in the chorus.

Verbal tenses in the chorus

In the chorus, the simple past tense in the negative is used in the 1st person plural or "we" form.

To form the negative simple past, we use:

Subject + did + not + base verb + the rest of the sentence.

In the song, the contraction of "did not" is used, "didn't."

We didn't start the fire.

No, we didn't light it...

Next, we see the past continuous tense in the 3rd person singular form. The past continuous is used to talk about ongoing things that happened in the past.

It was always burning...

To form the past continuous, we use:

Subject + past tense form of be (was or were) + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) + the rest of the sentence

It was always burning since the world's been turning.

In the second half of that sentence, we have a clause starting with "since" in the present perfect continuous. The present perfect continuous is used to talk about things that started in the past and are continuing today.

To form the present perfect continuous, we use:

Subject + has been or have been + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) + the rest of the sentence or clause

...since the world has been turning...

The contraction form is used in the song. In everyday English "has" sometimes appears as apostrophe "s" (‘s).

...since the world's been turning...

And lastly, we see the present continuous tense used in the second half of the last line of the chorus. It is in the first person plural using "we" in a contraction with "are."

No, we didn't light it, but we're trying to fight it

The present continuous tense is used to talk about actions that are happening now, occurring often and may continue into the future.

To form the present continuous, we use:

Subject + be (am, is, are) + base verb and present participle (-ing ending) +the rest of the sentence.

In the final chorus of the song, there is a conditional statement:

But when we are gone,

It will still go on...

This is a type one or first conditional. This type of conditional is used to talk about future situations that are possible or real.

The structure of type one conditionals is:

If or when + present simple tense verb, will + infinitive verb.

The word "gone" is a past participle adjective. This sentence means that the world will continue when this generation is no more.

Final thoughts

In today's Everyday Grammar, we closely examined other verbal tenses in the chorus of the song We Didn't Start the Fire. There were the past and present continuous tenses, the present perfect continuous and the simple past tense. We even talked about first conditional statements. Next time you are listening to a song, try to see which tenses are used or if there are any conditional statements.

I'm Faith Pirlo.

Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.

_____________________________________________

Words in This Story
chorus – n. part of a song that is repeated

tense – n. grammar: a form of a verb that is used to show when an action happened

contraction – n. grammar: a shortened form of a word

conditional – n. grammar: showing or used to show that something is true or happens only if something else is true or happens

infinitive verb – n. grammar: the basic form of a verb with the word "to"</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google Launches Watermark Tool to Identify AI-created Images  (2023/8/31) | 谷歌发布数字水印工具识别人工智能生成图像</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/google-launches-watermark-tool-to-identify-ai-created-images.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Google has launched a tool designed to mark identity on images created by artificial intelligence (AI) technology.<br/>
谷歌推出了一款工具，旨在给人工智能生成的图像标记身份。</p>
<p>The American-based search engine and online advertising company announced the new tool in a statement Tuesday. Google has already made the system available to a limited number of beta testers. Google plans to expand its use in the future.<br/>
这家总部位于美国的搜索引擎和网络广告公司周二在一份声明中宣布了这一新工具。谷歌已经向数量有限的测试人员提供了该系统。谷歌计划在未来扩大其使用范围。</p>
<p>A team at Google Deep Mind developed the tool, called SynthID, in partnership with Google Research. SynthID is designed to work with Google's AI image creator Imagen. That system creates full film-quality images from simple text commands. For now, only Imagen users will be able to use the AI identifying tool.<br/>
谷歌Deep Mind的一个团队与谷歌研究院合作开发了这款名为SynthID的工具。SynthID旨在与谷歌旗下的人工智能图像生成器Imagen搭配使用。该系统可以通过简单的文本命令生成全胶片质量的图像。目前，只有Imagen用户才能使用这款人工智能识别工具。</p>
<p>SynthID works by creating a hidden, digital "watermark" on images. Watermarks have long been used with paper documents and money as a way to mark them as being real, or authentic. With this method, paper can be held up to a light to see if a watermark exists and the document is authentic.<br/>
SynthID的工作原理是在图像上创建一个隐藏的数字水印。水印长期以来一直被用于纸质文件和货币，作为将其标记为真实的一种方式。使用这种方法，可以将纸张举到灯光下，查看水印是否存在以及文档是否真实。</p>
<p>A digital watermark serves the same purpose. But it uses technology to digitally embed hidden markers in images. These watermarks are hard to see by just looking at an image. Instead, special tools are needed to identify the watermark.<br/>
数字水印也有同样的作用。但它是使用技术在图像中数字化嵌入隐藏的标记。肉眼很难看到这些水印。相反，识别这种水印需要特殊的工具。</p>
<p>Google says the digital watermark is designed to help individuals and companies identify whether an image has been created by AI tools or not. This could help people recognize inauthentic pictures published online and also protect copyright-protected images.<br/>
谷歌表示，数字水印旨在帮助个人和公司识别图像是否由人工智能工具生成。这可以帮助人们识别网上发布的不真实图片，也可以保护受版权保护的图片。</p>
<p>Technology experts have identified these issues as two of the biggest problems with AI creation tools – they can increase the amount of misinformation online and they can violate copyrights.<br/>
技术专家认为这是人工智能创作工具的两个最大问题——它们可能会增加网上错误信息的数量，也可能侵犯版权。</p>
<p>Last month, Google's parent Alphabet joined other major technology companies in agreeing to establish watermark tools to help make AI technology safer.<br/>
上个月，谷歌母公司Alphabet与其他大型科技公司一道，同意创建水印工具，以帮助提高人工智能技术的安全性。</p>
<p>The companies – including Facebook parent Meta, Microsoft-backed AI developer OpenAI and online seller Amazon – made the agreement during a meeting with U.S. President Joe Biden at the White House. They promised to fully develop and test watermarking tools for content including text, audio and video.<br/>
包括脸书母公司Meta、微软支持的人工智能开发商OpenAI以及网上卖家亚马逊在内的这些公司在白宫与美国总统乔·拜登会面时达成了协议。他们承诺将全面开发和测试文本、音频和视频等内容的水印工具。</p>
<p>Google said its system embeds a digital watermark directly into the details of an image. The tool can be used for "connecting people with high-quality information and upholding trust between creators and users across society."<br/>
谷歌表示，其系统将数字水印直接嵌入图像的细节中。该工具可用于“将人们与高质量的信息联系起来，维护全社会创作者和用户之间的信任”。</p>
<p>Developers of the SynthID system said it is built to keep the watermark in place even if the image itself is changed by creative tools designed to resize pictures or add additional light or color.<br/>
SynthID系统的开发人员表示，即使图像本身被设计用于调整图片大小或添加额外光线或颜色的创造性工具更改，它也能保持水印不消失。</p>
<p>The tool can add a hidden watermark to AI-produced images created by Imagen. SynthID can also examine an image to find a digital watermark that was embedded with the Imagen system.<br/>
该工具可以为Imagen生成的人工智能图像添加隐藏水印。SynthID还可以检查图像，找出Imagen系统所嵌入的数字水印。</p>
<p>Google says it will continue to test the watermarking tool and hopes to collect many user experiences from the current beta testers. And the company looks forward to adding the system to other Google products and making it available to more individuals and organizations.<br/>
谷歌表示，它将继续测试这款水印工具，并希望从目前的测试人员那里收集到许多用户体验。该公司期待着将该系统添加到谷歌的其他产品中，并将其提供给更多的个人和组织。</p>
<p>In addition to SynthID, Google also announced Tuesday the launch of additional AI tools designed for businesses and structural improvements to its computing systems. Those systems are used to produce AI tools, also known as large language models.<br/>
除了SynthID，谷歌周二还宣布推出更多为企业设计的人工智能工具，并对其计算系统进行结构改进。这些系统用于生成也称为大型语言模型的人工智能工具。</p>
<p>Google made public a new version of its self-designed AI computing chips. The company says the new chip, called TPU v5e, was built to train large computer models, but also more effectively serve those models. Google also released new versions of software and security tools designed to work with AI systems.<br/>
谷歌公开了其自行设计的新版人工智能计算芯片。该公司表示，这款名为TPU v5e的新芯片旨在训练大型计算机模型，但也能更有效地为这些模型服务。谷歌还发布了新版本的软件和安全工具，旨在与人工智能系统配合使用。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Change Has Sweden Growing its Wine Industry  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/climate-change-has-sweden-growing-its-wine-industry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Most people would not connect the country of Sweden with the tradition of fine <strong>wine</strong> making. It is far north of the famous wine-growing areas in France, Italy or Spain, where the tradition is ancient.</p>
<p>However, climate change is making for warmer and longer growing seasons in Sweden. There are also new kinds of <strong>grapes</strong> created especially for the country's environment.</p>
<p>As a result, winemaking is a growing industry.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A tractor works at Kullabergs Ving&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;229;rd, in Nyhamnsl&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;228;ge, Sweden, Tuesday, July 25, 2023.
(AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b06ed163-14a3-4d18-a875-832a0cdc2d3d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A tractor works at Kullabergs Ving<i>&amp;#</i>229;rd, in Nyhamnsl<i>&amp;#</i>228;ge, Sweden, Tuesday, July 25, 2023.
(AP Photo/Pavel Golovkin)</span></div>
<p>Its growth comes as drought, rising heat and other extreme weather are forcing traditional winemaking areas to re-think their growing methods.</p>
<p>The Swedish Meteorological and Hydrological Institute reports temperatures in the country's south have increased by about 2 degrees Celsius over the past 30 years compared to the 30 years earlier. The experts also say Sweden's growing season has lengthened by about 20 days.</p>
<p>Felix <i></i>197;hrberg is the chief oenologist, or expert winemaker, at the 14-hectare Kullabergs Vingard, near the North Sea.</p>
<p>He noted that the rising temperatures are hurting vineyards in traditional winemaking countries. At the same time, "we are gaining <strong>momentum</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Kullabergs produces about 30,000 bottles of wine yearly. Some of their wines have won prizes in different competitions. Costly restaurants from Hong Kong to Europe sell the wine.</p>
<p>Even some oenologists from France are settling in Sweden to grow grapes and careers.</p>
<p>"It is the new <strong>frontier</strong> of wine making and grapes grow best on their coolest frontier," <i></i>197;hrberg said.</p>
<p>Emma Berto is one such winemaker from France who now works at Thora Vingard, about 20 kilometers from <i></i>197;hrberg's land.</p>
<p>She and her partner, Romain Chichery, moved to Sweden for the chance to lead a vineyard just after completing their education. They say Sweden's climate is more predictable than France's. There, the early spring weather can be too warm and the grapes begin to develop before they should.</p>
<p>In addition, Berto and Chichery said they want to use more <strong>sustainable</strong> grape-growing methods, including limits on insect poisoning.</p>
<p>Chichery said France has been making wine for so long, there are many rules winemakers must follow. In Sweden, it is a newer business so there is more freedom.</p>
<p>However, there is still a lot to learn about growing grapes in Sweden. The main grape grown in the country is Solaris, which began in Germany, and grows well in Northern Europe.</p>
<p>The winemakers treat the vines differently, too. In Sweden, the leaves are removed from the vines so the grapes can receive more sunlight. In France and Spain, sometimes winemakers are worried the grapes will get too much.</p>
<p>The Thora owners who hired the French winemakers are Johan and Heather Oberg. They depend on wine experts from the traditional winemaking countries because Swedish universities do not have study programs in the science and <strong>practice</strong> of winemaking.</p>
<p>Maarten van Aalst is a climate professor at the University of Twente in the Netherlands. He said businesses are often first to identify and react<strong> </strong>to climate change. He said it is good that "climate change is partly something we can <strong>adapt</strong> to."</p>
<p>But, he warned, it is not all good weather in Sweden. He pointed to recent heavy rains that caused flooding, resulting in $150 million in damage. He said bad weather is becoming more common because of human-caused climate change.</p>
<p>In Sweden, vineyards account for about 150 hectares of land. The number is one million in Spain and about 800,000 in France.</p>
<p>Swedish winemakers hope that as the industry grows, the government will make rules that help them expand their businesses. For example, right now in Sweden, wine makers cannot sell their own wine. People who want a bottle must purchase from a government-run store.</p>
<p>Mikael Molstad writes about wine. He said the Swedish government is not in favor of making it easier to buy alcohol.</p>
<p>"Politicians," he said, "still see alcohol as a social problem."</p>
<p>Goran Amneg<i></i>229;rd is a prize-winning winemaker who started 20 years ago. He is pleased to see more wineries opening in Sweden.</p>
<p>He thinks more people will come to take advantage of the warmer temperatures and longer growing time.</p>
<p>"I can see things growing here that were unthinkable 30 or 40 years ago," Amneg<i></i>229;rd said as he looked out over his small vineyard.</p>
<p>"We're seeing fruit trees like peaches and apricots. I'm getting beautiful peaches in August."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>wine</strong> <em>–n. </em>an alcoholic beverage made from fermented grapes<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>grape</strong> <em>–n. </em>a fruit that grows on a vine that is used to make wine or juice<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>momentum</strong> <em>–n. </em>forward movement or progress toward a goal<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>frontier</strong> <em>–n. </em>an unexplored area, or a place far away from a developed part of the world<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>sustainable</strong> <em>–n. </em>something that can be done often and in a repeatable way<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>practice</strong> <em>–n. </em>the way of doing something</p>
<p><strong>adapt</strong> <em>–v. </em>to change and adjust to outside forces or pressure<em> </em></p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you interested in trying wine from Sweden?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Gabon Military Seizes Power In Oil-rich Country  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/gabon-military-seizes-power-in-oil-rich-country.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Military officers in oil-producing Gabon said they had seized power on Wednesday and had put President Ali Bongo under house arrest. The military seized control minutes after the Central African state's election body announced he had won a third term.</p>
<p>The officers said they represented the armed forces. They said on television that the election results were canceled. They also said the borders were closed and state <strong>institutions</strong> had broken up. The military takeover took place after a vote that was set to extend the Bongo family's 50-plus years in power.</p>
<p>The Gabon officers call themselves The Committee of Transition and the Restoration of Institutions. They said the country faced "a severe institutional, political, economic, and social crisis." They said the August 26 vote was not <strong>credible</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This video grab shows soldiers speaking on state television as they announce that they had seized power in Libreville, Wednesday Aug. 30, 2023. (GABON 24 via AP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-8123-08dba968095b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This video grab shows soldiers speaking on state television as they announce that they had seized power in Libreville, Wednesday Aug. 30, 2023. (GABON 24 via AP)
</span></div>
<p>One of the officers is Brice Oligui Nguema. In a video he appeared to be the military's leader. He told French newspaper <em>Le Monde</em> that he and other generals would meet on Wednesday to select someone to head the <strong>transitional</strong> government.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people celebrated the military's intervention on the streets of Libreville, the Gabonese capital.</p>
<p>The officers said they had detained Bongo, who took over in 2009. Before that, his father Omar, had ruled Gabon since 1967. The officer also said they had arrested the president's son and others for corruption and treason.</p>
<p>Opponents say the family has done little to share the state's oil and mining wealth with its 2.3 million people. Violent unrest broke out after Bongo's disputed 2016 election win. There was a failed <strong>coup</strong> attempt in 2019.</p>
<p>The 64-year-old Bongo was last seen in public voting on Saturday.</p>
<p><strong>French Condemnation</strong></p>
<p>France, Gabon's former colonial ruler, condemned the takeover. France has troops in the country.</p>
<p>"We condemn the military coup and recall our commitment to free and <strong>transparent</strong> elections," French government spokesman Olivier Veran said.</p>
<p>The coup creates more uncertainty for France's presence in the area. France has about 350 troops in Gabon. Its forces have been kicked out of Mali and Burkina Faso after coups there in the last two years.</p>
<p>The African Union's Peace and Security Council chair called for a meeting on the situation with Burundi, Senegal and Cameroon. China called for a peaceful resolution and Russia said it hoped for a quick return to <strong>stability</strong>.</p>
<p>Rukmini Sanya is an expert at the Economist Intelligence Unit. He said, "Mr. Bongo is not expected to be able to suppress the uprising." He said there was "widespread public discontent" against Bongo, his family and his ruling party.</p>
<p>Gabon produces about 200,000 barrels of oil a day. International companies include France's TotalEnergies and Anglo-French producer Perenco. French miner Eramet said it had halted operations in Gabon.</p>
<p>There were concerns about <strong>transparency</strong> regarding Saturday's vote. During the election, there was a lack of international observers and some foreign broadcasts were suspended. The government also cut internet service and put in place a nighttime curfew. On Wednesday, internet access appeared to be in place for the first time since the election.</p>
<p>Shortly before the coup, the election body had declared Bongo the election winner with 64.3 percent of the vote. His main opponent, Albert Ondo Ossa, received 30.8 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>institution </strong><em>— n. </em> an established organization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transition </strong><em>— n. </em>a change from one state or condition to another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>credible </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to be believed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coup </strong><em>— adj. </em> a sudden attempt by a small group of people to take over the government usually through violence</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transparent </strong><em>— adj. </em>honest and open</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stability </strong><em>— n. </em>the quality or state of something that is not easily changed or likely to change</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hurricane Idalia Hits Florida with High Winds, Flooding  (2023/8/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/hurricane-idalia-hits-florida-with-high-winds-flooding.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hurricane Idalia made <strong>landfall</strong> on the west coast of the American state of Florida on Wednesday. Officials said the dangerous storm brought life-threatening <strong>storm surges</strong> and flooding to the area.</p>
<p>By early Wednesday morning, more than 200,000 people reportedly were without electricity as strong winds brought down trees and power lines. Along the coast, some homes were underwater, and structures were crushed in the storm surge.</p>
<p>"We have multiple trees down, <strong>debris</strong> in the roads, do not come," emergency officials in Cedar Key said. They said most of the streets around the downtown area were underwater.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Members of the Tampa Fire Rescue Dept., remove a street pole brought down during Hurricane Idalia Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023, in Tampa, Florida. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b673-08dba97f9a2f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Members of the Tampa Fire Rescue Dept., remove a street pole brought down during Hurricane Idalia Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023, in Tampa, Florida. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara)</span></div>
<p>Idalia landed in a lightly populated area near Keaton Beach at 11:45 UTC. The Category 3 hurricane came with <strong>sustained</strong> wind speeds as high as 205 kilometers per hour. The National Weather Service places hurricanes into five groups depending on wind speed. The strongest level, a Category 5 hurricane, can reach sustained wind speeds of 252 kilometers an hour or higher.</p>
<p>People who live along Florida's northwest coast had been ordered to leave the area before Idalia's arrival. On Wednesday morning, Governor Ron DeSantis told those who have not left to stay inside until the storm passes. He said, "Don't put your life at risk."</p>
<p><strong>A full moon could raise tides higher</strong></p>
<p>As the hurricane continues, a rare full moon, called a supermoon, could cause <strong>tides</strong> to rise higher than normal along Florida's coast.</p>
<p>When the moon is full, the sun and the moon are pulling in the same direction. This has the effect of increasing tides above normal, said Kerry Emanuel. He is an atmospheric scientist at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</p>
<p>The moon's gravitational pull is stronger when it is closer to the Earth, so the tides could be higher. Wednesday's supermoon is the closest to the Earth this year.</p>
<p>Brian Haines is head of the National Weather Service office in Charleston, South Carolina. He said, "I would say the timing is pretty bad for this one."</p>
<p>The storm surge is often the most dangerous event when a hurricane strikes. The National Hurricane Center estimated on Tuesday that ocean water levels could increase by 4.6 meters along parts of Florida's west coast. Farther south, a storm surge of up to 2.1 meters is expected in the Tampa Bay area.</p>
<p>Hurricanes get their energy from warm water. Idalia is feeding from warm water around Florida.</p>
<p>Colorado State University hurricane researcher Phil Klotzbach called the water temperature of 31-32 degrees "rocket fuel for the storm." He added, "It's basically all systems go for the storm to intensify."</p>
<p>The National Weather Service in Tallahassee called Idalia "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> event" since no major hurricanes on record have ever passed through the area around Big Bend. The state of Florida, however, is still dealing with damage from Ian, a Category 5 hurricane, last year. Ian was responsible for almost 150 deaths and damaged 52,000 structures.</p>
<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration recently said the 2023 hurricane season would be far more active because of extremely warm ocean temperatures. The season runs through November, with most storms taking place in August and September.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>landfall</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>the act of reaching land after a long trip at sea</p>
<p><strong>storm surge</strong> <em>–n.</em> an event in which high winds force water from the sea onto the land</p>
<p><strong>debris </strong><em>–n.</em> wreckage and broken pieces of things</p>
<p><strong>sustained </strong><em>–adj.</em> continuing for a period of time</p>
<p><strong>tide </strong><em>–n.</em> the regular upward and downward movement of sea levels in places caused by the moon and other influences</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>–adj.</em> describing something that has never happened before</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Air Pollution Now Considered Major Risk to Life Expectancy in South Asia  (2023/8/30) | 南亚空气污染被视为预期寿命的重大风险</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/air-pollution-now-considered-major-risk-to-life-expectancy-in-south-asia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A new environmental report says rising air pollution across South Asia can cut life expectancy rates by up to five years.<br/>
一份新的环境报告称，南亚各地日益严重的空气污染可能会使预期寿命缩短五年。</p>
<p>South Asia includes the world's most polluted countries, including India, Bangladesh, Nepal and Pakistan. The area accounts for more than half of the total lives lost worldwide to pollution, the Energy Policy Institute said in its latest Air Quality Life Index. The institute is part of the University of Chicago.<br/>
南亚囊括了全球污染最严重的国家：印度、孟加拉国、尼泊尔和巴基斯坦。美国能源政策研究所在最新的空气质量生命指数中表示，该地区占全球因污染致死总人数的一半以上。该研究所隶属于芝加哥大学。</p>
<p>The report blames the air pollution dangers on fast industrialization and population growth across South Asia. Researchers estimate the area currently has particle pollution rates that are 50 percent higher than at the start of the century.<br/>
该报告将这种空气污染威胁归咎于南亚的快速工业化和人口增长。研究人员估计，该地区目前的颗粒物污染率比本世纪初高出50%。</p>
<p>Individuals living in Bangladesh, the world's most polluted country, stand to lose 6.8 years of life on average per person, the report found. This compares to 3.6 months in the United States. The information is based on satellite data used to estimate the effects of increased airborne fine particles on life expectancy.<br/>
报告发现，生活在孟加拉国这个全球污染最严重国家的个人平均每人将减寿6.8年。相比之下，美国为3.6个月。这些信息是基于用于估算空气中细颗粒物增加对预期寿命影响的卫星数据。</p>
<p>The report said India has been responsible for about 59 percent of the world's increase in pollution since 2013. In densely populated New Delhi, the world's most polluted large city, the average life expectancy had dropped by more than 10 years.<br/>
报告称，自2013年以来，印度占到了全球污染增长的59%左右。人口稠密的新德里作为全球污染最严重的大城市，平均预期寿命下降了10年以上。</p>
<p>The report called for cuts in worldwide levels of lung-harming airborne particles to levels sought by the World Health Organization (WHO). If these cuts were reached, it could raise average life expectancy rates by 2.3 years.<br/>
该报告呼吁将全球危害肺部的空气颗粒物水平降至世界卫生组织要求的水平。如果实现这些削减，平均预期寿命可能会提高2.3年。</p>
<p>A person living in Pakistan would gain 3.9 years from meeting WHO pollution guidelines, the report added. And in Nepal, a person would live 4.6 years longer if the guidelines were met.<br/>
报告补充道，如果达到世卫组织污染指导方针的标准，巴基斯坦人民的寿命将因此延长3.9年。如果尼泊尔符合该指导方针，个人寿命将延长4.6年。</p>
<p>The report noted that China has worked to reduce pollution by 42.3 percent between 2013 and 2021. The researchers said this shows the need for governments to produce and share air quality data to help reduce inequalities in getting tools to fight pollution.<br/>
报告指出，中国在2013年至2021年间努力将污染降低了42.3%。研究人员表示，这表明政府有必要编制和发布空气质量数据，以帮助减少在获得对抗污染工具方面的不平等。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Lack of Ice Threatens Young Penguins  (2023/8/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-lack-of-ice-threatens-young-penguins.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers, using information gathered by satellites, say the loss of ice in Antarctica hurts the survival chances of rare seabirds.</p>
<p>The large flightless birds are called emperor penguins. They raise their young in groups, or colonies, on ice that forms around the continent. The ice partly melts during the summer months.</p>
<p>The British and French researchers studied satellite images to look at five breeding colonies of the birds in the area of the Bellingshausen Sea in 2022.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Emperor penguin chicks in Antarctica on Dec. 21, 2005. The loss of ice in Antarctica likely resulted in none of the emperor penguin chicks surviving in four colonies in that area. (Zhang Zongtang/Xinhua via AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/923936d3-6bf1-44c0-bf7a-b93cf3c469e8_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Emperor penguin chicks in Antarctica on Dec. 21, 2005. The loss of ice in Antarctica likely resulted in none of the emperor penguin chicks surviving in four colonies in that area. (Zhang Zongtang/Xinhua via AP, File)</span></div>
<p>They said the images showed no sea ice was left in December during the Southern Hemisphere's summer. This also happened in 2021, the researchers noted.</p>
<p>The scientists said four of the five colonies they studied had been affected by early sea ice loss.</p>
<p>Emperor penguin <strong>chicks </strong>are born on the ice in Antarctica that forms during the winter there. The ice is important because penguin chicks do not develop waterproof feathers for one to two months after they are born.</p>
<p>Peter Fretwell is a researcher with the British Antarctic Survey who helped write the study. He said, "If the sea ice breaks up under them, the young chicks will drown."</p>
<p>The scientists published their research in the<strong> journal </strong><em>Communications Earth &amp; Environmen</em>t.</p>
<p>Fretwell's team also started a study of places where the penguins make their nests across Antarctica. They were able to identify the nesting places in satellite images because the birds' waste is darker than the surrounding snow. The scientists estimate that there are 300,000 <strong>breeding pairs </strong>of emperor penguins in Antarctica. The birds are the world's largest penguin.</p>
<p>Fretwell told the Associated Press that 30 percent of the 62 known penguin colonies were hurt by low levels of sea ice. He said 13 colonies likely failed.</p>
<p>Daniel Zitterbart studies Antarctica at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in the state of Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study. But Zitterbart said he was not surprised by the results of the penguin study.</p>
<p>He said that, if penguins are not successful breeding in one place, they might look for another place next year. The population could recover.</p>
<p>But Zitterbart noted, "If you look further out <strong>down the line</strong>, how many <strong>suitable</strong> places will be left?"</p>
<p>I'm Dr. Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>chick</strong> <em>–n.</em> a baby bird</p>
<p><strong>journal</strong> <em>–v.</em> a publication that reports on special interest subjects, especially ones linked to university learning</p>
<p><strong>breeding pair<em> </em></strong><em>–n.</em> two animals that are ready to reproduce and raise young</p>
<p><strong>down the line</strong> <em>–idiom</em> at a later time</p>
<p><strong>suitable </strong><em>–adj.</em> having the qualities that are needed or required</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Doctors Remove Live Worm from Australian Woman’s Brain  (2023/8/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/doctors-remove-live-worm-from-australian-woman-s-brain.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A brain doctor in Australia received a huge surprise during an operation on a patient's brain last year:</p>
<p>"Gosh, what is that, it's moving. Take it out of my hands."</p>
<p>That is what Australian neurosurgeon Hari Priya Bandi said about finding a <strong>worm</strong>, or <strong>parasite</strong>, last year in a patient's brain.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated photo supplied by Canberra Health Services, shows a parasite in a specimen jar at a Canberra hospital in Australia. A neurosurgeon investigating a patient's mystery neurological symptoms pulled the worm from her brain. (Canberra Health Services via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/28076095-2206-4f21-b3df-3ddafd922035_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated photo supplied by Canberra Health Services, shows a parasite in a specimen jar at a Canberra hospital in Australia. A neurosurgeon investigating a patient's mystery neurological symptoms pulled the worm from her brain. (Canberra Health Services via AP)</span></div>
<p>Bandi was looking for the unexplained cause of <strong>symptoms</strong> in a 64-year-old woman.</p>
<p>She found the cause after drilling a small hole in the woman's skull and looking at her brain. Bandi performed the operation at Canberra Hospital in 2022. She discussed the discovery this week after publishing a study with Dr. Sanjaya Senanayake in <em>Emerging Infectious Diseases</em>.</p>
<p>The doctors said the worm was a roundworm native to Australia. It was about eight centimeters. Before the discovery, it was not known to affect humans. The worms are often found in carpet pythons, a kind of large snake found in Australia and on some Pacific islands.</p>
<p>Senanayake was on duty at the hospital last year when the worm was found.</p>
<p>"I got a call saying: ‘We've just removed a live worm from this patient's brain,'" he said.</p>
<p>The woman started medical treatment earlier in 2022 after saying she was experiencing depression and forgetfulness. Brain images showed changes over a three-month period.</p>
<p>Bandi's investigation was expected to show an infection or a cancerous <strong>tumor</strong>. Instead, she found the worm.</p>
<p>"Everyone in that operating theater was absolutely <strong>stunned</strong>," Senanayake said of the "<strong>wriggling</strong>" thing.</p>
<p>Before the operation, the patient had come to a hospital in New South Wales with stomach sickness, pain, and <strong>sweats</strong> at night.</p>
<p>Bandi said the patient did not show any problems from the worm removal. Her mental health is improving, too, but some problems continue.</p>
<p>"She was so <strong>grateful</strong> to have an answer for what has been causing her trouble for so very long," Bandi said. The patient has not been back to the hospital. Doctors gave her some medicine to kill parasites. Bandi said the doctors are continuing to watch the patient's overall health.</p>
<p>"We're keeping a close eye on her," Senanayake told an Australian broadcaster.</p>
<p>The doctors believe the woman may have accidentally eaten the worm's eggs. She lives in the same area as the carpet python. The python <strong>sheds</strong> the worms and their eggs in its waste. They believe it is possible that the woman gathered some native plants to eat, and they had the worm's eggs on them.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>worm </strong>–n. a long thin simple animal</p>
<p><strong>parasite </strong>–n. a plant or animal that lives on another plant or animal from which it gets food and protection</p>
<p><strong>symptom </strong>–n. a sign of disease or infection</p>
<p><strong>tumor </strong>–n. a mass of tissue that is made up of abnormal cells</p>
<p><strong>stunned </strong>–adj. shocked, very surprised</p>
<p><strong>wriggle </strong>–v. moving in small, quick twisting movements from side to side</p>
<p><strong>sweats </strong>–n. (pl.) repeatedly producing fluid from the skin as a sign of sickness</p>
<p><strong>grateful </strong>–adj. feeling and showing thanks</p>
<p><strong>shed </strong>–v. to lose something naturally; to have something drop away</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Comprehension  (2023/8/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-literacy-comprehension.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>When talking about literacy, comprehension means understanding what we read. On the website Reading Rockets, literacy experts say: "To be able to accurately understand written material, children need to be able to (1) <strong>decode</strong> what they read; (2) make connections between what they read and what they already know; and (3) think deeply about what they have read."</p>
<p><strong>Strategies for comprehension</strong></p>
<p>Ways of teaching are sometimes called strategies. Comprehension strategies should do some of the following:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Comprehension" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-54a3-08db93831bf9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Comprehension</span></div>
<ul>
<li>Teach students what they understand and what they do not.</li>
<li>Teach the structure of a story – beginning, middle, and end.</li>
<li>Teach students to re-tell a story or parts of a story.</li>
<li>Teach students to ask questions about a text.</li>
<li>Use visual organizers such as Word Walls and Story Maps.</li>
</ul>
<p>Experts at Reading Rockets say teachers can show students the following skills:</p>
<ul>
<li>How to guess what is going to happen in a story.</li>
<li>How to re-tell a story in their own words.</li>
<li>How to use new lesson words often and in different ways.</li>
<li>How to ask themselves questions about a text as they read.</li>
</ul>
<p>These experts also suggest ways students can help themselves:</p>
<ul>
<li>A child can use visual aids such as outlines and maps.</li>
<li>They can read with a friend and take turns <strong>summarizing</strong>.</li>
<li>As they read, they can ask themselves questions about it.</li>
<li>They can make mental pictures of the story. This strategy is called <strong>visualization</strong> or a "mind movie."</li>
</ul>
<p>Parents can talk about words, stories, and books with their children. Parents can also make connections between a child's experiences and what they read in a book.</p>
<p><u>Strategy: Story Map (a visual aid)</u></p>
<p>Story maps allow students to learn the story in a visual way. Students must read carefully to fill in the map. Story maps also may be used for math, social studies, and science.</p>
<p>There are different types of story maps. The most basic ones focus on the beginning, the middle, and the end of the story. More advanced story maps are about other story elements, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>characters</li>
<li>setting</li>
<li>problem</li>
<li>solution</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Strategy: Active Reading </u></p>
<p>As you read a book to a child, talk about the story. This strategy turns a book into a lively conversation. Do not stop too much. If you do, the students may not understand the story. Keep it fun.</p>
<p>Ask questions about the story. This will help the child get more involved in the story. For early learners, ask easy questions. You can point to a picture in the book and ask, "What is this?" For more advanced learners, you can ask more difficult questions. For example, "What does this character want?"</p>
<p>When a student answers, give them feedback. "That's right! The character is sad because he is lost." Add to what the student said. "I was lost one time. And I felt really scared."</p>
<p><u>Strategy: Sequence</u></p>
<p>Putting events in the correct order (or <strong>sequence</strong>) is a great way to understand a story.</p>
<p>Why teach sequencing?</p>
<ul>
<li>It helps students of all levels to organize information. With beginning learners, you can use pictures too.</li>
<li>It teaches the structure of a story: beginning, middle, and end.</li>
<li>This strategy also tests a student's ability to re-tell a story in order or to summarize<strong> </strong>it.</li>
</ul>
<p>This strategy can be used with many kinds of writing. Students can sequence parts of a story or lines from a song or a poem. They can even sequence everyday activities - a math problem, or a <strong>recipe</strong> for making their favorite dish. Simply write or draw the text of a story or steps in a process. Then have students put the steps in order.</p>
<p><strong>Assessment for comprehension</strong></p>
<p>There are many types of reading comprehension assessments. Generally speaking, if a learner cannot do the following, they may have a problem with comprehension.</p>
<ul>
<li>They cannot tell you the main idea.</li>
<li>They cannot describe the characters or setting.</li>
<li>They cannot explain a character's thoughts or feelings.</li>
<li>They cannot connect a story to real life.</li>
<li>They can tell you what happened in a story but not why.</li>
<li>They cannot re-tell the story in their own words.</li>
<li>They cannot tell the events of the story in order.</li>
</ul>
<p>Apart from testing and assessment, experts suggest that teachers, parents, and caregivers should pay attention to the skills of describing, explaining, and connecting while reading with a child.</p>
<p>Experts add that adults should pay attention to what a child says. Comprehension may be a problem if a child says, "I couldn't follow the story," or simply, "I don't get it!"</p>
<p>Use these tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve you and your learners. Change them to fit your students and teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p>And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this article for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>decode </strong><em>–v.</em> to understand the hidden meaning of something</p>
<p><strong>summarize </strong><em>– v. </em>to express or cover the main points briefly</p>
<p><strong>visualize </strong><em>– v. </em>to see or form a mental image of</p>
<p><strong>sequence </strong><em>– v. </em>to arrange in an order</p>
<p><strong>recipe </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of instructions for making something from various ingredients</p>
<p><strong>character </strong><em>– n. </em>someone who appears in a book, movie; <strong> </strong>a representation of an individual personality in a fictional or dramatic work</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Surprised to Find Large Octopus Community  (2023/8/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/scientists-surprised-to-find-large-octopus-community.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Octopuses are not communal animals. Most live alone their entire lives.</p>
<p>So, scientists were surprised to find thousands of pearl octopuses living together as they protected their developing eggs. The community is on the ocean floor off the California coast.</p>
<p>Now, researchers may have solved the mystery of the strange pearl octopus behavior.</p><div class="contentImage"><img a="" alt="FILE - This 2019 image from video provided by MBARI shows female pearl octopuses nesting at the " ap="" approximately="" at="" california="" coast="" davidson="" depth="" garden="" meters.="" near="" octopus="" of="" off="" seamount="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9f089725-ea39-40a5-a885-c935cbdad3ce_w268_r1.jpg" the="" via=""/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This 2019 image from video provided by MBARI shows female pearl octopuses nesting at the "octopus garden" near the Davidson Seamount off the California coast at a depth of approximately 3,200 meters. (MBARI via AP)</span></div>
<p>An inactive underwater volcano heats the area where the mother octopuses settle. Their eggs <strong>hatch </strong>faster as a result.</p>
<p>"There are clear <strong>advantages </strong>of basically sitting in this natural hot tub," said Janet Voight. Voight is an octopus biologist at the Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago, Illinois. She co-wrote the study published in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://apnews.com/article/www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adg3247" target="_blank">Science Advances</a>.</p>
<p>The researchers found that the area's warmth greatly reduced the time it took for eggs to hatch. As a result, the eggs had a reduced risk of being eaten by snails, shrimp and other animals.</p>
<p>Researchers discovered the <strong>nesting</strong> area in 2018, calling it an "octopus garden."</p>
<p>Researchers used a robotic underwater vehicle to film the group of nearly 6,000 octopuses living around 3 kilometers deep.</p>
<p>The octopuses lay their eggs on warm rocks and then remain there, protecting their young with their bodies.</p>
<p>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration biologist Andrew DeVogelaere was a study co-writer. He described what researchers saw: "It was completely<strong> incredible</strong> – we suddenly saw thousands of pearly-colored octopus, all upside down, with their legs up in the air and moving around."</p>
<p>The octopus were pushing away possible predators and turning their eggs for an even flow of water and oxygen, he explained.</p>
<p>But scientists still did not know exactly why the octopuses had gathered there.</p>
<p>Scientists observed the area for three years to understand the hatching process. They recorded both the developmental stage of eggs at 31 nests and the deaths of octopus mothers.</p>
<p>"After the <strong>hatchlings</strong> come out of the nest and swim off immediately into the dark, the mothers, who never left their nest and never appeared to feed during nesting, soon die," said James Barry. Barry is a biologist at the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute and co-writer of the study.</p>
<p>The researchers found that eggs at this site hatch after about 21 months. The same process takes four years or more for other deep-sea octopuses.</p>
<p>"Usually, colder water slows down metabolism and embryonic development and extends life span in the deep sea. But here in this spot, warmth appears to speed things up," said Adi Khen. Khen is a biologist at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography and was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>Mike Vecchione is a zoologist and octopus expert with the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History. He praised the researchers for gathering "so much detailed data about such a <strong>remote</strong> location."</p>
<p>Such octopus gardens "may be widespread and really important in the deep sea," he said. "There's still so much to discover in the deep sea."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>hatch</strong> <em>– v. </em>to be born by coming out of an egg</p>
<p><strong>advantage</strong> <em>– n.</em> a good or desirable quality or feature</p>
<p><strong>nest </strong><em>– n.</em> a place where an animal lives and lays eggs</p>
<p><strong>incredible </strong><em>– adj.</em> difficult or impossible to believe</p>
<p><strong>hatchling</strong> <em>– n.</em> a very young creature that has just come out from an egg</p>
<p><strong>remote </strong><em>– adj.</em> far away from people, cities, etc.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Company Develops Digital ‘Clones’ of Individuals  (2023/8/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/japanese-company-develops-digital-clones-of-individuals.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A Japanese company is developing digital "<strong>clones</strong>" of individuals designed to take over some of a person's daily online duties.</p>
<p>The company is Tokyo-based Alt Incorporated. It is working on creating a digital double – an <strong>animated</strong> image that looks and talks just like its human owner.</p>
<p>The company's chief executive, Kazutaka Yonekura, told The Associated Press he believes such a double could make people's lives easier by helping them get more things done.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kazutaka Yonekura, head of Tokyo startup Alt Inc., demonstrates his digital clone on a personal computer in Tokyo, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Yuri Kageyama)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-996c-08dba7c483bc_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kazutaka Yonekura, head of Tokyo startup Alt Inc., demonstrates his digital clone on a personal computer in Tokyo, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Yuri Kageyama)</span></div>
<p>The digital clone, also called an avatar, could be used for things like carrying out early job interviews or communicating with a person's doctor ahead of a medical visit.</p>
<p>Yonekura said the main purpose of a digital double would be to "<strong>liberate</strong>" humans from the many daily duties. He showed AP reporters his own digital clone on a computer. It included an image and digitized version of his voice.</p>
<p>When his digital clone was asked, "What kind of music do you like," it waited several seconds before giving a long answer. The double explained that Yonekura favors lively music such as hip-hop or rock 'n' roll.</p>
<p>Yonekura argues that the technology he is developing is more personal than other digital assistants, such as Apple's Siri, Amazon's Alexa and Google Assistant. He said most importantly, the clone belongs to you and not the technology company that created it. Yonekura added that his developers had attempted to build tools into the system that are designed to prevent <strong>awkward</strong> social mistakes.</p>
<p>Currently, digital doubles are very costly. Each Alt clone costs about $140,000, so it will likely take time before there is a mass market for the clones.</p>
<p>Digital doubles are created by taking an individual's data from social media websites as well as publicly available records. The data is continuously changed and stored in the system. The data is designed to keep up with the individual's changing <strong>habits</strong> and activities.</p>
<p>Yonekura said he believes a digital clone could open the door for a society in which people can center on being more creative and waste less time on necessary daily activities.</p>
<p>The idea of a digital clone reportedly enjoys widespread appeal in Japan – the country that gave the world Pokemon, karaoke, Hello Kitty and emojis.</p>
<p>But Yonekura admits that cultures are different, and Westerners may not like the idea as much. "I can't tell you how many times I've been asked: Why does it have to be a personal clone, and not just a digital agent?" he said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>clone </strong><em>– n. </em>to make an exact copy of a person, animal or plant</p>
<p><strong>animate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make (something, such as a drawing) appear to move by creating a series of drawings, pictures, etc., and showing them quickly one after another</p>
<p><strong>liberate </strong><em>– v. </em>to help someone or something to be free</p>
<p><strong>awkward </strong><em>– adj. </em>difficult or causing problems</p>
<p><strong>habit </strong><em>– n. </em>something a person does regularly, almost without thinking about it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experimental Treatment Promises to Heal Some Eye Injuries  (2023/8/29) | 美国实验性手术有望治疗眼睛损伤</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/experimental-treatment-promises-to-heal-some-eye-injuries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>In 2017, a workplace accident resulted in Phil Durst losing sight in his left eye.<br/>
2017年，一场工作事故导致菲尔·德斯特左眼失明。</p>
<p>He experienced severe pain from the incident which left him unable to tolerate light. He also experienced severe headaches four or five times a day.<br/>
这次事故让他感到剧烈疼痛，并导致他无法忍受光线。他每天还会出现四五次剧烈头痛。</p>
<p>Then he underwent an experimental operation that aims to treat severe injuries in one eye with stem cells from the other eye.<br/>
然后他接受了一项实验性手术，旨在用另一只眼睛的干细胞治疗另一只眼睛的严重损伤。</p>
<p>Durst said he went from being completely blind to seeing well enough to drive. Regaining his sight was an emotional experience for the 51-year-old from Homewood, Alabama.<br/>
杜斯特说，他从完全失明到视力足够驾驶汽车。对于这位来自阿拉巴马州霍姆伍德的51岁的老人来说，重见光明是一次激动人心的经历。</p>
<p>Durst was one of four patients to get stem cell transplants as part of the first study to test the method in the United States. Although additional treatment is needed, experts say the stem cell transplant offers hope to people who are not getting results from other methods.<br/>
作为美国首次疗法测试研究的一部分，杜斯特是四名接受干细胞移植患者中的一员。虽然需要额外的治疗，但专家表示，干细胞移植为那些别无他法的人们带来了希望。</p>
<p>The experimental research results were published recently in Science Advances. A larger study is underway.<br/>
这项实验性研究结果最近发表在《科学进展》上。同时一项更大规模的研究正在进行中。</p>
<p>The operation is designed to treat "limbal stem cell deficiency." It is a disorder of part of the eye called the cornea. The problem happens after chemical burns and other injuries. Limbal cells are needed to keep the outer surface of the cornea healthy. Patients without limbal cells cannot have corneal transplants that are commonly used to improve sight.<br/>
这项手术旨在治疗“角膜缘干细胞缺乏症”，这是眼睛角膜部分的一种疾病。这种问题发生在化学烧伤和其他伤害之后。角膜外层的健康需要角膜细胞。没有角膜缘细胞的患者不能进行角膜移植，这是常用来改善视力的手段。</p>
<p>Dr. Ula Jurkunas is an ophthalmologist at the treatment center Mass Eye and Ear in Boston, Massachusetts. She was the main researcher for the study. She said the experimental method involves taking a few stem cells from the healthy eye, then expanding them and growing them on a graft. The research took place at a laboratory at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute in Boston.<br/>
 乌拉·尤尔库纳斯医生是马萨诸塞州波士顿市大众眼耳治疗中心的眼科医生。她是这项研究的主要研究员。她说，这种实验性方法包括从健康的眼睛中提取一些干细胞，然后将其扩增并在移植物上生长。这项研究是在波士顿癌症研究所的一个实验室进行的。</p>
<p>A few weeks later, the grafts are transplanted into the injured eye. Durst was the first patient to undergo the operation.<br/>
几周后，移植物被移植到受伤的眼睛里。德斯特是第一个接受手术的病人。</p>
<p>"The great part of it is that we're using a patient's own tissue," not donor tissue the body might reject, Jurkunas said.<br/>
尤尔库纳斯说：“最重要的是，我们使用的是患者自己的组织，”而不是身体可能会排斥的供体组织。</p>
<p>She said this method is better than a different operation that takes a very large piece of stem cells from a healthy eye for use on an injured eye – but risks damaging the good eye.<br/>
她说，这种方法比从健康的眼睛中取出一大块干细胞用于受伤的眼睛的另一种疗法要好，但是存在损伤健康眼睛的风险。</p>
<p>Both of Durst's eyes were hurt in the accident. For six to eight months, his sight was so bad that his wife or son had to lead him around. But his right eye was less injured than his left one and could provide stem cells for the transplant.<br/>
德斯特的两只眼睛都在事故中受伤。在六到八个月的时间里，他的视力非常差，以至于他的妻儿不得不领着他四处走动。但他的右眼比左眼受伤轻，可以为移植提供干细胞。</p>
<p>Jurkunas also works with Harvard Medical School. She said Durst's 2018 operation was the product of almost 20 years of research. She said the researchers were happy to finally do the operation.<br/>
尤尔库纳斯还跟哈佛医学院合作。她说，德斯特2018年做的手术是近20年研究的成果。她说，研究人员很高兴终于做了这项手术。</p>
<p>All patients in the study reported that their cornea surfaces improved to normal. Durst and another patient were then able to get transplants of man-made corneas. Two others reported improved sight with the stem cell transplant alone. A fifth patient did not receive the operation because the stem cells were not able to expand enough.<br/>
研究中的所有患者都报告称，他们的角膜表面已恢复正常。随后，德斯特和另一名患者得以进行人造角膜移植。另外两人报告称，光做了干细胞移植就提高了视力。第五名患者没有接受手术，因为干细胞不能充分扩增。</p>
<p>Durst said the vision in his right eye is nearly normal but the vision in his left could improve. He will have another operation in September to correct it.<br/>
德斯特说，他的右眼视力几乎正常，但左眼的视力有待改善。他将在9月份进行另一次手术来纠正这种情况。</p>
<p>Researchers are finishing the next step of the clinical trial, which includes 15 patients.<br/>
研究人员正在完成下一步的临床试验，该试验包括15名患者。</p>
<p>Jurkunas estimates that 1,000 people in the U.S. could be helped every year by this sort of stem cell transplant. The treatment has also been studied in Japan.<br/>
尤尔库纳斯估计，美国每年有1000人可以通过这种干细胞移植得到帮助。日本也对这种治疗方法进行了研究。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。<br/>
(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Son Taken at Birth Reunited with Chilean Mother after 42 Years  (2023/8/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/son-taken-at-birth-reunited-with-chilean-mother-after-42-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Forty-two years ago, hospital workers took Maria Angelica Gonzalez' son from her arms right after birth. Documents say they later told her he had died. Now, she was meeting him face-to-face at her home in Valdivia, Chile.</p>
<p>"I love you very much," Jimmy Lippert Thyden told his mother in Spanish as they hugged and cried.</p>
<p>"It <strong>knocked the wind out of</strong> me," Thyden told <em>The Associated Press</em> after the meeting.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Jimmy Thyden, right, sits with Maria Angelica Gonzalez, his Chilean birth mother, as they meet for the first time in Valdivia, Chile on Aug. 17, 2023.(Constanza Del Rio/Nos Buscamos via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6ef8-08dba7d80b44_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Jimmy Thyden, right, sits with Maria Angelica Gonzalez, his Chilean birth mother, as they meet for the first time in Valdivia, Chile on Aug. 17, 2023.(Constanza Del Rio/Nos Buscamos via AP)</span></div>
<p>His effort to find the birth family he never knew began in April. That was when he read news stories about <strong>adoptees</strong> who had been born in Chile and had been reunited with their birth relatives through a Chilean nonprofit group called Nos Buscamos.</p>
<p>The organization found that Thyden had been born <strong>prematurely</strong> at a hospital in Santiago, Chile's capital, and had been placed in an <strong>incubator</strong>. Gonzalez was told to leave the hospital, but when she returned to get her baby, she was told he had died and his body had been removed, documents say.</p>
<p>"The paperwork I have for my adoption tells me I have no living relatives. And I learned in the last few months that I have a mama and I have four brothers and a sister," Thyden said. He now lives in Ashburn, Virginia, where he works as a criminal defense lawyer.</p>
<p>He said his was a case of "<strong>counterfeit</strong> adoption."</p>
<p>The group Nos Buscamos estimates that tens of thousands of babies were taken from Chilean families in the 1970s and 1980s. That claim is based on a report from the Investigations Police of Chile, a civilian group, which examined the passports of Chilean children who left the country and never returned.</p>
<p>"The real story was these kids were stolen from poor families, poor women, that didn't know how to defend themselves," said Constanza del Rio, founder and director and Nos Buscamos.</p>
<p>The group said the disappearances took place during the rule of General Augusto Pinochet, who led the country for 17 years starting in 1973. Pinochet led a group which overthrew Marxist President Salvador Allende. Chile's government says at least 3,095 people were killed during that time.</p>
<p>Over the past nine years, Nos Buscamos has organized reunions for more than 450 adoptees and their birth families, del Rio said. Other nonprofit groups are doing similar work, both in Chile and the U.S.</p>
<p>Nos Buscamos has been partnering for two years with the <strong>genealogy</strong> company MyHeritage. MyHeritage gives DNA testing kits for use at home at no cost to Chilean adoptees and suspected victims of child trafficking in Chile.</p>
<p>Thyden's DNA test result said that he was 100 percent Chilean. It said he was related to another person who also uses MyHeritage. The website said the person was a first cousin.</p>
<p>Thyden sent the cousin his adoption documents, which included an address for his birth mother and a very common name in Chile: Maria Angelica Gonzalez. His cousin had a Maria Angelica Gonzalez on their mother's side and helped him make the connection.</p>
<p>Thyden said his reunion with his birth family was a success. But, he knows that reunification might not go as well for other adoptees.</p>
<p>"It could have been a much worse story," he said. "There are people who find out some really unfortunate details about their <strong>origin</strong>."</p>
<p>While in Chile, Thyden and del Rio met with one of seven investigators working on thousands of counterfeit adoption cases like his own. Thyden also met with Juan Gabriel Valdes, the Chilean ambassador to the United States, to seek government recognition of the adoption <strong>scheme</strong>.</p>
<p>He said there was no way to assist Chilean adoptees in their efforts to visit their home country. Thyden said he sold a truck to pay for his family's airplane tickets and other costs.</p>
<p>He said, "People need to be able to decide...what their name is going to be, where their citizenship is going to be...They should have all the rights and <strong>privileges</strong> of a Chilean citizen because this is a thing that happened to them, not that they chose."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p>And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>knock the wind out of </strong>–idiom to suddenly not be able to breathe because of a physical blow or from surprise and astonishment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>adoption </strong><em>— n. </em>the process of legally taking the child of another person as your own</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>premature </strong><em>— adj. </em>something that happens too early</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>incubator </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>a device in a hospital that protects newborn babies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>counterfeit </strong><em>—</em><em> adj. </em>a copy of something that is meant to deceive others</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>genealogy </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>the history of a family showing who is related to who</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>origin </strong><em>— n. </em>the place that a person or thing comes from</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scheme </strong><em>–n.</em> an organized plan</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>privileges </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> special rights or things that a person may have</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Neptune’s Disappearing Clouds Linked to Solar Cycle  (2023/8/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-neptune-s-disappearing-clouds-linked-to-solar-cycle.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists say they have discovered new evidence that cloud activity on Neptune is linked to atmospheric changes on the planet caused by the sun.</p>
<p>Researchers say the evidence is based on observations collected by several telescopes over a period of nearly 30 years. Data was collected by the Hubble Space Telescope – operated by the American space agency NASA – as well as the W.M. Keck Observatory in Hawaii and the Lick Observatory in California.</p>
<p>Astronomers recorded atmospheric changes on Neptune as they examined the cloud data. The researchers found that the changes followed the sun's natural cycle. Each natural <strong>cycle</strong>, known as the solar cycle, lasts about 11 years.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Image of Neptune, from Webb's Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam). (Courtesy of NASA, ESA, CSA, STScI)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/03370000-0aff-0242-4e5a-08daf2b265d8_cx12_cy9_cw87_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Image of Neptune, from Webb's Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam). (Courtesy of NASA, ESA, CSA, STScI)</span></div>
<p>During this cycle, the sun's magnetic field completely <strong>flips</strong>. This means the sun's north and south magnetic poles change places. They then flip back after another 11 years. Before the flip, a major increase in solar activity happens. This can send powerful collections of solar particles shooting through space.</p>
<p>The scientists who examined the telescope data said they found that Neptune appeared brightest in 2002, then <strong>dimmed</strong> in 2007. The planet became bright again in 2015, but then darkened in 2020 to the dimmest level ever observed.</p>
<p>The team said the observations also showed Neptune lost nearly all of its clouds beginning in 2019.</p>
<p>Astronomers at the University of California, Berkeley (UC Berkeley) led the research. They recently reported their findings <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0019103523002440?via%3Dihub">in a study</a> in the publication <em>Icarus</em>.</p>
<p>Imke de Pater is a retired professor of astronomy at UC Berkeley and was the lead writer of the study. She <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.keckobservatory.org/neptune-clouds/">said</a> in a statement she was surprised by how quickly clouds disappeared on Neptune. She noted cloud activity had dropped sharply "within a few months."</p>
<p>"Even four years later, the images we took this past June showed the clouds haven't returned to their former levels," said Erandi Chavez. She is a student at Harvard University's Center for Astrophysics who took part in the study while at UC Berkeley.</p>
<p>"This is extremely exciting and unexpected," Chavez said. She noted the finding was unusual "since Neptune's previous period of low cloud activity was not nearly as <strong>dramatic</strong> and <strong>prolonged</strong>."</p>
<p>Neptune, about four times wider than Earth, is the eighth and most distant major planet orbiting our sun, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/planets/neptune/overview/">says</a>. It receives sunlight with only about 0.1 percent intensity of our planet. For this reason, the researchers found it surprising that Neptune would be heavily influenced by solar activity. The planet also receives intense winds that can blow around clouds.</p>
<p>The scientists looked at images captured by the different telescopes. They discovered clear <strong>patterns</strong> between seasonal changes in Neptune's cloud cover and the solar cycle. The team found that during periods when the sun gave off more intense ultraviolet (UV) light, more clouds appeared on the planet two years later.</p>
<p>De Pater said the newly discovered data provides "the strongest evidence yet that Neptune's cloud cover <strong>correlates</strong> with the sun's cycle." He added the findings "support the theory that the sun's UV rays, when strong enough, may be <strong>triggering</strong> a photochemical reaction that produces Neptune's clouds." Photochemical is a term relating to how chemicals are affected by light.</p>
<p>The researchers are continuing to follow cloud activity on Neptune. They noted that the latest images taken of the planet, in June 2023, showed clouds started to return. The team says this finding further strengthens their evidence. This is because the scientists see a link between the increasing cloud cover and the release of intense UV light over the past two years.</p>
<p>The researchers say further study is needed to confirm their latest results. They say the research will be important not only for learning more about Neptune, but can also help scientists gain a better understanding of how similar planets outside our solar system behave.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA, the University of California,</em> <em>UC Berkeley and the W.M. Keck Observatory.</em> <em> </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cycle </strong><em>– n. </em>a series of events that happen in a particular order and are often repeated</p>
<p><strong>flip </strong><em>– v. </em>to turn something onto a different side</p>
<p><strong>dim </strong><em>– adj. </em>not bright or clear</p>
<p><strong>dramatic </strong><em>– adj. </em>very sudden or noticeable</p>
<p><strong>prolonged </strong><em>– adj. </em>continuing for a long time</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong><em>– n. </em>a particular way something is done or repeated</p>
<p><strong>correlate </strong><em>– v. </em>link pieces of information or things together</p>
<p><strong>trigger </strong><em>– v. </em>to make something begin to happen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Drug Officials Approve RSV Vaccine for Pregnant Women  (2023/8/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-drug-officials-approve-rsv-vaccine-for-pregnant-women.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>American food and drug officials recently approved the first RSV vaccine for pregnant women. The drug will <strong>inoculate</strong> the fetus and provide protection from the dangerous lung disease at birth.</p>
<p>RSV stands for respiratory syncytial virus. RSV cases fill hospitals with<strong> wheezing</strong> babies every fall and winter. Pfizer's newly approved vaccine will mean babies can be protected against RSV at birth. Experts say this will guard against severe RSV infections when babies are most <strong>vulnerable</strong> — from birth through 6 months.</p>
<p>The drug is named Abrysvo. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must issue guidelines, or recommendations, for use of Abrysvo during pregnancy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Pfizer shows the RSV vaccine. U.S. regulators on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023, approved the first RSV vaccine for pregnant women so their babies will be born with protection against the scary respiratory infection. (Pfizer via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/69e63351-c881-4a9d-a91c-418e83c28c0e_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Pfizer shows the RSV vaccine. U.S. regulators on Monday, Aug. 21, 2023, approved the first RSV vaccine for pregnant women so their babies will be born with protection against the scary respiratory infection. (Pfizer via AP)</span></div>
<p>"Maternal vaccination is an <strong>incredible</strong> way to protect the infants," said Dr. Elizabeth Schlaudecker of Cincinnati Children's Hospital in Ohio. Schlaudecker was among the researchers in Pfizer's international study of the vaccine. If shots begin soon, she said, "I do think we could see an <strong>impact </strong>for this RSV season."</p>
<p>RSV is a minor sickness for most healthy people but it can be life-threatening for the very young. It swells babies' airways, making breathing difficult. It can also lead to the disease pneumonia. In the U.S. alone, the disease leads to hospital stays for between 58,000 and 80,000 children under the age of 5 each year. It kills several hundred a year.</p>
<p>Last year's RSV season was bad in the U.S. It began sickening young children in the summer, far earlier than usual.</p>
<p>Babies are born with an under-developed defense<strong> </strong>system. They depend on their mothers for disease protection in the first few months after birth.</p>
<p>Here is how the RSV vaccination treatment will work: A single injection late in pregnancy gives enough time for the mother to develop antibodies. These pass to the fetus and are ready to work at birth.</p>
<p>It is the same way pregnant women pass along protection against other infections. Pregnant women have long been urged to get flu and whooping cough vaccines, and more recently, COVID-19 shots.</p>
<p>Pfizer's study included nearly 7,400 pregnant women and their babies. Maternal vaccination did not prevent mild RSV infection. However, it proved 82 percent effective at preventing a severe case during the first three months after birth. At age 6 months, it still was proving 69 percent effective against severe sickness.</p>
<p>Vaccine reactions were mostly tiredness and pain at the site of injection. In the study, there was a small difference in early birth — just a few weeks early — between vaccinated moms and those given an inactive shot. Pfizer has said that outcome was due to chance. The FDA said to avoid the possibility of early birth, the vaccination should take place between 32 weeks and 36 weeks of pregnancy. The researchers vaccinated the study patients a few weeks earlier in the process.</p>
<p>If enough pregnant women get vaccinated, Pfizer predicts the U.S. could prevent as many as 20,000 infant hospitalizations a year and 320,000 doctor visits.</p>
<p>The only other way to guard babies from RSV is to give them lab-made antibodies. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration also recently approved a new drug for all infants younger than 8 months. Called Beyfortus, it is a single <strong>dose</strong> treatment given before a baby's first RSV season. Sanofi and AstraZeneca made the drug, which is supposed to be available this fall.</p>
<p>Schlaudecker, the Cincinnati Children's Hospital doctor, predicts that doctors will try a combination of the treatments when they become available.</p>
<p>Another Cincinnati Children's Hospital doctor volunteered to take part in Pfizer's vaccine study when she became pregnant. Dr. Maria Deza Leon has cared for seriously sick RSV patients in her work.</p>
<p>"The last thing a parent wants to see is their kid struggling to breathe," she said. "I was also at risk of being the person that could get RSV and give it to my son without even realizing."</p>
<p>Deza Leon received her shot in late January 2022 and her son Joaquin was born the following month. The doctor has not yet learned if she received the vaccine or the inactive shot. However, Joaquin is a healthy little boy who has never had a confirmed case of RSV.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inoculate </strong><em>— v.</em> to introduce material (as a vaccine) into the body especially by injection to protect against or treat a disease</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>wheeze </strong><em>— v. </em> to breathe with difficulty usually with a whistling sound</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable</strong> <em>— adj. </em>open to attack or damage</p>
<p><strong>incredible </strong><em>— adj</em>.<strong> </strong>extraordinary</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>— n.</em> a forceful effect</p>
<p><strong>dose </strong><em>— n.</em><strong> </strong>the measured amount of a medicine to be taken at one time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Stone Carvers Carry on Tradition in Mexico  (2023/8/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/stone-carvers-carry-on-tradition-in-mexico.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>On most Sundays, the sound of hammers and other tools hitting stone can be heard in the burial area of ancient Xochiaca. It is a village in the Chimalhuacan area, on Mexico City's east side.</p>
<p>The sounds come from stone <strong>carvers</strong> who still work on a <strong>craft</strong> that has been passed down for generations - even after the local source of stone was used up.</p>
<p>The village burial area, or cemetery, is filled with meter-high statues of religious figures and other beautiful stone objects.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Master stone carver Tom&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;s Ugarte sculpts quarry at the cemetery in the Mexico City borough of Chilmalhuacan, once the ancient village of Xochiaca, Sunday, July 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Aurea Del Rosario)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1291e09f-b21d-4527-bac8-3bd9733da7a9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Master stone carver Tom<i>&amp;#</i>225;s Ugarte sculpts quarry at the cemetery in the Mexico City borough of Chilmalhuacan, once the ancient village of Xochiaca, Sunday, July 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Aurea Del Rosario)
</span></div>
<p>Generations of stone carvers in Chimalhuacan also created much of the stonework found on buildings and parks in the capital's downtown.</p>
<p>While carvers in other areas long ago turned to mechanical devices, the workers here use only hammers and other special hand tools.</p>
<p>Many are self-taught, but some, like Tomás Ugarte, age 86, learned in the traditional way. This method of rock cutting has been passed down between family members, dating back about five generations.</p>
<p>The rock cutters are generally older. There were about 600 official stone carvers about 10 years ago. Now, there are probably only around 300, said Carolina Montesinos Mendoza of the state office that supports traditional skills. The carvers are dying and their children generally do not want to take up the trade.</p>
<p>Still, the stone carvers keep the old traditions alive. Many people in the area use stone <strong>mortars</strong> and <strong>pestles</strong> made by the stone carvers. Known as "molcajetes" in Spanish, these bowl-like objects are the basic tool for making salsas.</p>
<p>Rev. Alberto Sandoval, who has known the stone workers since 1990, described them as "the backbone of the community."</p>
<p>Most of the carvers have individual work areas at home, which provide them with some money. They sell carvings for prices ranging from $500 to $2,000. But the stone carvers often do not sell much.</p>
<p>Unlike many craftspeople who want to see their works shown in<strong> museums</strong>, the carvers here work free of charge to create and maintain carvings for the local cemetery.</p>
<p>They also work for free at <strong>decorating</strong> and repairing the stonework at the 250-year-old local church, Santa María de Guadalupe.</p>
<p>One of the earliest signs of the stone carvers' work is a carved stone on the ground reading "Xochiaca, home of the stone carvers." It does not have a date.</p>
<p>The writing talks about a time when the lake that once covered much of the valley still touched Xochiaca. Builders would come looking for carvings and ship them to Mexico City on ships over the lake.</p>
<p>Juan Alfaro Bastidas, 75, is a carver, just as his father and grandfather were. He remembers going into the rock mines, or quarries, by candlelight to get blocks of stone.</p>
<p>But the quarries are just a memory now.</p>
<p>The land where the quarries stood was sold for housing developments.</p>
<p>Now, the carvers truck in stone from other states to the north and to the west, but sometimes from as far away as the southern state of Yucatan.</p>
<p>They get some help from the local government and local people.</p>
<p>"The neighbors have helped us out with donations of 100 or 200 pesos ($6 to $12). The people of the town buy the stone," said Bastidas.</p>
<p>Asked if the trade will survive, carver Mario Olivares read a poem written on the church wall: "Your art, your tradition, your culture and the <strong>nobility</strong> of the people keep the soul of this town alive."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Fabiola Sanchez and Gerardo Carrillo reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>______________________________</strong></h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>carve</strong><em> – v.</em> to make a sculpture or design by cutting off pieces of the material it is made of</p>
<p><strong>craft </strong><em>-- n.</em><strong> </strong>: an activity that involves making something in a skillful way by using your hands</p>
<p><strong>mortar</strong><em>– n. </em>a heavy, deep bowl in which seeds, spices, etc., are pounded or crushed with a heavy tool (called a pestle)</p>
<p><strong>pestle</strong> <em>– n.</em> the heavy tool that goes with a mortar</p>
<p><strong>museum </strong><em>– n.</em> a building in which interesting and valuable things are collected and shown to the public</p>
<p><strong>decorate </strong><em>– v.</em> to make (something) more attractive usually by putting something on it</p>
<p><strong>nobility</strong> <em>– n.</em> the quality or state of being noble in character or quality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India’s Rice Export Restrictions Affects Asia, Africa  (2023/8/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/india-s-rice-export-restrictions-affects-asia-africa.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>India's decision to halt some rice exports to prevent high prices at home has had affects stretching across Asia to Africa, observers say.</p>
<p>Rice prices in Kenya, for example, jumped when Russia invaded Ukraine. Russia is a big producer of fertilizer. That problem combined with years of little rain in the Horn of Africa hurt East Africa's rice production. Low-cost rice from India helped fill Africa's needs, feeding hundreds of thousands of people who live in poor areas of Nairobi on less than $2 a day.</p>
<p>But the price of a 25-kilogram container of rice in Kenya has risen by more than 12 percent, or more than $14 since June. Importers there say they have not received shipments from India.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE- Laborers stack rice in a private warehouse in Makhu, in the Indian state of Punjab, March 12, 2021. (AP Photo/Manish Swarup, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9d94-08dba4149411_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE- Laborers stack rice in a private warehouse in Makhu, in the Indian state of Punjab, March 12, 2021. (AP Photo/Manish Swarup, File)</span></div>
<p>Fifty-one-year-old Francis Ndege has been selling rice to the poor in Nairobi for 30 years. He said, "I'm really hoping the imports keep coming."</p>
<p>Cutting food exports is part of India's effort to keep prices at home low to prevent widespread public anger at the government. The restrictions, however, take 9.5 million metric tons off the worldwide market. That is about a fifth of rice exports worldwide.</p>
<p><strong>An inflection point</strong></p>
<p>In addition to India's moves, the Associated Press reports that Vietnam's rice export prices have reached a 15 year high. And Russia, which had earlier agreed to permitted agricultural exports from Ukraine, withdrew a United Nations-supported deal last month.</p>
<p>Beau Damen works with natural resources in Bangkok for the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization. He said the world is at an "<strong>inflection point</strong>."</p>
<p>Even before India restricted rice exports, countries were buying rice with the expectation that supplies would soon be limited.</p>
<p>Some observers worry that other nations will follow India. The AP reports that the United Arab Emirates has suspended rice exports to preserve supplies although it is not a supplier. Other observers worry that bad weather will affect rice harvests. They are saying the El Ni<i></i>241;o ocean event could affect harvests in many countries.</p>
<p>El Ni<i></i>241;o is a warm southern Pacific Ocean current that affects weather across a large area of the world. It takes place regularly but is difficult to predict.</p>
<p><strong>Rice demand in Africa growing</strong></p>
<p>In Africa, rice <strong>consumption</strong> has been growing regularly. Most countries depend heavily on imports. Some African nations with growing populations are trying to grow their own rice. But the results have not been what some had hoped.</p>
<p>Amadou Khan is a 52-year-old unemployed father of five children in Dakar. He said his children eat rice with every meal except breakfast. He said his family is "just getting by."</p>
<p>Seventy percent of Senegal's imported rice comes from India, but it is now too costly. So, Khan is buying rice grown at home which is two-thirds the price.</p>
<p>Senegal's agriculture ministry said more than half of the country's demand is grown locally. The ministry said Senegal is not "far from being <strong>self-sufficient</strong>."</p>
<p>Asian countries grow and use 90 percent of the world's rice. But even in Asia, some countries are struggling. The Philippines, for example, had an estimated 22 percent of its yearly production damaged by Typhoon Doksuri. The U.S. Department of Agriculture says the Philippines is the second largest rice importer after China.</p>
<p><strong>‘No one wants to take the risk'</strong></p>
<p>India's export restrictions and production problems blamed on the weather there make it an undependable export partner. That is what Ashok Gulati of the Indian Council for Research and International Economic relations said. He added, "That's not good for the export business because it takes years to develop these markets."</p>
<p>Vietnam hopes to make gains during the current market movements. With prices high, it hopes to increase production. The Agriculture Ministry also wants to use more land in the Mekong Delta to grow rice. The Philippines is negotiating with Vietnam to get favorable prices. Vietnam also wants to target Britain, which gets rice from India.</p>
<p>Thailand is another big rice producer. The government expects to export more rice this year than last. Exports in the first six months of 2023 were 15 percent higher than the same period last year.</p>
<p>But the situation in India has farmers and traders worried. Charoen Laothamatas is president of the Thai Rice Exporters Association. He said farmers are raising prices for <strong>unmilled </strong>rice and mill operators, who process the rice, are unwilling to sell it. The millers want to get the best price under current market conditions.</p>
<p>Lack of clarity about supplies leaves exporters unsure about prices and leads to an unwillingness to sell.</p>
<p>As a result, Laothamatas noted, "No one wants to take the risk."</p>
<p>I'm Dorothy Gundy. And I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted this Associated Press report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>inflection point</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. (math) </em>the point where a process changes suddenly or in an important way</p>
<p><strong>consumption</strong> <em>–n.</em> the act of using or buying some product</p>
<p><strong>self-sufficient </strong>–adj. able to live or operate without assistance from others</p>
<p><strong>unmilled </strong>–adj. grain that is not processed with machinery to remove undesirable parts of the seed</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Some Community Colleges Offer Free College Credit for High Schoolers  (2023/8/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/some-community-colleges-offer-free-college-credit-for-high-schoolers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Kara Baker recently graduated from high school in the state of Indiana. She earned more than a high school <strong>diploma</strong>, however. She also completed a two-year <strong>associate degree</strong> at the local community college, Ivy Tech.</p>
<p>This summer, Baker is taking more classes at Ivy Tech before beginning her studies at Purdue University, also in Indiana. She hopes to become a <strong>veterinarian</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE --Terre Haute Campus, Ivy Tech Community College (Courtesy photo, Ivy Tech Community College)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a1b3-08db92a3706c_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE --Terre Haute Campus, Ivy Tech Community College (Courtesy photo, Ivy Tech Community College)</span></div>
<p>In many areas in the U.S., students can earn college credit at community colleges while they are still in high school. Many of these programs are called dual-credit programs.</p>
<p>And in recent years, some community colleges have begun offering <strong>courses</strong> to high schoolers at no cost during the summer.</p>
<p>Programs like these aim to get more students to enter community college and to help them finish programs they have already started.</p>
<p>The National Student Clearinghouse Research Center provides reporting on issues in education. It said <strong>enrollment</strong> at community colleges has decreased by nearly 40 percent over the past 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Free summer programs for high school students</strong></p>
<p>Baker said she was looking for programs to help her recover time lost in her education during the COVID-19 pandemic. Ivy Tech was the answer.</p>
<p>"I felt very behind <strong>due to</strong> Covid," Baker says. "[High] school slowed down, but my online college classes continued on. I was so grateful."</p>
<p>With 43 <strong>campuses</strong> across the state of Indiana, Ivy Tech has the most students of any community college system in the U.S.</p>
<p>During the 2019-2020 school year, there were over 63,000 Indiana high school students in Ivy Tech's dual-credit program. But the COVID-19 pandemic made it more difficult for some students to finish the program.</p>
<p>As a result, Ivy Tech began its "Crossing the Finish Line" program in summer of 2021. The program lets high school students who are close to finishing their studies at Ivy Tech take their remaining classes at no cost during the summer.</p>
<p>The program saw completion of 714 programs of study in summer of 2021, and an additional 900 during the 2021-22 school year. Students paid for any courses they had to finish during the fall or spring.</p>
<p>The results of the Crossing the Finish Line program were good. So, in 2022, Ivy Tech began offering free college credit courses in summer to high school students, even if they were not in a dual-credit program. Any student from grades nine through 12 who meets the requirements may take the summer classes.</p>
<p>In the U.S., students from grades 9-12 are usually between 14 and 18 years old.</p>
<p>Including both the Crossing the Finish Line and other free summer courses, this year nearly 8,000 Indiana high schoolers are taking free college classes at Ivy Tech.</p>
<p><strong>Saving money and time</strong></p>
<p>Officials at Ivy Tech said the free classes have saved students and their families about 6.5 million dollars this summer. A three-credit class at Ivy Tech usually costs students about $510.</p>
<p>The Indiana Department of Education pays for the Crossing the Finish Line program, while Ivy Tech is spending about 3.6 million dollars to pay for other summer classes.</p>
<p>Baker told VOA Learning English that the college classes might save her up to two years of college credit as she works towards becoming a veterinarian. For her, the college credit she received means less money spent on student loans.</p>
<p>"As I look at future student loans, I am grateful for the opportunities Ivy Tech presented," she said.</p>
<p>Seeing students finish their programs and continue in higher education makes the cost worth it, said Monica Marianna Hingst. She is Interim Vice President for K-14 and Strategic Initiatives at Ivy Tech.</p>
<p>"Getting students to come here and take courses for free is great. It's even better when it's aligned toward a completion, because once you earn that certification, or once you earn that degree, you are now setting yourself up for success."</p>
<p><strong>Northern Virginia Community College</strong></p>
<p>Northern Virginia Community College (NOVA) is one of the largest community college systems in the U.S. Its JumpStart2NOVA program permits students who finish high school in the spring to take college courses for free during the summer. NOVA started the program in 2020 to help students continue their education during the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>In addition to classes, students receive free online help with their studies. They can also attend free weekly information sessions on how to succeed in their education.</p>
<p>There are about 700 students in the program this year. JumpStart2NOVA helps both the students, the community college, and the local community, said Dr. Eun-Woo Chang, Chief Academic Officer at NOVA.</p>
<p>He noted that having more students finish their programs of study helps provide skilled workers for the local economy.</p>
<p>"It's a good investment to make them to stay at NOVA and also Northern Virginia, so this helps the regional economy here."</p>
<p>He added, "Community colleges are in the community that needs a lot more resources...they are underserved. We are here for them."</p>
<p>Chemeketa Community College is in the state of Oregon. Its BOLT program offers 12 different five-week college credit courses for free for up to 450 students in the summer. The students must be entering or finishing their last year of high school. Like the program at Ivy Tech in Indiana, the BOLT program also pays for the cost of textbooks.</p>
<p>Chemeketa designed the BOLT program because Covid-19 affected the schools in the area. The program supports students who have fewer chances to take college courses for credit.</p>
<p><strong>Ready for college</strong></p>
<p>Back in Indiana, Kara Baker adds that Ivy Tech has helped her with more than time and money.</p>
<p>"Ivy Tech took my learning and thinking to that next level. I feel I am better prepared to manage the college experience," she said.</p>
<p>Baker added, "I felt I was driven more as a student, as I saw a more diverse future outlook compared to my fellow high school students."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>diploma </strong><em>–n.</em> a document that shows a person has completed a course of study from a school</p>
<p><strong>associate degree </strong><em>–n.</em> a degree after high school of two or three years that does not provide a bachelor's degree</p>
<p><strong>veterinarian </strong><em>–n.</em> a doctor for animals<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>course </strong><em>–n.</em> a class; a series of classes that lead to a degree</p>
<p><strong>enrollment </strong><em>–n.</em> the process of being accepted for study and entering a school, especially a college or university</p>
<p><strong>due to </strong><em>–conj.</em> because of; thanks to something</p>
<p><strong>campus </strong><em>–n.</em> the grounds or place of an organization especially a college or university</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Does 'On a Shoestring' Mean?  (2023/8/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/what-does-on-a-shoestring-mean.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give you definitions, examples, and notes on usage. Sometimes we even use them in conversations.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a common object. Shoestrings are very useful for keeping our shoes on. But they are also useful for describing a situation where money is <strong>tight</strong>, meaning there is not much of it.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A woman ties up her shoestrings on her sneakers. (Adobe stock image)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-362b-08dba4f2575c_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpeg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A woman ties up her shoestrings on her sneakers. (Adobe stock image)</span></div>
<p>A budget is the amount of money available for some purpose. So, if you are <u>on a shoestring budget</u>, you do not have a lot of money. You have just enough <u>to get by</u>. If you can <u>get by</u> on very little money, you are able to live on a shoestring. Sometimes we shorten this expression and just say "on a shoestring."</p>
<p>We have other ways of describing this situation. For example, you might say you are <u>living paycheck-to-paycheck</u>. This means you get your paycheck but by the time your next one comes, you have used all your money to pay your bills.</p>
<p>Living paycheck-to-paycheck can also be called <u>living hand-to-mouth</u>. The money goes right into your hand and then you must buy the most <strong>basic</strong> of <strong>necessities</strong> – food. You do not have money to spend on extras. Everything you <strong>earn</strong> goes to pay for your immediate needs – things like, food, shelter, medicine, and transportation.</p>
<p>But now let's go back to our shoestrings. You can do a lot of things "on a shoestring."</p>
<p>For example, if you can <u>travel on a shoestring</u>, you travel very <strong>cheaply</strong>. You do not spend money on costly hotels. You look for good deals. You might use <strong>coupons</strong>, <strong>discount </strong>offers or other ways to save money. And you may plan to travel at less costly times. People who travel on a shoestring are often called <u>budget travelers</u>.</p>
<p>I learned how to travel on a shoestring when I studied in China. As a student, I did not have much money. So I traveled everywhere by train and stayed at universities. Traveling on a shoestring let me go to many more places.</p>
<p>But how did shoestring come to describe a tight budget – one with little money? Well, some word experts say it comes from people who sold small items on the streets. These items often included shoestrings.</p>
<p>Now let's hear two friends use this expression.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, I hear you're going on vacation next week. Where are you off to?</em></p>
<p><em>B: First, I'm going to Paris and then heading to Barcelona. Finally I'll finish up my trip in Milan. </em></p>
<p><em>A: That is some trip! You must have saved up for a long time to have enough money for that kind of travel budget. </em></p>
<p><em>B: Not at all! I am an expert at <u>traveling anywhere on a shoestring</u>. In Paris, I'm staying with friends. In Barcelona, I found a cheap<strong> dorm room</strong> at a university. And in Milan, I'm working on a farm in exchange for a free room and meals. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Wow, you are REALLY good at shoestring travel. By not spending a lot of money on hotels, you're able to go to more places. </em></p>
<p><em>B: Exactly!</em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and This Stories.</em></p>
<p>Are you learning English on a shoestring? If so, keep listening to VOA Learning English. Our high-quality content is free!</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tight </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong>characterized by such difficulty</p>
<p><strong>basic </strong><em>– adj. </em>of, relating to, or forming the base or basis</p>
<p><strong>necessity </strong><em>– n. </em>something that is necessary</p>
<p><strong>earn </strong><em>– v. </em>to receive money in return for effort and especially for work done or services completed</p>
<p><strong>cheaply </strong><em>– adv. </em>available at low cost or at less than the true value</p>
<p><strong>coupon </strong><em>– n. </em>a voucher entitling the holder to a discount for a particular product</p>
<p><strong>discount </strong><em>– adj. </em>selling goods or services for less than their regular</p>
<p><strong>dorm room </strong><em>– n. a large sleeping room containing several beds in a college of university</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Medicinal Earthworms Sought in Vietnam to Fill Chinese Demand  (2023/8/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/medicinal-earthworms-sought-in-vietnam-to-fill-chinese-demand.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>China is facing a continuing decrease in its supply of earthworms used for medicine. Hunters in Vietnam are attempting to catch the animals to meet Chinese demand.</p>
<p>Chinese traditional medicine uses earthworms to treat several conditions, including fever, arthritis and lung problems. But overhunting has made it difficult to keep harvesting the animals in China.</p>
<p>This has led hunters in Vietnam to dig up earthworms to sell to Chinese companies. However, Vietnamese farmers depend on the animals to keep their fields fertile and the environment balanced. The earthworm harvesting, mainly in northern areas of the country, is hurting farming operations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Earthworms are being dried for use in Chinese medicine." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-97d3-08db99aeeac7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Earthworms are being dried for use in Chinese medicine.</span></div>
<p>Chinese buyers are offering a lot of money for earthworms, Vietnam's <em>VnExpress</em> recently reported. The harvests are taking place unlawfully at private fields and fruit farms, the news service said.</p>
<p>The hunts have led orange farmers in Hoa Binh province to carry out 24-hour guard operations to stop the <strong>poachers</strong>, Vietnam's <em>VTC News</em> reported. The farmers have asked Vietnamese agriculture officials for help. VOA's Vietnamese service contacted the country's Agriculture Ministry for comment, but did not receive an answer.</p>
<p>Catching earthworms is "easy money" for poachers, the <em>Vietnamnet</em> newspaper reported, with each kilogram of wet earthworms bringing in between $3 to $3.30. Some poachers can capture up to 100 to 120 kilograms of earthworms per night, earning hundreds of dollars, <em>Vietnamnet</em> said.</p>
<p>Hunters use electric signals to drive earthworms up to the surface. The animals are then processed before being sold to Chinese sellers, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>The harvesting activities have led to an "<strong>extinction</strong>-level ecological disaster" in China. Poachers who now face police enforcement in China are looking to Vietnam for earthworms.</p>
<p>Biologist Nguyen Lan Hung is a professor at Hanoi's National University of Education and chief of Vietnam's Association for Biological Sciences. He told VOA the usefulness of earthworms has a long history in traditional medicine.</p>
<p>"During the anti-French independence war, our soldiers used to eat earthworms to treat malaria," Hung said. He noted that they are now used to make heart and brain drugs. Hung suggested setting up legal farming of earthworms to prevent poaching. The country already has experience raising worms used for breaking down substances in soil.</p>
<p>Vo Tong Xuan is an agronomist who is also president of Vietnam's Nam Can Tho University. Both Xuan and Hung warned that the collection process damages the quality of the soil, crops and overall agriculture environment. Without earthworms, soil can become hard and roots find it difficult to draw in water, Xuan said. This can harm plant growth and also cause flooding.</p>
<p>Xuan said he would like Vietnam to criminalize the gathering of earthworms with electricity. For now, poachers are only detained and released after police seize their devices and captures, <em>VTC News</em> reported.</p>
<p>The earthworm is not the only in-demand product in China that has been sought in Vietnam. In the past, this has included buffalo hooves, <strong>leeches</strong> and nut products for use in traditional medicine. Those efforts also caused environmental damage in Vietnam.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Le Nguyen reported this story for VOA News. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>poach </strong><em>– v. </em>to illegally catch of kill animals</p>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>– n. </em>a situation in which a kind of animal no longer exists</p>
<p><strong>leech </strong><em>– n. </em>a kind of worm that lives in wet places and attaches itself to the bodies of humans and animals to feed on their blood</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>William Taft: Heavy  (2023/8/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/americans-presidents-william-taft.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>
VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about William Howard Taft, who took office in 1909.</p>
<p>In some ways, the story of Taft's presidency is also a story about <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-theodore-roosevelt/3986653.html" target="_blank">Theodore Roosevelt</a>'s presidency. Roosevelt had been president for the eight years before Taft. The two men were friends; Roosevelt was even a <strong>mentor</strong> to Taft.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - William Howard Taft" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a40e80e0-d613-407f-b1ab-22281965da8c_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - William Howard Taft</span></div>
<p>But the two men were very different. Roosevelt was energetic, both in his physical abilities and in his use of executive power. His vision for the country was progressive.</p>
<p>In <strong>contrast</strong>, Taft was a more conservative, heavy man who fell asleep in meetings, and who did not make decisions quickly.</p>
<p>In fact, Americans often remember Taft because of his size. His weight changed frequently, but as president Taft usually weighed about 135 kilograms.</p>
<p>One popular story claims that Taft got stuck in a White House bathtub. This story is not true. However, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://constitutioncenter.org/blog/why-william-howard-taft-was-probably-never-stuck-in-his-bathtub/">it is true</a> that Taft had a special bathtub made for him. Several men could sit comfortably in it.</p>
<p>As president, Taft did continue some of Roosevelt's reforms, but in a more orderly way. He also took some actions that <strong>contradicted </strong>Roosevelt's wishes.</p>
<p>In four years, the two men had gone from political allies to competitors for the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Taft was another president who was born in the state of Ohio. He grew up in the city of Cincinnati, along with five siblings.</p>
<p>Taft's father was a well-known lawyer, public official and diplomat. He was an advisor to President <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-ulysses-grant/3920036.html" target="_blank">Ulysses Grant</a>.</p>
<p>His mother was an intelligent, independent woman who also worked for the public good.</p>
<p>The Tafts had high expectations for their son. He became an excellent student, who went on to study at Yale and then the University of Cincinnati Law School.</p>
<p>Taft sought a career path that he hoped would lead him one day to the U.S. Supreme Court. He worked as a lawyer, and then as a judge in Ohio. Along the way, he met Theodore Roosevelt. Roosevelt helped Taft <strong>advance</strong> his career as a judge.</p>
<p>But one person was not happy about the career move: Taft's wife.</p>
<p>Taft had married an intelligent, independent woman named Helen Herron, known as Nellie. She had always wanted to be first lady, and she urged her husband to follow a path toward the White House.</p>
<p>In time, Nellie Taft had her wish. In 1900 President William McKinley offered Taft a position in the Philippines. The islands had come under the control of the United States after the Spanish-American War.</p>
<p>McKinley wanted Taft to help prepare the Philippines to be ruled by civilians, instead of by soldiers. Taft worried he would not like the job; however, he knew that it was a good chance to build a political career.</p>
<p>Taft was right about that. But he was wrong about disliking the job. He enjoyed it so much that he turned down two offers to return to the U.S. and serve on the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>In the Philippines, Taft successfully established courts, schools, a transportation <strong>network</strong>, and a health care system.</p>
<p>Taft did have <strong>pejorative</strong> views about the people who lived there – he did not think they were yet capable of governing themselves. But he performed his job as governor general effectively.</p>
<p>Taft might have even stayed in the Philippines if it were not for his friend Theodore Roosevelt. In 1901, Roosevelt became president. He asked Taft to become his secretary of war.</p>
<p>Taft agreed, partly so he could continue to supervise the Philippines. But the job also put him in a position to become president himself.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>William Taft did not really want to be president. But Theodore Roosevelt and Nellie Taft wanted him to be.</p>
<p>During the election of 1908, Taft permitted Roosevelt to do most of the campaigning for him. He spent a lot of time golfing. Taft was the first president to be strongly linked – so to speak – to the sport of golfing. (Another word for golf course is "links.")</p>
<p>Yet voters approved of Taft. They likely hoped he would continue the reforms of Roosevelt. He won the election easily.</p>
<p>Once in the White House, however, Taft did several things that <strong>reversed</strong> Roosevelt's positions.</p>
<p>First, Taft signed a bill that did not reduce <strong>tariffs</strong> as much as many <strong>progressive</strong> activists wanted.</p>
<p>Then, Taft removed one of Roosevelt's friends from a goverment position. Taft believed he was correct in making the move, but Roosevelt and many other Republicans were furious.</p>
<p>Some <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/presidents/williamhowardtaft">historians</a> say they did not give Taft enough credit for the many reforms he did make. His government pursued a large number of anti-trust suits against big business.</p>
<p>It also advanced two Constitutional amendments – one to establish a federal income tax, and another to permit voters to elect senators directly.</p>
<p>As the end of Taft's term in the White House came near, the Republican Party was divided. At their 1912 convention, a majority of delegates nominated Taft for president again. But a number left the meeting in anger. They created a new group, called the Progressive Party, and nominated as their candidate Theodore Roosevelt.</p>
<p>Taft and Roosevelt, along with the Democratic Party candidate, fought a bitter campaign during 1912. Of the three, Taft came in last.</p>
<p>Roosevelt came in second.</p>
<p>The divided Republicans had given control of the White House to the Democratic candidate Woodrow Wilson.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Happily for him, Taft's story does not end there.</p>
<p>Taft taught at Yale University Law School for a while. Then, when a Republican took the White House again, President Warren Harding appointed Taft as chief justice of the Supreme Court. He is the only person to lead both the executive and judicial branches of the U.S. government.</p>
<p>Taft was clear about which one he favored: He was much more <strong>comfortable</strong> as a justice than he was as president.</p>
<p>One journalist at the time <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/chief-justice-not-president-was-william-howard-tafts-dream-job-180961279/">described</a> Chief Justice Taft as "a smiling Buddha, placid, wise, gentle, sweet."</p>
<p>He even lost weight.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p>_______________________________________________<span style="font-size: 9pt;">________________________________</span></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p>mentor<strong> </strong>-<em> n. </em>someone who teaches or gives help and advice to a less experienced and often younger person</p>
<p><strong>contrast </strong>- <em>n. </em>the act of comparing people or things to show the differences between them</p>
<p><strong>contradicted </strong>- <em>v. </em>to not agree with (something) in a way that shows or suggests that it is false or wrong</p>
<p><strong>advance </strong>- <em>v. </em>to help the progress of something</p>
<p><strong>network </strong>- <em>n. </em>a system of lines, wires, etc., that are connected to each other</p>
<p><strong>pejorative</strong> -<em> adj. </em>insulting to someone or something</p>
<p><strong>reversed</strong> - <em>v. </em>to cause (something, such as a process) to stop or return to an earlier state</p>
<p><strong>tariffs </strong>- <em>n. </em>a tax on goods coming into or leaving a country</p>
<p><strong>progressive</strong> -<em> n. </em>a person who favors new or modern ideas especially in politics and education</p>
<p><strong>comfortable </strong>- <em>adj.</em> allowing you to be relaxed : causing no worries, difficulty, or uncertainty</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Peruvian Singer Aims to Introduce ‘Q-pop’  (2023/8/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/peruvian-singer-aims-to-introduce-q-pop.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By </span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Lenin Tamayo is named after the leader of the Russian Revolution, Vladimir Lenin. But he wants to revolutionize Peruvian popular music.</p>
<p>Tamayo aims to create popular music similar to South Korean K-pop songs, but he is using Quechua, the language of the Incas.</p>
<p>The Incas were the people who ruled western South America before the arrival of Spanish explorers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Peruvian singer Lenin Tamayo poses for a photo while taking a break from recording a music video in downtown Lima, Peru, Thursday, Aug. 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3126-08dba0173032_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Peruvian singer Lenin Tamayo poses for a photo while taking a break from recording a music video in downtown Lima, Peru, Thursday, Aug. 3, 2023. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)</span></div>
<p>Tamayo grew up speaking Quechua at his home in Lima.</p>
<p>His music mixes beats from Korean songs with <strong>folklore</strong> from the Andes Mountain area and traditional Peruvian sounds. It appears to be popular. Tamayo has received at least 4 million "hearts" on the video social media service TikTok.</p>
<p>Twenty-three-year-old Tamayo is not so concerned with how many people listen on social media. Instead, he hopes to bring attention to discrimination and the importance of Peru's past and those he claims as his ancestors.</p>
<p>He told Reuters: "My music had to <strong>embrace</strong> my <strong>origins</strong> strongly."</p>
<p>The young singer observed that the voice was very important to the people of the Andes, calling it a "<strong>primordial</strong> sound." And he added "the voice goes hand in hand with the language," noting that Quechua is what will define his sound.</p>
<p>Quechua is spoken by about 10 million people in South America. It is the most widely used native language there. It is spoken not only in Peru but also in parts of Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Chile and Ecuador.</p>
<p>In school, Tamayo began listening to Korean popular music, or K-pop, which started being popularized internationally by the group BTS about 10 years ago.</p>
<p>Study of Korean culture became a way for the young singer to make like-minded friends and to deal with <strong>bullying</strong> that he said he faced because of his appearance.</p>
<p>Tamayo told Reuters that he saw young girls listening to K-pop and watching Korean TV dramas. By trying to make friends, he thought he could get closer to Korean culture, he said.</p>
<p>The result is a musical mixture that people on the internet have called "Q-pop."</p>
<p>Tamayo's first album, <em>Amaru</em>, was released this month. Each song is based on Incan <strong>mythology</strong>. Ideas include Kay Pacha, or the living world; Uku Pacha, or the world of the dead; and Hanan Pacha, the heavenly kingdom. On stage, Tamayo dances and looks like a Korean male performer. But the sound of the music is based on traditional instruments from the Peruvian mountains.</p>
<p>Fans who recently attended a Lenin Tamayo performance were happy to take <strong>selfies</strong> and talk about the new artist. Gabriel Castro spoke to Reuters about it. He said the new music "helps raise awareness among all our people, all our new generations and the older ones too, who are part of Peru."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Gloria Lopez and Lucinda Elliott reported this story for Reuters. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>embrace</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to accept something readily and gladly</p>
<p><strong>origin</strong> <em>–n.</em> to beginnings or the roots of something; a person's ancestry</p>
<p><strong>folklore </strong><em>–n.</em> traditional customs, beliefs and stories</p>
<p><strong>primordial </strong><em>–adj.</em> existing from very early or even prehistoric times</p>
<p><strong>bully </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause someone to be unhappy or fearful by making threats and insults</p>
<p><strong>mythology </strong><em>–n.</em> ideas, stories and beliefs from the distant past that are still expressed in writing</p>
<p><strong>selfies </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> pictures taken of oneself on a smartphone</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ukrainian Child War Diaries Presented in Netherlands  (2023/8/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/ukrainian-child-war-diaries-presented-in-netherlands.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>An <strong>exhibition</strong> of war stories and artwork from children in Ukraine recently opened in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The event is being held in Amsterdam, where Anne Frank wrote her famous World War II <strong>diaries</strong> as she hid her family from <strong>Nazi</strong> occupiers.</p>
<p>The exhibition, called "War Diaries," shows the experiences of children caught in the war in Ukraine. The conflict began when Russian forces invaded the country in February 2022.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A drawing by Mykola Kostenko is part of the War Diaries exhibition, showcasing the personal diaries of Ukrainian children who have witnessed the war, hosted by the Amsterdam city hall , Netherlands, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Peter Dejong)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-b5b3-08dba3502b3c_cx6_cy2_cw88_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A drawing by Mykola Kostenko is part of the War Diaries exhibition, showcasing the personal diaries of Ukrainian children who have witnessed the war, hosted by the Amsterdam city hall , Netherlands, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Peter Dejong)</span></div>
<p>Khrystyna Khranovska developed the idea for the show. She said it is meant to describe the pains of war "through the children's eyes." Khranovska added, "It strikes into the very heart of every adult to be aware of the suffering and <strong>grief</strong> that the Russian war has brought our children."</p>
<p>The exhibition includes notes like those written by Anne Frank in the Amsterdam home where she hid with her family from the Nazis during World War II. The show shares the stories Ukrainian children have faced during the war, as told in writings, photos and video.</p>
<p>Among those taking part was Mykola Kostenko. The boy, who is now 15, spent 21 days surrounded by Russian forces in the Ukrainian port city of Mariupol. Kostenko created drawings with pen and paper torn from notebooks. One of them showed the small <strong>basement </strong>where he and his family sheltered from Russian forces before they fled the city.</p>
<p>Kostenko told the Associated Press, "I put my <strong>soul</strong> into all of these pictures because this is what I lived through in Mariupol. What I saw, what I heard. So, this is my experience, and this is my hope."</p>
<p>Katya Taylor is a curator for the exhibition, meaning she helps collect the materials included in the show. She said she thinks the diaries and artwork are useful tools for helping the children deal with the harmful effects of war.</p>
<p>Kostenko said drawing and painting helped calm him and provided a healing effect. "It also was an instrument to save the emotions that I lived through. For me to remember them in the future because it's important," he added.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials have estimated that more than 500 children have been killed during the war. In addition, the United Nations children's agency, UNICEF, estimates about 1.5 million Ukrainian children are at risk of depression, <strong>post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD)</strong> and other mental health problems.</p>
<p>The youngest diarist was 10-year-old Yehor Kravtsov, who also lived in Mariupol. In writing appearing next to the diary, he describes his dream of becoming a builder. But he said his experience living through the war changed his mind.</p>
<p>Kravtsov wrote, "When we got out from the basement during the occupation ... I was very hungry, I decided to become a chef to feed the whole world."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>exhibition </strong><em>– n. </em>an event at which objects such as paintings are shown to the public</p>
<p><strong>diary </strong><em>– n. </em>a book containing information about meetings and other things to remember</p>
<p><strong>Nazi </strong>–adj. related to the National Socialist German Workers' Party which ruled Germany from 1933 to 1945</p>
<p><strong>grief </strong><em>– n. </em>very great sadness, especially at the death of someone</p>
<p><strong>soul </strong>– <em>n.</em> the spiritual part of a person which is not material and is believed by many to be eternal</p>
<p><strong>basement </strong><em>– n. </em>the area in a house that is below ground</p>
<p><strong>post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) </strong><em>– n. </em>a mental condition in which a person suffers severe nervousness and depression after a very frightening or shocking experience</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Persons vs. People  (2023/8/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/persons-vs-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "persons" and "people."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Persons vs. People" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9c2e-08dba40cfcf6_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Persons vs. People</span></div>
<p>My name is Richard. I am from Uruguay. I would like to ask you about the differences between "persons" and "people."</p>
<p>I learned that I have to use "people" as a plural of "person," however I saw that in English sometimes they write "persons" as a plural instead of "people."</p>
<p>Thanks in advance,</p>
<p>Richard</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing to us, Richard.</p>
<p>This is a great question. Both words are the plural form of "person," but we use them in different situations. Let's explore each word further.</p>
<p><strong>Persons</strong></p>
<p>A "person" is a noun meaning an individual human. "Person" is in the singular form.</p>
<p>In English, we do have a plural form of that word, which is "persons." Although we do not use it much in everyday speech, the word "persons" is often used in law, especially when talking about "missing persons" or "persons of interest."</p>
<p><em>Police said they are seeking three persons of interest possibly in connection with the robbery.</em></p>
<p><strong>People and Peoples</strong></p>
<p>Most often, we use the word "people" to mean multiple or a group of humans. It is the most common plural form of "person." The word is a countable noun. And, although "people" is defined as many humans, it is not a collective noun. Collective nouns describe many individuals who form a group.</p>
<p><em>There were 50 people picking apples at the <strong>orchard</strong>.</em></p>
<p><em>Susan enjoys being around a lot of people.</em></p>
<p>We often use the word "people" when talking about one <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/descent-vs-ancestry-/7229681.html">ethnic</a> group or nationality.</p>
<p><em>The Ukrainian people celebrate their independence day on August 24th.</em></p>
<p>Sometimes you may see "peoples," with an "s." We use "peoples" when we are talking about different ethnic groups in the same area.</p>
<p><em>The peoples of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/how-to-eat-dumplings-in-georgia/7047660.html">Caucasus</a> are spread over six countries and include more than 50 ethnic groups.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Richard.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>orchard</strong> – <em>n. </em>an area of land on which fruit trees are grown</p>
<p><em>Do you have a question for the teacher? We want to hear from you. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study Suggests Links Between Fracking, Health in Children  (2023/8/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-suggests-links-between-fracking-health-in-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Three new studies suggest links between natural gas wells and cases of cancer, asthma and birth problems.</p>
<p>Children who lived closer to natural gas wells in heavily-<strong>drilled</strong> western Pennsylvania were more likely to develop lymphoma, a rare cancer, researchers found. Nearby <strong>residents</strong> of all ages had an increased chance of severe asthma, a lung disease, and low birth weight.</p>
<p>The University of Pittsburgh did the studies.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Work continues at a shale gas well drilling site in St. Mary's, Pa., March 12, 2020.(AP Photo/Keith Srakocic, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6236-08db9e996445_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Work continues at a shale gas well drilling site in St. Mary's, Pa., March 12, 2020.(AP Photo/Keith Srakocic, File)</span></div>
<p>The researchers found what they called strong connections between the gas industry activity called fracking and two health problems: asthma, and lymphoma in children. Lymphoma is a type of cancer less common among children.</p>
<p>The researchers were unable to say whether the drilling caused the health problems. The studies were not designed to do that. Instead, the researchers looked at health records to try to find out possible connections based on how close people lived to natural gas wells.</p>
<p>Gas industry groups say the studies had weaknesses, and had limited data.</p>
<p>In the cancer study, researchers found that children who lived within 1.6 kilometers of a gas well had five to seven times the chance of developing lymphoma compared with children who lived 8 kilometers or farther from a well. That is equal to about 60 to 84 lymphoma cases per million children living near wells. For kids living farther away, the number is 12 per million.</p>
<p>The researchers found that people with asthma who lived near wells were more likely to have severe reactions. However, researchers said they found no clear connection for severe reactions during periods when crews were building, drilling and fracking the well. Fracking is the process of putting liquid into the ground to <strong>extract</strong> natural gas.</p>
<p>The four-year, $2.5 million research project is coming to an end. It was established under pressure from the families of childhood cancer patients who live in the nation's largest natural gas <strong>reservoir</strong> in western Pennsylvania. A very rare form of bone cancer had been found in <strong>dozens </strong>of children and young adults in a heavily drilled area outside the city of Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>But the researchers said they found no connection between gas drilling and childhood leukemia, brain and bone cancers.</p>
<p>The researchers said their findings on early births and low birth weights among families living closer to gas wells were similar to the mixed results of similar studies. But it said babies born to mothers near active wells in production were about 28 grams lighter on average.</p>
<p>Edward Ketyer is a retired child doctor who sat on a board for the study. He said he expected that the studies would be similar to other research showing the "closer you live to fracking activity, the increased risk you have of being sick with a <strong>variety </strong>of <strong>illnesses</strong>."</p>
<p>A number of states have strengthened laws around fracking and waste <strong>disposal</strong> over the past 10 years. However, researchers have said that it is still unclear how much <strong>toxic</strong> substances<strong> </strong>the industry puts into the air, injects into the ground or produces as waste.</p>
<p>Large-scale fracking the past 20 years has made the United States into a worldwide oil and gas superpower.</p>
<p>But it also brought many protests about water and air pollution, as well as diseases, in states including Texas, Colorado and Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>drill </strong><em>— n. </em>tool used for making holes in hard substances</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resident </strong><em>— n. </em>someone who lives in a particular place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extract </strong><em>— v. </em>to remove by pulling it out or cutting it out</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reservoir </strong><em>— n. </em>an extra supply of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dozen </strong><em>— v. </em>a group of 12 people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>variety </strong><em>— n. </em> a number or collection of different things or people</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>illness </strong><em>— n. </em>a condition of being unhealthy in your body or mind</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>disposal </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of throwing something away</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>toxic </strong><em>— adj. </em>containing poisonous substances</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia, Iran among Six Countries Joining BRICS  (2023/8/25) | 沙特、伊朗等六国将加入金砖国家经济组织</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/saudi-iran-among-six-countries-joining-brics.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Iran and Saudi Arabia are among six countries set to join the BRICS economic group next year. The United Arab Emirates (UAE), Argentina, Egypt, and Ethiopia are the others to become members in 2024.<br/>
伊朗和沙特阿拉伯将于明年加入金砖国家经济组织。其它国家还包括阿拉伯联合酋长国、阿根廷、埃及和埃塞俄比亚。</p>
<p>BRICS stands for Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa. Brazil, Russia, India and China formed the group in 2009 to increase economic cooperation among growing economies. South Africa joined in 2010.<br/>
金砖国家代表巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非。巴西、俄罗斯、印度和中国于2009年成立了该组织，以加强增长中经济体之间的经济合作。南非于2010年加入。</p>
<p>The group has called for more representation of developing countries and those in the south in world affairs. The group announced the addition of new members Thursday at its meeting in Johannesburg, South Africa.<br/>
该组织呼吁增加发展中国家和南方国家在世界事务中的代表性。该组织星期四在南非约翰内斯堡举行的会议上宣布增加新成员。</p>
<p>BRICS currently represents around 40 percent of the world's population and more than 25 percent of the world's economic output. That is set to increase with the new members, which include three of the world's biggest oil producers in Saudi Arabia, the UAE and Iran.<br/>
金砖国家目前约占世界人口的40%，以及世界经济产出的25%以上。这一数字将随着新成员的加入而增加，新成员包括沙特阿拉伯、阿联酋和伊朗这三个世界上最大的石油生产国。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Changing world<br/>
不断变化的世界</span></p>
<p>BRICS nations have long called for reforms of organizations like the U.N. Security Council, the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank. They say the current structures "reflect yesterday's world."<br/>
金砖国家长期以来一直呼吁改革联合国安理会、国际货币基金组织和世界银行等组织。他们说，目前的结构“反映的是旧世界”。</p>
<p>South African President Cyril Ramaphosa is the host of the BRICS meeting this year. He said the expansion is an "effort to build a world that is fair, a world that is just, a world that is also inclusive and prosperous."<br/>
南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨是今年金砖国家会议的东道主。他说，这次扩建是“为了建设一个公平、公正、包容和繁荣的世界”。</p>
<p>In a sign of BRICS' growing influence, United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres also attended Thursday's expansion announcement. He said that international organizations "must reform to reflect today's power and economic realities."<br/>
联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯也出席了周四的扩大声明，这表明金砖国家的影响力正在增强。他说，国际组织“必须进行改革，以反映当今的权力和经济现实。”</p>
<p>China's President Xi Jinping called the expansion "historic." He added that the group wanted "unity and development."<br/>
中国国家主席习近平称此次扩张是“历史性的”。 他还表示，该组织希望“团结和发展”。</p>
<p>However, some observers have questioned whether the group will become anti-Western with the expansion. China's relationship with the United States is at a low point. Russia faces Western economic measures for its invasion of Ukraine.<br/>
然而，一些观察家质疑该组织是否会随着扩张而变得反西方。中国与美国的关系正处于低谷。俄罗斯因入侵乌克兰而面临西方的经济制裁。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">New members cheer the announcement<br/>
新成员为这一宣布欢呼</span></p>
<p>Mohammad Jamshidi is the top political aide of Iran's President Ebrahim Raisi. He called the decision to add his country a "victory for Iran's foreign policy."<br/>
穆罕默德·贾姆希迪是伊朗总统易卜拉欣·莱西的高级政治助理。他称接纳伊朗的决定是“伊朗外交政策的胜利”。</p>
<p>China and Russia were supporting Iran's inclusion. However, Brazil, India and South Africa, which have strong ties with the U.S., only gave their approval more recently.<br/>
中国和俄罗斯支持伊朗的加入。然而，与美国关系密切的巴西、印度和南非最近才批准。</p>
<p>UAE leader Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan welcomed the BRICS announcement. He said his nation would be joining an "important group" and would work with all nations and people around the world.<br/>
阿联酋领导人谢赫·穆罕默德·本·扎耶德·阿勒纳哈扬对金砖国家的声明表示欢迎。他说，阿联酋将加入一个“重要团体”，并将与世界各地的所有国家和人民合作。</p>
<p>Egypt President Abdel Fattah el-Sissi said in a statement that his country would work to "raise the voice of the Global South."<br/>
埃及总统阿卜杜勒·法塔赫·塞西在一份声明中表示，埃及将努力“提高全球南方的声音”。</p>
<p>The expansion also helps Ethiopia, Africa's second most populous country and one of the fastest-growing economies on the continent. Its government is working to reconnect with international partners and financial organizations after a violent two-year conflict in the country's Tigray area.<br/>
这一扩张也有助于埃塞俄比亚，该国是非洲第二人口大国，也是非洲大陆增长最快的经济体之一。在该国提格雷地区发生了为期两年的暴力冲突后，该国政府正在努力与国际合作伙伴和金融组织重新建立联系。</p>
<p>South African officials say more than 40 countries have said they want to join BRICS. And 22 countries have officially asked to join the organization.<br/>
南非官员说，已有40多个国家表示希望加入金砖国家。已经有22个国家正式要求加入该组织。</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Explosion Likely Brought Down Wagner Chief's Plane  (2023/8/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/russian-paramilitary-leader-believed-dead-in-plane-crash.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Intelligence officials from the United States and Western countries believe that an explosion brought down the plane <strong>presumed</strong> to carry Wagner group leader Yevgeny Prigozhin and others.</p>
<p>One of the officials told the Associated Press that the explosion was in line with Russian President Vladimir Putin's "long history of trying to silence his critics." The official was not permitted to comment publicly and did not want to be named.</p>
<p>Russian officials have not officially confirmed the identity of those who died on the private plane. However, President Putin expressed sympathy on Thursday to the families of those who were reportedly on the plane. He also spoke of Prigozhin, saying, "He made some serious mistakes in life, but he also <strong>achieved</strong> necessary results."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Russian serviceman inspects a part of a crashed private jet near the village of Kuzhenkino, Tver region, Russia, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. Yevgeny V. Prigozhin, the founder of the Wagner Group, was reportedly on the plane. (AP Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f40f1fe5-4de0-498e-9880-194226a7edc6_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Russian serviceman inspects a part of a crashed private jet near the village of Kuzhenkino, Tver region, Russia, Thursday, Aug. 24, 2023. Yevgeny V. Prigozhin, the founder of the Wagner Group, was reportedly on the plane. (AP Photo)</span></div>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, U.S. President Joe Biden said he did not know what happened, but he said, "I'm not surprised." He added, "There's not much that happens in Russia that Putin is not behind."</p>
<p><strong>The mutiny</strong></p>
<p>Prigozhin founded the Wagner group. It is an organization of fighters based in St. Petersburg who offer their services for money and are not officially linked to the Russian military. The fighters were known to support military leaders in Africa and the Middle East.</p>
<p>They had also been supporting Russian President Vladimir Putin's war in Ukraine. But Prigozhin criticized Putin and his military leaders and launched what was called a <strong>mutiny</strong> earlier this year.</p>
<p>On June 23 and 24, he and his soldiers moved against Russia's leaders, shooting down aircraft and started a <strong>convoy</strong> of military vehicles targeting Moscow.</p>
<p>The anti-Putin move ended when the two men reached a deal that permitted Prigozhin to go to Belarus. Reports, however, said he was able to move safely and freely between Russia, Belarus and parts of Africa. He appeared at a meeting between Russia and African nations in St. Petersburg in July.</p>
<p>Many wondered why Prigozhin seemed safe after moving against Putin. Other opponents of the Russian president had been sickened, killed or imprisoned in the past.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, rescue workers found 10 bodies, which included members of the Wagner group and the airplane crew.</p>
<p>Russian media reports said Prigozhin was on the plane, <strong>citing</strong> unnamed people. The lights on the group's main building in St. Petersburg were lit in the shape of a cross overnight. By Thursday, supporters made a small memorial with red and white flowers and Wagner Group flags.</p>
<p>There was no official statement from Russia's leaders on the crash or its cause. However, Rosaviatsia, Russia's aviation agency, published a list of those on board and it included Prigozhin.</p>
<p>A reporter from the Reuters news agency went to the place of the crash on Thursday and spoke to people who said they heard a loud sound before seeing the airplane fall to the ground.</p>
<p>One person, Anatoly, said he heard "a metallic bang" and not the kind of noise from a thunderstorm. Part of the plane's tail and other wreckage were seen on the ground.</p>
<p>Flight information services showed the plane flying normally until it disappeared from radar.</p>
<p>Prigozhin supporters called him "a hero" on messaging services. They said the flight had either been shot down by a missile or destroyed by a bomb on board. Those claims have not been <strong>verified</strong>, and Russian officials say they are investigating the crash.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reports by The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>presume </strong>–v. to think something is true without knowing that it is</p>
<p><strong>mutiny </strong>–n. when a group of people under the command of an officer, such as sailors or soldiers, take control away from the person who commands them and refuse to do their duty</p>
<p><strong>convoy </strong>–n. a long line of vehicles traveling together often for protection</p>
<p><strong>cite </strong>–v. to write, say or report the words of someone else, especially in news or educational report</p>
<p><strong>verify </strong>–v. to prove that something is true or correct</p>
<p><strong>coincidence </strong>–n. when two things happen at the same time but are not connected to each other</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. What do you think caused the crash in Russia?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Cleaning, Part 2  (2023/8/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/grammar-and-cleaning-part-2.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Cleaning is one of those activities that we have to do. But what kinds of words and structures do we use to talk about this common activity?</p>
<p>In today's<em> Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore a few ways to talk about cleaning. This lesson builds on the ideas of a recent lesson that explored verbs and objects.</p>
<p>Today we will explore phrasal verbs that connect to cleaning.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-08ed-08dba4b87241_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar</span></div>
<p><strong>Phrasal verbs </strong></p>
<p>Phrasal verbs are groups of words. They include a verb and another short word or words. Together, these groups of words take on a different meaning from what the individual words suggest.</p>
<p>There are many phrasal verbs in English. But we only use a small number of these when we talk about cleaning.</p>
<p>In this lesson, we will explore three phrasal verbs that connect with cleaning. All of them involve the short word "up."</p>
<p>The phrasal verbs are "clean up," "pick up," and "wash up." Let's explore each of these in turn.</p>
<p><strong>Clean up </strong></p>
<p>"Clean up" has a few closely related meanings. It means to remove dirt or waste. It also means to make a room clean and orderly.</p>
<p>"Clean up" comes in a few different forms. Sometimes we use clean up without a noun or noun<strong> phrase</strong> after it, as in:</p>
<p><em>"Let's take some time to clean up."</em></p>
<p>But we often use a noun or noun phrase with clean up, as in "clean up something."</p>
<p>So, you might say:</p>
<p><em>"I need to clean up the kitchen."</em></p>
<p>Or,</p>
<p><em>"He needs to clean up his room."</em></p>
<p>In our example, the noun phrases "the kitchen" and "his room" come after the phrasal verb.</p>
<p>But you should know that sometimes we use the noun or noun phrase in between "clean" and the short word "up," as in "clean something up."</p>
<p>So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>"She needs to clean this mess up."</em></p>
<p>You might be worried about these two forms – the one in which the noun or noun phrase comes in the middle of the phrasal verb and the one in which the noun or noun phrase comes after it.</p>
<p>The good news is that your meaning will still be understood<strong> regardless </strong>of which form you choose.</p>
<p>In other words, these two statements have the same basic meaning in most situations:</p>
<p><em>"She needs to clean this mess up."</em></p>
<p>And,</p>
<p><em>"She needs to clean up this mess."</em></p>
<p><strong>Pick up </strong></p>
<p>Our second phrasal verb is "pick up." "Pick up" has a few different meanings in different situations. But when we are talking about cleaning, we use it to mean the action of lifting something from the floor, ground, or other low surface.</p>
<p>Once again, we use "pick up" with a noun or noun phrase. And just like "clean up," "pick up" can have the noun phrase come after the phrasal verb or in the middle of the phrasal verb.</p>
<p>So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>"Could you pick up those toys?"</em></p>
<p>Or,</p>
<p><em>"Could you pick those toys up?"</em></p>
<p>Once again, the two forms have the same meaning although the grammar — the noun phrase placement — is a little different.</p>
<p>Here is another example. Imagine a situation in which a little baby has thrown some toys on the ground. A person might say:</p>
<p><em>"I will pick up the toys."</em></p>
<p>Or,</p>
<p><em>"I will pick the toys up."</em></p>
<p><strong>Wash up </strong></p>
<p>Our final phrasal verb is "wash up."</p>
<p>When we talk about cleaning, we generally use "wash up" in the sense of washing your hands, face, or dishes.</p>
<p>So, you might hear a person say:</p>
<p><em>"I need to wash up before we go to the concert."</em></p>
<p>Or,</p>
<p><em>"We need to wash up the dishes before we go to bed."</em></p>
<p><strong>The ending is important </strong></p>
<p>An important point about phrasal verbs. The short word at the end of the phrasal verb <strong>determines</strong> the meaning. So, by paying careful attention to the short word or words, you will improve your ability to use the correct phrasal verb at the right time.</p>
<p>That is why we chose to use phrasal verbs only with "up" for this lesson. Now, whenever you talk about cleaning, you will remember that you can use several phrasal verbs that end in "up," - clean up, pick up, and wash up.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>phrase</strong><em> – n. </em>a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
<p><strong>regardless </strong><em>– adv.</em> without being affected by (something)</p>
<p><strong>determine </strong><em>– v.</em> to establish (something) exactly; to be the cause of or reason for (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Successfully Lands Spacecraft on Moon  (2023/8/24) | 印度月船3号在月球南极成功着陆</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/india-successfully-lands-spacecraft-on-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>India became the fourth country to successfully land a spacecraft on the moon on Wednesday. It also became the first country to land a spacecraft near the moon's south pole.<br/>
印度于本周三成为第四个成功将航天器送上月球的国家。它也成为第一个在月球南极附近着陆航天器的国家。</p>
<p>Its moon lander, called Chandrayaan-3, touched down near the moon's south pole just after 6 p.m. in India.<br/>
其月球着陆器“月船3号”于印度当地时间下午6点刚过在月球南极附近着陆。</p>
<p>The landing brought cheers and applause from space scientists who were watching in the control center in city of Bengaluru. After a failed landing almost four years ago, India joined the United States, the Soviet Union and China as the only countries to send a spacecraft to the moon.<br/>
此次着陆让在班加罗尔市控制中心观看的太空科学家们发出欢呼和鼓掌。在近四年前的一次失败着陆后，印度加入了美国、苏联和中国的行列，成为仅有的几个能够向月球发射航天器的国家。</p>
<p>"This moment is unforgettable. It is phenomenal. This is a victory cry of a new India," said Prime Minister Narendra Modi.<br/>
印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪说：“这一刻令人难忘。这是非凡的（成就）。这是新印度的胜利呐喊。”</p>
<p>"India is on the moon," said S. Somanath, the head of the Indian Space Research Organization.<br/>
印度空间研究组织负责人索马纳特说：“印度现在登上了月球。”</p>
<p>The moon's south pole is thought to be an important area for exploration. Scientists believe it has important resources, including frozen water and minerals.<br/>
月球南极被认为是一个重要的探测区域。科学家们认为它拥有重要的资源，包括冰冻水和矿物质。</p>
<p>Just days earlier, Russia's Luna-25 spacecraft tried to land in the same area but spun out of control and crashed. It would have been Russia's first moon landing in 47 years.<br/>
就在几天前，俄罗斯的月球-25号宇宙飞船试图降落在同一地区，但失控坠毁。这本将是俄罗斯47年来首次登月。</p>
<p>People across India gathered in shops, offices, restaurants and their homes to watch the landing on television.<br/>
印度各地的人们聚集在商店、办公室、餐馆和家中，通过电视观看这次着陆。</p>
<p>The name Chandrayaan means "moon craft" in the Sanskrit language.<br/>
Chandrayaan这个名字在梵语中的意思是“月球飞船”。</p>
<p>The Indian Space Research Organization discussed the mission ahead of the landing. The organization called the possible landing "a remarkable milestone … a significant step forward for Indian science, engineering, technology and industry."<br/>
印度空间研究组织在着陆前讨论了这次任务。该组织称此次可能的着陆是“一座了不起的里程碑……是印度科学、工程、技术和工业向前迈出的重要一步。”</p>
<p>The group discussed the "sense of pride" that comes from the success and suggested it will lead to more innovation from India.<br/>
该机构讨论了成功着陆带来的“自豪感”，并表示这将给印度带来更多的创新。</p>
<p>The previous landing attempt broke down because of a software problem, according to India's space organization.<br/>
据印度航天组织称，之前的着陆尝试因软件问题而失败。</p>
<p>The moon vehicle will take up to one day to come out of the spacecraft and will operate for two weeks. It will run experiments on the minerals on the moon's surface, Somanath said.<br/>
月球车将需要一天的时间才能从航天器中出来，并将运行两周时间。索马纳特说，它将对月球表面的矿物进行实验。</p>
<p>Observers say the successful landing shows India's interest in demonstrating its strength in technology and space exploration. The landing should be an important part of Modi's campaign to keep his government in power leading up to the country's general election in 2024.<br/>
观察人士表示，此次成功着陆表明印度有兴趣展示其在技术和太空探索方面的实力。此次登陆应该是莫迪在2024年大选前夕，想要使其政府继续执政的竞选运动的重要组成部分。</p>
<p>Many countries want to know about the moon's south pole because it could hold resources that may help future space missions. Other countries and private companies are trying to land there.<br/>
许多国家都想了解月球南极，因为它可能拥有有助于未来太空任务的资源。其他国家和私营公司正试图在那里登陆。</p>
<p>The Indian landing comes after the failed Russian mission, plus recent crashes by spacecraft from both Japan and Israel. Japan will launch another mission this weekend. Two private U.S. companies have attempts planned by the end of 2023. And the American space agency NASA hopes to send astronauts to the moon's south pole in coming years.<br/>
在印度着陆之前，发生了俄罗斯的任务失败，以及最近日本和以色列的航天器坠毁。日本将于本周末再次发射。两家美国私营公司计划在2023年底前进行尝试。美国宇航局希望在未来几年将宇航员送上月球南极。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·费里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Media Companies Seek New Rules to Protect Content from AI Training  (2023/8/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/media-companies-seek-new-rules-to-protect-content-from-ai-training.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Major media organizations are calling for new laws to protect their content from use by trainers of artificial intelligence (AI) tools.</p>
<p>The request for new laws, or regulations, was contained in an open letter released earlier this month. The leaders of several large news and publishing organizations signed the document.</p>
<p>They include officials of the Associated Press<em> </em>(AP), Gannett and the News Media Alliance, which represents hundreds of media publishers. Representatives from Getty Images, the National Press Photographers Association and Agence France-Presse also signed the document.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The OpenAI logo is seen on a mobile phone in front of a computer screen displaying output from ChatGPT, March 21, 2023, in Boston. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a122-08db9f786a5d_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The OpenAI logo is seen on a mobile phone in front of a computer screen displaying output from ChatGPT, March 21, 2023, in Boston. (AP Photo/Michael Dwyer, File)</span></div>
<p>The organizations stated their support for the "responsible" development and deployment of AI systems. One AI tool, known as a "chatbot," has demonstrated the ability to produce human-quality writing based on short, written commands. Such tools are also known as "generative AI" or "large language models."</p>
<p>But the letter also expresses the need to develop regulations "to protect the content that powers" the increasing number of AI tools in development.</p>
<p>Media companies are worried about AI developers using their published content without permission. The media content enjoys <strong>copyright</strong> protections and the companies want governments to enact rules to restrict unapproved use of their material.</p>
<p>AI developers need huge amounts of data to train systems that aim to produce human-level results. Developers often collect this data from publicly available websites in a process called "scraping."</p>
<p>The letter states that the process of scraping gives AI developers free use of their media content. They can then use this data to create language models that strengthen their AI tools and businesses.</p>
<p>A few media companies have already signed <strong>licensing</strong> agreements with AI developers to give them permission to scrape their content. Last month, the Associated Press completed a deal with chatbot developer OpenAI to license the news agency's large news story collection.</p>
<p>Other news organizations have taken steps designed to block developers from collecting their content. The <em>New York Times</em>, for example, recently changed its "Terms of Service" agreement to include new guidelines for AI.</p>
<p>The new policy requires AI developers to have written permission to use any of its content to train language models. The policy covers different forms of content, including written text, images and audio and video material.</p>
<p>The open letter also describes another big problem with chatbots and other AI tools: the production of false or misleading information presented as truth. It calls on AI developers to build into their systems tools to prevent such falsehoods.</p>
<p>News and media content created by AI tools "can <strong>distort</strong> facts and leave the public with no basis to <strong>discern</strong> what is true and what is made up," the letter states. It adds that many language models can also produce results that include long-standing biases against minority and underrepresented communities.</p>
<p>Many news companies are currently experimenting with generative AI tools. They hope to learn how the tools can best serve the news production process. Several major news organizations <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/news-organizations-team-up-with-ai-companies/7198889.html">announced</a> last month they had teamed up with AI developers to find new tools to help reporters do their work.</p>
<p>The AP recently issued new guidelines for the use of AI tools across all departments at the news agency. The guidelines ban the use of such tools "to create publishable content and images for the news service," the AP said in a story about its new rules.</p>
<p>However, the news agency said that it is also urging its employees to study the technology to learn how its use might improve their work within the rules.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse. </em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>copyright </strong><em>– n. </em>the legal right to control the use of an original piece of work such as a book, play or song</p>
<p><strong>license </strong><em>– v. </em>to give someone official permission to do or have something</p>
<p><strong>distort </strong><em>– v. </em>to change information so that it is not true or realistic</p>
<p><strong>discern </strong><em>– v. </em>to see or recognize something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Learn More about Famous Mummy's Ancestry  (2023/8/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/researchers-learn-more-about-famous-mummy-s-ancestry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Many years after the famous <strong>mummy</strong> Oetzi was discovered in the Italian Alps, scientists have studied his DNA again.</p>
<p>Researchers found that the ancient hunter mostly had ancestors who were farmers in an area that is in present day Turkey. Oetzi had less hair on his head and darker skin than scientists had first thought, says the study.</p>
<p>The study appeared recently in the publication Cell Genomics.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This photo provided by The South Tyrol Museum of Archaeology shows Oetzi the Iceman, one of the oldest human glacier mummies. (Marco Samadelli, Gregor Staschitz/South Tyrol Museum of Archaeology/EURAC via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6935e464-e9b3-4a38-83c6-dc5c095cfbe1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This photo provided by The South Tyrol Museum of Archaeology shows "Oetzi the Iceman," one of the oldest human glacier mummies. (Marco Samadelli, Gregor Staschitz/South Tyrol Museum of Archaeology/EURAC via AP)</span></div>
<p>Oetzi, who lived more than 5,000 years ago, was frozen into the ice after someone shot him with an <strong>arrow</strong>. In 1991, German visitors to the area found his body, along with some of his clothing and tools.</p>
<p>Oetzi's belongings included a copper <strong>ax</strong>, a <strong>longbow</strong> and a bearskin hat. The remains are housed at the South Tyrol Museum of Archaeology in Bolzano, Italy.</p>
<p>Researchers published a study of Oetzi's genetic material, or genome, in 2012. However, the study of ancient DNA improved in the years that followed.</p>
<p>So, scientists decided to investigate the mummy's genes again, said study writer Johannes Krause of Germany's Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology. Researchers used DNA taken from Oetzi's hip bone.</p>
<p>The new genome is "providing deeper <strong>insights</strong> into the history of this mummy," said Andreas Keller of Germany's Saarland University. Keller worked on the earlier study but was not involved with the latest.</p>
<p>Based on the new genome, Oetzi's appearance when he died around age 45 was much like the mummy looks today. It is dark and does not have much hair on it, said study writer Albert Zink of the Institute for Mummy Studies at Eurac Research in Italy. Scientists previously thought the iceman was lighter-skinned and hairier in life, but that his mummified body had changed over time.</p>
<p>His genome also showed he had an increased chance of the diseases obesity and diabetes, the researchers reported.</p>
<p>Oetzi's ancestry suggests that he lived among an <strong>isolated</strong> population in the Alps, Zink said. Most Europeans today have a mix of genes from three groups: farmers from Anatolia, hunter-gatherers from the west and <strong>herders</strong> from the east. However, 92 percent of Oetzi's ancestry was from just the Anatolian farmers.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Maddie Burakoff reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mummy </strong><em>– n.</em> a dead body of a person or animal that has been preserved</p>
<p><strong>arrow </strong><em>– n.</em> a weapon that is made to be shot from a bow and is usually a stick with a sharp point on one end and feathers at the other</p>
<p><strong>ax </strong><em>– n</em>. a tool that has a heavy metal blade and a long handle</p>
<p><strong>longbow </strong><em>– n.</em> a large wooden weapon that shot arrows and was used for hunting or fighting</p>
<p><strong>insight </strong><em>– n.</em> the ability to understand people and situations</p>
<p><strong>isolated </strong><em>– adj.</em> far away from others; remote</p>
<p><strong>herder </strong>– n. a person who manages, breeds, or tends to livestock</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Baseball Player’s Vision Brings Partnership with Artist  (2023/8/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/baseball-player-s-vision-brings-partnership-with-artist.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ian Happ is a professional baseball player for the Chicago Cubs of Major Leagues Baseball in the United States. When he first started playing with the team in 2017, he was looking for pictures to hang in his home.</p>
<p>From that simple desire came an idea and an unlikely partnership with a British artist.</p>
<p>Happ wanted art that showed Wrigley Field, the Cubs ballpark, from a different viewpoint.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The works of British artist Pat Vale titled See What I See, Pat Vale With Ian Happ. (AP Photo/Charles Rex Arbogast)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-986c-08dba255b705_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The works of British artist Pat Vale titled "See What I See, Pat Vale With Ian Happ." (AP Photo/Charles Rex Arbogast)</span></div>
<p>Happ said that many fans have been to Wrigley but have never seen what the ballpark looks like from the field. He thought looking up from the field was "such a <strong>cool</strong> experience" that he wanted to "bring that to more Cubs fans."</p>
<p>He hired the British artist Patrick Vale to create three large drawings of Wrigley from his point of view five years ago.</p>
<p>Instead of having pictures to hang in his home, the partnership led to something quite different.</p>
<p>Happ's view of Wrigley Field became the <em>Through My Eyes </em>project, in which fans can purchase prints. The money goes toward Happ's <strong>charity</strong>. The drawings by Vale became <em>See What I See</em>, an <strong>exhibit</strong> at Chicago's Gallery Victor. The show is open through August 26.</p>
<p>All this started with Happ simply looking for artwork.</p>
<p>A college <strong>teammate</strong> at the University of Cincinnati had become an <strong>architect</strong> in New York. That teammate gave Happ the names of several artists. One was Vale.</p>
<p>Happ noticed the level of detail in Vale's drawings of cities. After talking with Vale, Happ got the idea to bring Vale to Chicago and draw Wrigley Field from a viewpoint few fans get to experience. The drawings would be from a player's point of view looking out onto the field and into the <strong>stands</strong> of the famous ballpark.</p>
<p>Happ brought Vale to Chicago in September of 2018 and showed him around Wrigley. Vale knew little about the sport of baseball. But he understood the connection fans have with Wrigley.</p>
<p>"I understand when people talk about baseball and their connections to family and family stories and childhood," said Vale, who lives in New York. "It's the same for me with cricket. I can remember summers in the garden with grandpa and listening to the radio."</p>
<p>Happ had to explain to Vale the importance of the 400 feet sign in center field and the famous <strong>manual</strong> scoreboard and <strong>ivy</strong>. He had to teach him the correct positioning of the players. Happ also explained what it feels like standing in the field under the bright lights with a loud crowd.</p>
<p>Vale took pictures and used them to help him create drawings in great detail. He would send rough drawings to Happ, who would mark them up in red ink, like a teacher, with suggestions.</p>
<p>The drawings are mostly in black and white. They show everything from the faces of the fans and the people selling drinks to the numbers and pictures on the video screen. They show a celebration from the view of someone looking down the left-field line. And there is the view from the <strong>dugout</strong> looking toward third base and right field as the pitcher throws with the bright lights shining.</p>
<p>"He was talking about very specific moments," Vale said of Happ. "The scoreboard needs to feel like the scoreboard, right? I had to respect it and the place."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cool </strong><em>— adj. </em>very fashionable, stylish, or appealing in a way that is generally approved of especially by young people</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>charity </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of giving money, food, or other kinds of help to people who are poor, sick, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exhibit </strong><em>— n. </em>to make available for people to see</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>teammate </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who is on the same team as someone else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>architect </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who designs buildings</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stands </strong><em>— n. </em>the rows of seats in a stadium that people sit in when they are watching a sports event, concert, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>manual </strong><em>— adj. </em>doing or involving hard physical work</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ivy </strong><em>— n. </em>a plant that has long stems and that often grows on the outsides of buildings</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dugout </strong><em>— n. </em>a low shelter that faces a baseball field and contains the bench where the players and coaches of a team sit</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan to Release Wastewater from Fukushima Nuclear Plant  (2023/8/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/japan-to-release-wastewater-from-fukushima-nuclear-plant.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Japan's Prime Minister, Fumio Kishida, signed off Tuesday on his country's plan to release treated and <strong>diluted</strong> radioactive wastewater from the Fukushima nuclear plant later this week.</p>
<p>If weather and sea conditions are good, Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, or TEPCO, will start to release the water into the Pacific Ocean on Thursday.</p>
<p>The water release is an important part of the process of cleaning up the plant, which was damaged by a disastrous earthquake and tsunami on March 11, 2011. A tsunami is a large ocean wave created by the movement of the land under the ocean.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Workers are seen near storage tanks for radioactive water at Tokyo Electric Power Co's (TEPCO) tsunami-crippled Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant in Okuma town, Fukushima prefecture, Japan. January 15, 2020. (REUTERS/Aaron Sheldrick)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/861AA4D9-2EB8-4D6A-AF5E-C7ACACC6E4A2_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Workers are seen near storage tanks for radioactive water at Tokyo Electric Power Co's (TEPCO) tsunami-crippled Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant in Okuma town, Fukushima prefecture, Japan. January 15, 2020. (REUTERS/Aaron Sheldrick)</span></div>
<p>The wave destroyed the power center's cooling systems and caused three of the plant's nuclear reactors to overheat, or meltdown. The result was <strong>contaminated</strong> cooling water that has been treated and stored for over 10 years.</p>
<p>The prime minister said everything has been done to ensure the plan's safety and to protect Japan's fishing industry. He said the government will continue to explain the plan's science until the cleanup is completed many decades from now. A decade is a period of 10 years.</p>
<p>Kishida said, "The government will take responsibility until the disposal of the...treated water is completed."</p>
<p>The government of South Korea said it understands the plan and it will hold Japan to its promises to supervise the safety of the water. South Korea agreed to support Japan's plan even with protests by lawmakers and activists.</p>
<p>Other East Asian nations, however, are not pleased with the plan to release the water. China said it will increase radiation testing on fish imported from Japan.</p>
<p>Japanese fishing organizations protested the plan partly because they are worried about being able to sell their catch.</p>
<p>But TEPCO says about 1,000 storage tanks which have held the contaminated water since the disaster of 2011 are now almost full. The company is also concerned about possible leaks. So, the treated water must be released.</p>
<p>Junichi Matsumoto is the TEPCO leader in charge of the water release. In an interview with the Associated Press last month, he said the release is "a <strong>milestone</strong>" but there is still a lot of work to do to close down the plant.</p>
<p>TEPCO will start by releasing 7,800 tons of water over the first 17 days. All of it will be diluted with seawater to reach safe levels of radiation. By March 2024, TEPCO plans to release over 31,000 tons of water. However, that equals only 10 of the 1,000 storage tanks. The speed of the release will increase over time.</p>
<p>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) said in July that Japan's release plan will have almost no effect on human health or the environment.</p>
<p>Rafael Grossi is the director general of the IAEA. He said the United Nations office at the plant will remain open to <strong>monitor </strong>the water as it is released.</p>
<p>Most scientists agree with the IAEA, but they said the slow release of radioactive water, even at very low levels, needs attention.</p>
<p>Japan's government is continuing to explain the plan in nearby countries so that the release does not damage diplomatic communication. TEPCO is also considering accepting responsibility for the financial losses of the Japanese seafood industry because of restrictions placed on its products by other countries and extra testing requirements by China.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>diluted </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>reduced in strength or concentration</p>
<p><strong>contaminated </strong><em>–adj.</em> containing something that isn't supposed to be there<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>milestone </strong><em>–n</em>. an important point in the development of a project</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>–v.</em> to observe carefully over a period of time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wealthy Developer Is Thai's New Prime Minister  (2023/8/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/wealthy-developer-is-thai-s-new-prime-minister.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Srettha Thavisin is Thailand's new prime minister after winning a parliamentary vote Tuesday.</p>
<p>He is the wealthy leader of one of Thailand's best-known property companies. He was elected prime minister just nine months after joining Pheu Thai, a political party known for supporting the poor.</p>
<p>Parliament confirmed the 61-year-old Srettha, ending months of political uncertainty following May elections. He will lead the Pheu Thai party's push to improve the economy and lessen inequality.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pheu Thai's prime ministerial candidate Srettha Thavisin who is the sole candidate nominated for a parliamentary vote, speaks to media at the party headquarters in Bangkok, Thailand Tuesday, Aug. 22, 2023. (AP Photo/Wason Wanichakorn)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-ee35-08dba33a0e6b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pheu Thai's prime ministerial candidate Srettha Thavisin who is the sole candidate nominated for a parliamentary vote, speaks to media at the party headquarters in Bangkok, Thailand Tuesday, Aug. 22, 2023. (AP Photo/Wason Wanichakorn)</span></div>
<p>Pheu Thai finished second to the Move Forward Party in the May elections. But the party was able to group together an 11-party coalition, including two pro-military parties, to approve Srettha.</p>
<p>"I will perform my duties to the best of my ability. I will work tirelessly to improve the <strong>livelihood</strong> of all Thais," Srettha told reporters at Pheu Thai's headquarters.</p>
<p>Hours before Tuesday's parliamentary vote, Thaksin Shinawatra, a former Prime Minister and founder of Pheu Thai, returned to Thailand after 15 years in <strong>exile</strong><strong>. </strong>Supporters greeted Thaksin who then began serving an eight-year prison sentence on corruption charges.</p>
<p>Thaksin, who was ousted by the military in 2006, dismissed the charges as being influenced by politics. Observers believe that Srettha's appointment was related to Thaksin's return and that it might help shorten his jail time.</p>
<p><strong>Political newcomer</strong></p>
<p>Earlier this year, Srettha stepped down as head of his family's company, Sansiri. Sansiri is one of Thailand's largest developers with property worth over $2.9 billion.</p>
<p>Srettha was born into a wealthy family. And some thought he would not be able to connect with Pheu Thai's main voters in the country's poorer, rural north. But after joining the party, he appeared at many campaign events targeting the working class.</p>
<p>Before starting his political career, Srettha was a major critic of the outgoing Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha. Prayuth was an army leader who led the <strong>coup</strong> against another Pheu Thai government led by Thaksin's sister Yingluck in 2014.</p>
<p>Srettha was among many opposition politicians, thought leaders and activists questioned by Prayuth's military government shortly after the coup.</p>
<p>He wrote many online posts accusing Prayuth and his government of <strong>mishandling</strong> the COVID-19 pandemic. Srettha earned support during student-led protests demanding democratic reforms in 2020.</p>
<p>Srettha became an adviser for Pheu Thai's economic team to promote the party's policies. That includes a plan to give 10,000 baht, about $290, in digital money to all Thais age 16 and above.</p>
<p><strong>Thaskin's controversial return</strong></p>
<p>Thaksin is still loved and hated in equal measure in Thailand. Hundreds of his supporters gathered at the airport, the court and outside the prison to greet his return. They wore red shirts, carried signs and chanted "PM Thaksin."</p>
<p>Thaksin was a former policeman who started a successful business selling computers. As prime minister, he won the hearts and votes of millions of Thais in rural areas with giveaways like money, loans, farm support and healthcare.</p>
<p>But his huge popularity and support for new <strong>capitalism</strong> put him in conflict with the military, businesses, and royal supporters. It started a political battle that is still being played out today.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>livelihood </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of earning money in order to live</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exile </strong><em>— n. </em>a situation in which you are forced to leave your country or home and go to live in a foreign country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coup </strong><em>— n. </em>a sudden attempt by a small group of people to take over the government usually through violence</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mishandle </strong><em>— v. </em>to deal with or manage badly or incorrectly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>capitalism </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of organizing an economy so that the things that are used to make and transport products are owned by individual people and companies rather than by the government</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Vocabulary  (2023/8/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-literacy-vocabulary.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The words we use to speak, write, and read are called our vocabulary. We need a strong vocabulary to share ideas.</p>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for vocabulary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An English teacher should <strong>focus</strong> heavily on building vocabulary. When you teach your students new words, use strategies and activities that allow them to draw, read, write, and repeat new words as much as possible.</li>
<li>Use examples <strong>suited</strong> to the age of your students. If you teach the word "happy" to younger students, your example might be, "My friend gave me a toy. I felt happy." But you probably would not use that example with an older student. In that case, an example might be, "My job makes me happy."</li>
<li>Create a sentence frame for the students to use. Sentence frames help students use a word quickly and in a complete thought. They are ready-made sentences. Sentence frames for the word "happy" could be:</li>
</ul>
<p><em>"I feel happy when ______."</em></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Vocabulary" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-32e9-08db93831514_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Vocabulary</span></div>
<p><em>"_______ makes me happy."</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Use <strong>visual</strong> aids and appeal to all your students' senses. When you teach a new word, show a picture. If you teach the word<em> "</em>bug," show or bring in a bug! If you teach the word "happy," show them happiness. Have them act it out. Use the senses often.</li>
<li>Once you teach a new word, use it often. The more students use a new word, the more likely they are to learn and remember it.</li>
<li>Use vocabulary across subject matter. Include words you use in other classes like math and science. Students are more likely to learn a word if they use it in different situations.</li>
<li>Finish the new word lesson with a question or quick activity. You could ask, "What do people look like when they are happy? Can you show me?" Then have each student show happiness.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Strategies for vocabulary</strong></p>
<p><u>Strategy: First Teach Important Words and Ideas</u></p>
<p>Before reading a story, your students should understand the words and ideas in the story. Make a vocabulary list of key words in the text. Post the list in the classroom. Say the words with students. Talk about the meanings. Also explain any new ideas in the story.</p>
<p><u>Strategy: Active Read-Aloud </u></p>
<p>This strategy can be used for vocabulary and comprehension.</p>
<p>When reading aloud to your class, ask questions about a new or important word. Let students answer in their home language or English. Correct or add to the students' answers.</p>
<p>Here is an example:</p>
<p><em>TEACHER: "What does it mean to hate somebody?</em></p>
<p><em>STUDENT: "You do not like them."</em></p>
<p><em>TEACHER: "Yes. But a little or a lot?"</em></p>
<p><em>STUDENT: "A lot. You do not like them a lot."</em></p>
<p>Explain the meaning of the word. Give a definition, related words, and examples. Use your face, objects, pictures, or physical movements to show word meanings while they read aloud.</p>
<p><u>Strategy: Word Map</u></p>
<p>A Word Map is like a picture. It organizes information in a visual<strong> </strong>way. Word Maps help students to think about new words in different ways.</p>
<p>On the board or on paper, write the new word in the middle of the map. Tell the students to think about the word. Then they fill in the rest of the map with a definition, sentences using the word, related words, unrelated words, and pictures to explain the word. Do this as a whole class or in small groups.</p>
<p><strong>Assessment for vocabulary</strong></p>
<p>Assessing, or testing, vocabulary in your students is very important. Here are some ways to assess vocabulary of early and advanced learners.</p>
<p><u>Match words with visuals </u></p>
<p>This type of assessment is very helpful for early learners and learners with a very low English level. Choose the target words —the words you want to test. Then, collect or draw pictures to go with each word. You can also use objects. Say the word and then have the student choose the correct picture or object.</p>
<p><u>Interviews</u></p>
<p>Chose the target words and ask the student questions:</p>
<p>- Can you use this word in a sentence?</p>
<p>- What word in your language means the same thing?</p>
<p>- Use your face and body to show the word's meaning.</p>
<p><u>In their own words (Summarize)</u></p>
<p>Give students a short text to read. Make sure the text has target vocabulary. Students then can show their understanding of the vocabulary by re-telling, describing, or explaining the text. You can also ask students to talk about a character or favorite part of the story using the target vocabulary.</p>
<p><u>Role-plays</u></p>
<p>Role-plays are a form of acting. Give students a text to read and have them act it out. More advanced students can write a play using the target vocabulary. Students can play the role of the teacher and review vocabulary with the class.</p>
<p>Use these tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve you and your learners. Change them to fit your students and teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this article for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>the center of activity, attraction, or attention</p>
<p><strong>suit </strong><em>– v. </em>to meet a person's needs or desires</p>
<p><strong>visual </strong><em>– adj. </em>something that is seen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Prepares Moon Landing after Failed Russian Attempt  (2023/8/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/india-prepares-moon-landing-after-failed-russian-attempt.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>India will soon attempt to land a spacecraft on the point farthest south on the moon, its south pole.</p>
<p>The attempt comes just days after the failure of a Russian moon lander. India's space agency on Monday released images its spacecraft captured on the far side of the moon. That is the part of the moon that cannot be seen from Earth.</p>
<p>The Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) launched the spacecraft called the Chandrayaan-3. ISRO had been in a race with Russia to be the first national space agency to land on the <strong>lunar</strong> south pole. The area is thought to hold water ice that could support a future moon settlement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This handout picture provided by the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) shows the surface of the moon taken by Moon Impact Probe. (REUTERS/Indian Space Research Organisation/Handout)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-1524-08dba267d667_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This handout picture provided by the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) shows the surface of the moon taken by Moon Impact Probe. (REUTERS/Indian Space Research Organisation/Handout)</span></div>
<p>As news of the failure of Russia's Luna-25 mission spread on Sunday, ISRO said that Chandrayaan-3 was set to land on August 23.</p>
<p>The mission is India's second attempt to land on the south pole of the moon. In 2019, ISRO's Chandrayaan-2 mission successfully launched an orbiter, but its lander crashed. Chandrayaan means "moon vehicle" in Hindi and Sanskrit</p>
<p>The ground at the lunar south pole is uneven making landing there difficult. A first landing would be historic. The area's water ice could supply fuel, oxygen and drinking water for future missions.</p>
<p>Images released on Monday showed <strong>craters</strong> on the moon's surface captured by the spacecraft's camera. The camera is designed to help identify a safe landing place for the spacecraft.</p>
<p>India's moon mission launched on July 14. The Chandrayaan-3's lander separated from the rest of the spacecraft last week.</p>
<p>For India, a successful moon landing would mark its arrival as a world space power. Prime Minister Narendra Modi's government aims to increase investment in private space launches and related satellite-based businesses.</p>
<p>Manish Purohit is a former ISRO scientist. "If Chandrayaan-3 succeeds, it will <strong>boost</strong> India's space agency's <strong>reputation</strong> worldwide," he said.</p>
<p><strong>Russia's Luna-25 crashes</strong></p>
<p>Russia's Luna-25 spacecraft crashed into the moon after it went into an uncontrolled orbit, the country's Roscosmos space agency said Sunday. The pilotless spacecraft had been expected to land Monday.</p>
<p>However, Roscosmos said it lost contact with the Luna-25 on Saturday after the spacecraft reported problems.</p>
<p>Vitaly Egorov is a popular Russian space expert. He said the mission had some successes although it crashed.</p>
<p>"Luna 25 showed important progress. It flew toward the Moon, carried out orbit correction, and tested <strong>onboard</strong> electronics and scientific tools," he said. "Russian <strong>cosmonautics</strong> was not at this level before. But then, an error occurred somehow."</p>
<p>The lunar mission was Russia's first since 1976, when it was known as the Soviet Union. Only three governments have successfully landed on the moon: the Soviet Union, the United States and China.</p>
<p>Scientists at ISRO have said they learned from the earlier moon mission's failure and made changes to Chandrayaan-3. They said a successful landing is now more likely. The changes include making it possible to land safely anywhere within a larger landing area in difficult conditions. It also holds more fuel, carries additional <strong>solar panels</strong> and has stronger legs.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>lunar </strong><em>— adj. </em>related to the moon<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>crater —</strong><em> n. </em>a hole in the surface of the ground caused by an explosion or something that is very heavy falling there</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>boost</strong> <em>–v.</em> to lift up; to raise</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reputation </strong><em>–n.</em> the common opinion that people have a person, group, organization or country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>onboard </strong><em>–adj.</em> carried on a vehicle and not placed somewhere else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cosmonautic </strong><em>— adj. </em>related to cosmonauts, Russia's version of astronauts</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>solar panel </strong><em>–n.</em> a flat device that creates electricity using energy from the sun</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New COVID-19 Vaccine to Launch in September  (2023/8/22) | 美国新版新冠疫苗将于9月面市</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/new-covid-19-vaccine-to-launch-in-september.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The latest COVID-19 vaccine is set for release in September. But health experts say it remains unclear how many Americans will choose to get the new shot.<br/>
最新的新冠肺炎疫苗将于今年9月发布。但卫生专家表示，目前尚不清楚有多少美国人会选择接种新疫苗。</p>
<p>The efforts to prepare a new vaccine come as hospitals in the United States report increases in COVID-19 patients since early July. But the number of hospitalizations is still far below those reported earlier this year and throughout the COVID-19 pandemic.<br/>
新疫苗的开发工作正值美国医院报告自7月初以来新冠肺炎患者增加之际。但住院人数仍远低于今年早些时候和整个新冠肺炎大流行期间报告的人数。</p>
<p>A drop in infections has caused demand for the vaccine to fall sharply since the first shot became available in 2021. Officials say that overall, more than 240 million people in the U.S. had received at least one COVID-19 injection. That number represents about 73 percent of America's population.<br/>
感染人数下降导致对疫苗的需求自2021年第一针疫苗问世以来的急剧下降。官员们表示，总体而言，美国有超过2.4亿人至少接种了一针新冠肺炎疫苗。这个数字约占美国人口的73%。</p>
<p>By autumn of 2022, fewer than 50 million people got the vaccine shots. By that time, most people in the U.S. had either been infected with COVID-19 or had received at least one shot.<br/>
到了2022年秋季，只有不到5000万人接种了疫苗。那时，大多数美国人要么感染了新冠肺炎，要么至少接种了一针。</p>
<p>Public health experts have advised people to look at COVID-19 vaccines the same as they do shots for other sicknesses, such as the flu. Flu vaccines are developed to fight the latest virus versions, called variants, and are generally administered once per flu season.<br/>
公共卫生专家建议人们像接种流感等其他疾病的疫苗一样，接种新冠肺炎疫苗。流感疫苗的开发是为了对抗最新版本的病毒，也就是所谓变种，通常每个流感季节都要接种一次。</p>
<p>But efforts to get people to seek COVID-19 shots are likely to be hurt by decreasing concern about the virus. Some people also question if the vaccines are safe.<br/>
但让人们接种新冠肺炎疫苗的努力可能会因为人们对该病毒的担忧减少而受到损害。一些人还质疑疫苗是否安全。</p>
<p>Healthcare providers and drug businesses have said they plan to start offering the new COVID-19 vaccine next month. The vaccine was developed to fight virus versions linked to the Omicron variant, which has been spreading in the U.S. since last year.<br/>
医疗保健提供商和制药企业表示，他们计划下个月开始提供新的新冠肺炎疫苗。该疫苗是为了对抗与奥密克戎变异株有关的病毒版本而开发的，奥密克龙变异株自去年以来一直在美国传播。</p>
<p>Ashley Kirzinger is a lead researcher with the Kaiser Family Foundation. She told Reuters news agency that health officials need to send a clear message to the public that COVID-19 has not gone away. In addition, the messaging should note the new vaccine can protect individuals from serious sickness and hospitalization.<br/>
阿什利·科齐格是凯撒家族基金会的首席研究员。她告诉路透社，卫生官员需要向公众发出一个明确的信息，即新冠肺炎尚未消失。此外，该信息还应该指出，新疫苗可以保护个人避免重症和住院治疗。</p>
<p>Kirzinger noted her foundation has carried out public opinion studies on the issue. She said the top reason vaccinated people gave for rejecting more vaccinations was the belief that people were protected from the virus because of earlier shots or infections.<br/>
科齐格指出，她所在的基金会已经对这个问题进行了民意调查。她说，接种过疫苗的人士拒绝接种更多疫苗的首要原因，是相信之前打过疫苗或已经感染过，不会再次感染病毒。</p>
<p>The two largest COVID-19 vaccine makers – Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna – have predicted far less demand this autumn for the shots. Last year, vaccine sales by Pfizer and Moderna reached a combined $56 billion worldwide. This year, experts estimate the shots will bring in $20 billion for the companies.<br/>
两家最大的新冠肺炎疫苗制造商——辉瑞生物技术公司和莫德纳公司——预计今年秋季对疫苗需求将大幅减少。去年，辉瑞和莫德纳在全球的疫苗销售额总计达到560亿美元。专家估计，疫苗今年将为这些公司带来200亿美元的收入。</p>
<p>The COVID-19 public health emergency officially ended in May. Since then, the government has handed over much of the vaccination effort to private companies. More than 1.1 million people in the United States have died from COVID, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reports.<br/>
新冠肺炎突发公共卫生事件于5月正式结束。自那时以来，政府已将大部分疫苗接种工作移交给私营公司。据美国疾控预防中心报道，美国已有110多万人死于新冠肺炎。</p>
<p>The CDC and U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) are considering for approval the final versions of the new vaccine. CDC Director Mandy Cohen said last week she expects the shots to be launched during the third or fourth week of September.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心和美国食品药品监督管理局正在考虑批准新疫苗的最终版本。美国疾控预防中心主任曼迪·科恩上周表示，她预计疫苗将在9月的第三或第四周接种。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·琳恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Gardeners Can Deal with Floods  (2023/8/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/how-gardeners-can-deal-with-floods.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Water is required for plant life. But what happens when there is too much of a good thing?</p>
<p>That has been the case in many parts of the world this summer. Scientists say extreme rainfall happens more often now as storms form in an atmosphere made warmer by climate change.</p>
<p>Nick Goltz is head of the UConn Plant Diagnostic Laboratory at the University of Connecticut in Storrs, Connecticut. He said too much water can mean dead plants in a <strong>garden</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This July 31, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a squash plant with yellow, wilted foliage — symptoms that present after both flood and drought — on Long Island in New York. (Jessica Damiano via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/51ec774b-0aee-4cad-8cbe-c88da45cefab_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This July 31, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a squash plant with yellow, wilted foliage — symptoms that present after both flood and drought — on Long Island in New York. (Jessica Damiano via AP)</span></div>
<p>Goltz explained that flooding cuts off the oxygen supply which leads to root-<strong>rot</strong> diseases. And then plants cannot pull enough water to survive. The result is yellow, weakening leaves, which would usually show a plant's need for water. But after flooding, those same signs mean that roots under water cannot <strong>function</strong> in really wet conditions.</p>
<p><strong>What you can do</strong></p>
<p>Avoid walking on wet soil if your garden has been affected by flooding. Wait until the soil has mostly dried before looking at the damage. Adding any weight or pressure to wet soil can cause even more oxygen to be pressed out from around struggling roots.</p>
<p>A plant with just a few signs of damage may recover, but a plant that is completely weakened probably will not, Goltz said. He added that plants with strong, deep roots – like trees and yearly returning plants – have the best chances of recovery.</p>
<p>Annuals are plants that live for less than a year. Their roots are not as deep and they are at risk if flooded. Goltz advised removing annuals if they look unhealthy.</p>
<p>Plants weakened or stressed by flood water can more easily get diseases and unwanted insects. So keep an eye on them and treat problems as they come, which could be months later.</p>
<p>Broken tree branches should be removed immediately. But save any major removal of leaves and branches for when conditions improve to avoid further weakening an already stressed tree.</p>
<p><strong>Are fruits and vegetables safe to eat?</strong></p>
<p>Flooded fruits, vegetables, and other crops should be considered unsafe and not eaten.</p>
<p>Goltz said, "If the part you're eating touches the water, then it's unsafe," even if washed or cooked. That is because in addition to bacteria from standing water, runoff from nearby gardens, chemicals, and other waste could be present, Goltz added.</p>
<p>However, if your garden was flooded but the food part of the plant was not, "then it can be eaten," Goltz said. But even then, he said, it is best to wash and cook the food part.</p>
<p><strong>Repairing the soil</strong></p>
<p>After dealing with your plants' needs, turn your attention to the flooded soil, which will also need some care. Flooded soil loses nutrients and can damage the way water flows through it. Mixing in <strong>compost</strong> will help on both counts and mixing in sand will improve the way water flows through it as well.</p>
<p>If you live in an area that easily floods, there are steps you can take to avoid or lessen future damage, such as growing vegetables in higher areas or raised beds. Or you could direct water away from the plants you care about most.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>rot </strong>– <em>v.</em> to slowly decay or cause (something) to decay</p>
<p><strong>function </strong>– <em>v. </em>to work or operate</p>
<p><strong>compost </strong>– <em>n.</em> a decayed mixture of plants (such as leaves and grass) that is used to improve the soil in a garden</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
