<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>New Rules Aim to Protect Valuable Horseshoe Crabs  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/new-rules-aim-to-protect-valuable-horseshoe-crabs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>New rules aim to protect horseshoe crabs, which are used in medical research, and also to support an endangered bird <strong>species</strong>.</p>
<p>Blue blood from horseshoe crabs is used by researchers to test for dangerous substances in vaccines, medicines and medical devices. The animals are also used by fisherman as <strong>bait</strong> to catch eels and sea snails.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Horseshoe crabs spawn at Reeds Beach in Cape May Court House, N.J., Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-8df0-08db920c47ff_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Horseshoe crabs spawn at Reeds Beach in Cape May Court House, N.J., Tuesday, June 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke)</span></div>
<p>In addition, the eggs of horseshoe crabs are an important food for an endangered bird called the red knot.</p>
<p>Scientists say horseshoe crabs have been living in ocean environments for more than 400 million years. But they are different from other crabs. They are more closely related to spiders and scorpions. The animals have been decreasing in numbers in areas they live in, called habitats, along the U.S. East Coast.</p>
<p>The blue blood is taken from the animals for medical research. The process returns the crabs to the environment. But many die from the blood harvesting process.</p>
<p>Blood from the crabs can be manufactured into limulus amebocyte lysate, or LAL, a substance used to identify dangerous substances in some medications and vaccines.</p>
<p>Fishermen collect the crabs by hand or with special equipment on boats for use by biomedical companies. The blood – which contains immune cells sensitive to bacteria – is then separated and proteins are processed. It takes many crabs to produce enough blood to fill a single glass tube, which contains cells that are sensitive to bacteria.</p>
<p>New guidelines for dealing with horseshoe crabs were approved in May by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. Industry officials said those changes should keep more crabs alive. But, in recent years, environmentalists brought attention to the issue of the horseshoe crabs, including their relationship to the red knot.</p>
<p>Red knots are birds that travel about 30,500 kilometers back and forth from South America to Canada. During their long trip, the birds must stop to eat along the way and horseshoe crabs are an important food.</p>
<p>Bethany Kraft is a coastal <strong>conservation</strong> specialist with the environmental organization the Audubon Society. Kraft told The Associated Press (AP) that red knots need horseshoe crab eggs to give them enough fuel to complete their long flights. "There's very clear linkage between horseshoe crabs and the survival of the red knot in the coming <strong>decades</strong>," she added.</p>
<p>Kraft said horseshoe crabs currently need stronger protection to survive. She and other wildlife conservationists have noted the new guidelines are currently only voluntary. This, they say, still leaves the red knot at risk. They say the bird needs stronger legal protection.</p>
<p>The new guidelines urge best practices for the biomedical industry's harvesting and processing of the crabs. They include measures aimed at limiting <strong>exposure</strong> to sunlight and keeping crabs cool and wet.</p>
<p>Caitlin Starks is a fishery specialist with the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. She told the AP the goal of the guidelines "is to give the crabs that are bled a better chance of surviving."</p>
<p>That is exactly what the new guidelines will do, said Nora Blair, an operations official with Charles River Laboratories. The company manufactures LAL from horseshoe crab blood. Blair was a member of a working group that created the new guidelines along with other industry groups.</p>
<p>Blair said the industry is working to find <strong>synthetic</strong> materials that could be used for biomedical research. Conservationists have been pushing for years for such a solution. Lonza, a Switzerland-based company that manufactures LAL, offers an animal-free testing solution.</p>
<p>But Blair said that, for now, the wild harvest of horseshoe crabs remains extremely important for drug safety. The animals play an important part in supplying and testing drugs and the coastal environment makes their conservation "<strong>imperative</strong>," she added.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>bait </strong>–n. a piece of foot that is used to catch fish or other animals</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong><em>– n. </em>a period of ten years<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>expose </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove what is covering something so that it can be seen</p>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong><em>– adj. </em>a group of products made from artificial substances, often copying a natural product</p>
<p><strong>imperative </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely important or necessary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Colleges Ask for More Writing after Affirmative Action Ban  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-colleges-ask-for-more-writing-after-affirmative-action-ban.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>August 1 is the start of the new college <strong>admissions</strong> season in the United States. It is the day students can start to complete the Common Application for college admission in 2024.</p>
<p>The Common Application is accepted by over 1,000 colleges and universities. The service permits students to <strong>apply</strong> to many schools by submitting their information only one time.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sign points the way to the Harvard College Admissions Visitors Center at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, U.S., July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/13cb9c21-c17c-4e4c-ac4b-e322b40519e0_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sign points the way to the Harvard College Admissions Visitors Center at Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, U.S., July 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)</span></div>
<p>However, some colleges and universities that accept the Common Application are asking students to send in an extra piece of writing. They are using the extra "<strong>prompt</strong>" to give students a chance to discuss their background.</p>
<p>The reason for this new writing prompt is the U.S. Supreme Court's recent decision to end affirmative action in college decisions.</p>
<p>The court said <strong>selective</strong> colleges and universities, such as Harvard University or the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, can no longer use race as a way to decide between two qualified students.</p>
<p>But the court did say schools can consider "an applicant's discussion of how race affected his or her life..."</p>
<p>That is why some schools are re-writing their prompts.</p>
<p>At Yale University, students who apply with the Common Application must also answer one of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://admissions.yale.edu/essay-topics" target="_blank">three questions</a>.</p>
<p>The first question permits students to write about a time they discussed an important issue with someone holding an opposing view.</p>
<p>Another question asks students to discuss a meaningful community to which they are connected.</p>
<p>But a third question is new, compared to past years. It asks students to talk about part of their "personal experience that you feel will <strong>enrich</strong> your college."</p>
<p>That question permits a student to state their race and discuss how they would add something special to the group of students at Yale.</p>
<p>At Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, a new prompt asks students to "tell about a community that you have been part of where your <strong>participation</strong> helped to change or shape the community for the better."</p>
<p>Timothy Fields is a top admissions official at Emory. He said the new questions "are going to be much more targeted."</p>
<p>At Sarah Lawrence College outside of New York City, a new question asks students how the Supreme Court decision on affirmative action might affect their lives.</p>
<p>Kevin McKenna is a vice president at the college. He said the new question gives students a chance to discuss the decision "that could <strong>impact</strong> the student bodies of the colleges to which they are applying."</p>
<p><strong>An acceptance campaign</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the new questions, many colleges and universities are thinking about how to connect with Black and Latino students. The school leaders worry that those students may think they are no longer welcome at selective universities after the Supreme Court decision.</p>
<p>Amin Abdul-Malik Gonzalez is the top admissions official at Wesleyan University in Connecticut. He and his team are planning extra time at high schools and more meetings at college information events to tell minority students they are still welcome.</p>
<p>He also will offer more training to his admissions officers so they can work to build a <strong>diverse</strong> group of students without going against the Supreme Court's decision.</p>
<p>Visits such as those by the Wesleyan team are important, said Angel Perez. He is head of the National Association for College Admission Counseling. Perez said some college counselors for high school students are uncertain how their students should address their race in applications.</p>
<p>"The general feeling with school counselors right now is mostly <strong>anxiety</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>But those who work with students, like private admissions counselor Shereem Herndon-Brown, say students should not overstate how race affects their lives.</p>
<p>Herndon-Brown wrote a book with Fields, the admissions leader at Emory. He said students need to write "<strong>authentically</strong>" about how they think and have developed as a result of their background.</p>
<p>He gave an example of a Black student from New York who recently visited relatives in the southern part of the U.S. Herndon-Brown encouraged the student to write about that experience although it was not in the student's original plan.</p>
<p>That he said, is a better idea than declaring their race or overstating their disadvantage.</p>
<p>"There is no way to trick an admissions officer or a school into believing you're something that you're not," he says.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>admissions </strong>–<em>n</em>. the act or process of accepting a student into a college or university study program</p>
<p><strong>apply </strong><em>–v.</em><em> </em>to submit information to an organization such as a college for the right to be admitted as a student</p>
<p><strong>prompt</strong> <em>–n. </em>a suggestion for a conversation or piece of writing</p>
<p><strong>selective</strong> <em>–adj. </em>choosy; interested in picking something of higher quality</p>
<p><strong>enrich</strong> <em>–v. </em>to add something memorable to an experience</p>
<p><strong>participation</strong> <em>–n. </em>the act of being involved in something</p>
<p><strong>impact</strong> <em>–v. </em>to make an impression or have an effect on something</p>
<p><strong>diverse</strong> <em>–adj. </em>used to describe a group made of people or things that are different from each other</p>
<p><strong>anxiety</strong> <em>–n. </em>an emotional state of being worried or very concerned</p>
<p><strong>authentic</strong> <em>–adj. </em>something true or real</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Run Something Up the Flagpole' to Test an Idea  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/run-something-up-the-flagpole-to-test-an-idea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Great ideas can be the <strong>lifeblood </strong>of any project. That means they can bring a project to life or even back from the dead. From redesigning a home to creating an educational product, <strong>bold</strong>, creative ideas are valuable.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Flags of member nations at NATO headquarters." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e62f-08db343e7c1a_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Flags of member nations at NATO headquarters.</span></div>
<p>But often even a great idea needs a little work. It may need <strong>tweaking</strong>,<strong> </strong>meaning you need to make<strong> </strong>small changes. So, before sharing an idea with a large group, we may want to share it with a smaller group. We can test it out first, before putting the idea into action.</p>
<p>But first, let's talk about getting that big idea.</p>
<p>You may have heard of brainstorming. This is an idea-creating activity. When we brainstorm, we say ideas as quickly as we think of them.</p>
<p>In informal situations, we can call this <u>throwing spaghetti at the wall</u>. Why, you may ask? Well, cooked spaghetti is sticky. If spaghetti is cooked enough, it will stick when you throw it against the wall. If it is not cooked enough, it might not stick.</p>
<p>Good ideas stick too. In brainstorming, we often say we throw ideas around. And the good ones stay or stick. But as we said earlier, even if an idea sticks, we may want to test it out before sharing it with a large group of people.</p>
<p>That is when we can <u>run it up the flagpole</u>. Running an idea, plan, or proposal up the flagpole is a way to test interest or get <strong>feedback</strong>. The full phrase is "run it up the flagpole and see if anyone salutes." Military members <strong>salute</strong> when our flag is present and when they hear the first note of the national anthem.</p>
<p>Let's listen to an example: If you are the leader of a project, you could say to your team, "I like that plan. But it is risky. Let's run it up the flagpole before <strong>pitching</strong> it to the boss." In other words, you want to get more opinions before making the plan official.</p>
<p>Here is another example: When writing these stories, I often run my ideas up a flagpole. I respect the opinions of my co-workers and often take their suggestions <u>on board</u> – meaning I take them into consideration. So, I like bouncing ideas off them.</p>
<p>And that is a more common way to express this idea. <u>Bouncing something off someone</u> is a way to know their thoughts. You are asking their opinion and are looking to see their reaction. Bouncing ideas around is a good way to <strong><u>gauge</u></strong><u> interest</u> – to find out what people think.</p>
<p>So, the next time you have an idea, and you are unsure about it, run it up the flagpole! Bounce it off some friends! With the right people, you will soon know if it is good, bad, or needs work.</p>
<p>And that is all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lifeblood </strong><em>–n</em>. the most important part of something</p>
<p><strong>bold </strong><em>–adj.</em> strong, clear and without fear</p>
<p><strong>tweak </strong><em>–v. </em>to change something a little to improve it</p>
<p><strong>feedback </strong>–n. advice or criticism given to a person or group providing a product or service</p>
<p><strong>salute </strong><em>–v. </em>to honor (a person, a nation, an event, etc.) by a conventional military or naval ceremony</p>
<p><strong>pitch in </strong><em>–v. </em>to contribute to a common task</p>
<p><strong>gauge </strong>–v. to judge the qualities of someone or something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Benjamin Harrison: Grandson  (2023/8/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/americas-presidents-benjamin-harrison.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Benjamin Harrison.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Benjamin Harrison" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fbc85745-b2a6-494e-be5a-05b8b04f862a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Benjamin Harrison</span></div>
<p>His family name may sound familiar. That is because he was the grandson of President <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-william-henry-harrison/3806092.html" target="_blank">William Henry Harrison</a>. That situation is unique in U.S. history so far.</p>
<p>Harrison played an unusually active <strong>role</strong> as president at a time when most chief executives saw themselves as simply administrators. As a result, American writer and intellectual Henry Adams said Harrison was the best president since Lincoln.</p>
<p>But most Americans remember little about him, except his connection to the previous President Harrison, who himself died after only a month in office.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Benjamin Harrison grew up on a farm in the Midwestern state of Ohio as one of eight children.</p>
<p>His grandfather was not the only famous political Harrison.</p>
<p>His great-grandfather signed the Declaration of Independence. And his father had been a congressman.</p>
<p>Young Benjamin Harrison respected these men and believed he had a role to play in history, too. He received a good education, and even outside of school he read many books.</p>
<p>His hard work and intelligence carried him to Miami University in Ohio, and then to a career as a lawyer.</p>
<p>Along the way, he married a woman he had known since he was a teenager, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/carolineharrison" target="_blank">Caroline Lavinia Scott</a>. The couple settled in another Midwestern city, Indianapolis, Indiana, and had a son and daughter.</p>
<p>Over time, Harrison steadily built a career as a public official. But his political path was <strong>interrupted</strong> by the American Civil War.</p>
<p>Harrison rose to the rank of general in the Union Army. He fought under General William T. Sherman, and was one of the first soldiers to enter Atlanta, Georgia after the city surrendered.</p>
<p>After the war, he returned home to Indiana and continued his legal and political career. In 1881, he was elected to the U.S. Senate. But six years later he lost his seat when Democrats came to power in his state.Reports say that Harrison was an excellent soldier. But he did not enjoy fighting or find war <strong>romantic</strong>.</p>
<p>Harrison's loss of his Senate seat soon turned to a victory. The Republican Party nominated him as their candidate to run against Grover Cleveland in the 1888 presidential election.</p>
<p>Cleveland's economic policies had become unpopular, and Republicans worked hard to support their candidate. They succeeded. Although Cleveland won the popular vote, Harrison won the Electoral College.</p>
<p>In 1889, he followed his grandfather's footsteps all the way to the White House.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency </strong></p>
<p>Harrison's election was a major victory for his Republican Party. In addition to winning the White House, Republicans gained seats in the House of Representatives, held a majority in the Senate, and appointed several Republican justices to the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Harrison and other Republican lawmakers used their power to take action on issues at home and internationally.</p>
<p>One act was to preserve forests. Harrison identified 17 protected natural areas, and helped create Yosemite National Park in California.</p>
<p>His government also established Ellis Island in New York to make immigration to the U.S. a more orderly process.</p>
<p>Internationally, Harrison's administration sought to build ties with Latin American countries. His government established what would, in time, become the Organization of American States.</p>
<p>His administration also increased the United States' global trade – as well as the country's navy.</p>
<p>But, for the most part, the most pressing issues of the day were economic. The federal government at that time had an unusually large surplus. Some argued that the surplus was hurting business. In answer, Harrison's government placed a high protective tariff on imported goods. The legislation was known as the McKinley Tariff of 1890.</p>
<p>Officials also aimed to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.britannica.com/event/Sherman-Antitrust-Act">limit the power of large corporations</a> to control important markets in the U.S.</p>
<p>Finally, they agreed to require the government to buy silver to use as currency.</p>
<p>These actions pleased some of his supporters. But, they <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.historylink.org/File/2030">may have contributed</a> to the severe economic depression that followed Harrison's term.</p>
<p>And in general, voters disapproved of the amount of money Republican lawmakers were spending. Although the country was at peace, the 51<sup>st</sup> Congress <strong>appropriated</strong> $1 billion. At the midterm elections, many lawmakers paid for all the spending with their seats.</p>
<p>Two years later, voters turned Harrison out of the White House, too. They returned Grover Cleveland to the presidency.</p>
<p>Harrison did not express much disappointment. He had worked hard to become president like his grandfather. But he found he did not like being the chief executive. He said when he left the White House, it was like being released from prison.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Among U.S. presidents, Harrison does not have one of the most dramatic biographies. The facts of his life show an intelligent, disciplined man who tried to live by his beliefs.</p>
<p>But he was not considered <strong>passionate </strong>about many things, except perhaps his enjoyment of nature. And he did not have an easy way with people. Even his staff called him "the human iceberg" because he could be <strong>aloof</strong> and act coldly toward people.</p>
<p>Yet Harrison's family brought some warmth to his administration. His wife, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/carolineharrison">Caroline</a>, was known to be a lively, social person. She was the first to install a Christmas tree in the White House.</p>
<p>Some of Harrison's grandchildren also lived in the White House. Harrison permitted them to play on the grounds with their pet animals. During Harrison's term, the family kept a goat, which the children called "Old Whiskers."</p>
<p>Harrison's time in the White House saw sorrow, too. Toward the end of her husband's term, the first lady became seriously ill with tuberculosis. For months, Benjamin Harrison divided his attention between his wife and his job, and yet in the end lost both.</p>
<p>After his term as president ended, Benjamin Harrison returned to his home in Indianapolis. He did some work as a teacher and lawyer, and kept a good public image in his community.</p>
<p>He also re-married. His second wife was a widow herself, as well as his first wife's niece.</p>
<p>He and Mary Scott Lord Dimmick Harrison had a daughter together. The child was only four when Harrison died from pneumonia at age 67.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Mario Ritter was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p>____________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Check your understanding by taking a listening quiz. Play each video, then choose the best answer.</p>
<p>____________________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>role </strong>- <em>n.</em> a part that someone or something has in a particular activity or situation</p>
<p><strong>interrupt</strong> -<em> v.</em> to cause (something) to stop happening for a time</p>
<p><strong>romantic</strong> - <em>adj.</em> not realistic or practical : not based on what is real</p>
<p><strong>appropriate</strong> - <em>v. </em> to get or save (money) for a specific use or purpose</p>
<p><strong>passionate</strong> - <em>adj.</em> having, showing, or expressing strong emotions or beliefs</p>
<p><strong>aloof</strong> - <em>adj.</em> not involved with or friendly toward other people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russia’s Bolshoi Ballet Aims to Perform again in the West  (2023/8/5) | 俄罗斯著名芭蕾舞团渴望重返西方舞台</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/russia-s-bolshoi-ballet-aims-to-perform-again-in-the-west.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The artistic director of Moscow's state-owned Bolshoi Ballet has promised the group will one day perform in the West again.<br/>
莫斯科国有的莫斯科大剧院芭蕾舞团的艺术总监承诺，该团终有一天会再次在西方演出。</p>
<p>The famous ballet company performed last week in China at Beijing's National Centre for the Performing Arts. It was the company's first performance outside of Russia since the COVID-19 pandemic began in 2020. The company has faced boycotts from many countries because of Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2022.<br/>
这家著名的芭蕾舞团上周在北京国家大剧院演出。这是该舞团自2020年新冠肺炎疫情开始以来首次在国外表演。由于2022年2月俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，该舞团面临许多国家的抵制。</p>
<p>Artistic director Mahkar Vaziev said the Bolshoi was "not suffering" from being unable to perform in the West.<br/>
艺术总监马哈尔·瓦齐耶夫表示，莫斯科大剧院无法在西方演出“并不痛苦”。</p>
<p>"I have no doubt that one day everything will go back to how it should be because culture is a wave that is very hard to suppress," Vaziev said.<br/>
瓦齐耶夫说：“我毫不怀疑，总有一天一切都会回到它应有的状态，因为文化是一股很难压制的浪潮。”</p>
<p>For many people, the Bolshoi represents the highest level of Russian culture. The ballet company was founded in 1776 by Empress Catherine the Great. The company performed around the world even during the most difficult times of the Cold War.<br/>
对许多人来说，莫斯科大剧院代表了俄罗斯文化的最高水平。这支芭蕾舞团由女皇凯瑟琳大帝于1776年创立。即使在冷战最困难的时期，该舞团也在世界各地演出。</p>
<p>Bolshoi's dancers hope their performance in China is a sign that they will return to performing around the world.<br/>
莫斯科大剧院的舞者们希望他们在中国的表演是他们将重返世界各地表演的标志。</p>
<p>However, only two other performances are currently on the company's schedule. The dancers are set to perform in the Belarusian capital Minsk in November and Oman next January.<br/>
然而，目前该舞团日程上只有另外两场演出。舞者们将于11月在白俄罗斯首都明斯克表演，明年1月在阿曼表演。</p>
<p>The Bolshoi's time in Beijing includes two performances that will show parts of its best-known ballets. It will then give a three-day staging of the 19th-century ballet "Don Quixote".<br/>
莫斯科大剧院在北京的演出将包括两台演出，它将展示其最著名的芭蕾舞剧的部分内容。然后它将连续三天上演19世纪芭蕾舞剧《堂吉诃德》。</p>
<p>The Bolshoi still receives around 70 percent of its financial support from the Russian government, a company official said. No current performers have spoken out against the Russian invasion. The United Nations reports the war has injured or killed about 8,500 civilians.<br/>
莫斯科大剧院官员表示，其70%左右的财政支持仍来自俄罗斯政府。目前没有任何表演者公开反对俄罗斯的入侵。联合国报告称，这场战争已造成约8500名平民受伤或死亡。</p>
<p>In February 2022, the day after Moscow sent thousands of troops into Ukraine, London's Royal Opera House canceled Bolshoi performances planned for the summer of that year.<br/>
2022年2月，在莫斯科向乌克兰派遣数千名士兵的第二天，伦敦皇家歌剧院取消了原定于当年夏天举行的莫斯科大剧院演出。</p>
<p>Cancellations in other Western cities soon followed. Creative work with Western artists and theaters came to a stop.<br/>
其他西方城市也很快取消了预订。该舞团与西方艺术家和剧院的创造性工作陷入停滞。</p>
<p>Several Russian and foreign dancers also quit the company to show their strong disapproval of the Ukraine war. Former principal ballerina Olga Smirnova was among those who quit.<br/>
几名俄罗斯和外国舞者也退出了该舞团，以表达他们对乌克兰战争的强烈不满。前首席芭蕾舞演员奥尔加·斯米尔诺娃也在辞职之列。</p>
<p>Elizaveta Kokoreva joined the company at the beginning of the pandemic. She is now its principal ballerina. She said, "I would really like to visit other countries, see the world, and get to know different venues, theatres, teachers and choreographers."<br/>
伊丽莎维塔·科科雷娃在疫情开始时加入了该舞团。她现在是该舞团的首席芭蕾舞演员。她说：“我真的很想访问其他国家，看看世界，了解不同的场地、剧院、老师和编舞家。”</p>
<p>She added, "But it is what it is right now."<br/>
她补充道，“但现状就是这样。”</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AM Radio Stations Oppose Removing AM Radios from Cars  (2023/8/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/am-radio-stations-oppose-removing-am-radios-from-cars.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The move by automobile manufacturers to include radios in cars nearly 100 years ago helped spread AM radio across the United States.</p>
<p>But now, some carmakers want to stop providing AM radio in their new vehicles.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - The number of AM radio stations in the United States is dwindling and could get smaller: Some automakers want to kick AM off their dashboard radios." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-6236-08db8fa412d7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - The number of AM radio stations in the United States is dwindling and could get smaller: Some automakers want to kick AM off their dashboard radios.</span></div>
<p>The first cars to be sold with radios were introduced in the 1930s. They only received one kind of radio <strong>transmission</strong>, those that broadcast using AM, or amplitude modulation.</p>
<p>After some time, radios could receive transmissions in AM and FM. FM stands for frequency modulation.</p>
<p>For many years, those were the only choices. But after a while, car makers added <strong>8-track</strong> players, audio <strong>cassette</strong> players, <strong>compact disc</strong> players and eventually Bluetooth connections so people could play music from mobile devices such as an iPhone.</p>
<p>However, cars are no longer sold with 8-track players or compact disc players. And now, some new electric cars are being sold with radios that only receive FM signals. Car makers say the driving systems in electric vehicles interfere with the AM signal.</p>
<p>That concerns the people who own and work at about 4,000 radio stations in the U.S. that broadcast in AM. One of them is in the small town of Dimmitt, Texas. Nancy and Todd Whalen own the radio station KDHN-1470, which has been broadcasting since 1963. They are the only employees, and they talk on the radio every morning. The Whalens have run the station for eight years.</p>
<p>They say they do it, so Dimmitt has something to feel good about. "We feel like what we've done and continue to do is provide that, not just for Dimmitt, but for all the small towns in the area that no longer have local radio stations."</p>
<p>KDHN also runs a translator, or a system that changes the signal so their programs can also be heard on FM. But the AM signal is much stronger. The FM signal covers about a 30-kilometer radius from the transmitter while the AM signal covers 160 kilometers.</p>
<p>Nancy Whalen called the AM signal "our <strong>bread and butter</strong> since the beginning."</p>
<p>The reduction in the number of AM stations has many people worried. That includes broadcasters, business owners, farmers and lawmakers. Some broadcasting companies that own AM radio stations are selling their land because it is more profitable than running a radio station.</p>
<p>Amy Klobuchar is a senator from Minnesota. She is concerned about losing AM radio stations. They keep people in her large state informed.</p>
<p>In an online <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/amyklobuchar/status/1673481193462063105?lang=en">video</a>, Klobuchar said AM radio "gives people the information they need in many of our <strong>rural </strong>areas..." She noted that "a lot of people drive long distances" in rural areas and listen to the radio in the car. She also said of AM radio: "This is where people find their local news."</p>
<p>Klobuchar and others are working on the "AM For Every Vehicle Act."</p>
<p>They want to keep AM radio in cars. The lawmakers say the car makers should find a way to keep AM radio.</p>
<p>When Klobuchar talks about people in rural areas, she is talking about people like Rodney Hunter. He supervises two grain storage structures, called silos, in Texas. He said farmers will listen to the radio on their way to sell grain. Without the news on AM radio, they would not know if grain prices were up or down.</p>
<p>"Farmers are in their (trucks or tractors) going up and down the road," Hunter said. He added it is easier for them to listen to the agriculture news on AM radio than to try to find the information online.</p>
<p>But the people who run AM radio stations are not just farmers and small-town business people with a sense of civic pride.</p>
<p>About five hours southeast of the grain-storage building, Joann Whang is a <strong>pharmacist</strong> who listens to KKDA-730 in Dallas, Texas. It is a Korean-language station. At first, Whang said she thought listening to a Korean station was only for old people.</p>
<p>"But it actually was pretty interesting," she said. She said she got a lot of information and even heard Korean pop songs, known as K-pop.</p>
<p>The station is owned by DK Media Group. The company also runs two Korean-language newspapers. Stephanie Min Kim is the president. She said removing AM from cars would hurt small companies like hers that broadcast in languages other than English. It is too costly to buy a license, or government permission, to broadcast in FM, she said.</p>
<p>Kim once worked for the Korean broadcaster KBS. She said, "We feel that it is our duty to help and support our Korean immigrants <strong>integrate</strong> into American society." She said her radio station hosts discussions with experts in law, healthcare and education that help people from Korea learn about life in the U.S.</p>
<p>She said, if AM is removed from cars, the transmissions face an "existential threat." That means the existence of the stations is threatened.</p>
<p>Radio Caravan is another small broadcaster in Dallas. It broadcasts in Hindi, Tamil and English on AM 700. Aparna Ragnan is a radio host. She said carmakers should find a way to keep AM.</p>
<p>Vaibhav Sheth is the station manager. He said the sound quality of the AM stations is not a problem. He said the information that the stations provide is more important than sound quality. In addition, he notes that AM stations are important in emergencies. The emergency signals go off to alert listeners about bad weather, like a tornado, or a child who is in danger.</p>
<p>"Whatever it is that's happening," he said, "it goes to the AM <strong>frequency</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Steve Herman. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Steve Herman wrote this story for 51voa.com. Dan Friedell adapted it for Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transmission </strong>–n. (broadcasting) the sending of a specific radio signal for broadcast</p>
<p><strong>8-track, cassette, compact disc </strong><em>–n.</em><em> </em>different kinds of devices that store information to play back sound</p>
<p><strong>rural</strong> <em>–adj. </em>in the countryside and not in the city or suburbs</p>
<p><strong>bread and butter</strong> <em>–adj. (idiomatic) </em>very basic and necessary<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>pharmacist</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person whose job it is to prepare and provide drugs and medicines called for by a medical doctor's orders</p>
<p><strong>integrate</strong> <em>–v. </em>to make a person part of a large group, organization or community</p>
<p><strong>frequency </strong>–n. <em>(broadcasting)</em> a measure of a radio wave signal that is received by a radio</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hear vs. Listen  (2023/8/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/listen-vs-hear.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "listen" and "hear."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Hear vs. Listen" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a684-08db944445f4_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Hear vs. Listen</span></div>
<p>My name is Waleed. And I am from Egypt. I would like to ask about the difference between "hear" and "listen."</p>
<p>Thanks in advance,</p>
<p>Waleed</p>
<p><strong>Answer: </strong></p>
<p>Thanks for writing to us, Waleed.</p>
<p>This is an excellent question. Both words have to do with sounds and our ears, but they do not mean the same thing. Let's look at each.</p>
<p><strong>Hear</strong></p>
<p>"Hear" is a verb that can either take a direct object or not. It has several meanings. First, in its simplest form, the word means to receive sound through the ear.</p>
<p><em>Every few hours I hear the <strong>whistle</strong> of the train.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>"Hear" can mean to get information or knowledge by hearing something.</p>
<p><em>I hear that we need to clean out our offices soon!</em></p>
<p>"Hear" also means to receive communication from someone.</p>
<p><em>Nathan has not heard from his mother in a while. He needs to call her.</em></p>
<p>"Hear" can share a meaning with the word "listen." To say you "hear" someone means that you listened to them with attention.</p>
<p><em>I hear your side of the story, but I do not agree.</em></p>
<p>Let's move on to "listen."</p>
<p><strong>Listen</strong></p>
<p>Just like the last meaning we gave for "hear," "listen" means to hear with attention and understanding. We often use the preposition "to" with it.</p>
<p><em>It is difficult to listen to my teacher for a long time.</em></p>
<p>"Listen" can mean paying attention to sounds or being alert enough to catch and understand sounds.</p>
<p><em>Maria listens to a lot of different kinds of music.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>My cat listens for the sound of the can-opener to know when it is dinner time.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>And when speaking informally, "listen" can be a noun meaning the act of listening itself.</p>
<p><em>Give this a listen! It's Carly Rae Jepsen's new song.</em></p>
<p>The biggest difference between "hearing" something and "listening" to something is the amount of attention given to the process. "Hearing" is what we usually call a <strong>passive </strong>activity, sounds are coming into your ear, you receive them, but you are not necessarily paying attention to them. "Listening" suggests an <strong>active</strong> effort that requires attention.</p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Waleed.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>whistle </strong><em>– v.</em> to make a high sound by forcing air through a small hole in the mouth</p>
<p><strong>passive </strong><em>–</em><em> adj. the quality of not being active or not taking action and letting things happen</em></p>
<p><strong>active </strong><em>–</em><em> adj. the quality of taking action or being the agent of some effort or activity</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Worry About News Stories Written with Artificial Intelligence  (2023/8/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/experts-worry-about-news-stories-written-with-artificial-intelligence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google is developing an artificial intelligence tool that produces news articles. And the development is troubling some experts.</p>
<p>They say such tools risk spreading propaganda or threatening the safety of people who provide reporters with information, or sources.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A ChatGPT prompt is shown on a device near a public school in Brooklyn, New York, Thursday, Jan. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Peter Morgan)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/06a20000-0aff-0242-32bd-08daf7d1d5d4_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A ChatGPT prompt is shown on a device near a public school in Brooklyn, New York, Thursday, Jan. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Peter Morgan)</span></div>
<p><em>The New York Times</em> reported last week that Google is testing a new product named Genesis. It uses artificial intelligence (AI) to produce news stories, or articles.</p>
<p><em>The New York Times</em> said Genesis gathers information, like details about current events, to create news stories. Google already has <strong>pitched</strong> the product to the <em>Times</em> and other organizations, including <em>The Washington Post</em> and News Corp., which owns <em>The Wall Street Journal </em>newspaper.</p>
<p>The launch of AI chatbot ChatGPT last fall created a debate about how AI ought to be used in the news industry.</p>
<p>AI tools can help reporters research by quickly examining data from large computer files. AI can also help reporters confirm or disprove information from sources. But there is fear that AI tools could spread propaganda and cause journalists to lose the skill of reporting.</p>
<p>John Scott-Railton studies disinformation at the Citizen Lab, part of the University of Toronto. He told VOA that a lot of information gathered by AI comes from places on the internet "where disinformation and propaganda get targeted."</p>
<p>Paul M. Barrett is with New York University's Stern Center for Business and Human Rights. He agrees that AI could increase the spread of false information.</p>
<p>"It's going to be easier to generate <strong>myths</strong> and disinformation," he told VOA. "The supply of misleading <strong>content</strong> is, I think, going to go up."</p>
<p>In an emailed statement to VOA, a Google spokesperson said its tool is designed to help reporters, or journalists, in their work, not replace them. AI cannot replace the "role journalists have in reporting, creating and fact-checking their articles," the spokesperson said.</p>
<p>AI tools in journalism could also hurt trust in news organizations. Public opinion researchers Gallup and the Knight Foundation released a study in February about trust in the media. It said that half of Americans believe that national news organizations try to mislead or misinform the public.</p>
<p>"I'm <strong>puzzled</strong> that anyone thinks that the solution to this problem is to introduce a much less credible tool," said Scott-Railton. He earlier received support from Google's research group Google Ideas.</p>
<p>Reports say that AI chatbots regularly produce answers that are wrong or made up. Digital experts are also concerned about the security risks of using AI tools to produce news stories.</p>
<p>Reporters would have to be careful not to reveal to AI systems information like "the identity of a <strong>confidential</strong> source, or, I would say, even information that the journalist wants to make sure doesn't become public," Barrett said.</p>
<p>Scott-Railton said he thinks AI probably could be used in most industries. But it is important not to introduce the technology too quickly, especially in the news.</p>
<p>"What <strong>scares</strong> me is that the lessons learned in this case will come at the cost of well-earned <strong>reputations</strong>, will come at the cost of factual <strong>accuracy</strong> when it actually counts," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Liam Scott wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pitch </strong><em>— v. </em>to try to sell something to someone; to talk about something or someone in a way that will make others accept it</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>myth</strong><strong> </strong><em>— n. </em>an idea or story believed by many people but that is not true</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>content</strong><strong> </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>the information that appears in media such as books, newspapers, television, movies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>puzzle </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to be confused; to make something difficult to understand</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>confidential </strong><em>—</em><em> adj. </em>secret or private</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scare</strong><strong> </strong><em>—</em><em> v. </em>to make a person afraid or fearful<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reputation</strong><strong> </strong><em>—</em><em> n. </em>the common opinion people have about a person</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>accuracy </strong>–n. the quality of having no mistake or error</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Heat Spreading Ocean Currents Could Collapse by Midcentury  (2023/8/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/study-heat-spreading-ocean-currents-could-collapse-by-midcentury.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new study has predicted that a system of ocean currents that transports warm water northward could collapse in the next 70 years.</p>
<p>Climate scientists have warned that such collapse could cause sea level rise in the U.S. and extreme weather in Europe.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, the sun rises over fishing boats in the Atlantic Ocean, Sept. 8, 2022, off of Kennebunkport, Maine. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-533e-08db91cb4fdb_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, the sun rises over fishing boats in the Atlantic Ocean, Sept. 8, 2022, off of Kennebunkport, Maine. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty, File)</span></div>
<p>The currents spread, or circulate, water in the Atlantic Ocean, the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/amoc.html">explains</a>. The currents carry warm water north and cold water south.</p>
<p>Two years ago, the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change said it was unlikely that ocean currents would cause disastrous conditions in the next 80 years or so.</p>
<p>However, the new study recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-39810-w">published</a> in <em>Nature Communications</em> suggests that the huge ocean current system might collapse sooner than some scientists believe.</p>
<p>Altogether, the currents studied by the scientists are known as the Atlantic meridional overturning circulation, or AMOC. It circulates water throughout the Atlantic Ocean. The circulation is very lengthy, taking an estimated 1,000 years to complete. But NOAA says the circulation has been slowing since the mid-1990s.</p>
<p>The Atlantic current called the Gulf Stream is part of this huge current system, NOAA says.</p>
<p>Scientists in the United States and Germany have warned that a further slowdown or complete halt to the circulation process could create more extreme weather in the Northern Hemisphere. It could also cause sea-level rise on the U.S. East Coast and <strong>drought</strong> in southern Africa. But predictions about the possible timing remain unclear.</p>
<p>In the new study, Danish researchers Peter and Susanne Ditlevsen examined sea surface temperatures in the North Atlantic between 1870 and 2020. Under current conditions, they have suggested the circulation system could collapse as soon as 2025 or as late as 2095.</p>
<p>Their prediction is different from a prediction made by the United Nations' Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) in 2021. The IPCC said the collapse was not likely to happen before 2100.</p>
<p>Julio Friedmann is chief scientist at New York City-based Carbon Direct, a carbon management company. He said in a statement he thinks the latest study makes clear that "action must be <strong>swift </strong>and <strong>profound</strong>" to reduce major climate risks.</p>
<p>Stefan Rahmstorf co-wrote a 2018 <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0006-5">study</a> on ocean currents in the Atlantic. He also <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2023/07/what-is-happening-in-the-atlantic-ocean-to-the-amoc/">published his comments</a> about the Danish-led study on the website RealClimate. Rahmstorf noted that the timing of a collapse of Atlantic Ocean currents remains "highly <strong>uncertain</strong>."</p>
<p>He added that he finds the IPCC's estimate conservative. "Increasingly, the evidence points to the risk being far greater than 10 percent during this century," Rahmstorf wrote. He added that the problem is likely to remain "...rather worrying for the next few <strong>decades</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>– n. </em>a long period of time during which there is very little or no rain</p>
<p><strong>swift </strong><em>– adj. </em>happening or moving quickly</p>
<p><strong>profound </strong><em>– adj. </em>very great or intense</p>
<p><strong>uncertain </strong><em>– adj. </em>not sure about something</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong><em>– n. </em>a period of ten years</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Agency Permits Sesame to be Added to Foods  (2023/8/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/us-agency-permits-sesame-to-be-added-to-foods.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) recently said that by law food makers are permitted to add sesame to their products. They also must identify sesame content in their foods on product <strong>packaging</strong>.</p>
<p>Sesame is the seed of the sesamum or benne plant. It is used to make oil and the seeds themselves are often used on bread or baked goods. The seeds come in black and white colors.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Sesame dinner rolls sit on a mat in Concord, N.H., on Oct. 12, 2015. (AP Photo/Matthew Mead, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/68e498de-e754-477d-951f-2392b1d6645a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Sesame dinner rolls sit on a mat in Concord, N.H., on Oct. 12, 2015. (AP Photo/Matthew Mead, File)</span></div>
<p>Sesame is used in many foods to add a nutty flavor or some <strong>crunch</strong>.</p>
<p>But the American non-profit group, the Center for Science in the Public Interest (CSPI), says about 1.6 million people are <strong>allergic</strong> to the seeds. Someone who is allergic can get very sick after eating the seeds. People with the allergy usually learn to stay away from traditional foods that contain sesame.</p>
<p>The CSPI is protesting to the FDA about a law that went into effect in January.</p>
<p>The Food Allergy Safety, Treatment, Education, and Research Act, known as FASTER, listed sesame as a major allergen requiring identification on packaging for the first time.</p>
<p>Some food companies made changes to their production centers in reaction to the new law. Some cut sesame use completely. Others, however, decided to add sesame to products that did not usually contain it. As long as they identified the sesame on the food packaging, they were obeying the law fully.</p>
<p>The CSPI and other organizations argue that adding sesame to foods that did not contain it in the past limits food choices for allergic people.</p>
<p>Some food companies say it is too hard to prevent sesame from getting into some products, or it is too costly to change their production centers. It is easier to add sesame and identify it legally.</p>
<p>Some restaurants are also adding sesame to their foods and noting it on menus or meal listings in order to meet the requirements of the food law.</p>
<p>Robert Earl is a food safety <strong>advocate</strong>. He said the <strong>practice</strong> will put people with food allergies in danger of getting sick. "It puts our community at greater risk," he said. Earl added that food companies and restaurants adding sesame to products reduces food choices.</p>
<p>Earl said his organization – Food Allergy Research and Education – has received a number of complaints from people who said they got sick by eating formerly "safe" products.</p>
<p>Ruchi Gupta is a children's doctor at Northwestern University. She is director of the Center for Food Allergy and Asthma research there. Gupta called the FDA's decision "disappointing," and noted that the food company and restaurant changes are permitted by law. However, she said she hoped the FDA would have "come out in a way to try to <strong>discourage</strong>" putting sesame in unusual products.</p>
<p>Robert Califf leads the Food and Drug Administration. In a message posted online in 2023, he wrote about companies adding sesame to their foods. He called it "a practice with an outcome we do not support." He said it does not break any rule but that it "limits <strong>options</strong> for <strong>consumers</strong> who are allergic to sesame."</p>
<p>He also noted that consumers should "check the <strong>label </strong>every time you buy a food product – even if you have eaten it before and didn't have an allergic reaction."</p>
<p>The F.D.A. also said companies cannot use language like "may contain sesame" if the product does not contain it.</p>
<p>Peter Lurie heads the CSPI. He said he hoped the FDA's recent statements would send a message to food companies. He said "it's on the companies to act responsibly," if the FDA is not going to force them to make changes.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>packaging</strong> <em>–n. </em>the outside container a product comes in, such as a box</p>
<p><strong>crunch </strong>–<em>n</em>. a word used to describe the sound or feeling of chewing something that has a hard outer part</p>
<p><strong>allergic </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>used to describe the experience of getting sick from some part of food or a bite from a bug</p>
<p><strong>advocate</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who speaks for something or someone else who does not have a strong voice</p>
<p><strong>discourage</strong> <em>–v. </em>to argue against something happening</p>
<p><strong>commissioner</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who is in charge of an agency or organization</p>
<p><strong>practice</strong> <em>–n. </em>a way of doing things, such as making a food product</p>
<p><strong>option</strong> <em>–n. </em>something that may be chosen</p>
<p><strong>consumer</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person or group of people who purchase a product</p>
<p><strong>label</strong> <em>–n. </em>a piece of information on the outside of product that tells what is inside</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Blend Words: Portmanteaus  (2023/8/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/blend-words-portmanteaus.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>What do the words "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/teen-vs-tween/7174983.html">tween</a>," "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/barbenheimer-two-movies-one-day/7187869.html">Barbenheimer</a>" and "brunch" have in common?</p>
<p>These words are portmanteaus -- words that are formed by combining parts of two separate words.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: Blend Words: Portmanteaus " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7b07-08db92c97a97_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: Blend Words: Portmanteaus </span></div>
<p>But unlike compound nouns, which are formed from two words, portmanteaus combine parts of the spelling of each word <em>and</em> their meanings.</p>
<p>In this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will learn more about how portmanteaus are created. We will also learn about their history and find out some common portmanteaus in English.</p>
<p><strong>What are portmanteaus?</strong></p>
<p>Portmanteaus are blend words in English. They are formed from words or parts of words that are combined in some way. The spellings of the original words are combined into the new word and their meanings are blended, too.</p>
<p>At the start of this lesson, you heard the word "tween." This is is a blend of "teen" and "between." This portmanteau means the age in between childhood and the teenage years, or around 10 to 12 years old.</p>
<p>"Barbenheimer" is a blend word of the movies "Barbie" and "Oppenheimer." It is used to describe the event of seeing both movies on the same day. Both films came out in movie theaters on the same day last month.</p>
<p>And "brunch" is a common weekend meal that combines "breakfast" and "lunch." "Brunch" is often eaten in the late morning and early afternoon and includes food and drink choices from both meals.</p>
<p><strong>Why are blend words called a "portmanteau?"</strong></p>
<p>Where does the idea of portmanteaus come from?</p>
<p>We borrow the word "portmanteau" from French. "Porter" means "to carry" in French, and "manteau" in French is a coat. When both words are blended, a "portmanteau" means a large suitcase that folds in half and can carry a lot of things.</p>
<p>So how did a suitcase come to mean all blend words in English?</p>
<p>We have British writer Lewis Carroll to thank for linking the word "portmanteau" to blend words in English. Carroll wrote <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em>. In his follow-up book <em>Though the Looking Glass</em>, Carroll wrote about the idea of portmanteaus.</p>
<p>In the story, Alice reads a book with a poem called "Jabberwocky." In the poem, Carroll makes up several blend words. Alice is confused so she asks another character, Humpty Dumpty, about the words. He answers, "You see, it's like a portmanteau — there are two meanings packed up into one word."</p>
<p>Just like the piece of luggage called a "portmanteau" has two sections folded into one, a portmanteau blend word carries both meanings of the original words but folds them together to create a new word.</p>
<p>Let's look at some common portmanteaus.</p>
<p><strong>Examples of portmanteaus </strong></p>
<p>Portmanteaus can be nouns, verbs or adjectives. Some portmanteaus are created by combining the beginning section, syllable or letters of the first word with the final part, syllable or letters of the second word.</p>
<p>They are often used in entertainment, for names of places, in government, for food and for technology.</p>
<p>Here are a few common portmanteaus.</p>
<p>A "biopic" is a blend of <em>"</em>bio<em>graphy" and "picture." It means a film about a person based on their life. </em></p>
<p><em>"Chillax" is a blended verb of "chill" and "relax" and means to calm down. </em></p>
<p>"Cosplay" is a combination of "costume" and "roleplay." "Cosplay" is when people dress up as characters from videogames, literature, films or television.</p>
<p>"Hangry" means to be angry because you are hungry.</p>
<p>"Motel" is a combination of "motor" and "hotel." It is like a hotel, but for people driving on long road trips.</p>
<p>"Smog" blends the words "smoke" and "fog" to create the noun that describes air pollution.</p>
<p>"Email" is a blend of "electronic" and "mail." It is the computer-based alternative to paper mail.</p>
<p>"Internet" is also a portmanteau, which combines "interconnected" and "network."</p>
<p>"Podcast" combines "iPod" with "broadcast." Podcasts are digital audio programs.</p>
<p>And lastly, we have "vlog." It is a blend of "video" and "log." These are journals that people record with a video camera and publish online.</p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts</strong></p>
<p>In today's report, we learned about "portmanteaus." Portmanteaus have an interesting history in the English language. Writer Lewis Carroll created several portmanteaus and described the term in his book,<em> Through the Looking Glass</em>. Portmanteaus blend the spelling and meanings of two words together. "Brunch," "vlog," and "hangry" are all portmanteaus.</p>
<p>Now it's your turn. Take the portmanteaus you learned today and try to use them in sentences.</p>
<p>You can write your sentences in the comments or send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>!</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>brunch </strong>– <em>n. </em>a meal usually taken late in the morning that combines a late breakfast and an early lunch</p>
<p><strong>suitcase</strong> – n. a large case that you use to carry your clothing and belongings when you are traveling</p>
<p><strong>luggage </strong>– <em>n.</em> bags and cases used by travelers</p>
<p><strong>creativity</strong> – <em>n.</em> the ability to make new things or think of new ideas</p>
<p><strong>syllable </strong><em>– n. </em>a unit of spoken language that consists of one or more vowel sounds alone or with one or more consonant sounds preceding or following</p>
<p><strong>chill </strong>– <em>v.</em> to calm down</p>
<p><strong>costume </strong>–<em> n. </em>clothing worn by people, such as actors, who are trying to look like people living in different places or times</p>
<p><strong>roleplay</strong> – <em>v</em>. to pretend to be a character and act in the same way as that character</p>
<p><strong>iPod</strong> – <em>n</em>. small, handheld Apple device that played music</p>
<p><strong>journal </strong><em>– n. </em>a record of experiences, events, ideas, etc.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Can AI Chatbots Learn to Be More Truthful?  (2023/8/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/can-ai-chatbots-learn-to-be-more-truthful.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Newly-developed artificial intelligence (AI) systems have demonstrated the ability to perform at human-like levels in some areas. But one serious problem with the tools remains – they can produce false or harmful information repeatedly.</p>
<p>The development of such systems, known as "chatbots," has progressed greatly in recent months. Chatbots have shown the ability to interact smoothly with humans and produce complex writing based on short, written commands. Such tools are also known as "<strong>generative</strong> AI" or "large language models."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, text from the ChatGPT page of the OpenAI website is shown in this photo, in New York, Feb. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-9bc9-08db93742dc9_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, text from the ChatGPT page of the OpenAI website is shown in this photo, in New York, Feb. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>Chatbots are one of many different AI systems currently under development. Others include tools that can produce new images, video and music or can write computer programs. As the technology continues to progress, some experts worry that AI tools may never be able to learn how to avoid false, outdated or damaging results.</p>
<p>The term hallucination has been used to describe when chatbots produce <strong>inaccurate</strong> or false information. Generally, hallucination describes something that is created in a person's mind, but is not happening in real life.</p>
<p>Daniela Amodei is co-creator and president of Anthropic, a company that produced a chatbot called Claude 2. She told the <em>Associated Press</em>, "I don't think that there's any model today that doesn't suffer from some hallucination."</p>
<p>Amodei added that such tools are largely built "to predict the next word." With this kind of design, she said, there will always be times when the model gets information or <strong>context</strong> wrong.</p>
<p>Anthropic, ChatGPT-maker OpenAI and other major developers of such AI systems say they are working to make AI tools that make fewer mistakes. Some experts question how long that process will take or if success is even possible.</p>
<p>"This isn't fixable," says Professor Emily Bender. She is a language expert and director of the University of Washington's Computational Linguistics Laboratory. Bender told the <em>AP</em> she considers the general relationship between AI tools and proposed uses of the technology a "<strong>mismatch</strong>."</p>
<p>Indian computer scientist Ganesh Bagler has been working for years to get AI systems to create <strong>recipes</strong> for South Asian foods. He said a chatbot can generate misinformation in the food industry that could hurt a food business. A single "hallucinated" recipe element could be the difference between a tasty meal or a terrible one.</p>
<p>Bagler questioned OpenAI chief Sam Altman during an event on AI technology held in India in June. "I guess hallucinations in ChatGPT are still acceptable, but when a recipe comes out hallucinating, it becomes a serious problem," Bagler said.</p>
<p>Altman answered by saying he was sure developers of AI chatbots would be able to get "the hallucination problem to a much, much better place" in the future. But he noted such progress could take years. "At that point we won't still talk about these," Altman said. "There's a balance between creativity and perfect accuracy, and the model will need to learn when you want one or the other."</p>
<p>Other experts who have long studied the technology say they do not expect such improvements to happen anytime soon.</p>
<p>The University of Washington's Bender describes a language model as a system that has been trained on written data to "model the likelihood of different strings of word forms." Many people depend on a version of this technology whenever they use the "autocomplete" tool when writing text messages or emails.</p>
<p>The latest chatbot tools try to take that method to the next level, by generating whole new passages of text. But Bender says the systems are still just repeatedly choosing the most predictable next word in a series. Such language models "are designed to make things up. That's all they do," she noted.</p>
<p>Some businesses, however, are not so worried about the ways current chatbot tools generate their results. Shane Orlick is head of marketing technology company Jasper AI. He told the AP, "Hallucinations are actually an added <strong>bonus</strong>." He explained many chatbot users were pleased that the company's AI tool had "created takes on stories or <strong>angles</strong> that they would have never thought of themselves."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>generate </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce something</p>
<p><strong>inaccurate </strong>– <em>adj</em>. not correct or exact</p>
<p><strong>context </strong><em>– n. </em>all the facts, opinions, situations, etc. relating to a particular thing or event</p>
<p><strong>mismatch </strong><em>– n. </em>a situation when people or things are put together but are not suitable for each other</p>
<p><strong>recipe </strong><em>– n. </em>a set of instructions and ingredients for preparing a particular food dish</p>
<p><strong>bonus </strong><em>– n. </em>a pleasant extra thing</p>
<p><strong>angle </strong><em>– n. </em>a position from which something is looked at</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Believe Chinese Fossil Shows Mammal Attacking Dinosaur  (2023/8/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/researchers-believe-chinese-fossil-shows-mammal-attacking-dinosaur.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A new fossil study by researchers from China and Canada suggests that ancient mammals may have attacked and eaten larger dinosaurs.</p>
<p>The scientists looked at a fossil found by a Chinese farmer in 2012. A fossil is the mineralized remains of an animal or plant left in an ancient rock.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration shows the Cretaceous carnivorous mammal Repenomamus robustus attacking the plant-eating dinosaur Psittacosaurus lujiatunensis moments before a volcanic debris flow buries them both about 125 million years ago in China. (Michael W. Skrepnick/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6b253f1c-667c-408c-a598-9833df7c7af1_cx0_cy12_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration shows the Cretaceous carnivorous mammal Repenomamus robustus attacking the plant-eating dinosaur Psittacosaurus lujiatunensis moments before a volcanic debris flow buries them both about 125 million years ago in China. (Michael W. Skrepnick/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The scientists said the fossil is from 125 million years ago. They published their findings recently in the journal <em>Scientific Reports</em>.</p>
<p>The scientists believe a mammal, similar to a badger, attacked a small, <strong>beaked</strong> dinosaur. During the attack, the animals were caught up in a <strong>lava</strong> flow from a nearby volcano. The moment was locked in time until it was found over 12 years ago.</p>
<p>Researchers call the place where the fossil was found "China's Pompeii." Pompeii was a city in Italy that was caught in a volcanic <strong>eruption</strong> about 2000 years ago. Ash covered the city and preserved moments from daily life. Researchers discovered the ruins of the city about 500 years ago.</p>
<p>In the past, dinosaur researchers believed small, <strong>scavenging</strong> mammals might have eaten dead dinosaurs. However, they were not sure that mammals attacked living dinosaurs.</p>
<p>Jordan Mallon is a <strong>paleobiologist</strong> at the Canadian Museum of Nature in Ottawa, Ontario. He was one of the study's writers.</p>
<p>"I've never seen a fossil like this before," he said.</p>
<p>Steve Brusatte is a paleontologist at the University of Edinburgh in Scotland. He did not work on the study. He described the fossil as a "freeze frame" or something like a photograph.</p>
<p>"It turns the old story on its head," he said. Brusatte said the old idea was that dinosaurs ruled the world with small mammals "in the shadows."</p>
<p>Mallon said he would be happy for other scientists to examine the fossil if they are concerned that it might not be real.</p>
<p>He described the mammal as about the size of a house cat. He said the dinosaur was about the size of an average dog.</p>
<p>He said the <strong>species</strong> of dinosaur is Psittacosaurus and the mammal is called Repenomamus. The dinosaur ate plants, but other dinosaurs ate meat and hunted mammals.</p>
<p>Mallon said it would have been more common for a dinosaur to hunt a mammal, but the fossil he studied shows something new.</p>
<p>"We now know that the mammals were able to fight back, at least at times," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>beaked </strong>–adj. having a beak like a bird which is made of hard material</p>
<p><strong>lava </strong><em>–n.</em><em> </em>melted rock</p>
<p><strong>eruption</strong> <em>–n. </em>the explosion that results when pressure underneath a volcano bursts out</p>
<p><strong>scavenging</strong> <em>–adj.</em><em> </em>something that does not hunt for live food but that looks for animals killed by other causes</p>
<p><strong>paleobiologist </strong>–n. a scientist who studies prehistoric life</p>
<p><strong>species</strong> <em>–n. </em>a kind of animal or plant that can reproduce with others of its kind</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Trump Indicted, Accused of Trying to Overturn 2020 Election  (2023/8/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/trump-indicted-accused-of-trying-to-overturn-2020-election.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>A United States federal grand jury indicted former President Donald Trump on Tuesday with crimes connected to the 2020 presidential election.</p>
<p>The charging document, called an indictment, accuses Trump of four crimes: conspiracy to defraud the government, blocking an official meeting of Congress and plotting to do so, and threatening people's right to vote.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Nadine Seiler holds a sign in front of the federal courthouse where former U.S. President Donald Trump is expected later this week to answer charges in the investigation of efforts to overturn his 2020 election defeat In Washington, U.S. August 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1e552eb7-c058-4bed-9ff8-b74a6e10c970_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Nadine Seiler holds a sign in front of the federal courthouse where former U.S. President Donald Trump is expected later this week to answer charges in the investigation of efforts to overturn his 2020 election defeat In Washington, U.S. August 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst)</span></div>
<p>The indictment centers on the months after the November 2020 election. It says Trump knew that he had lost the election but spread lies about the voting results as he was "<strong>determined</strong> to remain in power."</p>
<p>The former president, it says, tried and failed to use federal and state officials to overturn the election. It said he blocked the counting of electoral votes certifying Biden's victory on January 6, 2021, as thousands of his supporters attacked the Capitol building and police where the process was taking place.</p>
<p>In the announcement of the indictment, Special Counsel Jack Smith called the attack an "assault on the seat of American democracy." He added, "It was fueled by lies, lies by the defendant targeted at obstructing a <strong>bedrock function</strong> of the U.S. government: the nation's process of collecting, counting and certifying the results of the presidential election."</p>
<p>The document refers to six other co-conspirators it says worked with Trump to undo the election results. But the former president was the only one charged in Tuesday's indictment. He is expected to appear in court on Thursday.</p>
<p><strong>Other legal actions against Trump</strong></p>
<p>The latest legal action is the second time that Smith has charged Trump with criminal wrongdoing. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-indicts-former-president-donald-trump-with-crimes/7130540.html">In June, the special counsel accused Trump</a> of illegally holding classified national security documents, obstruction, making false statements, and plotting with others to carry out a crime. A trial has been set for May 2024.</p>
<p>In March, the office of the Manhattan District Attorney in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/former-us-president-trump-to-face-criminal-charges-for-first-time/7036299.html">the state of New York charged Trump</a> with criminally falsifying "business records to conceal crimes that hid damaging information from the voting public during the 2016 presidential election." That indictment made Trump the first former president to face criminal charges. That trial is set for next March.</p>
<p>Additionally, Trump and his business, the Trump Organization, are being accused of misleading banks and tax officials to get loans and tax benefits. The office of the New York State Attorney General is seeking to ban Trump from doing business in the state. A trial will start in state court in October.</p>
<p>In the southern state of Georgia, a grand jury has been investigating whether Trump and his allies had tried to illegally overturn the 2020 election result in that state. In early 2021, Trump was recorded on a phone call asking Georgian state election officials to "find" him 11,780 votes, one more than Biden's winning margin, so Trump could claim the 16 electoral votes.</p>
<p>Trump is seeking reelection in 2024 and is the leading candidate for the Republican presidential nomination. He has denied wrongdoing in all cases. And his campaign attacked the latest indictment, saying it was an "attempt by the Biden Crime Family and their weaponized Justice Department" to interfere in the 2024 election.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for Learning English based on reports from VOA News and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>determine</strong> - v. decide</p>
<p><strong>bedrock</strong> - n. strong idea, principle</p>
<p><strong>function</strong> - n. special purpose or activity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Many US Workers Criticize Low Pay, Long Hours  (2023/8/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/many-us-workers-criticize-low-pay-long-hours.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>From truck drivers to Hollywood actors, many workers in the United States are complaining about low pay and long hours.</p>
<p>The unhappiness is a result of changes in technology and the economy. And worker's jobs have changed as companies try to meet customer expectations for speed and ease.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - UPS workers hold placards at a rally held by the Teamsters Union on July 19, 2023 in Los Angeles, California, ahead of an August 1st deadline for an agreement on a labor contract deal. (Photo by Frederic J. BROWN / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5e47fdd4-04b3-4984-8d68-0c98a5557496_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - UPS workers hold placards at a rally held by the Teamsters Union on July 19, 2023 in Los Angeles, California, ahead of an August 1st deadline for an agreement on a labor contract deal. (Photo by Frederic J. BROWN / AFP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Delivery drivers </strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Palmerino is a driver for the <strong>delivery</strong> company United Parcel Service (UPS) near Albany, New York. The full-time driver said he was forced to work <strong>overtime</strong> during the pandemic to deal with a large increase in orders. And 14-hour days in trucks without air conditioning became usual.</p>
<p>"For two straight years... A lot of us were forced to work six days a week, and that is not any way to live your life," said Palmerino.</p>
<p>The working conditions led to talk of a strike by a labor group known as the Teamsters. But UPS and the Teamsters last week reached an early deal that would put off the strike. Labor activists said the deal would pressure other companies facing labor issues to raise their <strong>standards</strong>.</p>
<p>Patricia Campos-Medina is with the Worker Institute at the School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University. The Institute released a report this year that found the number of U.S. labor strikes rose 52 percent in 2022.</p>
<p>"The whole idea that consumer convenience is above everything broke down during the pandemic. We started to think, ‘I'm at home ordering,'.... but there is actually a worker who has to go the grocery store, who has to cook this for me so that I can be comfortable,'" Campos-Medina said.</p>
<p><strong>Screenwriters and actors</strong></p>
<p>Some UPS drivers recently joined the Writer's Guild of America (WGA) for protests.</p>
<p>Hollywood screenwriters and actors are holding their first strikes in 40 years because the rise of <strong>streaming </strong>services has changed entertainment economics. The result has been decreased pay and faster production times with smaller teams.</p>
<p>Actors and writers have long depended on residuals, or long-term payments, for reruns and other airings of films and television shows. But reruns do not exist on streaming services, where shows and movies are available at all times.</p>
<p>There is also no easy way, such as<strong> ticket</strong> sales or ratings, to determine their popularity. As a result, streaming services often pay little for residuals.</p>
<p>Adam Shapiro is an actor known for the Netflix hit Never Have I Ever. He said many actors were happy at first to accept lower pay for the sudden increase in acting jobs that streaming services offered. But the need for better pay gained urgency when it became clear streaming is the future of the business, he said.</p>
<p>"Over the past 10 years, we realized: ‘Oh, that's now how Hollywood works. Everything is streaming,'" Shapiro said during a recent union event.</p>
<p>Shapiro said he agreed to a deal offering 20 percent of his normal pay for Never Have I Ever because it seemed like "a great <strong>opportunity</strong>, and it's going to be all over the world." He added, "Unfortunately, we're all starting to realize that if we keep doing this we're not going to be able to pay our bills."</p>
<p>Danielle Sanchez-Witzel is co-creator of the recently released Netflix show Survival of the Thickest. She said television shows traditionally hire a team of writers for the length of the series production. However, Netflix only lets her keep one writer after pre-production to deal with any changes in the story.</p>
<p>"It's not <strong>sustainable</strong> and I'll never do that again," the screenwriter said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Alexandra Olson reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>delivery<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> the act of taking something to a person or place</p>
<p><strong>overtime </strong><em>– n.</em> time spent working at your job that is in addition to your normal working hours</p>
<p><strong>standard</strong> <em>– n. </em>a level of quality, achievement, etc., that is considered acceptable or desirable</p>
<p><strong>streaming</strong> <em>– n. </em>playing shows or films by using data sent over the Internet</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>–<em> n.</em> an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
<p><strong>ticket </strong><em>- n. </em>a piece of paper that allows you to see a show</p>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong><em>-- adj. </em> able to last or continue for a long time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Chipmakers Celebrate End of Chip Surplus  (2023/8/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/chipmakers-celebrate-end-of-chip-surplus.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>From Intel in the United States to South Korea's Samsung, producers are celebrating the beginning of the end of the <strong>chip</strong> surplus. Still, the expectations for demand from buyers outside the artificial intelligence (AI) industry remain weak.</p>
<p><strong>Chip markets </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a circuit board of a computer in this illustration picture taken February 25, 2022. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fa918b34-78cb-4d29-8251-7f8024695932_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a circuit board of a computer in this illustration picture taken February 25, 2022. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>All the major markets for chips - smartphones, computers and data centers - have decreased this year. Both companies and people have reduced spending during a weak international economy, high inflation and rising interest rates.</p>
<p>The decreased demand has created a large oversupply of chips. The result: a record combined $12 billion first-half operating loss for the world's two largest memory chipmakers, Samsung and SK Hynix of South Korea.</p>
<p>This time of oversupply, however, has started to ease. Chip companies have cut production. And a decline in personal computer shipments eased to 11 percent in the June <strong>quarter</strong> compared to a 30 percent decrease in each of the previous two quarters, data from the research company Canalys showed.</p>
<p>The smartphone market is also looking better, with cellphone shipments falling 8 percent in the June quarter, versus 14 percent in the first quarter, says research firm Counterpoint.</p>
<p>"Demand is recovering very <strong>gradually</strong>," Woohyun Kim, chief financial officer at SK Hynix, said on an earnings call last week.</p>
<p>Intel chief Pat Gelsinger recently said an oversupply in server central processing units (CPUs) will continue until the second half of the year. He also said that data center chip sales will decline in the third quarter before recovering in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>A slow recovery in China, the world's biggest chip buyer, is also lowering market expectations.</p>
<p>Both Samsung and SK Hynix said China's reopening failed to live up to expectations that it would bring back the smartphone market. The two companies said they were lengthening production cuts of NAND memory chips, widely used in smartphones to store digital data.</p>
<p>American chipmaker Texas Instruments, which does a lot of business in China, predicted third-quarter earnings and profit below targets last week.</p>
<p>"China was roughly half of sales at the end of fiscal 2022, so China has the largest impact on TI's (Texas Instruments) business," said Logan Purk of the investment business Edward Jones.</p>
<p><strong>Artificial intelligence </strong></p>
<p>Demand for chips to support generative artificial intelligence has increased since OpenAI's ChatGPT was launched late last year. Still, AI only accounts for a small amount of overall chip demand.</p>
<p>Manufacturers of the equipment used to make chips such as KLA Corporation and Lam Research in the U.S. are early winners of the AI boom. Both companies predicted quarterly earnings above Wall Street estimates last week.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Joyce Lee reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>chip</strong> <em>– n. </em>a very small piece of hard material (called silicon) in a computer or other device that contains many electronic circuits</p>
<p><strong>quarter</strong> <em>– n.</em> a period of three months</p>
<p><strong>gradually</strong> <em>– adv.</em> happening in a slow way over a long period of time</p>
<p><strong>fiscal</strong><em> -- adj. </em>of or relating to money and especially to the money a government, business, or organization earns, spends, and owes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Record-breaking Hot Summer Is Only Half Over  (2023/8/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/record-breaking-hot-summer-is-only-half-over.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>At about summer's halfway point, scientists say the world's record-breaking heat and weather extremes are both <strong>unprecedented</strong> and unsurprising.</p>
<p>American and European <strong>meteorologists</strong> also expect a hotter-than-normal August and September.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People swim in the ocean off of Crandon Park, July 28, 2023, in Key Biscayne, Fla (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-5d9b-08db92b37b70_cx19_cy21_cw80_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People swim in the ocean off of Crandon Park, July 28, 2023, in Key Biscayne, Fla (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell, File)</span></div>
<p>Gavin Schmidt is a NASA climate scientist. He told <em>The Associated Press,</em> "The heat waves that we're seeing in the U.S. and in Europe, in China are <strong>demolishing</strong> records left, right and center. This is not a surprise."</p>
<p>"We're going to be seeing this pretty much this year and into next year," Schmidt said. Along with human-caused climate change, there is also the natural El Nino warming of the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>Here is a look at what has happened so far this summer:</p>
<p><strong>Record-breaking heat</strong></p>
<p>The month of June this year was the hottest June on record in the world. Scientists say July has been so hot that even before the month was over they could say it was the hottest month on record. In some places, the heat has been deadly.</p>
<p>In Phoenix, Arizona, the last day of June and each day of July has been at least 43 degrees Celsius. The area also set records for the longest period with temperatures at 32 and higher.</p>
<p>El Paso, Texas, had 44 days of 37-degree heat. Schools closed in Nuevo Leon state in northern Mexico a month earlier than normal as temperatures reached 45 degrees.</p>
<p>Beijing, China experienced 27 days of 35 degrees in July. That came after three 40-degree days in June.</p>
<p>Heat records fell all over southern Europe. Sardinia, Italy, hit 47 degrees. Palermo in Sicily broke a record that goes back to 1791 by 2 degrees.</p>
<p>Spain reported nearly 1,000 extra deaths from the heat by mid-July, mostly among older people.</p>
<p><strong>Too much rain</strong></p>
<p>More than 10,000 people had to be <strong>evacuated</strong> in central Hunan province in China. Heavy rainfall there caused at least 70 houses to collapse. In Yichang, rain caused a landslide that buried a construction site and killed at least one person.</p>
<p>Australia's Queensland desert got 13 times its normal monthly July rain in just one day.</p>
<p>Thousands of people were evacuated from Delhi in India as rains caused floods and landslides. Heavy rain and flooding caused several deaths in northeastern states of the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>Wildfires and smoke</strong></p>
<p>Too little rain in Greece and Spain worsened wildfires. In the Canary Islands, a fire caused 4,000 people to evacuate and 400 firefighters battling it.</p>
<p>Hot and dry conditions caused about 160 wildfires to break out in Israel in early June.</p>
<p>In northern Quebec, Canada, wildfire smoke spread to create the world's dirtiest air in cities like New York and Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>As of late July, more than 600 wildfires were out of control in Canada. A record 123,000 square kilometers burned, and fire season is not nearly done. That is an area larger than North Korea.</p>
<p><strong>Water temperatures</strong></p>
<p>Water temperatures in the Florida Keys and off the Everglades hit the high 30s.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic had hot spots that alarmed scientists. The world's oceans as a whole were the hottest ever in June and got even hotter in July. In Antarctica, sea ice broke record-low levels.</p>
<p>Ocean temperatures take a long time to warm up and cool down, said Victor Gensini who teaches meteorology at the University of Northern Illinois. He added that it does not look good for the rest of the summer.</p>
<p><strong>A hot forecast</strong></p>
<p>U.S. National Weather Service meteorologist Matt Rosencrans expects above normal temperatures for the next three months.</p>
<p>The only possible relief he sees, especially in the hot Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico, is if a <strong>hurricane</strong> or tropical storm moves through. But the height of hurricane season in September has not even started.</p>
<p>With the summer's weather extremes so far, University of Pennsylvania climate scientist Michael Mann had one question: "How on God's Earth are we still burning <strong>fossil fuels</strong> after witnessing all this?"</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>— adj. </em>not done or experienced before</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>meteorologist </strong><em>— n. </em>a scientist that deals with the atmosphere and with weather</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>demolish </strong><em>— v. </em>to damage so that it cannot be repaired</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>evacuate </strong><em>— v. </em> to remove from a dangerous place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hurricane </strong><em>— n. </em>an extremely large, powerful, and destructive storm with very strong winds that occurs especially in the western part of the Atlantic Ocean</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>— n. </em>energy in the form of gas, coal and oil that is taken from the ground and comes from the breakdown of old matter</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Bhutanese Youth Look to Australia for a Better Life  (2023/8/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/bhutanese-youth-look-to-australia-for-a-better-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Young people are leaving Bhutan as Australia has reopened its borders to international students after the pandemic. Young people from Bhutan are seeking opportunities outside the country as more are becoming unhappy with the South Asian kingdom's economy.</p>
<p>The number of students arriving in Australia from Bhutan has increased sharply. Over 12,000 arrived during the 11 months ending in May. That number represents about 1.5 percent of the small South Asian country's population. The country has a youth unemployment rate above 25 percent.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Buddha Dordenma statue overlooks the town of Thimphu, Bhutan, April 16, 2016. (REUTERS/Cathal McNaughton/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4abb68e9-5fb2-4768-9ccd-a527fde1df84_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Buddha Dordenma statue overlooks the town of Thimphu, Bhutan, April 16, 2016. (REUTERS/Cathal McNaughton/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Most of the recent arrivals have settled in Perth, Western Australia. They are taking classes in fields like childcare, <strong>hospitality</strong>, and accounting.</p>
<p>Tashi Kipchu is 25 years old. He is one of many who came to Australia last year in search of better <strong>opportunities</strong>.</p>
<p>"Right after COVID, everything died," said Kipchu, who studied marketing at the University of Western Australia. He said he did not see any opportunities at home.</p>
<p>Bhutanese students did not start going to Australia until 2017. The number sharply increased after Australia reopened its borders in 2022. Australian government data shows that the number of Bhutanese students asking for visas increased by five times in the financial year ending in June.</p>
<p>The increase of student arrivals has made Australia home to one of the largest Bhutanese communities outside of South Asia.</p>
<p>Bhutanese students represent just a small part of Australia's 600,000 international student population. But the increase of students comes as the $27 billion education industry in Australia tries to make up lost ground from the decrease during the pandemic. Students from China, for example, are returning at a slower rate than Australian officials had hoped.</p>
<p>Phil Honeywood is Chief Executive Officer at International Education Association of Australia. He said Australian universities want to <strong>diversify</strong>. Honeywood said they got the message from the former and current government that they should not depend too much on China, India, and Nepal.</p>
<p>Sonam Tobgay is Bhutan's ambassador to Australia. He said students want to go to Australia for a less costly education and visas that permit students' dependents to work for unlimited hours.</p>
<p>Bhutan's mostly closed economy is dependent on hydropower and <strong>tourism</strong>. Its economy has more recently been hurt by high energy costs and limited trade.</p>
<p>Government reforms have added to the number of working professionals leaving.</p>
<p>Found between India and China, Bhutan reopened its borders last September. But higher taxes on tourism have slowed the country's recovery. Youth unemployment hit 28 percent last year.</p>
<p>Bhutan might be most famous for its Gross National Happiness index. It is a measure of citizens' happiness rather than the country's wealth.</p>
<p>Kipchu trained as a chemical engineer in Bhutan. But he saw a business opportunity soon after arriving in Perth and started an education <strong>consultancy</strong> to help students from Bhutan. Now, his company employs 40 to 50 people in his home country. </p>
<p>"I came to Australia to study but somehow this country gave me an opportunity," said Kipchu. He predicted that the increase of people moving to Australia would continue.</p>
<p>"The job opportunities and the <strong>flexibility</strong> for students to work here makes it more <strong>attractive</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Stella Qiu and Gopal Sharma reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em> </p><p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>hospitality </strong><em>–n. (business)</em> the term to describe the industry of providing hotels, restaurants and places of interest for travelers</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong>– <em>n.</em> an amount of time or a situation in which something can be don</p>
<p><strong>diversify </strong>– <em>v. </em>to change (something) so that it has more different kinds of people or things</p>
<p><strong>tourism </strong>– <em>n.</em> the activity of traveling to a place for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>consultancy </strong>– <em>n.</em> a company that gives professional advice to other companies for a fee</p>
<p><strong>flexibility </strong>– <em>adj. </em>able to change or to do different things</p>
<p><strong>attractive </strong>– <em>adj.</em> having a feature or quality that people like</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Sound-language Awareness  (2023/8/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202308/early-literacy-sound-language-awareness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 August 2023</span><br/>
<p>Spoken language is made up of sounds. If students want to read, they must be aware of the sound-language connection.</p>
<p><strong>Phonological awareness</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Sound-language Awareness" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0c17-08db82595aea_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Sound-language Awareness</span></div>
<p>The ability to hear sounds in language and work with them is called phonological awareness. Phonological awareness begins with easy skills and moves to more difficult ones. It is important to note that the development of these skills may <strong>overlap</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Phonemic awareness</strong></p>
<p>The smallest part of the spoken language is called a <strong>phoneme</strong>.</p>
<p>A student with phonemic awareness can hear individual sounds and work with them. Phonemic awareness also allows students to understand that the sounds of spoken language work together to make words.</p>
<p>We will talk about phonemic awareness a little later in this article. But for now, know that it is the most advanced type of phonological awareness.</p>
<p><strong>What does phonological awareness look like? </strong></p>
<p><u>Students with early phonological awareness can: </u></p>
<ul>
<li>find and make rhymes</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>count words in a sentence</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>count the number of beats (or <strong>syllables</strong>) in a word</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Students with advanced Phonological Awareness can: </u></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>blend</strong> small sounds into words</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>hear the same first sounds, like <strong>t</strong>oe and <strong>t</strong>ip</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>hear the same ending sounds, like su<strong>n</strong> and bi<strong>n </strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>hear the same middle sounds, like b<strong>a</strong>g and t<strong>a</strong>g</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for phonological awareness</strong></p>
<p>It is important to know the difference between the name of a letter and the sound of a letter. A letter between two slashes // shows its sound. So, the letter "t"<em> </em>between two slashes represents the sound /t/.</p>
<p><u>Students should learn each letter by its sound.</u></p>
<p>At an early stage, say the sound of the letter, not the letter name. This will help students blend words later on. For example, when teaching the letter "n" say /n/ as in "net", not /en/.</p>
<p><u>When teaching letter sounds, do not add vowel sounds.</u></p>
<p>For example, when saying the letter "f," do not say the sound /ef/. Just say /f/. Adding the /e/ vowel sound at the beginning of the letter makes it harder to blend the sounds in a word later. The most common example is the letter "s." Simply say /s/. Do not say /es/. Students later may say /e/school, /e/scared, /e/snake –- which would be incorrect.</p>
<p><u>Teach easier consonants first.</u></p>
<p>Some languages lack some sounds, such as /f/ and /v/. Don't teach those to your students first. Some consonants are easier to say. You can stretch them out, saying them for a longer amount of time. They are m, s, f, l, r, n, v, z.</p>
<p>Some consonants end sharply with a puff of air. They are a little harder to say. They are b, c, d, g, p, t, k, and j. Some consonants are simply difficult to say and are less common. Teach them last. They are h, w, y, x, q.</p>
<p>However, some English sounds do not exist in other languages. If students have trouble with some sounds, teach easier ones first.</p>
<p><u>Teach short vowel sounds first.</u></p>
<p>Long vowel sounds may be easier to say. But short vowel sounds are in many easy words, such as "mat" and "sun." However, short vowel sounds can be very confusing. So, first teach them separately – then altogether.</p>
<p><strong>What does phonemic awareness look like?</strong></p>
<p>As we said earlier, phonemic awareness is the most advanced type of phonological awareness.</p>
<p>Students with phonemic awareness can do the following:</p>
<p><u>Sound <strong>isolation</strong></u></p>
<p>They can hear a single sound in a word and isolate it.</p>
<p>TEACHER: What is the first sound in "bug?"</p>
<p>STUDENT: The first sound in "bug" is /b/.</p>
<p><u>They can identify and group sounds (or phonemes).</u></p>
<p>Students can identify sounds that are the same. These sounds may come at the beginning, the middle, or the end of words. Identifying middle sounds is more advanced than identifying beginning or ending sounds.</p>
<p><u>They can break apart sounds (also called <strong>segmenting</strong> phonemes.)</u></p>
<p>Segmenting is the ability to break a word into smaller sounds.</p>
<p>TEACHER: How many sounds in "flag?"</p>
<p>STUDENT: /f/ /l/ /a/ /g/ -- "Flag" has four sounds!</p>
<p><u>They can blend sounds together (also called blending phonemes).</u></p>
<p>Blending is the ability to say separate sounds together to make a word.</p>
<p>TEACHER: What word is this -- /b/ /a/ /g/?</p>
<p>STUDENT: Bag!</p>
<p>Blending and segmenting are the most important phonemic awareness skills. These are two phonemic awareness skills most linked to fluency. Both segmenting and blending should be practiced regularly.</p>
<p><u>They can lose a sound to make new words (also called deletion.)</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: Pin. If I take away the /p/ sound, what do I have left?</p>
<p>STUDENT: In!</p>
<p><u>They can add a sound to make new words (also called addition.)</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: Lap. If I add the /f/ sound to the beginning, what word do I have?</p>
<p>STUDENT: Flap!</p>
<p><u>They can change a sound to make new words (also called substitution).</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: If I take away the /s/ in "sat" and add /p/, what word do I have?</p>
<p>STUDENT: Pat!</p>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for phonemic awareness</strong></p>
<p><u>Use words your students know.</u></p>
<p>When doing phonemic awareness activities with your class, use words from a story your students are currently reading. It is helpful to use words the students already know.</p>
<p><u>Focus on sounds not the letters.</u></p>
<p>The focus of phonemic activities should be on the sounds of words and not on the letters or spelling. However, you can teach phonemic awareness while teaching meaning and pronunciation.</p>
<p>Identify sounds that are different or the same in the home language in comparison to English.</p>
<p><strong>Assessment for Phonological Awareness</strong></p>
<p>Students with poor phonemic awareness skills cannot do the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>isolate single sounds in a word;</li>
<li>break up (or segment) single sounds in a word: paper /pa/-/per/;</li>
<li>blend sounds into words: /s/ /a/ /t/ = sat;</li>
<li>add, delete, or substitute sounds.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some questions for assessing phonological awareness.</p>
<p><u>Count words in a spoken sentence</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: How many words are in this sentence? "You are my friend."</p>
<p>STUDENT: Four!</p>
<p><u>Do They Rhyme?</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: Do these words rhyme: "bit," "sit?"</p>
<p>STUDENT: Yes!</p>
<p>TEACHER: Do the words "big" and "bag" rhyme?</p>
<p>STUDENT: No!</p>
<p><u>Syllable</u><u> blending</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: I am going to say a word in parts. Listen: /o/ - /pen/. What word did I say?</p>
<p>STUDENT: Open!</p>
<p><u>Syllable <strong>deletion</strong></u></p>
<p>TEACHER: Say "sat" without the /at/.</p>
<p>STUDENT: /s/</p>
<p><u>Syllable substitution</u></p>
<p>TEACHER: If I take the /s/ away from "sit" and replace it with /p/, what word do I have?</p>
<p>STUDENT: Pit!</p>
<p>Use the tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve your learners. Change them to fit your students and your teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>overlap </strong><em>–v</em>. the share or cover part, but not all, of nearby things</p>
<p><strong>phoneme </strong><em>–n.</em><strong> </strong>the smallest part of spoken language</p>
<p><strong>syllable </strong><em>–n. </em>a single, unbroken sound of a spoken (or written) word.</p>
<p><strong>blend</strong> <em>–v</em>. to mix so that two or more things are combined completely</p>
<p><strong>isolate </strong><em>–v.</em> to set apart and keep alone; apart from other things</p>
<p><strong>segment </strong><em>–v.</em> to divide things into separate parts</p>
<p><strong>deletion </strong><em>–n</em>. the act of removing something or taking something out</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Studies: Meat Sickness from Tick Bites Getting More Common  (2023/8/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/studies-meat-sickness-from-tick-bites-getting-more-common.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>More than 100,000 people in the United States have become <strong>allergic</strong> to red meat since 2010 in reaction to tick bites, the government reports.</p>
<p>Medical researchers say they believe many more people have the allergy and do not know it.</p>
<p>The National Centers for Disease Control and Prevention released two reports on the subject recently.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated photo provided by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows a female Lone Star tick, is found mainly in the Southeast. (James Gathany/CDC via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-54f8-08db91dfaf87_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated photo provided by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows a female Lone Star tick, is found mainly in the Southeast. (James Gathany/CDC via AP)</span></div>
<p>Ticks are very small animals that feed on the blood of other animals.</p>
<p>One report estimated that as many as 450,000 Americans have developed the meat allergy. That would make it the 10th most common food allergy in the U.S., said Dr. Scott Commins. The University of North Carolina researcher co-wrote both reports.</p>
<p>Health officials said they do not know of any confirmed deaths. However, people with the allergy have described it as strange and terrifying.</p>
<p>"I never connected it with any food because it was hours after eating," said one patient, Bernadine Heller-Greenman.</p>
<p>The reaction, called alpha-gal syndrome, happens when an infected person eats beef, pork, or other meat of mammals. Taking in other mammal products, such as milk, also causes the reaction.</p>
<p>A sugar called alpha-gal exists in mammal meat and in the <strong>saliva</strong> of ticks. When the sugar enters the body through the skin, the body's own defense, or immune, system reacts too strongly.</p>
<p>Scientists saw such reactions in patients taking a cancer drug that was made in mouse cells containing the alpha-gal sugar. But in 2011 researchers first reported that it could spread through tick bites, too.</p>
<p>They tied it to the lone star tick. Scientists say the ticks live mainly in the eastern and southern U.S.</p>
<p>One of the studies released recently examined test results from the main U.S. private laboratory looking for alpha-gal antibodies. Those tests showed the number of people who had the antibodies rose from about 13,000 in 2017 to 19,000 in 2022.</p>
<p>Experts say cases may have increased for several reasons. They say the lone star tick population is expanding. They also suggest more doctors might be learning about the disease and ordering tests for it.</p>
<p>But many doctors are not.</p>
<p>The second study was based on a <strong>survey</strong> last year of 1,500 U.S. general care doctors and health professionals. It found nearly half of them had never heard of alpha-gal syndrome, and only five percent said they felt very sure they could identify it. Researchers used that information to estimate the number of people with the allergy — 450,000.</p>
<p>People with this condition can experience <strong>symptoms</strong> including <strong>hives</strong>, <strong>nausea</strong>, <strong>vomiting</strong>, diarrhea, severe stomach pain, difficulty breathing, and swelling of the lips, throat, tongue or eyes. Unlike some other food allergies, which happen soon after eating, these reactions hit hours later.</p>
<p>Some patients have only stomach symptoms. The American Gastroenterological Association says people with unexplained diarrhea, nausea and stomach pain should be tested for the syndrome.</p>
<p>Doctors advise people with the allergy to stop eating meat and other foods that cause the reaction and to have <strong>epinephrine </strong>available to them at all times. And, doctors say, avoid tick bites.</p>
<p>The allergy can go away in some people. Commins said he has seen that happen in about 15 to 20 percent of his patients. Staying free of tick bites is extremely important.</p>
<p>"The tick bites are central to this. They <strong>perpetuate</strong> the allergy," he said.</p>
<p>One of his patients is Heller-Greenman, a 78-year-old art historian in New York. She spends summers on Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts. She said she is used to getting bitten by ticks on the island. She has had Lyme disease, also caused by tick bites, four times.</p>
<p>About five years ago, Heller-Greenman started experiencing terrible, itchy hives on her back, middle and legs in the middle of the night. Her doctors decided it was an allergic reaction but could not identify the cause.</p>
<p>She never ate a lot of meat, but one day in January 2020 she had two beef meals in a row. Six hours after eating the second, she woke up nauseated, then vomited, had diarrhea and a lack of balance, or dizziness. She <strong>passed out</strong> three times.</p>
<p>Doctors identified alpha-gal syndrome as the cause soon after the incident. Heller-Greenman was told to avoid ticks and to stop eating red meat and milk products. There have been no allergic reactions since.</p>
<p>"I have one grandchild that watches me like a hawk," she said, making sure she reads food <strong>labels</strong> and avoids foods that could cause a reaction.</p>
<p>"I feel very lucky, really, that this has worked out for me," she said. "Not all doctors are knowledgeable about this."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p>And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em><span style="color:black">_________________________________________________</span></em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>saliva</strong> <em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em><span style="color:black">fluid from the mouth</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>survey</strong><strong> </strong><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. </span></em><span style="color:black">a kind of study in which people are asked question to find something out about a subject</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>symptom</strong><strong> </strong><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. </span></em><span style="color:black">a sign that disease is present</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hives</strong><strong> </strong><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. (pl.) </span></em><span style="color:black">a condition when the skin becomes red, swollen, and itchy<em> </em></span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>nausea</strong><strong> </strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em><span style="color:black">a feeling of sickness in the stomach</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vomiting </strong><em>–n. </em>to expel the food in your stomach out of your mouth</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pass out </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to lose consciousness</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>perpetuate </strong>–v. to cause something (that should be stopped) to continue</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>label </strong>–n. a piece of paper on a product that has information about that product for people who want to know more about it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Catch Garden Pests, Diseases Early to Save Plants  (2023/8/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/catch-garden-pests-diseases-early-to-save-plants.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>In her latest gardening story, Jessica Damiano tells of the <strong>garden</strong> <strong>pests</strong> and diseases she has seen in her plants.</p>
<p>The <em>Associated Press </em>writer suggests acting quickly when combatting garden pests and diseases. When not dealt with quickly, pests and diseases can quickly grow and reproduce. That can result in less plant growth and worse health, less flower and fruit production, or even death of your plants.</p>
<p>Her measure always begins with the gentlest treatment possible. She only intensifies her treatments when necessary. Even then, she has her limits. Damiano says she would rather lose a flower or vegetable plant than use strong chemicals.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This July 5, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a scarlet lily beetle on an Asiatic lily stem on Long Island, N.Y.(Jessica Damiano via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1132a559-a88a-4262-907b-3501ce93cbdf_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This July 5, 2023, image provided by Jessica Damiano shows a scarlet lily beetle on an Asiatic lily stem on Long Island, N.Y.(Jessica Damiano via AP)</span></div>
<p>In the case of her tomato plants, Damiano caught the aphids, a pest, early. She washed them off and removed the ones that would not come off by using her fingers under moving water. They have not returned in the week since removing them, but she looks out for them every day, just in case.</p>
<p>Had the invasion been severe or the water and finger removal method been ineffective, she would have used Neem oil. The organic oil, which comes from the seeds of the Neem tree, kills aphids by not permitting them to breathe. It is safe to use on plants that will be eaten and it is not harmful to people, animals, and birds. Still, it should be used after the sun has set when helpful insects are less active.</p>
<p>The same day Damiano found the aphids, she found another pest called scarlet lily beetles on her Asiatic lily plants. The adult red insects feed on a grouping of plants called true lilies and fritillaries.</p>
<p>In an earlier <strong>stage</strong> of life, called the larval stage, they cover themselves in waste. This makes them less appealing to those that would want to eat them. But the coating also protects them from chemicals, making them difficult to remove.</p>
<p>The pests had already damaged some of her plants. To prevent more damage, she removed them by <strong>tapping</strong> them off of the plant into some water with soap and vinegar, or household cleaners.</p>
<p>Her rhododendron, a flowering plant, were attacked by a pest called azalea bark scale last summer. She saw the white insects had come back this year. Some of the leaves were <strong>infested</strong>, so she cut them off. But because most of the leaves only had a few of the pests, she was able to remove them by touching each insect with some rubbing alcohol.</p>
<p>By working early, Damiano slowed or stopped infestations that could have killed her plants. The same would be true for diseases, many of which also respond better to early treatments.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>pest </strong>– <em>n.</em> an animal or insect that causes problems for people especially by damaging crops</p>
<p><strong>stage </strong>– <em>n.</em> a particular point or period in the growth or development of something</p>
<p><strong>tap </strong>– <em>v.</em> to hit (your fingers or feet) against something lightl</p>
<p><strong>infest </strong>– <em>v.</em> to be in or over (a place or an animal) in large numbers</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Norwegian Woman, Nepali Sherpa Guide Set Mountain Climbing Record  (2023/8/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/norwegian-woman-nepali-sherpa-guide-set-mountain-climbing-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>A Pakistani mountaineering official says a Norwegian woman and her Nepali Sherpa guide have completed the fastest climb of the world's 14 highest mountains.</p>
<p>Kristin Harila, age 37, and her guide Tenjen Sherpa, age 35, reached the top of the final mountain, K2, last Thursday.</p>
<p>All the <strong>peaks</strong> the two reached are above 8,000 meters, said Karrar Haidri, the secretary at the Pakistan Alpine Club.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Norwegian climber Kristin Harila, 37, right, and her guide Tenjen Sherpa pose for a photograph in Kathmandu, Nepal, Tuesday, June 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b173-08db66b76585_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Norwegian climber Kristin Harila, 37, right, and her guide Tenjen Sherpa pose for a photograph in Kathmandu, Nepal, Tuesday, June 6, 2023. (AP Photo/Niranjan Shrestha)</span></div>
<p>"A big congratulations to Kristin Harila and Tenjen Sherpa on this remarkable achievement," said Haidri, adding, "They did it in 92 days."</p>
<p>The former record-holder, Nirmal Purja, a Nepali-born British citizen, climbed the 14 peaks in 189 days in 2019.</p>
<p>Most mountain climbers spend years trying to climb the world's greatest peaks.</p>
<p>Both climbers topped Shishapangma in the Tibet area of China on April 26. They have since climbed Everest, Kanchenjunga, Lhotse, Makalu, Cho Oyu, Dhaulagiri, Manaslu, and Annapurna in Nepal before going to Pakistan, where they climbed Nanga Parbat, Gasherbrum I, Gasherbrum II and the Broad Peak before topping K2.</p>
<p>The company Seven <strong>Summit</strong> Treks (SST) provided support for the climbers' efforts.</p>
<p>Garrett Madison of the U.S.-based Madison Mountaineering company is also on K2 leading a different group. He said the climbers used a window of good weather to go to the top of the mountain.</p>
<p>"They have made a summit a short while ago," Madison told Reuters, adding that the Norwegian woman was "extremely <strong>tough</strong> mentally and physically."</p>
<p>Harila first attempted to break the record and climb all 14 top peaks in 2022. However, China restricted foreign climbers during the coronavirus pandemic so Harila was unable to attempt two of the 14 peaks.</p>
<p>K2 has one of the deadliest records for mountaineers, with most deaths happening on the return down. Any wrong move can cause an avalanche, or snowslide, and kill. Only a few hundred climbers have successfully reached its summit.</p>
<p>And one more climber made that list and set another record on Thursday, reported SST director Tashi Lakpa Sherpa. Seventeen-year-old Nima Rinjin Sherpa became the youngest person to climb K2, Tashi said.</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Gopal Sharma reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>peak</strong> – n. the top of a hill or mountain ending in a point</p>
<p><strong>summit</strong> – n. the highest point of a mountain</p>
<p><strong>tough</strong> – n. able to stand hard work and hardship</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN Aims to Remove Oil from Tanker in Red Sea  (2023/8/1) | 联合国欲转移红海油轮上的石油</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/un-effort-aims-to-remove-oil-from-tanker-in-the-red-sea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>An international team is working to remove oil from a ship anchored in the Red Sea off the coast of Yemen.<br/>
一个国际小组正在努力转移停泊在红海也门海岸一艘油轮上的石油。</p>
<p>The oil tanker, called the SOF Safer, has not been used for at least eight years. It contains over 1 million barrels of oil.<br/>
这艘萨菲尔号油轮已经至少8年没有使用了。它装载了100多万桶石油。</p>
<p>Experts say the ship is at risk of breaking up or exploding.<br/>
专家说，这艘船有发生破裂或爆炸的危险。</p>
<p>The Associated Press reported in 2020 that seawater entered the ship's engine room and caused damage. The water also put the ship in danger of sinking.<br/>
美联社2020年报道称，海水进入该船的机舱并造成损坏。这些积水也使这艘船面临沉没的危险。</p>
<p>For years, the United Nations and governments of nearby countries warned that an explosion or oil leak could disrupt shipping in the Middle East. The ship is close to the Yemeni ports of Hodeida and Ras Issa. Many ships travel from the Persian Gulf, past Yemen and through Egypt's Suez Canal to get to the Mediterranean Sea.<br/>
多年来，联合国和周边国家政府一直警告说，爆炸或石油泄漏可能会扰乱中东的航运。该船靠近也门荷台达港和拉斯伊萨港。许多船只从波斯湾出发，经过也门，通过埃及苏伊士运河到达地中海。</p>
<p>The United Nations purchased another oil tanker so crews could move the oil from the Safer.<br/>
联合国购买了另一艘油轮，以便船员能够从萨菲尔号上转移石油。</p>
<p>Antonio Guterres is the UN Secretary General. In a statement, he said the work is a "critical next step in avoiding an environmental and humanitarian catastrophe."<br/>
安东尼奥·古特雷斯是联合国秘书长。他在一份声明中表示，这项工作是“避免环境和人道主义灾难的关键一步”。</p>
<p>The U.N. said the job will be done in less than three weeks.<br/>
联合国表示，这项工作将在三周内完成。</p>
<p>The Safer was built in the 1970s and sold to the Yemeni government in the 1980s so it could move oil pumped from the fields in Marib.<br/>
萨菲尔号建造于20世纪70年代，并于20世纪80年代出售给也门政府，以便运送从马里卜油田开采的石油。</p>
<p>The U.N. said a leak could have been worse than the 1989 Exxon Valdez oil spill, one of the largest ecological disasters.<br/>
联合国表示，若发生泄漏，可能比1989年埃克森瓦尔迪兹号油轮泄漏更严重，这次事故是最大的生态灾难之一。</p>
<p>When the oil is removed, the work will not be over, however. The Safer will be anchored to an underwater oil pipeline before it is taken away to a scrapyard.<br/>
但是当石油被转移后，工作不会结束。萨菲尔号在被送往废料场之前，将被锚定在水下输油管道上。</p>
<p>David Gressly is the U.N. humanitarian official for Yemen. He said moving the oil will prevent a "worst-case scenario." Guterres said, cleaning up an oil spill in Yemen could have cost "tens of billions of dollars."<br/>
大卫·格雷斯利是联合国也门人道主义事务官员。他说，转移石油能防止“最坏的情况”。古特雷斯说，若也门发生石油泄漏进行清理，可能需要“数百亿美元”。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·菲利德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>GPS Data Could Predict Earthquakes Hours Ahead  (2023/7/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/gps-data-could-predict-earthquakes-hours-ahead.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say they have identified earth movement signals that could predict earthquakes up to two hours before they hit.</p>
<p>The signals were recorded, or detected, by <strong>GPS</strong> collection devices. The devices were positioned in areas where major earthquakes had struck in the past.</p>
<p>Scientists noted, however, that the right equipment does not currently exist to use the data to predict earthquakes. But if the sensitivity of current GPS measuring devices can be improved, the researchers say a new earthquake warning system could be possible.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt=" In this March 27, 2011 file photo, a man walks through an earthquake destroyed neighborhood below Weather Hill in Natori, Japan. (AP Photo/Wally Santana, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3bf2-08db8f86bb4d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption"> In this March 27, 2011 file photo, a man walks through an earthquake destroyed neighborhood below Weather Hill in Natori, Japan. (AP Photo/Wally Santana, File)</span></div>
<p>Earthquakes are caused by movements, or slips, in existing faults under Earth's surface, the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.usgs.gov/programs/earthquake-hazards/earthquake-facts-earthquake-fantasy#:~:text=An%20earthquake%20is%20the%20ground,we%20feel%20during%20an%20earthquake.">explains</a>. A fault is a long break in rock attached to Earth's crust. When tension builds up along a fault, energy waves are released and travel through the crust. This causes the ground to shake.</p>
<p>Technology for predicting earthquakes currently remains very limited. But the USGS does have equipment that can pick up seismic data when an earthquake is just starting. The term seismic relates to earthquake activity.</p>
<p>The USGS method makes it possible to warn people in areas where seismic activity is expected. But this method generally can only provide a warning several seconds before an earthquake hits. The USGS system is called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.shakealert.org/">ShakeAlert</a>. It has already been deployed along the U.S. West Coast. That is where the majority of earthquakes happen in the country.</p>
<p>But the new detection method could produce warnings up to two hours before the damaging effects of an earthquake are felt. Such a system could save lives by giving people the chance to get out of buildings that might collapse in an earthquake.</p>
<p>Two scientists from France's National Research Institute for Sustainable Development carried out a study that described the latest results. The findings recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adg2565">appeared</a> in the publication <em>Science</em>.</p>
<p>For the study, researchers examined GPS data collected before and after past earthquake events around the world. The data was collected on 90 earthquakes measuring larger than 7 on the Richter scale. The study period covered the past 20 years.</p>
<p>The team identified a <strong>pattern</strong> of fault movements as they examined the data collected from different areas. The movement signals were recorded within two hours of an earthquake striking. The researchers said the study demonstrates that faults generally begin to move about two hours before a large earthquake.</p>
<p>Scientists had identified such signals before single earthquakes in the past. But until now, researchers were not able to link those signals to all seismic events.</p>
<p>While the data identified this pattern, the scientists said the instruments that could capture GPS data in real time do not currently exist.</p>
<p>The National Research Institute for Sustainable Development issued a statement on the development. It said that in order to make predictions, researchers "would need to measure signals at least 10 times smaller than what we can presently do."</p>
<p>Another way to possibly build a better earthquake prediction system would be to develop "dense measurement networks" that sit very close to faults. However, such an effort would require major technological progress, the institute said.</p>
<p>Quentin Bletery is a geophysicist at C<i></i>244;te d'Azur University in the city of Nice. Bletery worked together on the study with Jean-Mathieu Nocquet, another researcher at the university.</p>
<p>Bletery <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.science.org/content/article/warning-signs-detected-hours-ahead-big-earthquakes">told</a> <em>Science</em> that the study found that no observable movement was identified in the first 46 hours leading up to an earthquake. But starting around two hours before an earthquake, the GPS signals recording movement started to increase.</p>
<p>To confirm its findings, the team compared that data to more than 100,000 <strong>random</strong> time periods recorded when no earthquakes were reported. That experiment found that similar patterns in non-earthquake areas happened just 0.03 percent of the time.</p>
<p>"This tells us earthquakes are predictable in nature," Bletery told <em>Science</em>.</p>
<p>The scientists note that more research is needed to support their findings. Much of the information used in the latest study, for example, depended heavily on data from GPS stations near major earthquake sites.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from Science and the French National Research Institute for Sustainable Development. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>GPS </strong><em>– n. </em>a system that follows the movements of something with an electronically-powered piece of equipment</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong><em>– n. </em>a regular and repeated way in which something happens</p>
<p><strong>resolution </strong><em>– n. </em>a measure of the sharpness of an image or the fineness a device operates at</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Japan, Silkworms, Crickets, Bugs Are on the Table  (2023/7/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/in-japan-silkworms-crickets-bugs-are-on-the-table.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>More restaurants in Japan are offering bugs in their dishes.</p>
<p>On a recent vacation in Tokyo, Takumi Yamamoto ate a special lunch of cricket curry and silkworm sashimi, which is usually made with raw fish. He drank a water bug <strong>cider</strong>.</p>
<p>The 26-year-old office worker is one of many people around the world with a growing interest in entomophagy, or the practice of eating insects. Bugs are slowly becoming more usable as a food source.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Shunnosuke Suga eats beetle larvae, as he eats Almond tofu with beetle larvae at Take-Noko cafe in Tokyo, Japan, July 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-c3c8-08db8ece982a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Shunnosuke Suga eats beetle larvae, as he eats Almond tofu with beetle larvae at Take-Noko cafe in Tokyo, Japan, July 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon)</span></div>
<p>Yamamoto said he sometimes ate grasshoppers dipped in soy sauce as a child. In Tokyo, he ate insect foods at Take-Noko cafe, which serves many bug dishes.</p>
<p>"It's fun to select from a wider variety of dishes," Yamamoto said. "Everything was tasty. In particular, the water bug <strong>cider</strong> was quite refreshing ... like a green apple."</p>
<p>Entomophagy started to be taken seriously after the United Nations declared bugs a good source of protein to feed a growing world population. With livestock farming's effects on climate change and world hunger issues from weather and war, there has been more interest in the nutrition bugs can provide.</p>
<p>Some people think eating insects is just <strong>gross</strong>. But Japan has a rich history of using insects as food.</p>
<p>Grasshoppers, silkworms and wasps were traditionally eaten in areas of the country with little meat and fish. It was a <strong>practice</strong> that grew in popularity because of food shortages during and after World War II, said Take-Noko <strong>manager</strong> Michiko Miura.</p>
<p>"Recently, there have been advances in <strong>rearing</strong> things like crickets and mealworms for food, so the possibility of using insects as ingredients is really growing," she added. Several companies in Japan sell cakes and <strong>snacks</strong> made from cricket flour.</p>
<p>Interest has also grown at Take-Noko, which is often fully <strong>reserved</strong> on weekends.</p>
<p>The restaurant's curry contains crickets in meatball form. The "sashimi" is the left-over shell of silkworms, and the cider contains water bug <strong>extract</strong> and is topped with a whole insect.</p>
<p>Takeo Saito started the restaurant. He also has a <strong>packaged</strong> food company that offers more than 60 kinds of bug foods, from scorpions to tarantulas.</p>
<p>"Our aim is not for insects to be something separate, but to be enjoyed at the same table as vegetables, fish, and meat," Saito said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em><span style="color:black">Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</span></em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em><span style="color:black">_______________________________________</span></em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong><span style="color:black">cider </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>a drink made from apples</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">gross </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— adj. </span></em>very disgusting</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">practice </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>to do something again and again in order to become better at it</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">manager </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>someone who is in charge of a business, department, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">rear </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— v. </span></em>to take care of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">snack </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>a small amount of food eaten between meals</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">reserve </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— v. </span></em>to make arrangements so that you will be able to use or have at a later time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">extract </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— v. </span></em>to remove by pulling it out or cutting it out</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">package </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>a box or large envelope that is sent or delivered usually through the mail or by another delivery service</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Dubai, ‘Gourmet Water’ Injected with Minerals  (2023/7/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/in-dubai-gourmet-water-injected-with-minerals.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 July 2023</span><br/>
<p><span style="color:black">New kinds of drinks like smoothies, lattes, beers, and cocktails have become popular in recent years. Now a place in Dubai is serving what it claims to be "<strong>gourmet</strong> water."</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Thirty different kinds of it. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">The Aqua Water Bar by Luqel gets its water the traditional way – from the pipe that runs water to your house. The government of Dubai in the United Arab Emirates says water from the pipe, called tap water, is safe to drink and meets international standards. But people in the Middle Eastern city still prefer bottled water.</span></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Roia Jabari, managing director of AQUA Water Bar by LUQEL poses at her store in Dubai, United Arab Emirates on July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7c789374-f0f3-4e22-b76b-a4f4a7a82a82_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Roia Jabari, managing director of AQUA Water Bar by LUQEL poses at her store in Dubai, United Arab Emirates on July 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Kamran Jebreili)</span></div>
<p><span style="color:black">The water at Aqua Water Bar is said to be different. The <strong>bar</strong> says it injects a very small amount of minerals, called micro-dosing, into the water. The system is designed by the German water filtration company Luqel. And its water is compared to costly water like Alpine or Arctic-sourced.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Roia Jabari is a director at Aqua Water. She said experts have designed its water to fit your "needs and <strong>mood</strong>." And she added, "We can give you the perfectly mineralized <strong>recipe</strong>."</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">One drink, "Runners Heaven," is high in sodium and potassium to help runners after being in the desert heat. Another, "Vegan's Choice," offers minerals that could be lacking when not eating meat. Buyers can fill up their bottles with any of the mineral combinations for around 50 cents per 500 milliliters or pay more for a nonalcoholic mixed drink. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">It is not an entirely new idea. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">A water bar serving what it said was heavily <strong>filtered</strong> New York City tap water opened in the city's East Village area in 2012. It received heavy criticism. Another briefly opened in Washington, DC in 2019. It also did not get the best <strong>reviews</strong>. Neither appears to have stayed open for very long. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">But Dubai, a modern city built on desert sands, could be such a place for the product. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Alcohol is available in bars in the UAE, but the Muslim country's population does not drink alcohol. As a center of international business, it brings in wealthy, health-centered people who support the wellness industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Although Aqua Water is often visited by businessmen who work in the surrounding Dubai Media City, Jabari says that the bar is not just for wealthy buyers. She says the water, which sells for 54 cents per 500 milliliters, is not too costly. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">To help the environment, buyers can either fill their own bottles or buy a reusable one starting at around $2.50. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Early reviews appear to be good, with the bar having 4.6 stars on Google reviews based on around 12 reviews. "(The water) was actually different," said Bilal Rizvi, who stopped in to try it out recently. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Jabari was born in San Diego, California, and is a designer who has lived in the UAE for 24 years. She designed the bar around ideas based on water. Additionally, the bar also serves Persian food as a way to honor her ancestry. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">Jabari hopes to expand the business. She sees room for growth in neighboring countries. She said, "Saudi Arabia is a huge market for us. I believe that Abu Dhabi is our next step."</span></p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em><span style="color:black">Nick El Hajj reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:black">________________________________________________</span></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></h2>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">gourmet </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> a person who enjoys and knows a lot about good food and wine</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">bar </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> </span>a building or room where alcoholic drinks and sometimes food are served</p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">mood </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> the way someone feels</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">recipe </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> a set of instructions for making food</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">filter </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>v. </em>to pass (something, such as a gas or liquid) through a filter to remove something unwanted</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">review </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> </span>a report that gives someone's opinion about the quality of a book, performance, product, etc.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Churches in Europe See Record Numbers of Visitors  (2023/7/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/churches-in-europe-see-record-numbers-of-visitors.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Famous Christian religious places in southern Europe are seeing record numbers of visitors. But not everyone is happy about the large crowds. Church leaders are finding it difficult to balance the needs of <strong>tourists</strong> and the people who come to pray.</p>
<p><strong>Dealing with more visitors</strong></p>
<p>This spring, the Vatican opened a separate "pathway" starting outside St. Peter's Basilica for those who want to take part in religious services. St. Peter's spokesperson Roberta Leone said officials made the change because of long lines for the 55,000 daily visitors.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Tourist line up to enter at the Sagrada Familia basilica in Barcelona on July 18, 2023. (Photo by Pau BARRENA / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2b4eea31-f993-40c1-ad81-5c822d176e34_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Tourist line up to enter at the Sagrada Familia basilica in Barcelona on July 18, 2023. (Photo by Pau BARRENA / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The Vatican's move is an example of what many churches are doing. They have tourists and religious people go separate ways. Religious services are sometimes held in different places. And sometimes tourists are not permitted at worship times.</p>
<p>With an estimated 330 million people visiting religious places yearly around the world, religious tourism is one of the largest parts of the tourism market.</p>
<p>Worshippers often come because celebrated churches generally have more services than regular churches. They need to be able to enter at no cost. Tourists often pay fees that are important for churches to maintain their buildings.</p>
<p>Daniel Olsen of Brigham Young University in Utah studies religious tourism. Olsen said of the situation, "It's just really hard because you also want people to experience your faith."</p>
<p><strong>Different opinions</strong></p>
<p>Some religious people are unhappy with the large numbers of visitors.</p>
<p>After the ceremony of <strong>Mass</strong> in the burial area of the Sagrada Familia church in Barcelona, Spain, Joan Albaiges said, "The <strong>temple</strong> needs to be a place for services and not a <strong>theme park</strong>."</p>
<p>He praised the policy change in recent years to celebrate one Sunday Mass at the main<strong> altar</strong>.</p>
<p>But there is such demand for the 800 free tickets that several hundred people waiting often do not get in, said Josep Maria Turull. Turull is the <strong>rector</strong> at Sagrada Familia who also oversees tourism for the local church organization.</p>
<p>Religious leaders say the histories of the sacred buildings should be presented to visitors. These visitors increasingly do not know about faith traditions in churches.</p>
<p>José Fernández Lago is rector of the Cathedral of Santiago de Compostela. Filled with beautiful art, Santiago's<strong> cathedral </strong>draws hundreds of thousands of tourists and religious visitors known as pilgrims.</p>
<p>To remain a special place for religious pilgrims, Lago said, the cathedral does not charge money for entry. The cathedral also does not limit visitor numbers or require people to wear <strong>formal</strong> clothing.</p>
<p>But visits are not permitted during the four daily Masses celebrated at the main altar. And priests as well as security guards always have to ask visitors to lower their voices so that worshipers can pray in peace.</p>
<p>"Some people go to the cathedral, and they don't realize they're in a church," Lago observed. He added, "It's a situation that's developing in nations that were majority Christian, and now faith is cooling off."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Giovanna Dell'Orto reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tourist </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who travels to a place for pleasure</p>
<p><strong>Mass</strong> –<em> n.</em> a Christian ceremony in the Roman Catholic Church</p>
<p><strong>temple</strong> <em>–n.</em> a building for worship</p>
<p><strong>theme park </strong><em>–n.</em> a place with rides and fun things to do that are all connected by a cultural or artistic idea</p>
<p><strong>altar</strong> <em>– n.</em> a platform or table used as a center of worship in Christian ceremonies</p>
<p><strong>rector</strong> <em>– n.</em> a priest or minister who is in charge of a church or parish</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Offers Satellite Technology to Help Fight Amazon Deforestation  (2023/7/30) | 美国宇航局向巴西提供卫星技术帮助对抗亚马逊森林砍伐</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/nasa-offers-satellite-technology-to-help-fight-amazon-deforestation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The American space agency NASA has offered its satellite technology to Brazil to help identify destruction in the Amazon rainforest.<br/>
美国宇航局向巴西提供卫星技术帮助确定亚马逊雨林的破坏情况。</p>
<p>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson made the offer during a recent trip to Brazil. The NASA chief visited the country's space agency – the National Institute for Space Research – in the southeastern city of Jose dos Campos. Nelson's trip to South America also included visits to Argentina and Colombia.<br/>
美国宇航局局长比尔·纳尔逊在最近的巴西之行中提出了这一提议。纳尔逊访问了位于该国东南部城市何塞·多斯坎波斯的巴西国家太空研究院。纳尔逊的南美之行还包括对阿根廷和哥伦比亚的访问。</p>
<p>Brazilian Science Minister Luciana Santos showed Nelson around the institute and explained some of the space agency's programs.<br/>
巴西科技部长卢西亚娜·桑托斯陪同纳尔逊参观了该研究院，并解释了该航天机构的一些项目。</p>
<p>During a news conference, Nelson described one new NASA satellite that he said would be completed by January. He said the satellite, called NISAR, will even be able to capture images of what is happening in real time below the forest cover.<br/>
纳尔逊在新闻发布会上谈到了美国宇航局的一颗新卫星，他说这颗卫星将于明年1月完工。他说，这颗名为NISAR的卫星甚至能够捕获森林覆盖下的实时图像。</p>
<p>"It is going to be able to look through the canopy of the jungle so that we can see if someone has burned the undergrowth and that would ultimately kill the big trees," Nelson said.<br/>
纳尔逊说：“它将能够穿透丛林的树冠观察，这样我们就可以看到是否有人烧毁了灌木丛，这样做最终会毁灭大树。”</p>
<p>NASA says the new satellite will support a project called SERVIR Amazonia. It helps provide Earth science data to scientists and decision-makers across the Amazon area to record environmental changes in near real-time. The project helps predict climate threats like deforestation and food insecurity. It can also provide data to emergency workers during natural disasters.<br/>
美国宇航局表示，这颗新卫星将支持一个名为SERVIR Amazonia的项目。它有助于向亚马逊地区的科学家和决策者提供地球科学数据，以近乎实时地记录环境变化。该项目有助于预测气候威胁，如森林砍伐和粮食不安全。它还可以在自然灾害期间为应急人员提供数据。</p>
<p>Brazil's space agency has launched a series of satellites in partnership with China since 1999. Those satellites aim to gather data on agricultural operations and the environment.<br/>
自1999年以来，巴西航天机构与中国合作发射了一系列卫星。这些卫星旨在收集有关农业经营和环境的数据。</p>
<p>Brazil depends on satellite imagery to watch over the Amazon. But cloud cover often makes it difficult for satellites to capture clear and timely images. The NASA chief said the satellites NASA plans to place into orbit early next year will add an "extreme ability to understand what is happening" to the rainforest.<br/>
巴西依靠卫星图像来监视亚马逊。但云层覆盖往往使卫星难以捕捉到清晰及时的图像。纳尔逊表示，美国宇航局计划明年初将这颗卫星送入轨道，它将为雨林增加一种“了解正在发生的事情的极限能力”。</p>
<p>Nelson, a former U.S. senator who once flew to space, also met with President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva in Brasilia. After the meeting, he told reporters he thanked the president "for his continuous effort to save the Amazon rainforest."<br/>
作为一位曾飞往太空的前美国参议员，纳尔逊还在巴西利亚会见了巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦。会后他告诉记者，他感谢巴西总统“为拯救亚马逊雨林所做的持续努力”。</p>
<p>Nelson said that when he flew aboard NASA's Space Shuttle Columbia in 1986, he witnessed the destruction of the rainforest by the different colors he could see from his spacecraft window.<br/>
纳尔逊说，当他在1986年乘坐美国宇航局的哥伦比亚号航天飞机时，他从飞船窗户看到了不同颜色，亲眼见证了人类对雨林的破坏。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Effects of Affirmative Action after 10 Years in Brazil  (2023/7/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/effects-of-affirmative-action-after-10-years-in-brazil.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Late last month, the U.S. Supreme Court <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-supreme-court-rejects-race-consideration-in-college-admissions/7160538.html">ruled</a> that race cannot be the reason for colleges to accept students.</p>
<p>The high court ruled that the Equal Protection Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment does not permit such decisions based on race.</p>
<p>The policy that many colleges used to increase the percentage of minorities they admitted was called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-supreme-court-rejects-race-consideration-in-college-admissions/7160538.html">affirmative action</a>. They said the policy helped make their groups of students more <strong>diverse</strong> and improved the ability of minority groups to get higher education.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A student holds a sign that reads in Portuguese To Educate is Freedom during a protest against the budget cuts by President Jair Bolsonaro&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/i&gt;180;s government of public schools and universities, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Tuesday, Oct. 18, 2022. (AP Photo/Silvia Izquierdo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/162c809e-1eff-4c31-8ef7-b4ec15ee4851_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - A student holds a sign that reads in Portuguese "To Educate is Freedom" during a protest against the budget cuts by President Jair Bolsonaro<i>&amp;#</i>180;s government of public schools and universities, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Tuesday, Oct. 18, 2022. (AP Photo/Silvia Izquierdo)</span></div>
<p>Those opposed to affirmative action said the policy prevented some qualified students from getting into <strong>selective</strong> universities.</p>
<p>Colleges in much of the U.S. were permitted to partly consider a student's race in their admissions decisions for over 50 years.</p>
<p>As a result of the high court's decision in June, most colleges and most universities must now consider <strong>factors</strong> other than race.</p>
<p><strong>Quotas in Brazil</strong></p>
<p>In Brazil, a version of affirmative action has been a part of admissions since 2012. The country has a law that permits both racial and economic <strong>quotas</strong> for its federal or public universities.</p>
<p>Three <a class="wsw__a" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/joes.12564">researchers</a> wrote about the effects of affirmative action in Brazil for the <em>Journal of Economic Surveys</em>. They <strong>condensed</strong> their findings in a piece for <em>The Conversation, </em>an online publication.</p>
<p>Neil Lewis Jr. of Cornell University in New York state, Inacio Bo of the University of Macau and Rodrigo Zeidan of New York University's Shanghai <strong>campus</strong> worked on the article.</p>
<p>They explained the background of affirmative action in Brazil and the kinds of students the policy affects. They say the policy "has proved to be quite beneficial."</p>
<p><strong>Concerns about quotas</strong></p>
<p>The quotas became law in August 2012. At the time, many people worried that Brazilian students, who were already attending college, would suffer. They argued that professors would have to lower the level of their teaching in order to connect with a larger number of Black and indigenous students from poor areas. They said wealthy students with a good early education would leave for private universities. In some cases, the writers noted, wealthy students did go to other universities.</p>
<p>Others said Black high school students in Brazil would not work as hard because they knew the universities were holding places for them. A study showed that this was true for students who were already achieving. However, the writers said students in a lower group worked harder because they knew they could continue with their studies. Overall, they said, the quotas permitted a larger group of minority students to continue their education.</p>
<p>Only one of Brazil's 81 senators voted against the law. In a story published in 2012, the <em>New York Times</em> quoted Brazil's current president, Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, as saying the policy would help some racial groups "make up for lost time." Lula had been president from 2003 to 2010.</p>
<p>The researchers talked about what they considered the difference between Brazil's quota system and the affirmative action policy in the United States.</p>
<p>In Brazil, at least half of the places at federal universities are held for students who are either poor or from racial minority groups. In the U.S., quotas have been unlawful for more than 40 years. But universities could use data about race and wealth to decide the best combination of students.</p>
<p>In Brazil, most students, including those from wealthy families, hope to go to federal universities. The schools are both high-quality and cost-free. One concern about the federal universities, however, is that openings are limited. Some people will not get in and will have to find other schools for higher education.</p>
<p><strong>Benefits in Brazil</strong></p>
<p>The writers said, for those who do attend the federal universities, the last 10 years of quotas have had good results.</p>
<p>The researchers said students admitted because of the quotas performed well. If they lacked learning compared to wealthier students, they learned the necessary skills by graduation.</p>
<p>In addition, some quota students got better grades than the traditional students. The researchers said not all students from wealthy parts of Brazil with good high schools were guaranteed to do well in their university studies.</p>
<p>When the affirmative action plan came out in Brazil, da Silva said it was hard to find Black doctors, dentists and bank supervisors. But Lewis, Zeidan and Bo said the students admitted because of affirmative action were seven percent more likely to have those jobs because of the policy. Many students, they said, would not have moved on to higher education if they did not have places set aside at the universities.</p>
<p><strong>What does it mean for the U.S.?</strong></p>
<p>The writers said the quota system helped diversify students in federal universities. Before 2012, it was difficult for Brazilian universities to make sure poor and minority students could receive higher education. Some universities developed policies to bring in more students from poor areas. However, that did not always make a clear difference in the race of students attending the college.</p>
<p>The writers of the piece worried that a similar plan by American colleges and universities would not work as well as affirmative action. They advised university leaders that race-based polices work better than other systems.</p>
<p>"University leaders," they wrote, "must find...new ways to make their campuses more diverse. How to achieve that may be a <strong>challenge</strong>, but it seems to remain a worthwhile <strong>pursuit</strong>."</p>
<p>In their article, the writers said other nations should be able to enact policies similar to the ones in Brazil without worrying that students will be deeply hurt. The one group they said they are concerned about is the group of wealthier students who lost their places at the federal universities because of quotas. Those students face the high cost of attending private universities.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on an article first published by </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://theconversation.com/what-the-us-can-learn-from-affirmative-action-at-universities-in-brazil-208647"><em>The Conversation</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>diverse </strong>–adj. made up of people different from each other</p>
<p><strong>selective </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>choosing only top-level candidates</p>
<p><strong>factor</strong> <em>–n. </em>something that helps people make a decision or a choice<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>quota</strong> <em>–n. </em>a limit, number, percentage or ratio of people who are permitted</p>
<p><strong>condensed</strong> <em>–adj.</em><em> </em>made shorter by removing parts that are less important</p>
<p><strong>campus</strong> <em>–n. </em>the grounds surrounding an institution, especially a college or university</p>
<p><strong>challenge</strong> <em>–n. </em>a difficult thing to do</p>
<p><strong>pursuit</strong> <em>–n. </em>an effort directed at gaining, finding or completing something</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Beating a Dead Horse' Is Pointless  (2023/7/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/beating-a-dead-horse-is-pointless.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give examples, notes on usage, and sometimes we even use them in short stories.</p>
<p>Today's idiom does not sound nice. In fact, it sounds quite <strong>cruel.</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - National Treasure, right, with jockey John Velazquez, beats Blazing Sevens, with jockey Irad Ortiz Jr., wins the 148th Preakness Stakes horse race at Pimlico Race Course, May 20, 2023, in Maryland. (AP Photo/Julio Cortez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d855-08db598cfa59_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - National Treasure, right, with jockey John Velazquez, beats Blazing Sevens, with jockey Irad Ortiz Jr., wins the 148th Preakness Stakes horse race at Pimlico Race Course, May 20, 2023, in Maryland. (AP Photo/Julio Cortez)</span></div>
<p>Today, we talk about <u>beating a dead horse</u>.</p>
<p>Why would anyone do something as pointless as beating a dead animal? Well, that is how we use the expression: to describe something that is a useless thing to do. You are just wasting your time. It is not productive. There is no point.</p>
<p>Merriam-Webster's online dictionary says this expression comes from the mid-19th century. Back then, some people may have beaten horses to make them go faster. At the time, this was often thought of as an acceptable practice.</p>
<p>But <u>beating a dead horse</u> would be pointless – because it's dead. No amount of beating will change that fact. We often use this expression in the <strong>negative</strong>. We say things like "I don't want to beat horse ..." or "Not to beat a dead horse..."</p>
<p>Now, if you are a horse lover and don't want to talk about beating one, please do not worry. We have many other expressions and idioms that have a similar meaning.</p>
<p><em>Let's say your friend talks about the same problem. They do not take your advice and they do not seem to want to accept any solution. If you don't want to say to them, "Now you're just beating a dead horse," you can say, "Look, we've <u>gone over the same ground</u> and nothing has changed. So, can we please change the topic?"</em></p>
<p>When you go over the same ground, you talk about the same thing over and over again.</p>
<p>There is another expression with the word "ground" that means the same thing as "beat a dead horse." If I have a problem and talk about it too much, I have <u>run it into the ground</u>. Running something into the ground means you have talked about to death. You have talked about it <strong><u>ad nauseam</u></strong>. This means you are making other people sick over it.</p>
<p>So, it is not a good idea <u>to <strong>dwell</strong> <strong>on</strong> an old topic</u>. Hearing about the same thing over and over again is tiring. Many people have lost good friends from <strong><u>belaboring</u></strong><u> a point or an issue.</u></p>
<p>And that is all the time we have for this Words and Their Stories.</p>
<p>But join us again! We explore so many expressions and idioms in this program. In fact, each week we teach new ones. Not to beat a dead horse, but we really are a great resource for learning English.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cruel </strong><em>– adj.</em><strong> </strong><span style="color:#212529">ready to hurt others <strong>: </strong>without humane feelings</span></p>
<p><strong>negative </strong><em>– adj</em>. showing <span style="color:#212529">the opposite of something else</span></p>
<p><strong>ad nauseam </strong><em>– adv. </em>to a sickening or excessive degree</p>
<p><strong>dwell</strong> <strong>on </strong><em>– phrasal v. </em><span style="color:#212529">to think or talk about (something) for a long time</span></p>
<p><strong>belabor </strong><em>– v. </em><span style="color:#212529">to explain or insist on excessively</span></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Canada Releases Plan to End Inefficient Fossil Fuel Subsidies  (2023/7/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/canada-releases-plan-to-end-inefficient-fossil-fuel-subsidies.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Canada on Monday presented its plan for ending many of its fossil fuel industry <strong>subsidies</strong>. The plan's release makes Canada the first member-country of the Group of 20 to honor a 2009 promise to end government financial support to the industry.</p>
<p>Climate policy experts say the announcement marks an important step forward. But some argue that the plan falls short by continuing to permit government support for some oil and gas projects. The proposed measure includes exceptions that would permit subsidies for projects that plan to reduce <strong>emissions</strong> through technology like carbon capture and storage, or CCS.</p>
<p>Canada said it will not cancel any current multi-year subsidy agreements that are already in place.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - ExxonMobil renewable diesel complex at the Strathcona refinery near Edmonton, Canada. (Photo: Business Wire)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-7264-08db8f7a5e62_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - ExxonMobil renewable diesel complex at the Strathcona refinery near Edmonton, Canada. (Photo: Business Wire)</span></div>
<p>Steven Guilbeault is Canada's Environment Minister. He said the plan guarantees that "federal support for oil and gas goes to projects that decarbonize" their production and show substantial reductions in <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> emissions.</p>
<p>Active fossil fuel operations are <strong>exempt</strong> from the policy if they fall into one of six <strong>categories</strong>. One category is the ability to reduce carbon emissions. Another is support for clean energy. Businesses that provide critical energy to rural communities are another exempted category, as are those that support native communities in fossil fuel activities or those that have a plan to reach <strong>net-zero</strong> emissions by 2030.</p>
<p>Bringing an end to fossil fuel subsidies is part of a 2022 deal signed by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's minority Liberal party and the New Democratic Party (NDP).</p>
<p>The NDP critic for Climate Change and Environment, Laurel Collins, said the new rules do not go far enough.</p>
<p>Collins said, "it is clear that this announcement doesn't meet the urgency of the moment when climate disasters are putting everything we value at risk."</p>
<p>Canada is the world's fourth-largest oil producer. Carbon capture is expected to play a major part in decarbonizing the industry. Canada last year announced a CCS investment tax credit. Carbon capture is a process by which carbon dioxide is taken from the atmosphere and stored underground.</p>
<p>The Pathways Alliance is a partnership between Canada's six largest oil sands producers. It is planning to develop a $12 billion CCS center in northern Alberta. Pathways President Kendall Dilling said in a statement that the organization was happy the framework recognized the need for government partnership on the project.</p>
<p>Canada is expected to release a plan to end public financing of fossil fuel projects within the next year.</p>
<p>Julia Levin is with the climate group Environmental Defense. "The Government of Canada must quickly take the final step and end all fossil financing – without any <strong>loopholes</strong> for fossil gas, fossil hydrogen or CCS," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em><span style="color:black">Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Reuters.</span></em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em><span style="color:black">_________________________________________________</span></em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong><span style="color:black">subsidy </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>money that is paid usually by a government to keep the price of a product or service low or to help a business or organization to continue to function</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">emission </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em> the act of producing or sending out something from a source</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">greenhouse gas </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>any of various gaseous compounds (such as carbon dioxide or methane) that absorb infrared radiation, trap heat in the atmosphere, and contribute to the greenhouse effect</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">exempt </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— adj. </span></em>not required to do something that others are required to do</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">category </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>a group of people or things that are similar in some way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">net-zero </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— adj. </span></em>when a country, city, etc. removes as many emissions as it produces</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">loophole </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em>an error in the way a law, rule, or contract is written that makes it possible for some people to legally avoid obeying it</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grover Cleveland: Repeated  (2023/7/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/americas-presidents-grover-cleveland.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Grover Cleveland. When Americans remember him, it is mostly because he makes writing presidential timelines difficult. Cleveland was the nation's 22nd president, and also its 24th.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Grover Cleveland" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2d7b1b83-5c2c-4f17-ba9b-34af26f5f124_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Grover Cleveland</span></div>
<p>He remains the only U.S. president to date whose second term did not immediately follow the first.</p>
<p>Cleveland is also notable because of his personal life, and because he held office during one of the country's worst economic crises.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Stephen Grover Cleveland was born in the northeastern state of New Jersey and grew up mostly in New York. He was a middle child in a family of nine children. His father was a minister, and the family did not have much money.</p>
<p>As a result, Cleveland had little formal education. He was one of the few presidents who did not go to college. But he was able to become a lawyer. He earned enough money and developed a good professional image.</p>
<p>In time, he became a sheriff, a mayor, and the governor of the state of New York.</p>
<p>In his early life, Cleveland did not marry and have children. Instead, he had many friends, with whom he enjoyed hunting, fishing, and eating and drinking in restaurants.</p>
<p>But Cleveland did have a relationship with a <strong>widow</strong> named Maria Halpin. She became pregnant and said Cleveland was the baby's father.</p>
<p>Cleveland said he was not sure if he was. However, he gave the child some financial support, the name of one of his closest friends, and his own family name. The child was called Oscar Folsom Cleveland.</p>
<p>Shortly after the boy was born, his mother was sent to an institution for the mentally unstable. Doctors quickly confirmed that her mental health was fine, but her son was taken from her and raised by another family.</p>
<p>The story about Halpin and the child became an issue in the election of 1884. The Democratic Party had nominated Cleveland as their candidate for president.</p>
<p>In general, voters liked his message of limiting federal spending, reducing the power of wealthy interests, and stopping political corruption. Some called him "Grover the Good."</p>
<p>But Cleveland's opponents said his history with Maria Halpin showed that he was an <strong>immoral</strong> man. At anti-Cleveland rallies, Republicans chanted, "Ma, ma, where's my Pa?" Pa is another word for father.</p>
<p>But Cleveland did not comment much on the matter. His defenders said Cleveland's honesty as a public official was more important than his bad judgment as a private citizen.</p>
<p>Voters seemed to agree. Cleveland narrowly won the election. His supporters answered the Republicans' chants of "where's my Pa?" by saying, "Gone to the White House, ha, ha, ha!"</p>
<p><strong>First presidential term</strong></p>
<p>Grover Cleveland's presidency was unusual because he did not want to use the office to propose laws. Instead, he mostly aimed to keep the federal government operating efficiently. He also wanted to limit lawmakers' power to help special interest groups.</p>
<p>As a result, Cleveland vetoed many bills in his first term. He set a record at that time for saying no to proposals from Congress.</p>
<p>One of the few ideas that he supported was reducing<strong> tariffs</strong>.</p>
<p>Many of his fellow Democrats liked that idea, too. But a number of Republicans did not. In the next election, their candidate, Benjamin Harrison, defeated Cleveland.</p>
<p>Cleveland returned to being a lawyer in New York.</p>
<p>In 1892, Cleveland was chosen to run against Benjamin Harrison again. The tariff issue returned: the Republicans' protective tariffs had hurt some industries, and voters answered this time by voting Harrison out of office.</p>
<p>Cleveland returned to the White House. But this time he was not alone.</p>
<p><strong>White House wedding</strong></p>
<p>Two years into his first term as president, Cleveland married the daughter of his close friend, Oscar Folsom.</p>
<p>The bride's name was Frances Folsom. She was 21 years old at the time. The president was 49.</p>
<p>Cleveland was not the first president to get married while in office. But he was the first one to be married in the White House.</p>
<p>The event <strong>captivated</strong> the public. What's more, Americans adored the new first lady. She was known for being social, charming, and beautiful. Historians conclude that she was the most popular first lady since Dolley Madison. She remains the youngest.</p>
<p><strong>Second presidential term</strong></p>
<p>When the Clevelands returned to the White House, the country was entering a severe economic recession. Some of the country's biggest businesses were failing, including a railroad and many banks.</p>
<p>As a result, investors withdrew their money from the stock market. The withdrawal caused many other businesses to fail. The series of events is known as the Panic of 1893.</p>
<p>Soon, more and more Americans were out of work. Many could not afford houses or food. Some begged President Cleveland to intervene. But he declined. He did not think it was the role of the federal government to create jobs in order to reverse the depression.</p>
<p>However, Cleveland did use the power of the federal government to intervene during a famous labor strike. In that event, workers in Chicago who helped keep the trains operating walked out of their jobs. They were protesting a major decrease in their pay that did not include a decrease in their living expenses.</p>
<p>Since the owner of the company also controlled the price of housing and food, workers appealed to him to treat them more fairly. But the company owner refused even to meet with the workers.</p>
<p>Soon, the workers' boycott grew. Workers at other railyards stopped working. Farmers could not get their goods to market, and others could not get the supplies they needed. Even the mail stopped being delivered.</p>
<p>So Cleveland sent federal troops to break the strike.</p>
<p>In the short term, Cleveland's actions worked. The trains moved again, and both the courts and most of the public agreed with the president's decision.</p>
<p>But in the long term, Cleveland's handling of the panic, depression, and workers' strike lost the support of many voters. At the next opportunity, they voted him out of the White House again.</p>
<p><strong>Cleveland's legacy</strong></p>
<p>Cleveland returned to New York, and later settled in a large house in Princeton, New Jersey.</p>
<p>There, he wrote, made speeches, sat on corporate boards, became a <strong>trustee</strong> of Princeton University and enjoyed the respect of the people who lived in the town.</p>
<p>He died at age 71 of problems with his stomach, heart, and kidneys. Several people said his final words were, "I have tried so hard to do right."</p>
<p>Then and now, many people agreed with that idea. Cleveland was generally an honest man who worked hard and tried to act independently as president.</p>
<p>But he is not considered one of America's best leaders. He did not have a clear idea about how to guide the country.<br/>
<br/>
Yet the opposing party, at least, may have considered Cleveland's presidency a success. After Cleveland's final election defeat, six of the next seven presidents were Republicans.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Mario Ritter was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Write to us in the Comments Section.</em></p>
<p>
</p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>widow</strong> -<em> n.</em> a woman whose husband has died</p>
<p><strong>immoral </strong>- <em>adj. </em>not morally good or right : morally evil or wrong</p>
<p><strong>tariffs</strong> - <em>n. </em>a tax on goods coming into or leaving a country</p>
<p><strong>captivate</strong> - <em>v.</em> to attract and hold the attention of someone by being interesting or pretty</p>
<p><strong>trustee</strong> - <em>n. </em>a member of a group that manages the money of an organization</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Torch Will Bring its Light to the 2024 Olympics  (2023/7/29) | 2024年巴黎奥运会火炬亮相</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/torch-will-bring-its-light-to-the-2024-olympics.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Olympic Games organizers in France presented the 2024 Olympic torch that will light the Summer Games in the country a year from now. In the Olympic torch tradition, many people carry the torch in turn from Greece to the current location of the Games. After it has traveled thousands of kilometers, the torch will light the Olympic cauldron at the Opening Ceremony of the next Olympic Games.<br/>
法国奥运会组织者展示了2024年奥运火炬，它将在一年后点燃该国夏季奥运会的圣火。在奥运火炬的传统中，许多人轮流将火炬从希腊传递到奥运会当前的举办地。火炬在经过数千公里的传递后，将在下一届奥运会开幕式上点燃奥运圣火。</p>
<p>French designer Mathieu Lehanneur created the torch, which is 70 centimeters long and made of lightweight steel. Lehanneur said its shape is inspired by the famous Seine river, which flows through Paris. He said the torch is equal from top to bottom and all around the middle, which stands for equality between athletes. The twisting shape of the torch represents peace.<br/>
法国设计师马修·勒汉纽尔设计了这款火炬，它长70厘米，由轻钢制成。勒汉纽尔表示，火炬形状受到了流经巴黎的著名的塞纳河的启发。他说，火炬从上到下以及中部都是对称的，它象征着着运动员之间的平等。火炬曲线的形状象征着和平。</p>
<p>The torch was made with lightweight steel. Its lower half copies the movement of the Seine, along which the opening ceremony will take place for over 500,000 viewers.<br/>
火炬是用轻钢制成的。它的下半部分重现了塞纳河的流动，开幕式将沿着塞纳河举行，届时将有50多万观众观看。</p>
<p>Lehanneur said he wants the torch to represent the kind of event that Paris 2024 hopes to be. "I wanted to move away from the torch appearing as an object of conquest," Lehanneur said.<br/>
勒汉纽尔表示，他希望火炬能呈现2024年巴黎奥运会所希望的那种活动。勒汉纽尔表示：“我想摆脱火炬被视为征服对象的形象。”</p>
<p>He also told reporters that designing the torch was much more technical than he thought it would be. "The magic is not the torch itself, but the flame," Lehanneur said.<br/>
他还告诉记者，火炬的设计比他想象的更有技术性。勒汉纽尔表示：““神奇的不是火炬本身，而是火焰。”</p>
<p>The torch will begin burning in Olympia, Greece, where the first Olympics were held, on April 16. The Games will begin in Paris on July 26, 2024.<br/>
火炬将于明年4月16日在首届奥运会举办地希腊奥林匹亚点燃。这届奥运会将于2024年7月26日在巴黎开幕。</p>
<p>On May 8, the torch will arrive in the Mediterranean city of Marseille. It will then pass through several important places, which include Strasbourg, the Pantheon in Paris, the Mont Saint-Michel and multiple French territories.<br/>
明年5月8日，火炬将抵达地中海城市马赛。然后，它将经过几个重要的地方，包括斯特拉斯堡、巴黎万神殿、圣米歇尔山和多处法国领土。</p>
<p>Tony Estanguet, the Paris 2024 chief, said the torch is "very, very beautiful." He also said it is "...very pure. It's perfectly balanced in the hand."<br/>
2024年巴黎奥运会主席托尼·埃斯坦盖表示，火炬“非常、非常美丽”。他还表示，火炬“非常纯净。它在手中完美地平衡。”</p>
<p>I'm Dominic Varela. And I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是多米尼克·瓦雷拉。我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate vs. Environment  (2023/7/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/climate-vs-environment.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there. This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "environment" and "climate."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Hello, VOA learning English, </span></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-597f-08db8eb831f3_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p><span style="color:#242424">My name is Sukhwant, and I am from India. I have a question about the difference between "environment" and "climate." </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Thank you so much,</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Sukhwant</span></p>
<p><strong>Answer: </strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Thank you, Sukhwant, for this important question!</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">"Climate" is part of the "environment." Let's look at the meanings of each.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Let's start with "environment."</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#242424">Environment</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">"Environment" has many meanings. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Your "environment" can be everything that surrounds you. Different conditions and objects make up your environment. </span></p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">My home environment is a peaceful place that includes my husband and my pets. </span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">"Environment" can also be social and cultural elements that contribute to your life or a community.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">The phrase "nature or <strong>nurture</strong>" describes the debate about whether your biology or your environment shapes you. </span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">When we are talking about science, the "environment" is all the physical, biological and chemical conditions around you. The "environment" includes things like climate, geography, <strong>diversity </strong>of plants and animals and many other things. The environment affects the condition and survival of the things within it. And those things, likewise, affect the environment. </span></p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">Deserts are environments with land features like sand or dry ground and extreme temperatures of hot and cold. </span></em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">We must protect our environment.</span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Note that the word "environment" can be used in specific professions like computer science and linguistics, or the study of language. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Let's move onto "climate." </span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#242424">Climate </span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">"Climate" has several different meanings. In science, "climate" is the overall weather <strong>pattern</strong> for an area over time. Climate includes amounts of rain and snow, temperatures and other weather conditions. Climate is part of the environment. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">"Climate" also can describe an area that has a certain kind of climate.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">She moved to the southern US last year for the warmer climate. </span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">And lastly, "climate" can mean a general atmosphere or situation in a place or period.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="color:#242424">The political climate of 1950s in the United States was marked by fears about the spread of communism. </span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:#242424">Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you,</span><span style="color:#242424"> Sukhwant.</span></p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? <span style="color:#242424">Send us an email </span><span style="color:black">at </span><a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a><span style="color:black">.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black">And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</span></p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong><span style="color:#222f3a">nurture </span></strong><em><span style="color:#222f3a">– v. </span></em><span style="color:#222f3a">to take care of, feed and protect someone or something, especially young children or plants</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#222f3a">diversity </span></strong><em><span style="color:#222f3a">– adj. </span></em><span style="color:#222f3a">characteristics or qualities that are different</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#222f3a">pattern </span></strong><span style="color:#222f3a">– <em>n. </em>the regular and repeated way in which something happens or is done</span></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI Method Creates Six Language Versions of K-Pop Song  (2023/7/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/ai-method-creates-six-language-versions-of-k-pop-song.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>A South Korean music production company is using a method of artificial intelligence (AI) to create different language versions of pop music songs.</p>
<p>The company using the method is HYBE. The company represents and produces music for some of South Korea's top pop music performers. Korean pop music is also known as K-pop.</p>
<p>The AI method combines voice recordings of South Korean pop stars with recordings of song <strong>lyrics</strong> read by native speakers of other languages. The process aims to produce complete K-pop songs in multiple languages.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="HYBE IM President Chung Wooyong speaks during an interview with Reuters at a company office in Seoul, South Korea, June 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-55b9-08db8939f978_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">HYBE IM President Chung Wooyong speaks during an interview with Reuters at a company office in Seoul, South Korea, June 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)</span></div>
<p>Officials at HYBE say the method does not change the singer's natural voice. Instead, it uses AI to produce different language versions of the same song.</p>
<p>In May, the AI method successfully created a song by K-pop singer MIDNATT in six languages – Korean, English, Spanish, Chinese, Japanese and Vietnamese. The 40-year-old artist, whose real name is Lee Hyun, recorded the song <em>Masquerade</em> in each language.</p>
<p>Chung Wooyong is the head of HYBE's interactive media department. He explained the creation process to reporters with Reuters news agency. He said the process involved dividing groups of sounds into separate elements. These included things like <strong>pronunciation</strong>, voice <strong>tone</strong> and sound level.</p>
<p>Wooyong added that the technical team's members then "used their imagination" to see what kind of results they could get from the technology. HYBE says the "deep learning" method permitted a first in the music industry – releasing the same song in multiple languages at the same time.</p>
<p>The song is the latest sign of the growing influence of AI in the music industry. AI-produced music has been flooding online music services and social media in recent months. The American-based Grammy Awards recently introduced new rules for AI-created music. In general, the rules aim to protect the music of "human creators" over works created by AI systems.</p>
<p>Wooyong said HYBE is currently considering how to use the AI method in its future music production operations. He noted the technology could be provided to other music creators and the public. Wooyong did not say whether the company would charge others to use the system in the future.</p>
<p>MIDNATT said using the AI method had given him a "wider <strong>spectrum</strong> of artistic expressions." He added, "I feel that the language barrier has been lifted and it's much easier for <strong>global</strong> fans to have an <strong>immersive</strong> experience with my music."</p>
<p>While the technology is not new, this method demonstrates a new way to use AI in music, said Valerio Velardo. He is the director of The Sound of AI, a Spain-based company that advises organizations on AI music and audio development.</p>
<p>Velardo added that he thinks such methods can help professional musicians and the general public in the future. "It's going to lower the barrier of music creation," he said. "It's a little bit like Instagram for pictures, but in the case of music."</p>
<p>For now, HYBE's AI method takes "weeks or months" to do its job, said <em>Masquerade</em> producer Choi Jin-woo, who also uses the name Hitchhiker. However, he noted that when the process speeds up, it could serve a wider range of purposes, such as <strong>interpreting</strong> languages in video conferences.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>lyrics </strong><em>– n. </em>the words of a song</p>
<p><strong>pronounce </strong><em>– v.</em> to make the sound of a letter or word</p>
<p><strong>tone </strong><em>– n. </em>the quality of a sound, especially someone's voice</p>
<p><strong>spectrum </strong><em>– n. </em>all the different ideas, opinions, possibilities, etc. that exist</p>
<p><strong>immersive </strong><em>– n. </em>completely surrounding something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Unrest in Niger Raises New Questions About Security in West Africa  (2023/7/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/unrest-in-niger-raises-new-questions-about-security-in-west-africa.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Wednesday's attempt by military members to seize power in Niger puts the West African country's security into question.</p>
<p>A group of soldiers said late Wednesday they had ousted democratically elected President Mohamed Bazoum.</p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday, however, the president's Twitter account released a message saying he and his family were safe. It said other military members planned to support the president.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Supporters of Nigerien President Mohamed Bazoum gather to show their support for him in Niamey on July 26, 2023. (Photo by AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/96ef9097-c9e4-44e5-b59c-71cb49dedb30_cx0_cy18_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Supporters of Nigerien President Mohamed Bazoum gather to show their support for him in Niamey on July 26, 2023. (Photo by AFP)</span></div>
<p>The leadership situation in Niger creates a question of what will happen to the West African country that is campaigning against religious extremism.</p>
<p>Western nations, including France and the U.S., have considered Niger to be a <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_0uvExBkM">democratic ally</a>. Both countries have about 1,000 soldiers in Niger. The soldiers are there to support the country if it is attacked by Islamic extremist fighters.</p>
<p>France has been active in the area, offering similar support to the nearby countries of Mali and Burkina Faso. The French soldiers, however, left Mali in late in 2022 after tensions with the country's military leadership.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State, Antony Blinken, visited Niger in March. He called the country a "model of democracy." Blinken announced $150 million in aid while he was there.</p>
<p><strong>Concern about western support</strong></p>
<p>The military leaders of Mali and Burkina Faso use the Russian Wagner Group for military support. The concern is that Niger will do something similar, removing any western influence from the area.</p>
<p>Paul Melly is an Africa expert at the Chatham House research group in London. Before the military action on Wednesday, he said Niger had been open to working with international partners. "So, quite a lot is at stake here," he added.</p>
<p>Melly pointed to one important difference between what is happening in Niger and other nations in the area whose leaders have been ousted.</p>
<p>In Guinea, Mali and Burkina Faso, the people on the streets supported the military <strong>coup</strong>. In Niger, Melly said, that was not what happened. People were supporting Bazoum, the president.</p>
<p><strong>Future of western positions</strong></p>
<p>Western nations are concerned about Niger because they have used the country as an operations base in actions against extremist fighters.</p>
<p>The concern is that a leadership change in Niger will limit what western countries can do to fight terrorist groups in West Africa and the Sahel. The Sahel is the area south of the Sahara Desert.</p>
<p>In 2021, the United States said it had supported Niger with over $500 million of military aid and training since 2012. Earlier in 2023, the European Union started a $30 million training program in Niger. The U.S. is known to have a <strong>drone</strong> base it uses to fight militant extremists in the northern part of Niger.</p>
<p>John Manley is a spokesman for the U.S. Africa Command. He said it is too soon to know how the coup attempt in Niger will affect U.S. activities in the country.</p>
<p><strong>Other African nations are worried</strong></p>
<p>Other African nations say they are worried that fighting in the northern part of West Africa will move south. Omar Touray is president of the ECOWAS Commission. ECOWAS is the economic group formed by 15 West African nations.</p>
<p>Touray recently told the United Nations that extremist fighting could move into Ghana and Ivory Coast if Niger loses western support. West African nations say there were about 1,800 extremist attacks this year resulting in almost 4,600 deaths – mostly in Burkina Faso and Niger.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>coup (d'état) </strong><em>–n. (diplomatic)</em> a sudden attempt by a small group to take over a government usually by force</p>
<p><strong>drone </strong><em>–n.</em> an unmanned aircraft</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar and Libraries  (2023/7/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/grammar-and-libraries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Imagine you are at a library – a place where books, movies, and other publications are available to borrow.</p>
<p>What kinds of terms and structures would you need to know in order to express yourself well at a library?</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore one possible answer to that question: phrasal verbs.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar - Library phrases" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9d1b-08db8eb47ad1_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar - Library phrases</span></div>
<p><strong>Definition </strong></p>
<p>Phrasal verbs are groups of words made up of a verb and another short word or words. Together, these groups of words mean something different from what the individual words suggest. As a result, you can think of phrasal verbs as kinds of special expressions.</p>
<p>We will now explore three phrasal verbs that connect to the library: look up, look for, and check out.</p>
<p><strong>Look up </strong></p>
<p>Our first phrasal verb is "look up." "Look up" means to search for something in a <strong>reference</strong> book, publication, or on the internet.</p>
<p>We often use a noun or noun phrase after "look up." For example, you might say:</p>
<p><em>I need to look up an <strong>article</strong>. </em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>I need to look up a news story.</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>I need to look up that word in the <strong>dictionary</strong>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Look for </strong></p>
<p>Our second phrasal verb is "look for." "Look for" means to try to find something or to search for something. "Look for" is often followed by a noun or noun phrase.</p>
<p>You might look for general things or specific things.</p>
<p>For example, if you wanted to find science <strong>fiction</strong> books at the library, you could say:</p>
<p><em>I am looking for science fiction books. </em></p>
<p>If you wanted to find an exact book, you might say something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am looking for "Dune" by Frank Herbert.</em></p>
<p><strong>Check out </strong></p>
<p>Our third phrasal verb is "check out." "Check out" means to borrow something from a library.</p>
<p>So, you might say:</p>
<p><em>I went to the library to check out new books. </em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>I checked out a book from the library. </em></p>
<p><strong>Combine </strong></p>
<p>So, we have our three phrasal verbs for the library: look up, look for, and check out.</p>
<p>We can think of these phrasal verbs as taking place in steps. Perhaps look up is step one, look for is step two, and check out is step three.</p>
<p>For example, you might look up book <strong>reviews</strong>. After you read a book review that covers an interesting book, you might look for the book itself. After you find the book, you might check out the book.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Imagine you have a book that you want to borrow from the library. How can you ask to borrow it? Use the phrasal verb "check out. "</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here is one answer:</p>
<p><em>Can I check out this book? </em></p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>In today's report, we explored some useful phrasal verbs for the library. There are other phrasal verbs for the library, but the three we explored today are probably the most common ones you will find.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story </strong></h2>
<p><strong>reference </strong><em>– adj.</em> used to find information about something</p>
<p><strong>article</strong><em> – n. </em>a piece of writing other than fiction or poetry that forms an independent part of a publication (as a magazine)</p>
<p><strong>fiction</strong> <em>– n.</em> something told or written that is not fact</p>
<p><strong>dictionary</strong> <em>– n.</em> a kind of reference book that has words listed in alphabetical order and that gives information about the words' meanings</p>
<p><strong>review</strong> <em>– n.</em> a critical evaluation (as of a book or play)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>News Organizations Team Up with AI Companies  (2023/7/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/news-organizations-team-up-with-ai-companies.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Several major news organizations have teamed up with artificial intelligence (AI) developers to find new tools to help <strong>journalists</strong> do their work.</p>
<p>AI developer OpenAI recently signed a deal with the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.theajp.org/">American Journalism Project</a> (AJP) to use AI tools to support local news across the United States. OpenAI is backed by American software maker Microsoft. The AJP is a nonprofit group that provides financial assistance to local nonprofit U.S. news organizations.</p>
<p>Late last year, OpenAI released an AI tool called ChatGPT. ChatGPT and other so-called "chatbots" have demonstrated the ability to lead human-like discussions and produce complex writing based on short, written commands. Such tools are also known as "generative AI" or "large language models."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The logo for OpenAI, the maker of ChatGPT, appears on a mobile phone, in New York, Tuesday, Jan. 31, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/800f0000-c0a8-0242-0191-08db03d3882b_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The logo for OpenAI, the maker of ChatGPT, appears on a mobile phone, in New York, Tuesday, Jan. 31, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>In its deal with the AJP, OpenAI promised to provide $5 million to expand the project's work and strengthen local journalism efforts. OpenAI is also offering the AJP an additional $5 million to help local news organizations deploy the latest AI tools.</p>
<p>Sarabeth Berman is head of the American Journalism Project. She <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.theajp.org/news-insights/announcements/american-journalism-project-announces-new-partnership-with-openai-to-support-local-news/">said in a statement</a> the cooperation with OpenAI aims to ensure that local news organizations can help shape the ways AI is used in journalism. Berman added, the partnership seeks to find ways for AI to improve journalism, "rather than <strong>imperil</strong>" it.</p>
<p>In addition, the partnership aims to support AJP's efforts to "create healthier information <strong>ecosystems</strong>" at the local level to fight misinformation in news. The deal will help create a <strong>studio</strong> that can be used by local news organizations to experiment with OpenAI's technology.</p>
<p>The AJP's deal with OpenAI is one of several partnerships recently established between AI developers and news organizations.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, OpenAI announced it had signed a deal with The Associated Press to <strong>license</strong> the news agency's collection of news stories. OpenAI will use AP's news stories to train and develop its chatbot tool. No financial details of the deal were announced.</p>
<p>In addition, the two companies said in a statement they are examining how the AP could use "generative AI in news products and services."</p>
<p>The deal came after the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC) informed OpenAI it had opened an investigation into whether the company had taken part in unfair business activities. The investigation reportedly centers on whether OpenAI violated trade rules by training its language model on publicly available data.</p>
<p>Some news organizations, book writers and other creative artists have brought legal actions or sought <strong>compensation</strong> from companies that used their works to train AI systems.</p>
<p>The AP said it currently does not use any generative AI in its news story production. But it has long used other forms of AI. This includes a system that <strong>automatically </strong>produces corporate earnings stories and some sports reports.</p>
<p>U.S.-based search engine Google also recently confirmed it was in talks with major news publishers about using a new AI tool it developed to help journalists report and write their stories. The project was first reported by <em>The New York Times. </em>The tool is being tested by the <em>Times</em>, as well as <em>The Washington Post</em> and <em>The Wall Street Journal</em>, the French news agency AFP reported.</p>
<p>The <em>Times</em> said the AI tool – which Google calls Genesis – was still in early form testing. However, a demonstration of the system reportedly left newspaper officials "unsettled" when they saw the tool's abilities.</p>
<p>A Google spokeswoman confirmed in a statement the company had held discussions with news publishers on providing AI-based tools "to help their journalists with their work." The tool being tested was designed to do things like help journalists choose <strong>headlines</strong> and write in different <strong>styles</strong>, the <em>Times</em> reported.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman added that such tools were not meant to "replace the <strong>essential</strong> role journalists have in reporting, creating and fact-checking" their stories.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, AFP and the American Journalism Project. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>journalist </strong><em>– n. </em>someone who writes and reports news stories</p>
<p><strong>imperil </strong><em>– v.</em> to put someone or something in a dangerous situation</p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong><em>– n. </em>all the living things in an area and the way they affect each other and the environment</p>
<p><strong>studio </strong>–n. a place where video or movies are produced; a place where creative work is done</p>
<p><strong>license </strong><em>– v. </em>to give someone official permission to do or have something</p>
<p><strong>compensate </strong><em>– v. </em>to give money or something of value in return for some action, <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_l3mEW060">loss</a> or damage</p>
<p><strong>automatic </strong><em>– adj.</em> something controlled using machines and not people</p>
<p><strong>headline </strong><em>– n. </em>the title of a newspaper story that is printed in large letters above it</p>
<p><strong>style </strong><em>– n. </em><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_219Yt0n8">a way</a> or method of doing something</p>
<p><strong>essential </strong><em>– adj.</em> completely necessary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russians Can Qualify for Some Paris Olympic Events, Not Others  (2023/7/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/russians-can-qualify-for-some-paris-olympic-events-not-others.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>A year before the Paris Olympic Games, officials overseeing many of the sports on the 2024 program have not agreed on how to treat Russian <strong>athletes</strong>.</p>
<p>Increasingly, different governing bodies are permitting Russian athletes to take part in Olympic competitions as neutral competitors without their national flag or <strong>anthem</strong>.</p>
<p>At first, most Olympic sports barred Russians from competing soon after Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Russian flag is held above the Olympic Rings at Adler Arena Skating Center during the Winter Olympics in Sochi, Russia on Feb. 18, 2014. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e1ba1263-a26d-4ab8-9288-c42e26055728_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Russian flag is held above the Olympic Rings at Adler Arena Skating Center during the Winter Olympics in Sochi, Russia on Feb. 18, 2014. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)</span></div>
<p>The International Olympic Committee (IOC) says it strongly supports those moves although the body says it has not decided if athletes from Russia and Belarus can compete at the Paris Games. However, the IOC has delayed action on the one sport whose <strong>qualification</strong> it controls: boxing.</p>
<p>Most of the sports that have permitted Russians to return followed IOC advice on what to call Russian athletes. They call them "individual <strong>neutral</strong> athletes." The sports groups are continuing to ban Russians who are under contract with the Russian military. They also ban athletes who have publicly supported the war in Ukraine. The IOC also suggests blocking Russia from team sports like soccer or basketball.</p>
<p>Ukraine is opposed to any Russians competing. Since last year, Ukrainian athletes and national teams have not been competing in events permitting Russians. The Ukrainian government banned its athletes in team sports to compete against Russian teams. Ukraine supporters have been <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_V53iCtW6">looking</a> through Russian athletes' social media accounts for pro-war posts that could disqualify them from competing.</p>
<p>Here is what the Associated Press says about the situation in a few major Olympic sports:</p>
<p><strong>Track and field</strong></p>
<p>The sports group World Athletics governs track and field sports. It banned athletes from Russia and Belarus from competitions after the invasion of Ukraine. That ban remains in place "for the <strong>foreseeable</strong> future," after a vote of the World Athletics governing group in March. President Sebastian Coe said at the time that deaths and destruction in Ukraine have only "hardened" the decision to keep a ban in place.</p>
<p><strong>Swimming</strong></p>
<p>World Aquatics is the group that governs swimming. It is one of the sports taking Russia's return slowly. It has said it favors Russia and Belarus returning to its different sports, but it set up a group to study the issue, which will report in late July. That means no Russians can compete at the world championships this month in Japan.</p>
<p><strong>Tennis</strong></p>
<p>Men's and women's tennis permits individual Russian or Belarusian players. But the sport punished some competitions, including Wimbledon, which enforced restrictions.</p>
<p>Ukrainian players continue to compete but often do not shake hands with Russians or Belarusians. Aryna Sabalenka is from Belarus. She won the Australian Open in January. She also has been questioned about her past support for Belarus' <strong>authoritarian</strong> leader, President Alexander Lukashenko. She has said she does not support the war.</p>
<p>Russian and Belarusian players are barred from national team competitions like the Davis Cup and Billie Jean King Cup. The International Tennis Federation has not made a final decision on the Olympics. But it has a lot of time because qualification is decided by the June 2024 world positions.</p>
<p><strong>Gymnastics</strong></p>
<p>Those that compete in the sport gymnastics from Russia and Belarus will be permitted to take part in <strong>sanctioned</strong> competitions as "individual neutral athletes" from the start of 2024.</p>
<p>The world Championships are to be held in early October in Belgium.</p>
<p>Russian gymnasts have been some of the loudest supporters of the war. Days after the invasion, Ivan Kuliak wore a pro-war "Z" <strong>symbol </strong>on a competition stand while next to a Ukrainian athlete. He was suspended for a year. Other Russian gymnasts appeared on stage at an event to support the war. And Olympic gold medalist Nikita Nagornyy heads a military youth organization in Russia.</p>
<p><strong>Team Sports</strong></p>
<p>The IOC supports banning Russia from team sports and no Olympic sport has gone against that decision. The IOC also suggests a ban on "team events in individual sports" like the team all-around in gymnastics.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em><span style="color:black">Gregory Stachel adapted this story based on reporting from Voice of America.</span></em></p>
<p><span style="color:black">________________________________________________</span></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></strong></h2>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">athlete </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> a person who is trained in or good at sports, games, or exercises that require physical skill and strength</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">anthem </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> a song that praises a particular country and that is officially accepted as the country's song</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">qualify </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>v. </em>to give (someone) the right to do, have, or be a part of something</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">foreseeable </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>v.</em> to see or become aware of (something that has not yet happened)</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">authoritarian </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>adj.</em> expecting or requiring people to obey rules or laws: not allowing personal freedom</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">sanction </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>v.</em> to officially accept or allow (something)</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:black">symbol </span></strong><span style="color:black">– <em>n.</em> a letter, group of letters, character, or picture that is used instead of a word or group of words</span></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Hot Seawater in South Florida Reaches New High  (2023/7/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/scientists-hot-seawater-in-south-florida-reaches-new-high.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists say that a body of water at the southern end of Florida reached a new high temperature of over 38 degrees Celsius early this week.</p>
<p>Weather scientists, called meteorologists, say they measured the high seawater temperatures in Manatee Bay on both Sunday and Monday. They believe the water temperature may be the world's highest ever recorded. A floating device that sends information to the U.S. weather agency, NOAA, recorded the temperature.</p>
<p>A 2020 study showed that Kuwait Bay reached 37.6 degrees Celsius. That was thought to be the highest-ever water temperature.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provide by NOAA, shows a dead coral at Cheeca Rocks off the coast of Islamorada, Fla., on July 23, 2023. (Andrew Ibarra/NOAA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/d75db3b0-9797-4587-b9b9-030834995f46_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provide by NOAA, shows a dead coral at Cheeca Rocks off the coast of Islamorada, Fla., on July 23, 2023. (Andrew Ibarra/NOAA via AP)</span></div>
<p>Jeff <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_8qDsErCW">Masters</a> is a meteorologist with Yale Climate Connections, a weather news service. "This is a hot tub," he said. A hot tub is a heated water pool many people use for treating sore muscles. Jacuzzi, a company that makes hot tubs, recommends a water temperature of about 38 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_QOcI2S4t">Masters</a> and Brian McNoldy, a meteorologist at the University of Miami, both said the temperatures might not be an official record because the water is close to land and contains sea grass.</p>
<p>However, McNoldy said, "it's <strong>amazing</strong>."</p>
<p>The high temperatures could put sea life, such as coral, in danger.</p>
<p>Andrew Ibarra is a researcher for NOAA. He took a small boat out to the area called Cheeca Rocks to look at coral and said, "I found that the <strong>entire</strong> reef was bleached out."</p>
<p>Bleaching is when coral loses its color. It is a sign that the sea creatures are in danger of dying.</p>
<p>Ian Enochs studies coral for NOAA. He said coral bleaching was almost never seen before the 1980s. Now, he said, "We've reached the point where it's become <strong>routine</strong>."</p>
<p>Enochs added that the amount of bleaching he sees this early in the year makes him "nervous."</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_G3M5y4eV">high water</a> temperature in Florida goes along with all-time high sea surface temperatures in April, <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_Y4aOkRht">May</a> and June. NOAA also said water temperatures in the North Atlantic, near the Canadian <strong>province</strong> of Newfoundland are five to six degrees Celsius warmer than usual.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_qoU4bhBY"><strong>coral</strong></a> <em>–n. </em>very small organisms that live together and form a system along the seabed that supports other marine life</p>
<p><strong>amazing </strong>–<em>adj</em>. very impressive, worthy of admiration or notice</p>
<p><strong>entire </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>all of something</p>
<p><strong>routine</strong> <em>–adj. </em>usual or normal</p>
<p><strong>province</strong> <em>–n. </em>a governmental region in some nations, similar to a state</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The European Union Approves Spending Plan for Computer Chips  (2023/7/27) | 欧盟通过计算机芯片开支法案</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/the-european-union-approves-spending-plan-for-computer-chips.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The European Council gave final approval Tuesday to the European Parliament's plan to expand semiconductor production in Europe.<br/>
欧洲理事会星期二最终批准了欧洲议会扩大欧洲半导体生产的计划。</p>
<p>Semiconductors are computer chips which are important for everything from washing machines to cars.<br/>
半导体是指计算机芯片，它对从洗衣机到汽车的所有物品都很重要。</p>
<p>The EU's new law supports its larger aim of decreasing its dependence on Asian manufacturers for computer chips.<br/>
欧盟的新法律是为了支撑其减少对亚洲计算机芯片制造商依赖的更大目标。</p>
<p>The EU's Chips Act will provide $47 billion in public and private funds and permit state aid for Europe's semiconductor industry.<br/>
欧盟的《芯片法案》将提供470亿美元的公共和私人资金，并允许国家为欧洲半导体行业提供资助。</p>
<p>EU leaders want to make money available for new semiconductor manufacturing. The EU's goal is to double the 27-nation group's share of the world's semiconductor production to 20 percent by 2030.<br/>
欧盟领导人希望为新的半导体制造业提供资金。欧盟的目标是到2030年前将这个27国家集团在世界半导体产量中的份额翻一番，达到20%。</p>
<p>Asia produces most of the world's semiconductors. The important part Asian chipmakers play became clear during the COVID-19 pandemic. Western manufacturers blamed problems with supply chains for shortages of cars, smartphones, and medical devices.<br/>
亚洲生产世界上大部分的半导体。在新冠肺炎疫情期间，亚洲芯片制造商发挥的重要作用变得明显。西方制造商将汽车、智能手机和医疗设备短缺归咎于供应链问题。</p>
<p>Governments in Europe and North America are now trying to balance their use of suppliers. The U.S. launched its own $52 billion Chips Act, and Britain has a smaller $1.2 billion chip plan. Companies like Intel have announced large expansion plans for Europe.<br/>
欧洲和北美的政府现在正试图平衡他们对供应商的使用。美国出台了其价值520亿美元的芯片法案，英国出台了一个规模较小的价值12亿美元的芯片计划。像英特尔这样的公司已经宣布了在欧洲的大规模扩张计划。</p>
<p>The EU Chips Act will take effect after it is published in the Official Journal of the European Union.<br/>
《欧盟芯片法案》将在《欧盟官方公报》上发表后生效。</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.<br/>
我是吉尔·罗宾斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Hollywood Strike, AI’s Part Is Important  (2023/7/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/in-hollywood-strike-ai-s-part-is-important.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Labor unions for actors and writers are striking over pay, <strong>benefits</strong> and job protections. But Artificial intelligence technology has become a big issue in Hollywood's labor fight.</p>
<p>AI has introduced a new point of disagreement between artists and production companies. Here is a look at what both sides say they want.</p>
<p><strong>Why is AI such an important issue?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Members of the The Writers Guild of America picket outside Fox Studios on Tuesday, May 2, 2023, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Ashley Landis, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f774-08db8d411d6e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Members of the The Writers Guild of America picket outside Fox Studios on Tuesday, May 2, 2023, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Ashley Landis, File)</span></div>
<p>With AI, star actors fear they will lose control of their <strong>likenesses</strong>. Unknown actors fear they will be replaced altogether. Writers fear they will have to share credit with or lose credit to machines.</p>
<p>The proposed <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_WV5r2OMR">contracts</a> which the two sides have been attempting to negotiate is to last only three years. Even at the speed at which AI technology is developing, it is unlikely there would be a large displacement of writers or actors within that period of time. But unions and employers know that if they compromise on an issue, it will be harder to get what they want in the next set of negotiations.</p>
<p>New technology is important to filmmaking. AI has been used to make actors look younger, like Harrison Ford in the recent film <em>Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny</em>.</p>
<p>All sides in the strike know that use of new technology will continue to increase. That is why both sides are looking to establish legal and creative control.</p>
<p><strong>The actors' view</strong><br/>
<br/>
Actors in the labor discussions are represented by the Screen Actors Guild–American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA). The Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers (AMPTP) represents the production companies, which are the employers. The strike started on July 13.</p>
<p>SAG-AFTRA released an opinion of the studios' position on the use of AI and their images. The group said the production companies want "...to <strong>scan</strong> a background performer's image, pay them for a half a day's labor, and then use an individual's likeness for any purpose forever without their <strong>consent."</strong></p>
<p>The union also said employers want "...to be able to make changes to...<strong>dialogue</strong>, and even create new <strong>scenes</strong>, without informed consent."</p>
<p>The AMPTP said in a statement that its offers included an "AI proposal which protects performers' digital likenesses, including a requirement for performers' consent for the creation...of a performance."</p>
<p>SAG-AFTRA said it wants to protect "human-created work" including changes to the "voice, likeness or performance" of an actor.</p>
<p>Observers say that "voice" comes first on that list for a reason. AI voice technology might be more developed than visual technology. For example, the voices of the late Anthony Bourdain and the late Andy Warhol have both been recreated for recent films.</p>
<p><strong>Writers want credit</strong></p>
<p>During the writers' contract talks, which broke down in early May, the Writers Guild of America (WGA) said it did not oppose the use of AI. But AI should only be used as a tool to use in a writer's own work.</p>
<p>The union said writers might be willing to shape stories with help from AI software. But they did not want it to affect the credits that influence their position and pay.</p>
<p>The WGA wants to prevent entirely AI-created stories or dialogue from being considered "literary material<span style="color:black">." This means they would not be competing with computers for credit.</span></p>
<p>The AMPTP said in a document explaining its position that writers "want to be able to use this technology as part of their creative process, without changing how credits are determined, which is complicated given AI material can't be <strong>copyrighted</strong>."</p>
<p>"Only a ‘person' can be considered a writer," the AMPTP added. "AI-generated material would not be <strong>eligible</strong> for writing credit."</p>
<p>This position could calm writers' worries about sharing credit with AI. But it could also lead to no one getting credit when they use AI.</p>
<p>Modern movie writing contracts are very complex and hard to understand. So is the question of who receives credit for the work. Observers say adding AI makes the problem even more difficult.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em><span style="color:black">Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Reuters and The Associated Press.</span></em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em><span style="color:black">_______________________________________</span></em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong><span style="color:black">Words in This Story</span></strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">benefit </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em><span style="color:black">things received in addition to pay that employers offer to employees</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_bmDvfzEn"><strong><span style="color:black">likeness </span></strong></a><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. </span></em><span style="color:black">a picture or image of any kind of a person</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scan </strong>–v. to digitally capture the image of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_QpJv9H7z"><strong><span style="color:black">consent </span></strong></a><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. </span></em><span style="color:black">permission that is given by a person old enough and able to give it</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong><span style="color:black">dialogue </span></strong><em><span style="color:black">— n. </span></em><span style="color:black">speech that appears in performances like movies, plays and shows</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scene </strong>–n. a division of a movie, play or performance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_W6qwPPYs"><strong><span style="color:black">copyright </span></strong></a><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> n. </span></em><span style="color:black">the legal right to be able to reproduce, publish and sell recordings, books, <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_MAvybKIQ">movies</a> and other performances</span></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_Lo7CFSfQ"><strong><span style="color:black">eligible </span></strong></a><em><span style="color:black">—</span></em><em><span style="color:black"> adj. </span></em><span style="color:black">able to do or receive something under an agreement<em> </em></span></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korean Court Overturns Removal of Minister over Deadly Crowd Crush  (2023/7/26) | 韩国法院推翻部长因踩踏事件所受弹劾</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/south-korean-court-overturns-removal-of-minister-over-deadly-crowd-crush.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>South Korea's top court has overturned a parliamentary vote that removed the country's public safety minister over a deadly crowd incident in October.<br/>
韩国最高法院推翻了国会因去年10月发生的一起致命踩踏事件而罢免该国公共安全部长的投票。</p>
<p>The Constitutional Court ruled Tuesday to lift the impeachment of Lee Sang-min. Lee was serving as South Korea's Minister of the Interior and Safety when 159 people were crushed to death in a densely packed crowd during a Halloween celebration last October in Seoul.<br/>
韩国宪法法院星期二裁定撤销对李相民的弹劾。去年10月在首尔举行的万圣节庆祝活动中，有159人在密集人流中被踩踏致死，当时李相民正担任韩国内政安全部部长。</p>
<p>The court's decision permits Lee to return to his position, which had been filled by an acting minister. South Korea's opposition-controlled parliament voted in February to impeach Lee. Legislators sought to hold him responsible for the government's failure to put in place effective crowd control measures.<br/>
该法院裁决允许李相民官复原职，该职位之前由代理部长担任。韩国反对派控制的国会在2月投票弹劾了李相民。国会议员试图追究他对政府未能采取有效措施控制人流的责任。</p>
<p>In its rejection of Lee's impeachment, the Constitutional Court suggested that he alone could not be held responsible for the crowd crush. The court said it had not found enough evidence to prove that Lee had failed to carry out his legal and constitutional duties to protect the public's safety.<br/>
宪法法院在驳回对李相民的弹劾时表示，不能仅由他对人群踩踏事件负责。法院表示，没有找到足够的证据证明李相民未履行其保护公众安全的法律和宪法职责。</p>
<p>Instead, the court blamed a number of different government agencies for failing to "develop a combined ability to respond to large-scale disasters."<br/>
相反，法院指责另一些政府机构未能“发挥应对大规模灾难的综合能力”。</p>
<p>The 58-year-old Lee is considered an important ally of conservative President Yoon Suk Yeol. The president's office welcomed the court's decision. Yoon had rejected calls from opposition politicians to remove Lee as minister.<br/>
现年58岁的李相民被认为是保守派总统尹锡悦的重要盟友。总统办公室对法院的裁决表示欢迎。尹锡悦此前拒绝了反对党政客要求解除李相民部长职务的呼吁。</p>
<p>Relatives of people who died in the crowd crush criticized the court. The mother of victim Park Ga-young called the ruling "truly devastating." She told Reuters news agency, "Our children, young people, are living in a place that isn't safe to even walk in."<br/>
踩踏事件遇难者亲属批评了宪法法院。受害者Park Ga-young的母亲称这一裁决“真的是毁灭性的”。她告诉路透社，“我们的孩子，年轻人，生活在一个连走路都不安全的地方。”</p>
<p>In a statement released by his ministry, Lee expressed support to accident victims and their families. But he said it was time to end "wasteful political bickering" over the incident.<br/>
在韩国内政安全部发布的一份声明中，李相民对事故受害者及其家属表达了支持。但他表示，现在是时候结束针对这一事件的“浪费性政治争吵”了。</p>
<p>An investigation into the incident found that police and local officials in Seoul's Yongsan district had failed to plan effective crowd control measures before the Halloween celebration took place.<br/>
对这起事件的调查发现，首尔龙山区的警察和地方官员未能在万圣节庆祝活动之前制定有效的人流控制措施。</p>
<p>Investigators found that police had ignored calls placed by people warning of growing crowds before the incident late on October 29. The investigation also found mistakes were made during emergency response measures during the celebration.<br/>
调查人员发现，在10月29日晚些时候的事件发生之前，警方忽视了人们发出的人流激增的警告电话。调查还发现，庆祝期间的应急措施存在失误。</p>
<p>Police have brought criminal charges against 23 officials over the lack of crowd controls and safety measures. About half of those charged are law enforcement officers.<br/>
警方已对23名官员提出刑事指控，指控他们缺乏人流控制和安全措施。被指控者中约有一半是执法人员。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers, Lawmakers Debate Carbon Markets  (2023/7/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/researchers-lawmakers-debate-carbon-markets.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Agricultural emissions are getting more attention from U.S. officials, researchers, and industry professionals. One big area of debate is the link between carbon storage and carbon markets.</p>
<p><strong>New Policies </strong></p>
<p>Last week, the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) announced a $300 million investment to monitor agricultural emissions. The investment will help create a research group to monitor carbon levels in soil.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Shalamar Armstrong, associate professor of agronomy at Purdue University, holds a shovel full of soil, Thursday, July 13, 2023, in Fowler, Ind. (AP Photo/Joshua A. Bickel)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6ad56b02-d309-494b-9217-c2508c30ac37_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Shalamar Armstrong, associate professor of agronomy at Purdue University, holds a shovel full of soil, Thursday, July 13, 2023, in Fowler, Ind. (AP Photo/Joshua A. Bickel)</span></div>
<p>American lawmakers also proposed a measure to support research needed to "properly credit soil carbon storage."</p>
<p>The USDA announcement and the law are both aimed at the difficult question of how to measure carbon stored in soil. The issue is important if the young soil carbon market is to avoid the opposition directed at current carbon credit markets.</p>
<p><strong>Carbon storage </strong></p>
<p>The Congressional Research Services describes a carbon market as an economic idea "that supports the buying and selling of environmental <strong>commodities</strong> that <strong>signify</strong> GHG (greenhouse gas) emission reductions" or storage.</p>
<p>The general idea is that some kinds of farming methods can support carbon storage. As a result, some farmers can get money in the form of carbon offsets — payments that companies can make that support carbon storage in farms.</p>
<p>Shalamar Armstrong is an associate professor at Purdue University in West Lafayette, Indiana. "The more carbon you store from the atmosphere with your crops, and the more crops grown throughout the year, you offset some of your waste," he said. The carbon that was stored would have instead been released into the atmosphere, he explained.</p>
<p>But much about carbon storage remains unknown.</p>
<p>"The science piece (of carbon credits) has really <strong>lagged</strong> behind, particularly when it comes to things like monitoring, reporting and <strong>verification</strong>," said Cristel Zoebisch, a policy director at climate organization Carbon180.</p>
<p>Armstrong has been trying to help fix the problem of measuring carbon storage. He runs a lab where researchers are investigating how farming method affects the amount of carbon in soil across different kinds of land. He and others at Purdue have been studying soil samples that date back more than 40 years.</p>
<p>He hopes his findings will help farmers make decisions that could result in earnings from storing carbon and without losing any crop profit.</p>
<p><strong>Carbon markets </strong></p>
<p>But other experts worry that even if farmers do get paid for storing soil carbon, bigger issues remain.</p>
<p>Carbon offsets in the U.S. have to meet four conditions. They have to store carbon that would otherwise be released. The offsets also have to be verifiable in data, immediate and long-lasting, said John Sterman, a professor at Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</p>
<p>Carbon storage research might make the offsets more verifiable, but such research does not deal with other problems.</p>
<p>For example, many American farmers do not own the land on which they grow crops. As a result, these farmers cannot guarantee that carbon stored on their land will stay in place if someone else works the same property.</p>
<p>Barbara Haya of the Berkeley Carbon Trading Project at University of California, Berkeley, says the research she has worked on shows that the effects of carbon offset projects are commonly overestimated. Carbon trading has, in her words, "failed miserably" over the last 20 years. She advises moving away from the process.</p>
<p>Jared Huffman, a lawmaker in the U.S. House of Representatives, last month proposed a bill to support farmers in making improvements to soil health. He said farmers in the area he represents would be interested in entering carbon markets with strong accounting systems. But he added that those hoping for serious climate action should not depend only on offsets.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Melina Walling reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in The Story </strong></h2>
<p><strong>commodity</strong> <em>– n.</em> something that is bought and sold</p>
<p><strong>signify</strong> <em>– v.</em> to be a sign of (something) : to mean (something)</p>
<p><strong>lag</strong><em>– v.</em> to be in a position that is behind others</p>
<p><strong>verify</strong> <em>– v. </em>to prove, show, find out, or state that (something) is true or correct</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Early Literacy: Print Awareness  (2023/7/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/early-literacy-print-awareness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Words are all around us and not just in books. Students need to know that words have meaning. Educators call this print awareness. At this early stage,<strong> </strong>surround learners with English words and sounds.</p>
<p>Experts say that students who cannot read in their own language may not understand some literacy ideas. They need to be taught about the <strong>functions</strong> of print.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Early Literacy: Print Awareness" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-3d91-08db40586daf_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Early Literacy: Print Awareness</span></div>
<p><strong>Teaching tips for print awareness</strong></p>
<p><u>Bring in common items with written language – both the home language and English.</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Bring in calendars, food packages, magazines, mail, maps, and newspapers. Talk about these items. Compare English words with words from the home language.</li>
<li>Create fun activities with the items. For example, as an art project students can make a birthday card for a friend or family member. They could also make their own food product and make packaging for it.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Post words in your classroom.</u></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Label</strong> common objects in the classroom.</li>
<li>Post words to songs and poems.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Post the names and birthdays of students in the classroom.</li>
<li>Hang colorful <strong>posters</strong> with English words on the walls.</li>
</ul>
<p><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_KFE8OaWU"><u>Read</u></a><u> often to your class. </u></p>
<p>Read books that:</p>
<ul>
<li>fit the age and English level of your students.</li>
<li>repeat simple and useful sentences and words.</li>
<li>have limited text on a page with pictures explaining the text.</li>
<li>have active stories.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Make reading aloud fun and active!</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Ask questions about the story. Talk about important words or ideas. But do not stop too often. Students may lose interest in the story.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Use fun voices, facial expressions, music, objects, and pictures to make the story come to life.</li>
<li>Make connections to real life. Ask them, "Has this happened to you?"</li>
<li>Have students retell the story or change the story somehow.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Teach the parts of a book and different types of books.</u></p>
<p>As you read to your students, teach the parts of a book. Talk about different types of books.</p>
<ul>
<li>Explain the purpose of a book's title and where it is found.</li>
<li>Point out the names of the author and illustrator. Explain their jobs.</li>
<li>Show students the page numbers. Explain why pages are numbered.</li>
<li>Use many different books such as comics and picture books.</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Talk about different part of the story.</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Who is the story about (who are the <strong>characters</strong>)?</li>
<li>Where does the story take place (the <strong>setting</strong>)?</li>
<li>Talk about the problem and the solution. How do characters fix the problem?</li>
</ul>
<p><u>Teach <strong>punctuation</strong> when you read with your students.</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Point out periods, exclamation points, and question marks. Explain what they do.</li>
<li>Show how punctuation changes the meaning of a sentence.</li>
<li>Read a sentence with a period and then with an exclamation point with excitement!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Assessment for print awareness</strong></p>
<p>Early learners may not have print awareness. To assess or test for print awareness, give a student a book and ask questions. Here are some examples:</p>
<ul>
<li>Where is the title of the book?</li>
<li>Can you show me the author's name?</li>
<li>Where does the story begin?</li>
<li>Can you show me <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_tDoBBxJ4">a letter</a>? A word? A sentence?</li>
<li>Can you find the first and last words of a sentence?</li>
<li>Can you show me a punctuation mark? What does a question mark do?</li>
<li>Can you show me a capital letter? Can you show me a lowercase letter?</li>
</ul>
<p>Use the tips, strategies, and assessment methods that best serve you and your learners. Change methods to fit your students' abilities and the teaching situation.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>And I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this article for VOA Learning English. It is part of a larger collection of Early Literacy Materials.</em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>function </strong><em>–n.</em> the special purpose that something has or work that it does</p>
<p><strong>label</strong> <em>–v.</em> to put an object's name and information on it to show what it is</p>
<p><strong>poster </strong><em>–n.</em> a large sign or picture meant to gain attention</p>
<p><strong>character </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who appears in a story, play or movie</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_UZWMVh1t"><strong>setting </strong></a><em>–n.</em> where a story takes place</p>
<p><strong>punctuation </strong><em>–n.</em> markings that make it clear how to separate sentences and parts of sentences, so reading is easier</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Twitter Introduces New ‘X’ Logo to Replace Blue Bird  (2023/7/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/twitter-introduces-new-x-logo-to-replace-blue-bird.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Twitter owner Elon Musk has launched a new <strong>logo </strong>– the single letter "X" – to replace the social media service's famous blue bird.</p>
<p>The X design started appearing at the top of Twitter's computer version on Monday. But the old bird logo could still be seen across areas of the service.</p>
<p>Musk announced in a Twitter message Sunday that he had decided to change the company's logo. He said he had asked his millions of followers to provide logo ideas and if they would favor a change in the service's colors from blue to black.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A view of a lap top and monitors showing the Twitter signing in page displaying the new logo, in Belgrade, Serbia, Monday, July 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Darko Vojinovic)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2b0e-08db8c85b51b_cx2_cy0_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A view of a lap top and monitors showing the Twitter signing in page displaying the new logo, in Belgrade, Serbia, Monday, July 24, 2023. (AP Photo/Darko Vojinovic)</span></div>
<p>When asked what tweets would be called without the blue bird logo, Musk said they would now be known as "Xs."</p>
<p>The latest change is one in a series Musk has carried out since buying Twitter for $44 billion last year.</p>
<p>The billionaire businessman dismissed about 75 percent of the company's workforce soon after the deal closed. Musk said the move was necessary to make Twitter more effective and increase profits. He also announced plans to start charging Twitter users eight dollars a month to keep a <strong>verified</strong> account.</p>
<p>As Twitter chief, Musk also lifted some existing restrictions on user <strong>content</strong>. He said those changes were part of a larger effort to protect the free speech of Twitter users. Critics said his plans were likely to increase the amount of harmful content and hate speech appearing on the service.</p>
<p>Musk's changes led to drops in the number of Twitter users. Some advertisers stopped doing business with the company, as well.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/lindayacc/status/1683353772917940225">In a message</a> on Twitter Monday, chief executive Linda Yaccarino wrote, "X is here! Let's do this." Along with her message, she published a picture of the logo projected onto the building's headquarters in San Francisco</p>
<p>Musk also commented on the logo change, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1682964919325724673">writing</a>, "And soon we shall <strong>bid adieu</strong> to the twitter <strong>brand</strong> and, <strong>gradually</strong>, all the birds." Musk said the X.com web domain was already redirecting users to Twitter.com.</p>
<p>A three-member team designed the first Twitter logo in 2012. One of those designers, Martin Grasser, described the blue bird logo as "simple, balanced" and easy to read at very small sizes.</p>
<p>Matt Rhodes is with the British creative agency House 337. He told news agency <em>Reuters</em> that making changes to such an established brand presents big business risks. "Anything that makes it harder for people to find, or want to open the <strong>app</strong> on their <strong>cluttered</strong> phone screens risks harming usage," Rhodes said.</p>
<p>However, Paolo Pescatore, a technology and media specialist who founded advisory company PP Foresight, said the change could be good. He spoke to the<em> Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>Pescatore said social media users currently can get <strong>confused</strong> by too many apps and messaging services to choose from. Driving users to one central place will "<strong>engage</strong>" more users and could make Twitter easier to use, he said.</p>
<p>Musk has long been interested in the letter X. He had already changed Twitter's official name to X Corp after buying the company.</p>
<p>The billionaire is also CEO of rocket company Space Exploration Technologies Corporation, commonly known as SpaceX. He started an artificial intelligence company this month called xAI to compete with OpenAI. And in 1999, he founded a startup called X.com, an online financial services company now known as PayPal.</p>
<p>Musk's Twitter purchase and rebranding effort are seen as steps toward his stated plans to create what he has called an "everything app." Such an app would be similar to China's WeChat, which combines video, messaging, <strong>streaming</strong> and payments.</p>
<p>Yaccarino wrote on Twitter that she sees X becoming "the future state of unlimited interactivity – centered in audio, video, messaging, payments/banking – creating a global marketplace for ideas, goods, services, and opportunities."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters and The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>logo </strong><em>– n. </em>to interest someone in something and keep them thinking about it</p>
<p><strong>verify </strong><em>– v.</em> to prove something is true</p>
<p><strong>content </strong><em>– n. </em>information or ideas that appear in books, movies or on the internet</p>
<p><strong>bid adieu </strong><em>– v. </em>say goodbye</p>
<p><strong>brand </strong><em>– n. </em>a kind of product made by a particular company under a particular name</p>
<p><strong>clutter </strong><em>– n. </em>a state of being messy</p>
<p><strong>confuse </strong><em>– v.</em> to mix up someone's mind or ideas</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong><em>– v. </em>to interest someone in something and keep them thinking about it</p>
<p><strong>gradually</strong> <em>– adv. </em>moving forward in steps or degrees</p>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a computer program that performs a special function, usually found on mobile phones</p>
<p><strong>streaming </strong><em>– n. </em>the continuous transmission of video files from a server to a viewer</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grow Cutting Garden for Flowers Indoors All Season Long  (2023/7/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/grow-cutting-garden-for-flowers-indoors-all-season-long.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 July 2023</span><br/>
<p>Almost every flower can be cut and enjoyed indoors. But growing a cutting <strong>garden</strong> of flowers takes some planning.</p>
<p>Jessica Damiano writes about gardening for The Associated Press. Damiano says that she cuts lilacs to bring indoors for their <strong>scent</strong> in the spring. And hydrangeas and roses make it indoors on her dining room table for the summer.</p>
<p>The first step, Damiano says, is to think about flowers as a crop to be harvested. Just as some tomatoes are better for use in sauces, some flowers are better for cutting and showing than others.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This 2022 image provided by SOW Local shows freshly cut ranunculus flowers in Oakdale, N.Y. (Chris Demchak via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/37f3531a-24ea-42fc-9417-05673b3cb3a3_cx0_cy13_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This 2022 image provided by SOW Local shows freshly cut ranunculus flowers in Oakdale, N.Y. (Chris Demchak via AP)</span></div>
<p>Flowers that do not grow tall nor <strong>bloom</strong> are not the best to show indoors. Damiano says to look for this information in seed <strong>catalogs. </strong>The descriptions often include whether specific kinds of flowers, from perennials, annuals or tender perennials, work well for cutting and showing.</p>
<p>Perennials are plants that flower for more than one year. Some flower for just two or three weeks, while others flower repeatedly. And they usually flower in their second year, but sometimes third.</p>
<p>Annuals are plants that live for just one year. But they usually produce more flowers during the growing season.</p>
<p>Tender perennials are perennials in the sense that they live for more than one year. But, they are usually grown as annuals because some do not dependably return and some cannot survive winters.</p>
<p>To ensure a continual supply of flowers for cutting, Damiano says to plant seeds or young plants every two weeks.</p>
<p>Annuals that are good for cutting include cosmos, globe amaranth, larkspur, and Queen Anne's lace. Perennials to grow and cut include bee balm, coneflower, fox glove, lily, and rose. Tender perennials that work well for cutting include California poppy, snapdragon, and strawflower.</p>
<p>Both annuals and perennials can be grown in the ground, in raised beds, or even in containers. If you have enough room, growing them in separate beds will simplify yearly planting. But it is not necessary. If you are short on space, plant where you can.</p>
<p>Most flowers need fertile, well-<strong>draining</strong> soil, repeated watering, and at least six to eight hours of direct sunlight each day. You can use plants bought from a garden center, start your own from seed indoors, or plant seeds directly into the garden.</p>
<p>Add a large amount of <strong>compost </strong>into planting holes to provide nutrients to the plants. If you're planning ahead, top the soil with five to eight centimeters of compost in the fall, and the bed will be highly fertile by spring.</p>
<p>Beds should not be much wider than a meter. This will help to keep your harvests within easy reach from all sides. When planting, place the tallest flowers at the backside of the bed, middle-sized plants in the center, and smaller plants in the front so that all are easy to get to.</p>
<p>Be sure to follow directions for plants on how much space they need to understand their full-grown size. Plants that do not have enough space often become diseased plants.</p>
<p>After planting, add a balanced, slow-release fertilizer and five to eight centimeters of <strong>mulch</strong>, then water well. If you are planting seeds directly into the garden, fertilize and mulch when the growing plants are 10 centimeters tall.</p>
<p>Beginning three weeks after planting, add a liquid flower fertilizer that is low in nitrogen and high in phosphorus. And repeat every two weeks.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>garden </strong>– <em>n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>scent </strong>– <em>n.</em> a pleasant smell that is produced by something</p>
<p><strong>bloom </strong>– <em>v.</em> to produce flowers</p>
<p><strong>catalog </strong>– <em>n.</em> a book containing a list of things that you can buy or use, and often pictures</p>
<p><strong>drain </strong>– <em>v.</em> to remove (liquid) from something by letting it flow away or out</p>
<p><strong>compost</strong><strong> </strong>– <em>n</em>. a decayed mixture of plants (such as leaves and grass) that is used to improve the soil in a garden</p>
<p><strong>mulch </strong>–<em> n</em>. a material (such as straw, leaves, or small pieces of wood) that is spread over the ground in a garden to protect the plants or help them grow and to stop weeds from growing</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Jill Biden Visits Paris to Announce America’s Return to UNESCO  (2023/7/25) | 美第一夫人出访巴黎宣布重返联合国教科文组织</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202307/jill-biden-visits-paris-to-announce-america-s-return-to-unesco.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Jill Biden, the first lady of the United States, is in Paris this week to announce her country's return to UNESCO.<br/>
美国第一夫人吉尔·拜登本周在巴黎宣布美国重返联合国教科文组织。</p>
<p>UNESCO is the educational, cultural and scientific organization of the United Nations.<br/>
教科文组织全称为联合国的教育、文化和科学组织。</p>
<p>Biden flew overnight and arrived with her daughter, Ashley, early on Monday to be there for Tuesday's ceremony. They will see the American flag raised to mark the U.S. return to UNESCO after five years.<br/>
拜登连夜飞行，于周一早些时候带着女儿阿什利抵达巴黎，准备参加周二的仪式。他们将看到美国国旗升起，这标志着美国在五年后重返联合国教科文组织。</p>
<p>UNESCO is the organization that designates World Heritage sites – noting they should be marked for eternal preservation. Eternal means something that lasts forever. The organization also works to create collaboration among nations in education, science and culture.<br/>
联合国教科文组织负责选定世界遗产，指明这些遗址应被标记为永久保护地。Eternal意思是永久的。该组织还致力于促进各国在教育、科学和文化方面的合作。</p>
<p>UNESCO recently denounced attacks by Russia on Ukraine that have damaged historical places, such as a church in Odesa. The organization noted Russia had earlier agreed to limit attacks to prevent damage on such places.<br/>
联合国教科文组织最近谴责了俄罗斯对乌克兰的袭击，这些袭击破坏了历史遗迹，例如敖德萨的一座教堂。该组织指出，俄罗斯早些时候同意限制袭击，以防止对这些地方造成破坏。</p>
<p>The Bidens will return to the U.S. on Wednesday, but they plan to visit the famous Mont-Saint-Michel before they leave. The place is a world heritage site in Normandy, in northern France.<br/>
拜登夫妇将于周三返回美国，但他们计划在离开前参观著名的圣米歇尔山。这个地方是法国北部诺曼底的世界遗产。</p>
<p>Jill Biden will also meet with Brigitte Macron, the wife of French President Emmanuel Macron.<br/>
吉尔·拜登还将会见法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙的妻子布丽吉特·马克龙。</p>
<p>Spokespeople from the administration of President Joe Biden said rejoining UNESCO was part of the president's goal to strengthen partnerships around the world. The administration also said it shows America's interest in being a U.N. leader.<br/>
乔·拜登总统政府的发言人表示，重新加入联合国教科文组织是拜登总统加强世界各地伙伴关系目标的一部分。拜登政府还表示，这表明美国有兴趣成为联合国领导者。</p>
<p>Others said Jill Biden was the right person to take part in Tuesday's event because of her experience as a teacher and college professor. Elizabeth Alexander is a spokesperson for Biden. She said the first lady is "honored to help celebrate this important milestone."<br/>
另一些人则表示，吉尔·拜登是参加周二活动的合适人选，因为她作为一名教师和大学教授的经验。伊丽莎白·亚历山大是拜登的发言人。她说，第一夫人“很荣幸能共同庆祝这一重要里程碑。”</p>
<p>The U.S. left UNESCO in 2018 during President Donald Trump's time in office. Trump's administration was protesting what it called unfair treatment of Israel by UNESCO.<br/>
美国于2018年唐纳德·特朗普总统任期内退出了联合国教科文组织。特朗普政府是为了抗议联合国教科文组织对以色列的不公平待遇。</p>
<p>UNESCO voted earlier in July to approve the United States' readmission to the group. As part of rejoining UNESCO, the U.S. will pay more than $600 million over a number of coming years. That amount includes what the U.S. would have paid had it been a member since 2018. Clubs, labor groups and other organizations call these amounts dues.<br/>
联合国教科文组织7月早些时候投票批准美国重新加入该组织。作为重新加入联合国教科文组织的一部分，美国将在未来几年支付超过6亿美元。这一数额包括如果美国自2018年以来一直是会员国，它将支付的费用。俱乐部、劳工组织和其他组织称这些款项为会费。</p>
<p>The U.S. also withdrew from UNESCO in the 1980s during Ronald Reagan's presidency. It rejoined the group in 2003 under President George W. Bush. Bush's wife, Laura, announced the move at a UNESCO meeting that year.<br/>
美国也在20世纪80年代罗纳德·里根担任总统期间退出了联合国教科文组织。它于2003年在乔治·W·布什总统的领导下重新加入该组织。布什的夫人劳拉在当年的联合国教科文组织会议上宣布了这一举措。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
