<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>International Students in US Experience American Holidays  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/international-students-in-us-experience-american-holidays.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett and Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers report that more than one million foreign students attended college or university in the United States last year. The data comes from the government-supported study called Open Doors Report on International Educational Exchange.</p>
<p>Nearly one-third of those students were studying in the U.S. for the first time.</p>
<p>Just as they are getting comfortable with their classes, classmates, professors and speaking English full-time, school stops for three major American holidays: Thanksgiving, Christmas and New Year's.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Sarah Mannix and her students from the English Language Center at Old Dominion University celebrate Thanksgiving at her house. (Photo courtesy of Sarah Mannix)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-4046-08dbf1d17cca_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Sarah Mannix and her students from the English Language Center at Old Dominion University celebrate Thanksgiving at her house. (Photo courtesy of Sarah Mannix)</span></div>
<p>What do students do when their <strong>routine</strong> gets <strong>interrupted</strong>? VOA Learning English recently spoke with a number of international students to find out.</p>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving</strong></p>
<p>Most universities take a short break so students can celebrate Thanksgiving, which falls on the fourth Thursday of November.</p>
<p>American students leave school for four or five days to spend time with their families. But international students do not often have the money to travel home during breaks, so they find themselves on an empty<strong> campus</strong>.</p>
<p>Lucky ones, however, get to experience the holidays with Americans. Aimee Sanata is from the Dominican Republic. She is studying at the English Language Center at Old Dominion University in Norfolk, Virginia.</p>
<p>Sanata celebrated the holiday with her boyfriend's family. Before the break, she watched some videos on YouTube to learn about the history of the holiday.</p>
<p>"The videos are created for children, so there they explain everything clearly so that anybody can understand it," she said.</p>
<p><strong>First taste of turkey</strong></p>
<p>Many international students say they are excited to celebrate an American Thanksgiving because they have never tasted turkey. Turkeys are large birds mostly raised on farms. Some can weigh more than 10 kilograms. They can take three to five hours to cook.</p>
<p>Sarah Mannix is one of the English instructors at Old Dominion University. She knows it can be difficult for students to find something to do during school breaks. So Mannix invited a number of her students to celebrate Thanksgiving with her.</p>
<p>"They were all really excited when we took the turkey out of the oven because they had never seen cooked turkey before," she said. "Overall, I think they enjoyed it."</p>
<p>In fact, one student has been in the U.S. for six years, but had never tried Thanksgiving turkey before this year.</p>
<p>Victoria Stepanyants grew up in Russia and the Mediterranean island of Cyprus. She studied at Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore, Maryland and is now in medical school in Cleveland, Ohio. So she has a lot of experience with the school holiday breaks.</p>
<p>She often spent Thanksgiving with other international students and friends. They did not usually prepare <strong>traditional</strong> foods. But this year was different.</p>
<p>"That was actually the first time that I've been to Thanksgiving, where the food was, like, ‘Thanksgiving food,'" Stepanyants said. "It was the food I expected to see based on the way the media covers American Thanksgiving."</p>
<p>International students are not just at universities. Sofia Montanari is from Bologna, Italy and is in high school in the Midwestern state of Missouri. She said she knows sharing meals are a good way to connect with new people. So she brought food from Italy to the Thanksgiving she spent with an American family.</p>
<p>"I really like (the idea) that they show me some of their culture and I show some of mine back," she said.</p>
<p>One part of the Thanksgiving culture she enjoyed was the idea of giving thanks. People often talk about what they are thankful for before the Thanksgiving meal.</p>
<p>"It's always good to be thankful for what you have," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Long breaks, dark and cold days</strong></p>
<p>After Thanksgiving, students get back to school to attend classes and take exams, but about three weeks later, another break starts. Most schools close from mid-December until the last week of January.</p>
<p>That long period was hard, at first, for Stepanyants. Cyprus has a warmer climate. She said the island has over 300 sunny days per year. Her experience in the U.S. was very different.</p>
<p>"As soon as it hit October, November," she said, "the sunlight is gone. It gets colder. I think it's <strong>automatically</strong> <strong>depressing</strong> for anyone who is not used to it."</p>
<p>For international students, she said, it is important to maintain a regular schedule and spend time with people.</p>
<p>International students should speak up if they are concerned about being <strong>lonely</strong> during school breaks. For Stepanyants, such discussions came naturally as she got to know other international students. At that point, they would make plans to spend time together during the breaks.</p>
<p>When she lived in Baltimore, she would take day trips with other international students to nearby cities such as Washington, D.C. and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>Sometimes, Stepanyants said, the breaks can be <strong>boring</strong>. But if students talk about their concerns they can make plans.</p>
<p>"If you have other international student friends, it's good to just bring it up because they end up in a similar situation then actually, like, the long breaks can be a lot of fun."</p>
<p>At Miami University in Oxford, Ohio, the campus is closed during the last week of December. But international students are permitted to stay in their rooms during the winter break.</p>
<p>Dan Sinetar is a part of the staff that works to help international students feel at ease. He said people who live close to the university can take part in a program to make tasty "holiday treats" for international students.</p>
<p>Students who are staying at the university during the break can also take short winter term classes.</p>
<p>Stepanyants said, students should be sure to talk with someone at their university's international student office about activities for the holidays such as Christmas and New Year's during the long breaks.</p>
<p>"For example, at my school, they would sometimes do whole celebrations that international students could come to and just like have events over the long breaks for people to not feel super <strong>isolated</strong>, which was nice."</p>
<p class="paragraph"><strong>Visitors from home and trips to see family</strong></p>
<p class="paragraph">Students at Montanari's school are not permitted to stay on the campus during Christmas break. They have to make other plans. Last year, her parents came to visit the U.S. for two weeks. They visited New York and Washington, D.C. together. They also spent some time in the town where Sofia attends school.</p>
<p class="paragraph">The rest of the break Sofia spent with a <strong>host</strong> family.</p>
<p class="paragraph">Stepanyants, the medical student, has a younger sister who is attending college in the U.S. In recent years, they have been able to see each other during breaks, which makes them both feel better and less lonely.</p>
<p>Other students do make it back home. Sanata is traveling to the Dominican Republic for Christmas break because her brother is getting married. She is thankful because she misses her family so much. She said she also misses speaking Spanish.</p>
<p>For students who cannot get home, they try to stay connected to family. New Year's is the most important winter holiday for Stepanyants. When she could not get home, she would have meals with her family by video call after cooking traditional foods.</p>
<p>"It's a very huge meal that you cook all day. And presents happen on New Year's too. Then, there are fireworks," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett and Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>routine </strong>–n. something that happens regularly or daily</p>
<p><strong>interrupt </strong>–v. to stop something from happening</p>
<p><strong>campus </strong>–n. the location of school or university buildings and residences for students</p>
<p><strong>traditional </strong>–adj. a way of doing things that has taken place for many years</p>
<p><strong>automatic </strong>–adj. something that happens without deliberate thought</p>
<p><strong>depressing </strong>–adj. a condition of unhappiness</p>
<p><strong>lonely </strong>–adj. the feeling of being alone or without other humans</p>
<p><strong>boring </strong>–adj. a dull feeling or lack of excitment</p>
<p><strong>isolated </strong>–adj. the condition of being alone or far away from others</p>
<p><strong>host </strong>–n. a person who welcomes others to an event or puts on an activity</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. What would you do during school breaks if you were studying in the U.S.?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US City Wants Woman to Clean up Rock Art  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-city-wants-woman-to-clean-up-rock-art.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Iris Logan was having a hard time growing grass at her home in St. Paul, Minnesota. So, she covered the space with stones, statues, and other art.</p>
<p>More than 30 years later, it is something of a local <strong>landmark</strong>. But to a city inspector, it is a problem.</p>
<p>Logan, who is 70, has been told to clean up the different objects, like wood and large rocks, noted after a recent inspection, the <em>St. Paul Pioneer Press, </em>a local newspaper<em> </em>reported. The City Council will look at the issue on December 6.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this undated photo provided by the City of St. Paul, Minnesota, the front exterior of Iris Logan's home is pictured. (City of St. Paul, Minnesota via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3f34cf31-9acb-4786-9190-7763896c4ced_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this undated photo provided by the City of St. Paul, Minnesota, the front exterior of Iris Logan's home is pictured. (City of St. Paul, Minnesota via AP)</span></div>
<p>Logan said the city's actions forced her to create the art in the first place. She said city workers who were fixing the road dug so deep around one of her trees that its roots were open to the air. So, she brought in dirt, planted flowers, and added stones – and just kept adding.</p>
<p>Logan said that if she likes a rock, she will try to bring it home. "I'm a rock lover," the former farmer from Mississippi added.</p>
<p>Logan recently received written <strong>notice</strong> that a city official will suggest to the City Council that she be given until December 22 to clean things up. She wrote six pages of note by hand to appeal the order. The stones do not enter the street or block city vehicles, Logan wrote to answer one of the inspector's concerns.</p>
<p>"I just want to make a stand for the next person," Logan said.</p>
<p>Casey Rodriguez is a spokeswoman for the St. Paul Department of Safety and Inspections. She said about 16 other properties on the same street also received letters advising them to remove objects blocking the street to agree with city laws.</p>
<p>She said in an email to the <em>Pioneer Press</em> that large roads, called boulevards, should be clear of objects that can block <strong>access</strong> to power and water lines. She added that it also keeps the tree roots clear and provides a place for snow in the winter.</p>
<p>Justin Lewandowski is a community organizer who lives near Logan. He said that 150 people signed their support on a <strong>petition</strong> "in just a few hours." He is hopeful that the city will soon clear up their rules.</p>
<p>"The quick support from our neighbors has been a clear signal of how much this art means to our community," Lewandowski said. He said it is not just about how it looks; it is about their identity and how they work with each other and with city policy.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>landmark </strong>– <em>n</em>. an object or structure on land that is easy to see and recognize</p>
<p><strong>notice </strong>– <em>n</em>. information that tells you or warns you about something that is going to happen</p>
<p><strong>access </strong>– <em>n</em>. a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone</p>
<p><strong>petition </strong>– <em>n</em>. a written document that people sign to show that they want a person or organization to do or change something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>It's Time to 'See the Light'  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/it-s-time-to-see-the-light.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>In many places, the holiday season in December can be a magical time. During this month, many cultures celebrate with festivals of lights. From Amsterdam in the Netherlands to Sydney, Australia; from Lyon, France to many cities in Japan -- lights are used to lift the spirits and to celebrate.</p>
<p>So, today we will talk about a few expressions that use the word "light."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Light Up festival in Ashburn, Virginia (Photo by Iacopo Luzi/VOA)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1F21CED2-DB0A-4887-AE6F-D8CE024A23BF_cx0_cy11_cw0_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Light Up festival in Ashburn, Virginia (Photo by Iacopo Luzi/VOA)</span></div>
<p>The first is to be a <strong><u>beacon</u></strong><u> of light</u>. A beacon of light gives hope and happiness to others. If you have ever been called a beacon of light, take it as a big <strong>compliment</strong>. A person who is a beacon of light makes things better for everyone around them. A beacon of light can be a person who helps guide others to safety, much like a lighthouse does for ships and boats.</p>
<p>These people can even <u>cast light on the darkness</u> in our lives. When we <u>cast light on something,</u> we make it better. The expression can also mean that we explain something more fully or <strong>expose</strong> some unknown parts of an issue or problem. Some people like to say, "Let me cast a little light on the subject," before they explain something.</p>
<p>After someone casts light on a complex or difficult issue, you might begin <u>to see the light</u>. If you see the light, you understand something. Often, you have realized a difficult truth. For example, years ago my friend refused to believe that her boyfriend had a drinking problem. But when he was arrested for drunk driving, she began to see the light. She got him help and now he has been alcohol-free for many years. So, he saw the light, too.</p>
<p>This expression is very different from <u>seeing the light of day</u> --although they sound similar.</p>
<p>When something sees the light of day, it is made available to others. For example, some people write stories and poems. But these works never see the light of day. They stay hidden in a desk drawer or notebook.</p>
<p>To see the light of day can also mean to be born or to come into existence. Let's say you worked on a big project for many months or even years. You will probably feel very excited when it finally sees the light of day.</p>
<p>Now, let's talk about "bad light."</p>
<p>Bad lighting can make even the most beautiful person look bad in a picture or video. So, it is not surprising that seeing something <u>in a bad light</u> means to form a bad opinion of something or someone.</p>
<p>Sometimes our <strong>habits</strong> and <strong>attitudes</strong> can be seen in a bad light. For example, a scientist was seen in a bad light by her coworkers. They said she was not a team player.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear these some of these expressions used in a discussion between two friends.</p>
<p><em>A: Wow, you look awful. Are you sick?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. I haven't slept in a week.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Why? What's wrong?</em></p>
<p><em>B: My roommate started playing the bag pipes. They are SO loud. And she plays late at night!</em></p>
<p><em>A: The bag pipes?! Oh, that's too bad. Well, have you told her to stop?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. She's a really nice person. So, I don't want her to <u>see me in a bad light</u>. I mean, we all do annoying things, right?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Yes. But, we all don't play the bag pipes late at night. Look, you need to do something. You need your sleep! You could hide her bag pipes. Hide them somewhere so they will never see the light of day again!</em></p>
<p><em>B: You are so mean! But you are also right. I'm beginning <u>to see the light</u>. I'll say something later. But for now (yawn) can I <strong>crash </strong>on your couch. I'm <strong>beat</strong>!</em></p>
<p>And that's the end of this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>beacon </strong><em>–n.</em> a very bright light such as a light on a lighthouse</p>
<p><strong>compliment </strong><em>–n.</em> a comment on how good something is or an expression of praise</p>
<p><strong>expose </strong><em>–v.</em> to show something that was unknown or covered up earlier</p>
<p><strong>habit </strong><em>–n.</em> a regular behavior</p>
<p><strong>attitude </strong><em>–n.</em> a way of feeling or thinking that affects a person's behavior</p>
<p><strong>crash </strong><em>–v. (informal idiom)</em> to go to sleep after being very tired</p>
<p><strong>beat </strong><em>–adj. (informal)</em> very tired</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ronald Reagan: Communicator  (2023/12/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/americas-presidents-ronald-reagan.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Ronald Reagan. He was president for two terms, and served from 1981 to 1989. Before that, he was the governor of California, worked as an actor and led a labor union.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Ronald Reagan" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/bae5644b-91f7-4b84-bf84-8a1f4c44415d_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Ronald Reagan</span></div>
<p>As president, Reagan is credited for changing the direction of the country. He tried to establish a feeling of <strong>confidence</strong> in the American people.</p>
<p>Although not everyone profited equally from his policies, the president rarely suffered in public opinion polls. Reagan was called the "Great Communicator" because he was able to connect with many Americans, and to speak persuasively about conservative values.</p>
<p>He is remembered warmly by many Republican Party politicians and voters especially.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Ronald Reagan is often linked to California and the American West. But he was born and raised in Illinois, in the center of the United States.</p>
<p>His father sold shoes, and his mother mostly took care of Ronald and his older brother, Neil. The entire family supported the Democratic Party, especially President <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-franklin-roosevelt/4046663.html" target="_blank">Franklin Roosevelt</a>.</p>
<p>While the boys were growing up, the Reagans did not have much money, and the father suffered from alcoholism.</p>
<p>But Ronald was energetic and took part in many activities.</p>
<p>He played football and basketball; ran on the track team; swam; acted in plays; led student groups; wrote for school newspapers and yearbooks; and worked several jobs to help pay for his education and support his parents.</p>
<p>He attended Eureka College in Illinois, and completed his studies in 1932.</p>
<p>One of his first jobs out of college was as a sports announcer for a radio station. He had an appealing voice and a natural way of talking that was a good <strong>fit</strong> for radio.</p>
<p>Reagan was also good-looking, and a dependable worker. In time, he was offered a chance to act in movies and moved to California.</p>
<p>During his acting career, Reagan made more than 50 films. He also married actress Jane Wyman and had two children with her. But after several years, the relationship ended. Their marriage ended in <strong>divorce</strong>.</p>
<p>Four years later, Reagan married another actress. Her name was Anne Robbins, but she was called Nancy Davis. They also had two children.</p>
<p>As he was starting his second family, Reagan began another part of his career. He served as <strong>host</strong> of a popular television series about the American West. He also became president of a labor union, the Screen Actors Guild. It represented actors, announcers, and others working in the film and television industry.</p>
<p>During that time, Reagan's political beliefs changed. He increasingly supported conservative ideas. During public appearances, he often spoke in support of business interests. He also expressed concern that the federal government was limiting Americans' freedom.</p>
<p>The message was well-received by many Americans. Although the Democratic Party was in power for most of the 1960s, a number of Americans were becoming increasingly conservative.</p>
<p>Reagan won national recognition in 1966 when he successfully ran for governor of California as a Republican. In 1970, voters re-elected him to the position.</p>
<p>But Reagan had set his sights on the presidency. He sought the Republican nomination in both 1968 and 1976.</p>
<p>Finally, in 1980, he won the office. By that time, he had already had several careers, as well as a long life. At age 69, he was the oldest person until then to be elected president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>When Reagan took office, he made improving the U.S. economy his highest concern. One way to do that, he believed, was to reduce the influence of the federal government.</p>
<p>He wanted especially to cut some of the government programs that former president <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-lyndon-johnson/4095890.html" target="_blank">Lyndon Johnson</a> had put in place to help poor people. Reagan believed that cutting taxes – especially on big businesses – would help strengthen the economy, and in time help everyone.</p>
<p>In a speech after taking office, Reagan noted that, "Government is not the solution to our problem; government is the problem."</p>
<p>At first, the economy continued to struggle. But in a few years, Reagan's policies appeared to work. Unemployment dropped, the stock market rose, and many industries grew quickly. Americans often remember Reagan's presidency as a time of economic growth.</p>
<p>Not everyone <strong>benefited</strong> equally, however. Reagan's critics observed that his policies largely helped people who were already wealthy. The divide between rich and middle-class Americans increased during Reagan's presidency.</p>
<p>And Reagan did not reduce government spending in all areas. In fact, he sharply increased military spending.</p>
<p>One result was a large national debt. Another result, Reagan's supporters say, was a quicker end to the Cold War.</p>
<p>One of Reagan's major foreign policy goals was to end the <strong>stand-off</strong> with the Soviet Union. He believed that building up the U.S. military was the best way to pressure the Soviets to reach an agreement on arms control.</p>
<p>Reagan also spoke out strongly against communism. In his second term, he famously appealed to the new Soviet leader, Mikhail Gorbachev, to tear down the Berlin Wall. For some, the wall was a sign of communism.</p>
<p>Many historians say Reagan's policies worked. For sure, Reagan and Gorbachev improved relations between their countries. And in time, the Soviet leadership permitted the Berlin Wall to come down.</p>
<p><strong>Assassination attempt and Iran-Contra scandal</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the economy and the Cold War, Reagan is often remembered for his likable personality. He spoke easily with the public, often had a <strong>positive</strong> message about the country, and usually appeared cheerful.</p>
<p>He won even more public approval after a man with mental problems tried to kill him.</p>
<p>The bullets seriously injured several people nearby, and just missed Reagan's heart.</p>
<p>Yet, shortly after he was shot, the president joked with his wife and with his doctors. Opinion polls showed that the recovered president was more popular than ever.</p>
<p>Reagan's political image also survived a <strong>scandal </strong>known as Iran-Contra. In brief, Congress found that a number of government officials secretly sold U.S. weapons to Iran as part of a deal to free hostages. Then, the officials used some of the money to help rebels in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>The actions violated congressional rules. They also <strong>challenged</strong> Reagan's promise that he had not traded weapons for hostages.</p>
<p>The president apologized for any part he had played in the events. Polls showed that, in general, the American public accepted his apology and continued to trust him.</p>
<p>Unlike most U.S. presidents, who lose public support during their terms, Reagan finished his time in office as he had taken it – with the support of more than half of Americans.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>Reagan retired to his home in California with his wife, Nancy. For several years, he wrote about his life and helped organize his presidential library.</p>
<p>But in a few years, the former president announced that he suffered from Alzheimer's. The disease affects people's ability to think, remember, and express themselves.</p>
<p>Soon, Reagan disappeared from public life. He died in 2004.</p>
<p>But he is well-remembered as an able politician who could work effectively with many people. He is also remembered – by both supporters and critics – for being a powerful voice for conservative ideas and traditional values.</p>
<p>His influence extended beyond his two terms. Later generations of leaders and voters called themselves Reagan Republicans.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>________________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>confidence</strong> - <em>n. </em>a feeling or belief that you can do something well or succeed at something</p>
<p><strong>fit</strong> -<em> adj.</em> having the necessary skills</p>
<p><strong>divorce</strong> - <em>n.</em> the ending of a marriage by a legal process</p>
<p><strong>host</strong> -<em> n.</em> a person who talks to guests on a television or radio show</p>
<p><strong>benefit</strong> -<em> v.</em> to be useful or helpful to</p>
<p><strong>standoff </strong>-<em> n.</em> an argument or contest in which there is no winner</p>
<p><strong>positive</strong> - <em>adj.</em> hopeful or optimistic</p>
<p><strong>scandal</strong> -<em> n.</em> an occurrence in which people are shocked and upset because of behavior that is morally or legally wrong</p>
<p><strong>challenge</strong> - <em>v.</em> to say or show that (something) may not be true, correct, or legal</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Life Expectancy Rises after Drops Linked to COVID-19  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-life-expectancy-rises-after-drops-linked-to-covid-19.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Life expectancy in the United States rose by about one year in 2022 following earlier decreases linked to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Life expectancy predicts the average number of years a baby born in a given year can expect to live. Federal data showed that in 2022, U.S. life expectancy rose from 76.4 years to 77.5 years.</p>
<p>Researchers from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said 2022's increase came largely because of disappearing COVID-19 cases.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, a couple walks through a park at sunset, March 10, 2021, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-bc1d-08dbf1bcbd0b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, a couple walks through a park at sunset, March 10, 2021, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel, File)</span></div>
<p>For many years, life expectancy for Americans generally rose a little bit nearly every year. But about 10 years ago, the rate flattened and even decreased in some years. Those drops were blamed on drug overdose deaths and suicides.</p>
<p>The number of U.S. suicides reached an all-time high last year, a separate CDC report found. The national suicide rate also saw its highest level since 1941. U.S. drug overdose deaths rose slightly in 2022 after much larger increases during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, U.S. life expectancy dropped from 78 years and 10 months in 2019 to 77 years in 2020. Then, in 2021, the rate dropped further, to 76 years and 5 months.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Arias is a researcher for the CDC who worked on the latest report. She told The Associated Press the U.S. life expectancy rate was clearly hurt by COVID-19 and will take "some time before we're back to where we were in 2019."</p>
<p>But Arias noted there were several favorable developments. For example, "all the groups by race and sex experienced increases in life expectancy," she said.</p>
<p>Steven Woolf, a life expectancy researcher at Virginia Commonwealth University, said he expects the U.S. to one day get back to pre-pandemic levels. But he added, "That is not a great place to be."</p>
<p>Life expectancy in 2022 increased the most for American Indian and Alaska Native non-Hispanic newborns. The rate went from 65.6 to 67.9, followed by an increase of 2.2 years for Hispanic newborns, from 77.8 to 80.</p>
<p>The life expectancy for Black non-Hispanic Americans increased by 1.6 years, from 71.2 to 72.8. Researchers noted that people in that group were more severely affected by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Life expectancy increased by 1 year for Asian non-Hispanic babies to 84.5 years, and by 0.8 years for White non-Hispanic babies, to 77.5.</p>
<p>Life expectancy in the U.S. remains longer for females. In 2020, the difference between the two sexes reached 6 years, a level not seen since 1996. In 2022, the difference narrowed to 5.4 years, down from 5.8 years in 2021.</p>
<p>Life expectancy in the U.S. continues to be lower than that of numerous other countries. And the latest report shows that the U.S. did not <strong>rebound</strong> as quickly after the pandemic as some other countries, including France, Italy, Spain and Sweden.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rebound </strong><em>– v. </em>to recover from a difficult or frustrating situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Grinch Is Back with a New Christmas Story  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/the-grinch-is-back-with-a-new-christmas-story.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>One year has passed since the Grinch stole Christmas from the town of Whoville. Now, the green creature is back in a follow-up book called <em>How the Grinch Lost Christmas!</em></p>
<p>And he wants to prove to the Whos of Whoville that he has changed.</p>
<p>The Grinch is a<strong> character</strong> from the 1957 children's book <em>How the Grinch Stole Christmas! </em>by Dr. Seuss. In that story, the Grinch tries to ruin Whoville's Christmas by stealing their gifts, <strong>ornaments</strong> and food. But later he learns that the holiday is about spending time with family and friends.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An image provided by Dr. Seuss Enterprises shows a page from the new book How the Grinch Lost Christmas! (Photo/TM &amp; &lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;169; 2023 Dr. Seuss Enterprises, L.P., All Rights Reserved, via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/76e08e28-983e-4695-bda1-bfe4a7680537_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An image provided by Dr. Seuss Enterprises shows a page from the new book "How the Grinch Lost Christmas!" (Photo/TM &amp; <i>&amp;#</i>169; 2023 Dr. Seuss Enterprises, L.P., All Rights Reserved, via AP)</span></div>
<p>Dr. Seuss's book sold millions of copies and was <strong>translated</strong> into several languages. The story has been turned into a television program, two movies and even a Broadway musical.</p>
<p>Random House, the book's publisher, said in a statement, "One of the most asked questions we receive from Seuss fans of all ages is 'What do you think happened to the Grinch after he stole Christmas?'"</p>
<p>So, the decision was made to write a new book to follow up on the story.</p>
<p>The new book,<em> How the Grinch Lost Christmas!, </em>starts a year later in Whoville. The Grinch wants to prove that his heart has grown to love the holiday.</p>
<p><em>The Grinch had been patiently waiting all year,</em><br/>
<em>To celebrate Christmas and bring the Whos cheer,</em><br/>
<em>And to show every Who he was DIFFERENT now. </em><br/>
<em>"I've changed!" thought the Grinch, </em><br/>
<em>"And I'll prove it! But HOW?" </em></p>
<p>So, the Grinch tries to win a Whoville's Christmas award by making the largest and the best Christmas tree the Whos have ever seen.</p>
<p>But, things do not go as planned. Young Cindy-Lou Who wins the contest. The Grinch is shocked and his heart turns ice cold. The green creature threatens to leave Whoville for real this time. Cindy-Lou reaches out and tells the Grinch that her tree has ornaments from everyone in Whoville except one. In the end, the Grinch returns with an ornament for Cindy-Lou and regains his spirit of giving.</p>
<p>Dr. Seuss, whose real name was Theodor Seuss Geisel, died in 1991. So, Alastair Heim, who has worked on several Dr. Seuss' books, wrote the new story. And Aristides Ruiz provided the illustrations.</p>
<p>Heim told <em>The Associated Press</em> in an email last February, "All throughout writing the story, I couldn't fully believe that I was actually getting to play in the amazing creative sandbox Dr. Seuss created all those decades ago."</p>
<p>Ruiz said he jumped at the chance to draw for the book. But he said the work on the new book was "difficult" because it is such a big part of the Christmas tradition in the United States.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English with additional reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>character </strong>- n. a person who appears in a story, book, play, movie or show</p>
<p><strong>ornament</strong> - n. a small object that are hung on Christmas Tree</p>
<p><strong>translate</strong> - v. to change words from one language to another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Congress Member Expelled  (2023/12/2) | 美国国会议员被投票驱逐</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/us-congress-member-expelled.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The U.S. House of Representatives voted to remove Republican Congressman George Santos of New York on Friday.<br/>
周五，美国众议院投票决定罢免纽约州共和党众议员乔治·桑托斯。</p>
<p>The House voted 311 to 114 to immediately remove Santos. A two-thirds majority is required to expel a member from the House. Santos became just the sixth member to be removed in the history of the United States. Three lawmakers were removed for disloyalty during the U.S. Civil War. And two were removed after being found guilty of crimes in federal court.<br/>
众议院以311票对114票决定立即罢免桑托斯。将议员逐出众议院需要三分之二多数票。桑托斯成为美国历史上第六位被罢免的议员。三名议员因在美国内战期间不忠而被免职。还有两人被联邦法院判决有罪后被免职。</p>
<p>The vote to remove Santos came after a House ethics report accused him of defrauding donors and using campaign money for his personal use. The 56-page report contained "overwhelming evidence" of lawbreaking, violations of ethics and "misstatements" during his 2022 campaign.<br/>
在投票罢免桑托斯之前，众议院的一份道德报告指控他欺诈捐赠者，并将竞选资金用于个人用途。这份56页的报告包含了他在2022年竞选期间违法、违反道德和“错误陈述”的“压倒性证据”。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">A long record of wrongdoing<br/>
一长串不法行为记录</span></p>
<p>The 35-year-old Santos has been accused of wrongdoing since he was first elected to Congress in November 2022.<br/>
现年35岁的桑托斯自2022年11月首次当选国会议员以来，一直被指控有不当行为。</p>
<p>Santos admitted that he made up his life story following several newspaper reports. He falsely claimed that his grandparents were Jewish and that they escaped the Holocaust. But his mother's immigration record said they were born in Brazil.<br/>
桑托斯承认，他的人生故事是在几篇报纸报道后编造的。他谎称他的祖父母是犹太人，他们逃过了大屠杀。但他母亲的移民记录显示他们出生在巴西。</p>
<p>Santos claimed that his family owns and collects rent money on 13 properties. There are no records of Santos or his family ever owning any property. And Santos himself has been brought to court repeatedly for not paying rent.<br/>
桑托斯声称，他的家族拥有并收取13处房产的租金。没有桑托斯或他的家人拥有任何财产的记录。而桑托斯本人也多次因不付房租而被送上法庭。</p>
<p>Newspaper reports discovered that Santos also lied about his education at New York University, his work history with financial companies Goldman Sachs and Citigroup, and his involvement in a check fraud case in Brazil. There were no records of Santos ever going to college or working at the companies. Santos later admitted to the crime and paid money in the case in Brazil.<br/>
报纸报道发现，桑托斯还谎报了他在纽约大学的教育经历、他在金融公司高盛和花旗集团的工作史，以及他参与巴西一起支票欺诈案。没有桑托斯上过大学或在这些公司工作的记录。桑托斯后来在巴西的案件中认罪并交付罚款。</p>
<p>He is currently facing federal criminal charges including stealing public money, misuse of campaign money, credit card fraud and making false statements. Santos has pleaded not guilty to those charges. But two former campaign aides have pleaded guilty to related charges.<br/>
他目前面临联邦刑事指控，包括盗窃公款、滥用竞选资金、信用卡欺诈和虚假陈述。桑托斯对这些指控表示不认罪。但两名前竞选助手已对相关指控表示认罪。</p>
<p>A bipartisan congressional investigation last month found that he used congressional campaign money to pay for almost $4,000 in spa treatments, including Botox, a kind of beauty injection. He also spent more than $4,000 of campaign money on luxury goods and made "smaller purchases" from OnlyFans, an online website known for sexual material.<br/>
上个月，国会两党的一项调查发现，他用国会竞选资金支付了近4000美元的水疗费用，其中包括肉毒杆菌毒素，这是一种美容针。他还将4000多美元的竞选资金花在了奢侈品上，并从以性材料闻名的在线网站OnlyFans上进行了“小额购买”。</p>
<p>Santos rejected repeated calls for him to resign. Before the House vote to remove him, Santos said, "The people of the Third District of New York sent me here. If they want me out, you're going to have to go silence those people and go take the hard vote."<br/>
桑托斯拒绝了多次要求他辞职的呼声。在众议院投票罢免他之前，桑托斯说：“纽约第三区的人民把我送到这里。如果他们想让我下台，你就必须让那些人噤声，然后进行艰难的投票。”</p>
<p>His expulsion will shrink the Republican's narrow majority. And New York State Governor Kathy Hochul of the Democratic Party now has 10 days to call a special election for the seat representing part of Long Island.<br/>
他的驱逐将缩小共和党的微弱多数。民主党的纽约州州长凯西·霍楚尔现在有10天的时间为这个代表长岛部分地区的席位举行特别选举。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Price vs. Rate  (2023/12/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202312/price-vs-rate.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 December 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between the words "price" and "rate."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello VOA Learning English,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Price vs. Rate" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7fc2-08dbf13034ad_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Price vs. Rate</span></div>
<p>I am confused by the words "price" and "rate." Could you please explain these words for me?</p>
<p>Irfan from Pakistan</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, Irfan. Both words can describe an amount of money in exchange for either goods, services or a certain amount of time spent. We use them in different situations. "Rate" has more meanings and uses as well.</p>
<p>Let's start with "price."</p>
<p><strong>Price</strong></p>
<p>"Price" is a noun that can be countable or singular. As a countable noun, it means the amount of money that is exchanged for something. It can also be the amount asked for or paid.</p>
<p><em>The price for twelve eggs was almost $5.00. </em></p>
<p><em>The asking price of the house was $300,000, but it was sold for under $289,000 after negotiations. </em></p>
<p>As a singular noun, "price" is the cost, result or loss that is paid to get something else.</p>
<p><em>Amanda's loss of a <strong>flexible </strong>schedule is the price of going back to school.</em></p>
<p>We can also use "price" as a verb that takes a direct object.</p>
<p><em>Marc priced his used TV at $200. </em></p>
<p>Let's look more closely at "rate" now.</p>
<p><strong>Rate</strong></p>
<p>A "rate" is a cost or value per unit for services or time. This is different from the "price" of something.</p>
<p>For example, you hire a <strong>gardener,</strong> and their rate is $50 an hour. If the gardener worked three hours at a rate of $50 per hour, then the total price is $150.</p>
<p>"Rate" can also be used to talk about amounts, degrees, or speed of something in comparison to something else.</p>
<p><em>Your heart rate is the number of beats per minute. </em></p>
<p><em>The United States <strong>obesity</strong> rate is almost double that of Italy. </em></p>
<p>"Rate" can also be a verb that means to apply a value, worth, strength or estimation. It can take a direct object or not.</p>
<p><em>Finland, Demark and Iceland rate their happiness level as very high.</em></p>
<p><em>Saratoga Springs is rated as one of the best small cities in the U.S. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Irfan.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>flexible</strong> – <em>adj</em>. readily changed or changing</p>
<p><strong>gardener </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who cares for a garden</p>
<p><strong>obesity </strong><em>– n. </em>the state of being overweight in an unhealthy way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korean City Turns to Matchmaking to Increase Low Birth Rates  (2023/12/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/south-korean-city-turns-to-matchmaking-to-increase-low-birth-rates.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>While Christmas music played, 100 South Korean men and women gathered at a hotel near the capital of Seoul with their names written for others to see.</p>
<p>They were hoping to find love. The government hopes they will make babies.</p>
<p>The young men and women were at a blind dating event held by the city of Seongnam. Blind dating is when two people who do not know each other meet in hopes of forming a relationship.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin speaks during a mass blind date event in Seongnam, South Korea on November 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cacab718-c0ea-4146-9171-042057e32efc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin speaks during a mass blind date event in Seongnam, South Korea on November 19, 2023. (REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji)</span></div>
<p>The local government is attempting to fight the falling birth rate in a country where the popularity of marriage and parenthood has fallen.</p>
<p>Those who joined were in their 20s and 30s. They sat quietly next to one another until a relationship expert started the event with a game called rock-paper-scissors. People soon began to talk and laugh.</p>
<p>The city appeared set on making a <strong>match</strong>. It prepared food and drinks like red wine and chocolate. There were also games, free beauty services, and even services to look into people's <strong>backgrounds</strong> for the singles that joined.</p>
<p>Lee Yu-mi is 36 and works for the city government. She said she registered to join three times before she was finally accepted to join the event.</p>
<p>"I had no idea it would be this competitive," she said.</p>
<p>After five such gatherings this year, 198 people among 460 left the event as "<strong>couples</strong>", agreeing to exchange contact information, the city said.</p>
<p>The South Korean capital Seoul had considered a similar event but put the plan on hold after facing criticism. Some said the event was a waste of taxpayers' money and it failed to deal with the reasons people were choosing to not marry and have babies. Those reasons include the high costs of housing and education.</p>
<p>Hwang Da-bin took part in a September event. He said it saved him the cost of joining other social events or signing up for professional match-making services.</p>
<p>"We are facing a real <strong>demographic</strong> crisis and the government needs to do whatever it can. I don't understand people <strong>complaining</strong> over this," Hwang said.</p>
<p>The average number of children born to each South Korean woman, called the fertility rate, fell to 0.78 last year. The country has the lowest fertility rate in the world.</p>
<p>The number is far below 1.66 in the United States and 1.3 in Japan in 2021. The average rate among countries in the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development, a group of 37 democracies with market economies, was 1.58 that same year.</p>
<p>Jun Jae-hoon teaches social welfare at Seoul Women's University. He said it was "nonsense" to expect these events to lead to higher birth rates.</p>
<p>"You need to spend more money directly on supporting pregnancy, child delivery and parenting to call it a policy..." to increase<strong> </strong>birth rates, Jung said.</p>
<p>But even with criticism, thousands of people have signed up for this year's blind-dating events held by the Seongnam city.</p>
<p>Seongnam Mayor Shin Sang-jin said spreading good views on marriage would at some point help raise the birth rates. He said that the blind-dating events are just one of many policies his city has created to deal with the falling rates.</p>
<p>"Low birth rates cannot be <strong>resolved</strong> with a single policy," Shin said. "It's also the city's job to create the environment for people who want to marry find their partners."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Soo-Hyang Choi reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>match </strong>– <em>n</em>. two people or things that are suited to each other</p>
<p><strong>background </strong>– <em>n</em>. the experiences, knowledge, and education in a person's past</p>
<p><strong>demographic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to the study of changes that occur in large groups of people over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong>– <em>v</em>. to say or write that you are unhappy, sick, uncomfortable or that you do not like something</p>
<p><strong>resolve </strong>– <em>v</em>. to find an answer or solution to (something): to settle or solve (something)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Famed Diplomat Henry Kissinger Dies at 100  (2023/12/1) | 著名外交官基辛格百岁高龄去世</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/famed-diplomat-henry-kissinger-dies-at-100.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>American former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger died Wednesday at his home in Connecticut. He was 100 years old.<br/>
美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格星期三在康涅狄格州的家中去世。享年100岁。</p>
<p>Kissinger was famed for helping restore ties between the United States and China and negotiating the U.S. withdrawal from Vietnam.<br/>
基辛格以帮助恢复美中关系和谈判美国从越南撤军而闻名。</p>
<p>The German-born Jewish refugee served as national security advisor and secretary of state under two presidents, Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford.<br/>
这位出生于德国的犹太难民曾在理查德·尼克松和杰拉尔德·福特两任总统任期中担任国家安全顾问和国务卿。</p>
<p>During the 1970s, Kissinger led U.S. diplomacy and was involved in many world-changing events.<br/>
20世纪70年代，基辛格领导了美国外交，并参与了许多改变世界的事件。</p>
<p>He led the first "shuttle diplomacy" to improve ties between Israel and its Arab neighbors. He started secret talks that led to the recognition of Communist China and its return to the world community. His policy of "détente" led to arms control agreements with the former Soviet Union.<br/>
他领导了第一次“穿梭外交”，以改善以色列与其阿拉伯邻国之间的关系。他开始了秘密会谈，最终导致美国承认了中华人民共和国的地位及其重返国际社会。他的“缓和”政策促成了与前苏联的军备控制协议。</p>
<p>He negotiated the 1973 Paris Peace Accord to get the U.S. out of the conflict in Vietnam. The effort won him a Nobel Peace Prize. Vietnamese Communist forces won control of the country two years later.<br/>
他通过谈判达成了1973年的《巴黎和平协议》，以使美国摆脱越南冲突。这一努力为他赢得了诺贝尔和平奖。两年后，越南共产党军队赢得了对该国的控制权。</p>
<p>On Thursday, many world leaders praised Kissinger for his life's work. However, others sharply criticized the former diplomat for damaging the world in the process. And on social media, many posts described him as a war criminal.<br/>
周四，许多世界领导人赞扬了基辛格毕生的工作。然而，其他人尖锐地批评这位前外交官在这个过程中损害了世界。在社交媒体上，许多帖子将他描述为战犯。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Praise<br/>
赞扬</span></p>
<p>Former U.S. President George W. Bush said, "America has lost one of the most dependable and distinctive voices" on foreign relations.<br/>
美国前总统布什说，“美国失去了外交事务上最可靠、最独特的声音之一”。</p>
<p>French President Emmanuel Macron praised Kissinger in a post on the social media site X, formerly Twitter. He wrote: "Henry Kissinger was a giant of history. His century of ideas and of diplomacy had a lasting influence on his time and on our world."<br/>
法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙在社交媒体网站X（前身为推特）上发帖赞扬了基辛格。他写道：“亨利·基辛格是一位历史巨人。他一个多世纪以来的思想和外交成就对他的时代和我们的世界产生了持久的影响。”</p>
<p>China's state broadcaster CCTV said that President Xi Jinping sent U.S. President Joe Biden a message of sympathy Thursday. It said, "Dr. Kissinger will always be remembered and missed by the Chinese people." China's Foreign Ministry spokesperson called Kissinger an "old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of China-U.S. relations."<br/>
中国中央电视台表示，习主席向美国总统拜登发去唁电。电文称：“基辛格博士将永远被中国人民铭记和怀念。”外交部发言人称基辛格是“中国人民的老朋友、好朋友，是中美关系的开拓者和建设者”。</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin said in a message to Kissinger's wife that his foreign policy led to "the most important Soviet-American agreements" in strengthening world security.<br/>
俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在给基辛格妻子的一封信中表示，他的外交政策促成了加强世界安全的“最重要的苏美协议”。</p>
<p>In a message to Kissinger's family, Germany's President Frank-Walter Steinmeier wrote, "with his détente and disarmament policy, Henry Kissinger laid the foundation for the end of the Cold War and the democratic transition in eastern Europe" which led to Germany's reunification.<br/>
德国总统弗兰克·沃尔特·施泰因迈尔在给基辛格家人的一封信中写道，“凭借他的缓和政策和裁军政策，亨利·基辛格为冷战的结束和东欧的民主过渡奠定了基础”，这导致了德国的统一。</p>
<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog told U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken in Tel Aviv that Kissinger "laid the cornerstone of the peace agreement, which (was) later signed with Egypt, and so many other processes around the world I admire."<br/>
以色列总统艾萨克·赫尔佐格在特拉维夫告诉美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯，基辛格“奠定了后来与埃及签署的和平协议的基石，以及我钦佩的世界各地的许多其他进程。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Criticism<br/>
批评</span></p>
<p>However, criticism of Kissinger was especially strong for his actions during the war in Vietnam.<br/>
然而，对基辛格在越南战争期间的行为的批评尤其强烈。</p>
<p>The policy of "Vietnamization" was meant to shift the fighting against North Vietnam from U.S. forces to the South Vietnamese. It included a massive bombing campaign of North Vietnam and the mining of the Northern ports. The U.S. also bombed in Cambodia and Laos in 1969 although Kissinger kept that secret. The attacks in those countries intensified the civil war in Vietnam.<br/>
“越南化”政策旨在将对北越的战斗从美军转移到南越。其中包括对北越的大规模轰炸和对北部港口的挖掘。1969年，美国还轰炸了柬埔寨和老挝，尽管基辛格对此保密。对这些国家的袭击加剧了越南内战。</p>
<p>Kissinger also was criticized for his part in Angola's civil war, Pakistan's aggression toward Bangladesh, and the U.S. involvement in Chile, which ended with a government overthrow in 1973.<br/>
基辛格还因参与安哥拉内战、巴基斯坦对孟加拉国的侵略以及美国对智利的干预而受到批评，1973年智利政府被推翻。</p>
<p>Sophal Ear is a Cambodia expert at Arizona State University. He wrote in the online publication The Conversation: "Henry Kissinger's bombing campaign likely killed hundreds of thousands of Cambodians — and set (a) path for the ravages of the Khmer Rouge."<br/>
索法尔·厄尔是亚利桑那州立大学的柬埔寨问题专家。他在网络出版物《对话》中写道：“亨利·基辛格的轰炸行动可能导致数十万柬埔寨人死亡，并为红色高棉的蹂躏开辟了道路。”</p>
<p>"The cluster bombs dropped on Cambodia under Kissinger's watch continue to destroy the lives of any man, woman or child who happens across them," Sophal Ear added.<br/>
索法尔·厄尔补充道：“在基辛格注视下投向柬埔寨的集束炸弹继续摧毁着炸弹周围任何男人、女人或孩子的生命。”</p>
<p>Reporting the diplomat's death, the magazine Rolling Stone published this headline: "Henry Kissinger, war criminal beloved by America's ruling class, finally dies."<br/>
在报道这位外交官的死讯时，《滚石》杂志发表了这样的标题：“深受美国统治阶级爱戴的战犯亨利·基辛格终于去世了。”</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.<br/>
我是凯蒂·韦弗。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Grammar for Giving Gifts  (2023/12/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/grammar-for-giving-gifts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>We are now in between two major American holidays: Thanksgiving and Christmas. This is the most important time of the year for giving gifts.</p>
<p>So, in the holiday spirit, we will explore some common questions that connect to gift giving. Please note that what we explore in this lesson is not connected only to American holidays - it can be used more generally to describe any kind of gift-giving event.</p>
<p><strong>Questions </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6a66-08dbf103c425_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Imagine you want to get a gift for a family member. You need some advice from another family member or friend. How would you ask for such advice?</p>
<p>That question leads us to the first point in today's lesson. We are asking about what others want in terms of a gift.</p>
<p>One way to ask this question is by using a "what" question.</p>
<p>This is a kind of open-ended question. In other words, you are asking a question that requires more information than a simple answer of yes or no.</p>
<p>You might use <strong>modals</strong> or helping verbs in your question. You might also want to report who is going to receive the gift and the occasion that the gift is for.</p>
<p>Let's take an example to clarify these points.</p>
<p>Imagine you are doing Christmas shopping for your brother. Let's say his name is Tom. Here is how you might ask another person – say your mother – about a gift for Tom. You could ask: "What would Tom like for Christmas?"</p>
<p>Here, we have the "what" question word along with the modal "would" and then the name Tom followed by the verb "like." Please note that we also generally use the structure "for + holiday" where the holiday is a noun or noun <strong>phrase</strong>. In this case, the holiday is Christmas.</p>
<p>Another way you might ask the question is with the helping verb "do." The basic structure is the same as our example containing "would" and "like." But in this question, we replace those words with "do" and "want." So, you might ask, "What does Tom want for Christmas?"</p>
<p>Please note that the two questions we have discussed so far have almost the same meaning:</p>
<p><em>What would Tom like for Christmas?</em></p>
<p>And</p>
<p><em>What does Tom want for Christmas?</em></p>
<p><strong>Locations and nouns</strong></p>
<p>Now let us consider questions about places to get gifts. In such questions, we generally use the question word "where" along with the modal "can." We often use "find" as the main verb. And we often use nouns with similar meanings such as "sales," "deals," or "specials."</p>
<p>Let's explore three examples, all of which have a similar meaning.</p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday sales?</em></p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday deals?</em></p>
<p><em>Where can I find holiday specials?</em></p>
<p>Note that the question word always comes first. The modal "can" comes between the question word and the subject "I."</p>
<p>And then we have the main verb "find" along with the noun phrases such as holiday specials, holiday deals, and so on.</p>
<p>Once you find the correct location, then discussions about price might come. We explored that subject <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/grammar-and-the-economy-prices/7117170.html" target="_blank">in an earlier lesson</a>, which you can find in the Everyday Grammar area of our website, www.51voa.com.</p>
<p><strong>Quiz </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Imagine you are considering what gift to get for your mother for her birthday. How might you ask another family member about what to get?</p>
<p>Pause the audio to consider your answer.</p>
<p>Here are two possible answers:</p>
<p><em>What would Mom like for her birthday?</em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>What does Mom want for her birthday?</em></p>
<p>In our answers, we used the question word "what." Either the structure "...would Mom like..." or "...does Mom want..." will work.</p>
<p>What is important is that after the short word "for," we have the noun phrase "her birthday." This noun phrase provides information that makes the question clearer.</p>
<p>Future lessons will explore gift giving in greater detail.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>modal </strong><em>– n. </em>a verb (such as can, could, shall, should, ought to, will, or would) that is usually used with another verb to express ideas such as possibility, necessity, and permission</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong> <em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express an idea but do not form a complete sentence</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google to Start Removing ‘Inactive’ User Accounts  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/google-to-start-removing-inactive-user-accounts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Google is about to start <strong>deleting</strong> accounts considered "inactive."</p>
<p>The company plans to start removing inactive accounts that users have not used or signed into for more than two years on December 1.</p>
<p>Google announced the policy in May, saying it could begin removing affected accounts in December 2023. User data that could be deleted includes content stored within Google Drive, Docs, Gmail and other services.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1dd2-08dbf0fa624e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>Google says users with accounts at risk of being deleted should have already received email messages explaining the policy and the steps required to keep accounts active.</p>
<p>The company said the deletion process will start with Google accounts that were created, but never used again. Google is urging users who want to save their accounts and related data to take some form of action by the end of this week.</p>
<p><strong>Why is Google deleting inactive accounts?</strong></p>
<p>Google has said its policy to delete old, unused accounts is designed to remove security risks related to those accounts.</p>
<p>In its announcement, Google <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/updating-our-inactive-account-policies/">said</a> accounts that go long periods of time without activity are "more likely to be <strong>compromised</strong>." The reasons for this include the fact that forgotten or unused accounts often depend on old or reused passwords.</p>
<p>Another thing that puts such accounts at risk is the lack of two-step security processes that became popular in recent years to help users keep their accounts secure. This security tool, called "two-factor authentication," aims to reduce the risk of internet attackers taking over personal accounts and stealing data.</p>
<p>In addition, old and unused accounts "receive fewer security checks by the user," Google said.</p>
<p><strong>How can I prevent my account from being deleted?</strong></p>
<p>Google says the best way to keep a user account active is to sign into it at least once every two years.</p>
<p>But there are some other actions that meet the requirements for keeping a Google account active. These include sending or looking at emails, using Google search and watching videos on Google-owned YouTube. The user must be signed in to their Google account when performing these actions.</p>
<p>The policy covers Google Photos as well. The company <a class="wsw__a" href="https://support.google.com/photos/answer/10100180">explains</a> that the simplest way to avoid losing saved pictures and videos is "to visit Google Photos on the web or through the <strong>app</strong>." When signed in, users just need to perform some activity. For example, they can look through an image collection, share a photo or video or back up content in Photos.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any exceptions to the policy?</strong></p>
<p>Google says it only plans to delete old or unused accounts for personal users. Accounts that were set up for organizations, such as schools or businesses, will not be affected.</p>
<p>Other exceptions include Google accounts controlled by an adult for a child or accounts that have been used to buy goods or services on an ongoing basis.</p>
<p>Google has also noted there are no current plans to delete accounts with YouTube videos.</p>
<p><strong>How can I save data from my Google account?</strong></p>
<p>Google does offer users some tools to help them save and backup stored data. One of them is called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://takeout.google.com/">Takeout</a>. This service permits users to download and export account data outside of Google at any time. An account holder can use this method to back up stored data or to use it with a service outside of Google.</p>
<p>In addition, Google offers a tool, called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3036546?hl=en">Inactive Account Manager</a>, which permits users to choose what would happen to their accounts and data if it does become inactive. The choices for activating this service include having files sent to a set of trusted contacts or requesting that the whole account be deleted.</p>
<p>Google also asks that all its users provide a recovery email for their account. This can be an important method for getting a user back into a locked account and can also be helpful for sending inactive account messages and other communications.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Google reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>delete </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove something, especially from a computer's memory</p>
<p><strong>compromise </strong><em>– v. </em>to agree to something that is not exactly what you want</p>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device<em> </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>No Easy Solution for Carbon Capture  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/no-easy-solution-for-carbon-capture.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Countries are gathering for the 28th United Nations climate change conference in the United Arab Emirates at the end of November. Many will pay special attention to carbon capture to meet international commitments to decarbonize by mid-century.</p>
<p>Here are some details about the carbon capture industry as well as some of the issues facing its future.</p>
<p><strong>Different kinds of carbon capture </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Carbon dioxide storage tanks are seen at a cement plant and carbon capture facility in Wuhu, Anhui province, China September 11, 2019. (REUTERS/David Stanway/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0d75c659-9498-4d42-b0e1-010d95203b76_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Carbon dioxide storage tanks are seen at a cement plant and carbon capture facility in Wuhu, Anhui province, China September 11, 2019. (REUTERS/David Stanway/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>There are two main kinds of carbon capture technology: carbon capture and storage (CCS) and carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS).</p>
<p>CCS, the most common form of carbon capture technology, involves capturing the gas from a source like an industrial <strong>smokestack</strong>. From there, the carbon can be moved directly to underground storage.</p>
<p>CCUS involves capturing the gas and using it in another industrial activity before storage.</p>
<p>There are currently 42 CCS and CCUS projects across the world. The Global CCS Institute says these projects can store 49 million metric tons of <strong>carbon dioxide</strong> each year. That amount is about 0.13 percent of the world's roughly 37 billion metric tons of yearly energy and industry-related carbon dioxide <strong>emissions</strong>.</p>
<p>Another form of carbon capture is <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36K3XK&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">direct air capture</a> (DAC), in which carbon emissions are captured from the air.</p>
<p>About 130 DAC facilities are being planned around the world, says the International Energy Agency (IEA).</p>
<p>In August, the United States announced $1.2 billion in financing for two DAC projects in the states of Texas and Louisiana that promise to capture 2 million metric tons of carbon per year. However, a final investment decision on the projects has not been made.</p>
<p><strong>High costs </strong></p>
<p>Cost is one issue facing carbon capture technology.</p>
<p>CCS costs can go from $15 to $120 per metric ton of captured carbon depending on the emissions source. DAC projects are <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/nMT1ECMIIE17OJYQX7ZZG2PTI9IZJIAEOWT" target="_blank">even more</a> costly, between $600 and $1,000 per metric ton.</p>
<p>Some CCS projects in countries like <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36T56T&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Norway</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL1N3AW2X7&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Canada</a> have been paused for financial reasons.</p>
<p>Developers say they need a carbon price, either in the form of a carbon tax, trading system or tax break, that makes it profitable to capture and store the carbon. Without that, only carbon capture projects that increase money in a different way - like through increased oil output - are profitable.</p>
<p>Countries including the U.S. have announced<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL8N36E3E7&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank"> public <strong>subsidies</strong></a> for carbon capture projects. The Inflation Reduction Act, passed in 2022, offers a $50 tax credit per metric ton of carbon captured for CCUS and $85 per metric ton captured for CCS. The law also offers $180 per metric ton captured through DAC.</p>
<p>Although those are meaningful offers, companies may still need to take on some added costs to move CCS and DAC projects ahead, said Benjamin Longstreth, worldwide director of carbon capture at the Clean Air Task Force.</p>
<p><strong>Locations </strong></p>
<p>Where captured carbon can be stored is limited by geology – the land and processes of land formation in an area. The best storage places for carbon are in parts of North America, East Africa, and the North Sea, the Global CCS Institute says.</p>
<p>That means getting captured carbon to storage areas could require large pipeline networks or even shipping <strong>fleets</strong>. Developing such networks can create new difficulties.</p>
<p>In October, for example, a $3 billion CCS pipeline project proposed by <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.reutersconnect.com/all?search=all%3AL1N3BQ1NF&amp;linkedFromStory=true" target="_blank">Navigator CO2 Ventures</a> in the U.S. was canceled amid community concerns about possible leaks and damage during the building process.</p>
<p>Companies investing in carbon removal need to take seriously community concerns about new<strong> infrastructure</strong> projects, said Simone Stewart of the National Wildlife Federation.</p>
<p>"Not all technologies are going to be possible in all locations," Stewart said.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Leah Douglas reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>smokestack</strong> <em>– n. </em>a tall chimney on a factory, ship, etc., for carrying smoke away</p>
<p><strong>carbon dioxide</strong> <em>– n.</em> gas that is produced when certain fuels are burned</p>
<p><strong>emission</strong> <em>– n.</em> something sent out or given off</p>
<p><strong>subsidy </strong><em>– n. </em>money that is paid usually by a government to keep the price of a product or service low</p>
<p><strong>fleet</strong> <em>– n. </em>a group of ships or vehicles that move or work together</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>-- n. </em>the basic equipment (such as roads and bridges) that are needed for a country to function</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Passenger Jet Fueled by Cooking Fat Crosses the Atlantic  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/passenger-jet-fueled-by-cooking-fat-crosses-the-atlantic.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>British Businessman Richard Branson and Britain's Department of Transport organized a flight crossing the Atlantic Ocean by a jet using fuel made from animal fat.</p>
<p>The Boeing 787 passenger airplane flew from London to New York on Tuesday using what the organizers called <strong>sustainable</strong> jet fuel.</p>
<p>Branson founded Virgin Atlantic airlines. The airline said it used a fuel made from waste fats, including animal fat used in cooking. The transport department spent over $1.2 million for the flight.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt=" Virgin Atlantic's Flight100 Lands at JFK Airport in New York City from London Heathrow, Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2023 in New York. (Jason DeCrow/AP Images for Virgin Atlantic Airways Ltd)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/99e3ce64-535f-4786-ac03-55d609b2d2bd_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"> Virgin Atlantic's Flight100 Lands at JFK Airport in New York City from London Heathrow, Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2023 in New York. (Jason DeCrow/AP Images for Virgin Atlantic Airways Ltd)</span></div>
<p>Branson was on the plane, along with reporters, engineers and government officials as it crossed the Atlantic Ocean. There were no paying passengers.</p>
<p>"The world will always <strong>assume</strong> something can't be done, until you do it," Branson said.</p>
<p>The transport department called the trip "a huge step towards jet zero." "Jet zero" is a play on words. It means the trip did not use traditional jet fuel that comes from oil. Some officials in the international air travel industry say they hope their companies can reach what is called "net zero" by 2050. "Net zero" is a proposed balance between the release of carbon gases into the atmosphere and the capture of those gases.</p>
<p>However, organizers admit the mix of fuel used on Tuesday's trip will not be widely available anytime soon.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Energy says sustainable <strong>aviation</strong> fuel is the best way to reach the "net zero" target by 2050. The government says sustainable aviation fuel cuts the release of greenhouse gases, gases said to cause warming, by 70 percent. However, the Department of Energy said the 2050 goal is "aspirational." That means it is unlikely to be reached.</p>
<p>In the U.S., sustainable jet fuel production increased from about 8 million liters in 2016 to about 60 million liters in 2022. But that is only about 0.1 percent of the fuel used by major airlines. In 2018, the Federal Aviation Administration set a goal of producing about 15 billion liters per year.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden's administration said in 2021 that it wanted three times that amount by 2030 and for commercial airlines to fly on 100 percent sustainable fuel by 2050. In Britain, the goal is for 10 percent of jet fuel to come from what it calls sustainable sources by 2030.</p>
<p>Holly Boyd-Boland is an official with Virgin Atlantic. She said Tuesday's flight shows a sustainable flight is possible, but the difficulty is in producing enough of the new fuel "so that we're flying more sustainable aviation fuel every day."</p>
<p>Cait Hewitt is the policy director for the British non-profit group Aviation Environment Federation. The group is interested in reducing the effect of the aviation industry on the environment.</p>
<p>She said, "the idea that this flight somehow gets us closer to <strong>guilt</strong>-free flying is a joke." She said it will be difficult to increase production of sustainable jet fuel to the point that it makes a difference.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sustainable </strong>–adj. related to ideas about using resources without using them up completely</p>
<p><strong>assume </strong>–v. to think something is true without knowing that it is true</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong>–n. things related to flight and aircraft</p>
<p><strong>guilt </strong>–n. a feeling of shame over something you do or have done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Former Somali Refugee Wins UN Refugee Award  (2023/11/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/former-somali-refugee-wins-un-refugee-award.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency has named a former child refugee from Somalia winner of this year's Nansen Refugee Award.</p>
<p>The U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) recognized Abdullahi Mire for providing 100,000 books to Somali refugees in camps in Kenya. Mire is now 36 years old.</p>
<p>"Last year, 2022, Angela Merkel, the former Federal Chancellor of Germany, won the award and today a young refugee from Dadaab. The sky is not the limit," Mire told VOA Somalia.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This handout picture taken on Nov. 8, 2023, shows Abdullahi Mire, winner of the U.N. refugee agency's prestigious Nansen Award posing for a picture in one of the libraries he established in Kenya's Dadaab refugee camp. (AFP Photo/UNHCR)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-4d6c-08dbf0605025_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This handout picture taken on Nov. 8, 2023, shows Abdullahi Mire, winner of the U.N. refugee agency's prestigious Nansen Award posing for a picture in one of the libraries he established in Kenya's Dadaab refugee camp. (AFP Photo/UNHCR)</span></div>
<p>Filippo Grandi is the president of the UNHCR. He said Mire is living proof that "<strong>transformative</strong> ideas" can come out of displaced communities.</p>
<p>"He has shown great <strong>resourcefulness</strong> and <strong>tenacity</strong> in strengthening the quality of refugee education," Grandi said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mire was born in southern Somalia in 1987. In 1991, his family fled the country because of Somalia's civil war.</p>
<p>"I fled from Qoryooley in the Lower Shabelle region in 1991 with my mother and grew up and lived in the Dadaab refugee camps for 23 years," Mire told VOA.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>The Dadaab complex in northeastern Kenya today has a population of more than 240,000 refugees, most from Somalia. Over half of the camp's population are children.</p>
<p>Mire finished elementary and secondary schooling while living in the camp. He went on to earn a college degree in public relations and <strong>journalism</strong> from Kenya's Kenyatta University. He said his mother gave him help and support to become, in his words, "a voice for my <strong>vulnerable</strong> population."</p>
<p>Mire got a job with the United Nations International Organization for Migration in Somalia. He worked in the capital Mogadishu and the southern cities of Baidoa and Kismayo.</p>
<p>He said his childhood in Dadaab and professional experience taught him the importance of his education. So, he decided to <strong>dedicate</strong> his professional life to helping his fellow refugees.</p>
<p>In early 2018, he started an organization called Refugee Youth Education Hub. The organization centers on refugee education and youth development.</p>
<p>After shortly living in Norway, he returned to Dadaab to help.</p>
<p>"I had a <strong>yearning</strong> to serve my community that drew me back to the camp," he said.</p>
<p>A refugee woman who was studying medicine in Dadaab <strong>inspired</strong> him to collect books for refugee camps, Mire said.</p>
<p>"She told me about 20 girls normally shared one biology book. That inspired me to use social media for a book collection and donation campaign till we reached 100,000 books."</p>
<p>Mire is not the only Somali who has won the Nansen Refugee Award. In 2012, the UNHCR presented Hawa Aden Mohamed with the award for her work to help Somali refugee and displaced females.</p>
<p>The award is named for the Norwegian explorer, scientist, diplomat and humanitarian, Fridtjof Nansen.</p>
<p>"The win is not for me alone," Mire said in a statement. "It is for all the volunteers I work with... It is for the children in the schools."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Mohamed Olad Hassan wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>transformative </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing or able to cause a change</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>resourceful </strong><em>— adj. </em> able to deal well with new or difficult situations and to find solutions to problems</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tenacious </strong><em>— adj. </em>very determined to do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>— adj. </em>easily hurt or harmed physically, mentally, or emotionally</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dedicate </strong><em>— v. </em> to use time, money, energy, attention, etc. for something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>yearn </strong><em>— v. </em>to feel a strong desire or wish for something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inspire </strong><em>— v. </em>to make want to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reports: World Is ‘Off Track’ in Fighting Climate Change  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/reports-world-is-off-track-in-fighting-climate-change.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Three recent reports say the world is failing in its fight to slow climate change.</p>
<p>The medical publication <em>The Lancet</em> released its yearly report called The Countdown. The study measures human health in connection with climate change. The 2023 report says more people are dying due to heat waves than in the past. It says the numbers will rise sharply as temperatures continue to rise.</p>
<p>Researchers also released another report called <em>State of Climate Action</em>. Several groups took part in producing the report including the World Resources Institute, Climate Action Tracker, and the Bezos Earth Fund. The report says the world is failing in 41 of 42 important climate measurements. It said six <strong>indicators</strong> show the world is heading the wrong way – noting the way some governments are still helping fund the use of <strong>fossil fuels</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c81130a-45bf-401c-9ab1-c37cc02f3c11_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A fisherman walks across a dry patch of land in the marshes in Dhi Qar province, Iraq, Sept. 2, 2022. (AP Photo/Anmar Khalil, File)</span></div>
<p>And the U.S. government recently produced a 2,200 page National Climate Assessment that looked at how warming is harming America.</p>
<p><em>The Lancet's</em> report noted that deaths due to heat among people 65 or older were 85 percent higher in the last 10 years than from 1991 to 2000. There were 23,200 heat deaths of older people in 2022, the report found.</p>
<p>A computer program showed that the numbers would be much lower if the Earth had not warmed to its current levels.</p>
<p>"We are already seeing climate change claiming lives and livelihoods in every part of the world," said Countdown chief, Marina Romanello. But, the effects reported today could be, in her words, "an early symptom of a very dangerous future."</p>
<p>Romanello said that people also are increasingly reporting hunger because of<strong> drought</strong> and heat waves.</p>
<p>Dr. Jonathan Patz is the former director of the Global Health Institute at the University of Wisconsin and was not part of the study. He praised the study as the most thorough yearly scientific examination of climate change and health. Patz called its findings "<strong>stark</strong>."</p>
<p>Paul Elkins is an economics professor at University College of London. He worked on <em>The Lancet</em> report. He said the harms produced by the fossil fuel industry are "extremely <strong>relevant</strong>." He said its pollution is "killing people and making them ill."</p>
<p>The report also directly criticizes banks that loan money to the industry. It compared the fossil fuel business to the tobacco industry.</p>
<p><em>The Countdown </em>names 68 countries that it says gave more than $300 billion combined in assistance to companies that produced fossil fuels in 2020.</p>
<p>The <em>State of Climate Action</em> report also discusses such financial support. It described the business aid as one of six main signs that the world is going in the wrong direction on climate change.</p>
<p>Joe Thwaites is an expert with the Natural Resources Defense Council and one of the writers of the <em>State of Climate Action</em>.<em> </em>Thwaites said fossil fuel industry aid "reached an all-time high last year, over $1 trillion, driven by the war in Ukraine and the resulting energy price <strong>spikes</strong>."</p>
<p>Kelly Levin is with the Bezos Earth Fund. She said the financial aid for fossil fuels is an indicator that recently changed. That means, until recently, there was less financial aid available to pay for fossil fuels.</p>
<p>The State of Climate Action report noted five other areas where the world's progress has reversed: the high energy cost of making steel, the fuel efficiency of passenger cars, the sale of electric buses, the loss of mangrove forests and the amount of food waste.</p>
<p>The only improving measurement is that sales of electric vehicles are rising around the world.</p>
<p>Levin said the time for "<strong>tinkering</strong>" is over and instead asked for "<strong>radical</strong> decarbonization."</p>
<p>Levin's report went on to show all of the many changes that are needed to prevent a global temperature rise that many nations agreed to in Paris in 2015.</p>
<p>Justin Mankin is a climate scientist at Dartmouth College who was not involved in the reports. He said the first step in making changes should be "low-hanging fruit." That means countries should work together to make the easiest changes. He noted, however, that the reports show "we're really struggling to pick the low-hanging fruit."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>drought </strong><em>–n.</em> an environmental condition that comes from a long period without rain</p>
<p><strong>indicator </strong><em>–n.</em> a piece of information that provides an idea about a larger topic of concern</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuels </strong><em>–n.</em> a fuel (such as coal, oil, or natural gas) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>stark </strong><em>–adj.</em> an unpleasant and difficult to accept experience</p>
<p><strong>relevant </strong><em>–adj.</em> information that is connected and important to a larger concern</p>
<p><strong>spike </strong><em>–n.</em> a sharp rise in the price or cost of something</p>
<p><strong>tinker </strong><em>–v.</em> to work on something little by little</p>
<p><strong>radical </strong><em>–adj.</em> a serious or extreme idea or path to complete a job</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Market Grows for Costly ‘Fine Water’  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/market-grows-for-costly-fine-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>At a meeting in April in Athens, Greece, drink experts looked carefully at the liquid in their glasses. They held them up to the light. They tasted and, sometimes, spit them out into containers. And they discussed the mineral content and <strong>purity</strong>.</p>
<p>But these experts were not tasting wine. Instead, they were tasting "fine water."</p>
<p>The experts are members of the Fine Water Society. They had come together in Athens for the yearly tasting competition. Their activity reflects the growing market for <strong>luxury</strong> water—with some bottles costing over $100 per liter.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mineral water sommelier Martin Riese, right, examines a glass of fine water during an International Water Tasting Competition, in Athens, Greece, on Wednesday, April 26, 2023, accompanied by Michael Mascha, founder of the Fine Water Society. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-9ce4-08dbeb69c2a6_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mineral water sommelier Martin Riese, right, examines a glass of fine water during an International Water Tasting Competition, in Athens, Greece, on Wednesday, April 26, 2023, accompanied by Michael Mascha, founder of the Fine Water Society. (AP Photo/Petros Giannakouris)</span></div>
<p>Companies collect the so-called "fine water" from sources such as volcanic rock in Hawaii, melting ice from glaciers in Norway, and drops of <strong>mist</strong> from forests in the Amazon or the island of Tasmania. The most costly water is sold in bottles made with special glass painted with artwork.</p>
<p>At their meeting, Fine Water Society members learned about the environments from which the water is collected. And they compare the total <strong>dissolved</strong> solids, or TDS.</p>
<p>Waters with a low TDS are like rain that has not yet touched the earth. Those with high TDS — such as Vichy mineral water from hot springs in France and Catalonia, in northeastern Spain — have high mineral content that may include calcium, magnesium, potassium or sodium, among others.</p>
<p>A few restaurants in countries such as Spain and the United States now have <strong>menus</strong> that match food with certain kinds of fine water. Water with high TDS, for example, might go with beef. Low TDS, more like rainwater, might go with fish.</p>
<p>Ganesh Iyer is an Indian businessman who has worked in the beverage, or drink, industry for years. After he saw increased interest in non-alcoholic drinks, he studied to become a drink expert, also known as a water sommelier.</p>
<p>He is now the <strong>managing</strong> partner of Veen Waters India. The company bottles natural mineral water in the Himalayan country of Bhutan and sends it by truck to India. Veen Waters is mostly served in costly hotels and restaurants. It costs $6 a bottle, about a day's pay for an Indian laborer.</p>
<p>Veen Waters is exporting about 240,000 bottles of water into India each month. Iyer thinks the company has reached only about 10 percent of the possible market so far.</p>
<p><strong>Water-stressed India</strong></p>
<p>The story of water, however, is very different for many people in India.</p>
<p>The World Bank reports that India is one of the most water-stressed countries in the world. To get more water, the country has built huge plants to remove salt from seawater. Other countries, including Singapore, are collecting and cleaning up storm and wastewater to try to solve their water problems.</p>
<p>But these kinds of solutions are only used in some places, and the increasing need for water could lead to more disagreements.</p>
<p>At the same time, those in the fine water industry see their activity as part of an effort to protect the environment and its clean water.</p>
<p>Michael Mascha is a co-founder of the Fine Water Society. He told <em>The Associated Press</em>, "I think what we do is we raise the <strong>awareness</strong> of water — and if you <strong>cherish</strong> something, you're more likely to protect it."</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith</p>
<p><em>Martha Irvine wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>purity</strong> <em>-n. </em>clearness, being without unwanted elements or aspects</p>
<p><strong>luxury </strong><em>-n. </em>something expensive which is not necessary but which gives pleasure</p>
<p><strong>mist </strong><em>-n. </em>very small drops of water in the air, similar to fog</p>
<p><strong>dissolved </strong><em>-adj. </em>mixed into a liquid</p>
<p><strong>menu </strong><em>-n. </em>a list of food and drink at a restaurant</p>
<p><strong>manage </strong><em>-v. </em>to direct or be in charge of</p>
<p><strong>awareness </strong><em>-n. </em>knowledge of something and having it in mind</p>
<p><strong>cherish </strong><em>-v. </em>to highly value or appreciate</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Media Program Helps Young People in Washington, DC  (2023/11/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/media-program-helps-young-people-in-washington-dc.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A 17-year-old student in Washington, D.C. recently got the chance to <strong>interview </strong>retired American basketball star Magic Johnson. As a result, Magic offered to pay for the student's college education – all of it.</p>
<p>Jordan Williams studies at Bard High School Early College, a D.C. public school. The teenager is also in the city's Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, run by D.C.'s Parks and Recreation Department.</p>
<p>As a member of the Deanwood media program, Jordan attended a <strong>press conference</strong> at The Boy's and Girl's Club to interview Magic Johnson, a co-owner of the city's Washington Commanders football team.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Jordan Williams, a student in the Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, interviews basketball legend Magic Johnson in Washington, D.C. (Courtesy Photo) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-fe3a-08dbebc5a880_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Jordan Williams, a student in the Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program, interviews basketball legend Magic Johnson in Washington, D.C. (Courtesy Photo) </span></div>
<p>Standing with professional reporters, Jordan asked the famous athlete why he wanted to visit a youth club in Washington, D.C. Magic answered that he "wanted to make a difference." And he meant it. He offered Jordan a full scholarship on the spot.</p>
<p>Jordan: "You never know who's in the room. You never know who's watching. You never know who's listening. The fact that I was able to ask that question, that people were able to hear it and Magic Johnson was so impressed by it ... he was able to give me a scholarship."</p>
<p>VOA Learning English recently spoke with Jordan as well as Salih Williams (no relation to Jordan), the director of the media program.</p>
<p><strong>Why start a youth media program?</strong></p>
<p>Williams established the Deanwood program to address what he describes as a "<strong>language barrier</strong>" between local media and teenagers in two areas of the city -- Ward 7 and Ward 8. Crime is higher in those wards than in others.</p>
<p>"I knew the value of developing young voices. ... So, in the beginning it was just to develop communication skills but also to <strong>engage</strong> them in news ... because I felt a lot of times, the only time that people in Ward 7 and Ward 8 engage with media people was when there was a tragedy or a death."</p>
<p>Students in the program learn researching, communication, and interviewing skills as well as how to engage with the news media. The students complete 30 to 40 interviews a year. Williams says these skills will help the students whether they decide to stay in journalism or go into a different field.</p>
<p>The program has also become a<strong> gateway</strong> to college. Since the program began in 2016, 38 of its students have gone to college -- 23 on full scholarships.</p>
<p><strong>Network &amp; community</strong></p>
<p>Ayonlah Carter is a graduate of the program.</p>
<p>"I feel like, it kind of gives us the opportunity to kind of express ourselves or just voice our opinions. And in a bigger sense, this is a group with, you know, Black and Brown kids. That carries weight in itself. So, it's nice to be in a space where we're uplifted. But it also feels like we're making a difference. And I feel like in 10, 15 years from now we're going to see a lot more Black journalists or just people in media."</p>
<p>She says one of the best things about the program is the community of students. She says they look out for each other and have become "found family."</p>
<p>"I think we all just reach out and look out for each other. And I think that's what valued most. You know, some of us don't have the best backgrounds. But we still kind of pull each other up or help out where we can."</p>
<p>Ayonlah said her mother died when Ayonlah was only 10 years old. When she turned 17, she said her family situation changed so much that she had to leave. She wasn't sure what she was going to do. She said the media program and its founder Salih Williams gave her life direction.</p>
<p>"Coming upon, like, going to college, I really didn't know where I was going to go or what I was going to do. But (through) this program and (through) Salih ... I was able to go to college on a full scholarship and everything was taken care of."</p>
<p>A saying<strong> </strong>Salih Williams likes to use with the students is: "Your network is your net worth." Jordan agrees. He adds that connections are important in succeeding and growing.</p>
<p>"Just being treated like we matter. There (are) people there to listen to us, listen to our questions. Anything we need, they're there to help. I think that's what makes the program so special."</p>
<p>Jordan says he enjoys hearing success stories from people who share a similar background. Jordan hasn't even started college, but he already has his sights on being a <strong>role model</strong> some day, like those he has learned from.</p>
<p>Ayonlah Carter says she is also excited about her future ... wherever she ends up.</p>
<p>"I think, I'm just more excited to see where I end up at. Will I be on the news? Will I be writing my own books? Like, I genuinely don't know. And I think I'm in a space now where I <strong>trying my hand at</strong> everything."</p>
<p>The media program began as part of Washington, D.C.'s Summer Youth Employment Program. Now, it also includes a winter program which is administered by the Department of Employment Services' Office of Youth Programming.</p>
<p><strong>U.S. Congressional connection </strong></p>
<p>The Deanwood Radio Broadcast Youth Journalism Program partners with the Congressional Award Foundation.</p>
<p>Its website <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.congressionalaward.org/cafe-radio-podcast/">CongressionalAward.org</a> explains that "students will gain direct access to members of the Board of Directors, who will serve as <strong>mentors</strong> and guide the students through the Congressional Award program."</p>
<p>If students finish the required number of hours within the Congressional Award program, they can earn Congressional Award Certificates and Medals.</p>
<p>From Washington, D.C., I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>interview </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>a meeting at which information is obtained (as by a reporter) from a person</p>
<p><strong>press conference</strong> <em>– n. </em>an interview or announcement given by a public figure to the press by appointment</p>
<p><strong>language barrier </strong><em>– n. </em>a difficulty for people communicating because they speak in different ways or speak different languages</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong><em>– v. </em>to deal with especially at length</p>
<p><strong>gateway </strong><em>– n. </em>a passage into or out of a place or state</p>
<p><strong>role model</strong> <em>– n. </em>a person whose behavior in a particular role is imitated by others</p>
<p><strong>try your hand at (something) – </strong><em>idiom </em>To attempt to do something new; to try something for the first time.</p>
<p><strong>mentor </strong><em>– n. </em>a trusted counselor or guide</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>All Trapped Workers Pulled from Collapsed Tunnel in India  (2023/11/29) | 印度坍塌隧道被困工人获救</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/all-trapped-workers-pulled-from-collapsed-tunnel-in-india.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rescuers pulled out all 41 workers who were trapped for 17 days in a mountain tunnel in northern India on Tuesday.<br/>
周二，救援人员救出了印度北部一条山区隧道中被困17天的41名工人。</p>
<p>A crowd of people around the tunnel cheered and shouted, "Long live mother India." Officials put flowers around the necks of the workers as the crowd celebrated with firecrackers.<br/>
隧道周围人群欢呼着喊道：“祖国万岁。”当人群用鞭炮庆祝时，官员们把鲜花戴到工人的脖子上。</p>
<p>Nitin Gadkari, the minister of road transport and highways, said on X, "I am very happy that all the 41 trapped workers have come out and their lives have been saved."<br/>
印度道路运输和公路部长尼廷·加德卡里在X上说：“我很高兴41名被困工人全部出来了，他们的生命得到了拯救。”</p>
<p>The workers were pulled out through a passageway made from welded pipes that had been pushed through dirt and rocks to reach them.<br/>
工人们被从一条由焊接管道制成的通道中拉了出来，这些管道穿过了泥土和岩石到达他们身边。</p>
<p>One of the rescuers, Devender, told New Delhi Television that "the trapped workers were overjoyed when they spotted us in the tunnel. Some rushed toward me and hugged me."<br/>
其中一名救援人员德维德告诉新德里电视台，“被困工人在隧道里看见我们时欣喜若狂。一些人冲过来拥抱我。”</p>
<p>A landslide on November 12 caused part of a tunnel they were building in Uttarkashi to collapse. And they were stuck about 200 meters from the entrance. The men survived for more than two weeks on food and oxygen that was sent through steel pipes only 15 centimeters wide.<br/>
11月12日的山体滑坡导致他们在乌塔卡什修建的一条隧道部分坍塌。他们被困在离入口大约200米的地方。这些人靠通过只有15厘米宽的钢管输送的食物和氧气存活了两个多星期。</p>
<p>Kirti Panwar is a state government spokesperson. Panwar said a large drilling machine opened up about 47 of the 60 meters needed to reach the workers before it broke down on Friday. Rescuers then worked by hand overnight from Monday into Tuesday using digging tools and drills.<br/>
科尔蒂·潘瓦尔是州政府发言人。潘瓦尔说，周五一台大型钻机打开了工人所需的60米中的47米，然后发生了故障。从周一到周二，救援人员使用挖掘工具和钻机连夜徒手工作。</p>
<p>Many of the workers who were trapped are migrant workers who came from around India for the job. As word spread that the workers were close to freeing the trapped men, family members traveled long distances to gather at the tunnel and waited to see their loved ones.<br/>
许多被困的工人都是来自印度各地的外来工。随着工人们即将救出被困人员的消息传开，他们的家人长途跋涉聚集在隧道旁，等待见到他们的亲人。</p>
<p>Officials said the rescued workers were treated inside the 13-meter-wide tunnel. After a first health check, they were taken to a hospital about 30 kilometers away.<br/>
官方表示，获救的工人在13米宽的隧道内接受了治疗。在第一次健康检查后，他们被送往大约30公里外的一家医院。</p>
<p>"Their condition is first-class and absolutely fine ... just like yours or mine." said Wakil Hassan, a rescue team leader.<br/>
救援队队长瓦基勒·哈桑说：“他们的情况很好，绝对健康……就像你我一样。”</p>
<p>The tunnel is part of the Char Dham highway. It is one of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's largest projects. The plan is to build a network of roads covering almost 900 kilometers to connect four important Hindu religious sites. Some building experts, however, are concerned about the project. They say the work could create more landslides and hurt some small towns in the Himalayas which are already built on top of landslide debris.<br/>
该隧道是查尔丹高速公路的一部分。这是总理纳伦德拉·莫迪最大的项目之一。该计划是建立一个覆盖近900公里的道路网络，以连接四个重要的印度教宗教场所。然而，一些建筑专家对该项目表示担忧。他们说，这项工作可能会造成更多的山体滑坡，并伤害喜马拉雅山脉的一些小镇，这些小镇本身已经建在滑坡废墟上。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Return to Alzheimer's Vaccines  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/researchers-return-to-alzheimer-s-vaccines.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers are renewing efforts to find Alzheimer's disease treatments that remove harmful proteins from the brain. Such vaccines could possibly offer an easier and lower-cost choice for millions of people, several scientists and industry leaders say.</p>
<p>The brain-wasting disease causes thinking and memory problems.</p>
<p>The U.S. government website ClinicalTrials.gov shows that at least seven possible Alzheimer's vaccines are in human testing or have completed such trials. The experimental treatments are designed to use the body's natural defense system<strong> </strong>to destroy Alzheimer's-linked proteins in the brain. The proteins are beta amyloid and tau.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A doctor points out evidence of Alzheimer's disease on PET scans at the Center for Alzheimer Research and Treatment (CART) at Brigham And Women's Hospital in Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., March 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1a2ec41a-e74a-4f60-9b2f-5d5cd4a7f6fc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A doctor points out evidence of Alzheimer's disease on PET scans at the Center for Alzheimer Research and Treatment (CART) at Brigham And Women's Hospital in Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., March 30, 2023. (REUTERS/Brian Snyder)</span></div>
<p>The renewed interest in Alzheimer's vaccines follows a promising first attempt more than 20 years ago. That vaccine work halted after six percent of study volunteers developed a life-threatening brain condition called meningoencephalitis.</p>
<p>Researchers then found a safer method using closely targeted <strong>synthetic</strong> <strong>antibodies </strong>in patients. These antibodies avoid extreme <strong>immune system</strong> reaction.</p>
<p>Health care companies Eisai and Biogen launched a new medication called Leqembi and health care company Eli Lilly launched Donanemab. American government drug experts are reviewing the treatments.</p>
<p>The reported success of the drugs has strengthened the theories that amyloid removal is critical to fighting Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Scientists believe they now understand what went wrong with the first vaccine. They are testing shots they hope will cause an immune reaction without causing too much <strong>inflammation. </strong></p>
<p>Dr. Reisa Sperling is an Alzheimer's researcher at Mass General Brigham in Boston. She said she believes vaccines will play an important part as researchers look to prevent Alzheimer's. She said, "I'm very <strong>keen</strong> that that's where we need to go."</p>
<p>Sperling is leading a <strong>trial </strong>in people with Alzheimer's proteins in their brains but showing no signs of related problems. She is considering vaccines for her next study in people who have Alzheimer's proteins in their blood, but not enough to show on imaging of the brain.</p>
<p>Alzheimer's vaccines are still in the early stages and will require large, years-long trials to show they work.</p>
<p>But a vaccine given two or four times a year could offer a lower-cost solution than Leqembi. Leqembi is given twice a month. That could expand available treatment among the estimated 39 million people around the world with Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Dr. Walter Koroshetz is director of the part of U.S. National Institutes of Health that deals with disorders involving the brain. He said of the vaccines, "They could be worldwide, and not that expensive."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Julie Steenhuysen reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong>– <em>adj</em>. made by combining different substances: not natural</p>
<p><strong>antibodies </strong>– <em>n</em>. a substance produced by the body to fight disease</p>
<p><strong>immune system </strong>– <em>n</em>. the system that protects your body from diseases and infections</p>
<p><strong>inflammation </strong>– <em>n</em>. a condition in which a part of your body becomes red, swollen, and painful</p>
<p><strong>keen </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very excited about and interested in something</p>
<p><strong>trial </strong>– <em>n</em>. a test of the quality, value, or usefulness of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What the White House Looks Like for Christmas  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/what-the-white-house-looks-like-for-christmas.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>U.S. first lady Jill Biden wants everyone who visits the White House around Christmas to feel like a kid again.</p>
<p>On Monday, Biden held a gathering to show the White House Christmas <strong>decorations</strong>. "Magic, Wonder and Joy" is the <strong>theme</strong> this year. It will be the Bidens' third Christmas holiday in the White House.</p>
<p>"Each room on display is designed to capture the...<strong>delight</strong> and imagination of our childhoods," the first lady said. She also thanked some 300 people who volunteered to decorate the White House.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Holiday decorations adorn the Grand Foyer of the White House for the 2023 theme Magic, Wonder, and Joy, Monday, Nov. 27, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-2980-08dbef7720c1_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Holiday decorations adorn the Grand Foyer of the White House for the 2023 theme "Magic, Wonder, and Joy," Monday, Nov. 27, 2023, in Washington. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)</span></div>
<p>There are oversized holiday candies and other sweets in the hallway. There is a Santa Clause with eight reindeer suspended near the entrance.</p>
<p>Throughout two floors of the public area of the White House are reminders from the poem popularly known as <em>‘Twas the Night Before Christmas</em>. The U.S. Library of Congress helped with copies of the poem from the past 200 years.</p>
<p>The traditional gingerbread White House includes a large sugar cookie copy of the book opened to a page that says, "Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night." The book contains 40 sheets of sugar cookie dough. Another 40 sheets of gingerbread dough are used for the house with 14 kilograms of chocolate and 23 kilograms of royal icing.</p>
<p>The oversized decorations are meant to bring feelings of joy to children at this time of the year, White House aides said. Children of military families were among the first members of the public to see the decorations. And they were also treated to an afternoon performance of the Disney musical performance <em>Frozen</em>.</p>
<p>One of the first Christmas trees visitors will see upon entering the White House is decorated with golden wooden stars. The ornaments include the names of fallen service members.</p>
<p>The official White House Christmas tree is a 5.6-meter-tall tree that stands in its usual place in the Blue Room. The tree is decorated with cheerful pictures from across the country. A toy train runs around its base.</p>
<p>The State Dining Room has been turned into Santa's workshop. There are workbenches for Santa's helpers, the elves. Stools and ladders circle Christmas trees and gifts-in-progress round out the display.</p>
<p>In the library, the moons and the stars are ready to honor the tradition of bedtime stories. The China Room has been turned into a shop of baked goods. The Vermeil Room celebrates music with a display of a toy Marine Band.</p>
<p>In her prepared remarks, the first lady said she knows that magic, wonder and joy can be hard to find, especially as the days grow shorter, the weather turns colder. She said, "Our hearts grow heavy in the face of a <strong>tumultuous</strong> world."</p>
<p>"But it's in these times, when we are searching for hope and healing, that we need those points of light the most, that we need each other the most," she said. "It's in these times that I hope you remember, if even just for a moment or a season, how you saw the world as a child."</p>
<p>Overall, the White House uses 98 Christmas trees, nearly 34,000 ornaments, over 22,000 bells and more than 350 candles for the display. And they are lit with 142,500 lights.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Darlene Superville reported this for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>decoration</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>an object or ornament that is used to make a place more attractive and interesting</p>
<p><strong>theme</strong> <em>–v.</em> the main subject or repeated idea that is shown with objects in a place or with words in a piece of writing</p>
<p><strong>delight </strong><em>–n.</em> a feeling of happiness</p>
<p><strong>tumultuous </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving violence, confusion and disorder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Merriam-Webster Chooses ‘Authentic’ as Word of the Year  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/merriam-webster-chooses-authentic-as-word-of-the-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The <strong>dictionary</strong> company <em>Merriam-Webster</em> chose the word "authentic" as its word of the year for 2023.</p>
<p>Something that is authentic is real or true.</p>
<p>The publisher celebrated its 20th anniversary of choosing a word of the year on Monday. Speaking to <em>The Associated Press,</em> or AP, dictionary editor Peter Sokolowski said the world is in a "crisis of authenticity" in 2023. "What we realize," he said, "is that when we question authenticity, we value it even more."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Merriam-Webster dictionary sits atop their citation files at the dictionary publisher's offices on Dec. 9, 2014, in Springfield, Mass. Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2023 is " authentic.="" file="" photo="" savoia="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/32ea75dd-2180-4c01-8c34-4a9ae45c8b33_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Merriam-Webster dictionary sits atop their citation files at the dictionary publisher's offices on Dec. 9, 2014, in Springfield, Mass. Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2023 is "authentic." (AP Photo/Stephan Savoia, File)</span></div>
<p>Sokolowski said the word is often looked up on <em>Merriam-Webster</em>'s website, but in 2023 it was searched for even more than usual.</p>
<p>He noted that authentic is an important word in a world where artificial intelligence software permits people to create "deepfakes" or false videos that look real.</p>
<p>Often, Sokolowski said, words become "words of the year" because searches <strong>match</strong> world events. However, this year, there was a general increased interest in the word "authentic."</p>
<p>The AP noted that authenticity was a popular subject for discussion in 2023. People such as Taylor Swift and Prince Harry looked for authenticity in their performances and writing. Even businessman Elon Musk discussed authenticity at an event in February when he urged company leaders and politicians to operate their own social media accounts in order to "speak authentically."</p>
<p>Authenticity is important in education, Sokolowski said. He said we are in a time when students can use artificial intelligence tools such as ChatGPT to complete writing assignments to avoid work.</p>
<p>"We don't always trust what we see anymore," he said.</p>
<p>The dictionary includes a number of descriptions to help people understand the word's meaning. It notes something that is authentic is "not false," "true to one's own <strong>personality</strong>," and "something made or done the same way as an <strong>original</strong>."</p>
<p><strong>How the word is picked</strong></p>
<p>Merriam-Webster says it filters out some common search words such as "effect" and "affect" that are always among the top searches. The online word game "Wordle" also increases searches for some words as players check letters and words before they play them.</p>
<p>Some other possible words for 2023 included "X" after Musk changed the name of the social media service formerly known as Twitter. Others include "EGOT" after the actress Viola Davis won a Grammy award and "elemental" after Pixar released a new movie in June.</p>
<p>However, the company settled on authentic one year after choosing "gaslighting." Gaslighting is a word that is used to discuss the act of misleading someone over a long period of time. In a way, it is the opposite of authentic.</p>
<p><strong>Other popular words</strong></p>
<p>Other words that were popular in 2023 but did not win "word of the year" included "rizz," a slang word that has to do with charm or appeal. It is a shortened form of the word charisma.</p>
<p>"Implode" became a popular search in 2023 after a vessel used for undersea exploration was lost in June. Experts say the Titan vessel likely imploded or broke apart because of the high water pressure in the deep sea.</p>
<p>"Coronation" was looked up often in May when Charles III was crowned King of England.</p>
<p>"Kibbutz" is a word that came up in recent weeks after the terror group Hamas attacked the Israeli "communal farms or settlements" near Gaza on October 7.</p>
<p>You can visit Merriam-Webster's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/wordplay/word-of-the-year">website</a> to look at more words that did not quite <strong>make the cut</strong> to become "word of the year."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on The Associated Press story.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dictionary </strong>–n. a book that contains definitions of words in a language</p>
<p><strong>match </strong>–v. to have two things that are related to each other or are linked in some way</p>
<p><strong>personality </strong>–n. the qualities that make a person who they are</p>
<p><strong>original </strong>–adj. something that is produced for the first time and is not a copy of something else</p>
<p><strong>make the cut </strong>–v. (phrasal) to continue to the next level of a competition; to do enough to continue</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Deal Reached to Extend Cease-fire in Israel-Hamas War  (2023/11/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/deal-reached-to-extend-cease-fire-in-israel-hamas-war.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Negotiators have reached a deal to extend a cease-fire between Israeli and Hamas forces in Gaza.</p>
<p>A Qatari official <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/majedalansari/status/1729177252473274539">announced</a> Monday on the social media service X the agreement would continue an existing truce for another two days. Qatar and Egypt have led the negotiations surrounding the ongoing conflict.</p>
<p>The new deal came on the final day of a four-day ceasefire. Negotiators said they were also preparing for new exchanges of hostages and prisoners.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A Palestinian walks in Gaza City on Monday, Nov. 27, 2023. on the fourth day of the temporary ceasefire between Hamas and Israel. (AP Photo/Mohammed Hajjar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-72e0-08dbef850349_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A Palestinian walks in Gaza City on Monday, Nov. 27, 2023. on the fourth day of the temporary ceasefire between Hamas and Israel. (AP Photo/Mohammed Hajjar)</span></div>
<p>Israel had no immediate comment on the new truce. But Israeli officials had said the country would be open to extending the cease-fire by one day for every 10 additional hostages released. Hamas confirmed it had agreed to a two-day cease-fire extension.</p>
<p>Hamas freed 17 more hostages on Sunday – 14 Israelis and three Thais – in a third exchange under the earlier four-day truce. Israel released 39 Palestinian prisoners in the latest exchange.</p>
<p>About 240 hostages were captured by Hamas in its October 7 attack in southern Israel that started the war. So far, 62 hostages have been released. One was freed by Israeli forces and two were found dead inside Gaza. At least 117 Palestinians were freed under the latest truce.</p>
<p>An Israeli government spokesperson said the total number of hostages still held in Gaza as of Monday was 184. This included 14 foreigners and 80 Israelis with <strong>dual</strong> nationality.</p>
<p>Last week's cease-fire agreement – which was set to end Monday night – brought the first halt in fighting between Israel and Hamas in Gaza.</p>
<p>The Hamas-controlled Health Ministry in Gaza says more than 13,300 Palestinians have been killed since the start of the war, many of them women and children. The ministry does not differentiate between civilians and military-force deaths.</p>
<p>Israeli officials have said about 1,200 people have been killed in Israel, mostly during the first attacks by Hamas. At least 77 soldiers have been killed in Israel's ground offensive in Gaza.</p>
<p>An Egyptian official told Reuters news agency the new truce would permit the release of about 20 Israeli hostages in exchange for 60 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>
<p>The European Union's foreign policy chief, Josep Borrell, told reporters he hopes a truce extension will permit the international community to work on a lasting political solution.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said the country planned to push ahead with the war at the end of the cease-fires.</p>
<p>Wide areas of Hamas-ruled Gaza have been destroyed by Israeli air strikes and bombings. The war also led to a humanitarian crisis because of shortages of food, fuel, water and medicine.</p>
<p>The latest truce did lead to some increased shipments of fuel and supplies into Gaza. But aid groups say much more is needed to help the immediate needs of the 2.3 million Palestinians there.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dual </strong><em>– adj. </em>having two parts</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Laser Communication Test Gets Data from 16 Million Kilometers Away  (2023/11/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/nasa-laser-communication-test-gets-data-from-16-million-kilometers-away.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>NASA has successfully tested a laser-based communication method that sent data over 16 million kilometers. The American space agency hopes the system will greatly improve data links between Earth and spacecraft exploring deep space.</p>
<p>The method, called Deep Space Optical Communications (DSOC), is being tested aboard NASA's Psyche spacecraft. The agency <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-to-launch-spacecraft-to-observe-metal-rich-asteroid/7298628.html">launched</a> Psyche last month to observe a mostly metal <strong>asteroid.</strong></p>
<p>DSOC uses lasers to send large amounts of data very long distances. Traditionally, NASA has depended on radio frequency communications to send data to, and collect data from, deep space. But now the agency seeks to improve its systems to support new technologies and future trips to the moon and beyond.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="NASA's Psyche spacecraft is shown in a clean room at the Astrotech Space Operations facility near the agency's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Dec. 8, 2022. (NASA/Ben Smegelsky)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-8988-08dbeba6d103_cx5_cy2_cw94_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">NASA's Psyche spacecraft is shown in a clean room at the Astrotech Space Operations facility near the agency's Kennedy Space Center in Florida on Dec. 8, 2022. (NASA/Ben Smegelsky)</span></div>
<p>Laser communications, also known as optical communications, enable the fast <strong>transmission</strong> of data over long distances. In an explanation of lasers, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/technology/laser-communications-empowering-more-data-than-ever-before/">explained</a> the technology will permit "up to 100 times more data to be transmitted back to Earth than current radio frequency systems."</p>
<p>NASA estimates it would take about nine weeks to transmit a complete map of Mars back to Earth with current radio frequency systems. But with a laser-based method, the time would be cut to nine days. Also, laser communications equipment takes up less space in spacecraft and uses less energy.</p>
<p>Scientists from NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory in California recently announced a successful test of the DSOC method. The team said a device<strong> </strong>on the Psyche spacecraft was able to successfully send and receive data messages with a telescope in Southern California. NASA said the laser system works with signals that exist at near-infrared wavelengths.</p>
<p>The data transmitted by laser takes the form of bits – the smallest pieces of data a computer can process. These bits are <strong>embedded</strong> inside the laser's photons.</p>
<p>The NASA team <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/psyche-mission/nasas-deep-space-optical-comm-demo-sends-receives-first-data/">described</a> the successful data signal transmissions as "first light." The experiment represented "the farthest-ever demonstration of optical communications," at about 16 million kilometers.</p><p>Trudy Kortes is the director of Technology Demonstrations for the Space Technology Mission Directorate at NASA Headquarters in Washington. She said in a statement she sees the first light event as one “of many critical DSOC <strong>milestones</strong>” to look forward to in the coming months. The communication success is another step forward, she said, “in support of humanity’s next ... goal: sending humans to Mars.”</p>
<p>Optical communication has already been demonstrated in low Earth orbit and on the moon. But the research team working on the DSOC project said it was the first time this method has been successfully tested in deep space.</p>
<p>Abi Biswas is a project technologist on the DSOC team. He called the latest laser test “a tremendous <strong>achievement</strong>.” The team was, Biswas said, “able to send some data, meaning we were able to exchange ‘bits of light’ from and to deep space.”</p>
<p>The team said laser communication over long distances can be difficult as it requires complete exactness in following signals and linking up transmitters and receivers over millions of kilometers.</p>
<p>Project leaders say when Psyche is at its farthest from our planet, DSOC’s near-infrared photons will take about 20 minutes to travel back to Earth. During the successful experiment on November 14, DSOC took about 50 seconds to send the data from Psyche to Earth.</p>
<p>Jason Mitchell is a director in NASA’s Space Communications and Navigation program. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/psyche-mission/nasas-deep-space-optical-comm-demo-sends-receives-first-data/">called</a> optical communication “a <strong>boon</strong> for scientists and researchers who always want more from their space missions.” Mitchell said better data transmission methods will improve human exploration of deep space” and lead to many more data discoveries in the future.</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story, based on reports from NASA. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>an object made of rock and metal that orbits the sun, but is smaller than planets</p>
<p><strong>transmit </strong><em>– v. to send</em></p>
<p><strong>embed </strong><em>– v. </em>to fix something firmly into a substance</p>
<p><strong>milestone</strong><em> – n. </em>an important event in history or the development of something or someone<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>achievement </strong><em>– n. </em>something good that you achieve: to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
<p><strong>boon</strong><em> – n. </em>something helpful that improves your life</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Toymakers Aim More Products at Older People  (2023/11/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/toymakers-aim-more-products-at-older-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Toymakers are developing new games – and changing old ones – to target a different group: people over 65 years old.</p>
<p>Toy producers suggest the products could help older people increase their brain skills as well as reduce loneliness. However, some experts have raised doubts about their claims.</p>
<p>Toymaker Hasbro signed a deal with Ageless Innovation — which designs toys with older people in mind — to come out with new versions of games such as Scrabble, Trivial Pursuit and Life. The products offer larger letters that are easier to see and bigger game pieces.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Scrabble game with larger tiles is displayed at the 2023 Toy Fair, in New York's Javits Center, Monday, Oct. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2073d852-1559-4393-86a5-a7f24222e383_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Scrabble game with larger tiles is displayed at the 2023 Toy Fair, in New York's Javits Center, Monday, Oct. 2, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>The new versions of Life and Trivial Pursuit also have developed their content so that younger and older people alike can play. For example, the answer to a question in Trivial Pursuit about exercise can be Jack LaLanne or Zumba, depending on the player's age.</p>
<p>Jack LaLanne was a famous health and exercise person for a large part of the 20th century. Zumba has become a more popular exercise in recent times.</p>
<p>Educational Insights, which produces educational toys for young children, is including images of older people in its marketing efforts. The move came after the company noticed last year that its toys like Kanoodle and BrainBolt were popular with older customers in online reviews. Next year, Educational Insights will release a new BrainBolt Boost that has bigger buttons and is more simplified.</p>
<p><strong>Changes in behavior </strong></p>
<p>The new products come as the pandemic has changed toy-buying behaviors in the United States. Long before the pandemic, many adults purchased Legos or collectible items to connect with their inner child.</p>
<p>But the pandemic not only increased the <strong>trend</strong>, it also increased feelings of loneliness among adults when they were in lockdown. Many toy companies found adults using animals and robotic pets as companions.</p>
<p>Market research company Circana reports that toy sales are increasingly targeted toward adult buyers. About 5 percent of the total U.S. toy sales are for males ages 35 and over, up 13 percent since last year. About 4 percent of total U.S. toy sales are for females ages 35 and over, up 9 percent since last year.</p>
<p>While Circana does not examine sales data for the over -65 group, it estimated grandparents who bought a toy for their grandchild have big spending power. These grandparents made up 19 percent, or $7.8 billion, of total toy sales in the 12 months that ended in September. And grandparents spent on average 7 percent more per toy than the total market during the fourth quarter of 2022, the highest amount spent across all buyer groups.</p>
<p><strong>Can new games help? </strong></p>
<p>Ben Swartz, 92, lives with his 85-year-old wife in a retirement community in Des Moines, Iowa. Swartz ran 14 toy stores in the 1970s. He has noticed some of the new offerings from the toy industry, and he approves of the moves.</p>
<p>Swartz plays games five days a week, including bridge and poker with his friends. He said the games help his mind, otherwise, he said, he would worry that his "mind would start to go a little bit <strong>stale</strong>."</p>
<p>Still, while some scientists welcome toymakers paying attention to older buyers, they also warn of these products' <strong>limitations</strong>.</p>
<p>Neil Charness and Walter Boot, both of Florida State University, worked together to test the idea that brain games like crossword puzzles help <strong>preserve </strong>mental abilities such as reasoning or thinking, also known as cognitive function.</p>
<p>They found that people get better in the specific skills of the game if they play over and over again. But the games do not translate to the cognitive skills needed for everyday living activities, such as job performance or maintaining independent living, they said.</p>
<p>The researchers also said that there is limited evidence to date that playing games can greatly reduce loneliness.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Anne D'Innocenzio reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>trend </strong><em>– n.</em> a general direction of change</p>
<p><strong>stale</strong> <em>– adj.</em> not as strong, effective, or energetic as before</p>
<p><strong>limitation</strong> <em>– n.</em> something that controls how much of something is possible or allowed</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong><em>– v.</em> to keep (something) in its original state or in good condition</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ukraine’s Coal Mines Turn to Women during Wartime  (2023/11/27) | 乌克兰煤矿战时求助于女性</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/ukraine-s-coal-mines-turn-to-women-during-wartime.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>After more than a thousand of its workers went to fight Russia's invasion, a coal mine in eastern Ukraine needed workers. Its answer was to permit women to work underground for the first time in its history.<br/>
在一千多名工人前往抗击俄罗斯入侵后，乌克兰东部的一座煤矿急需工人。它的解决办法就是历史上第一次允许女性在地下工作。</p>
<p>Over a hundred accepted the offer.<br/>
超过一百人接受了这份工作。</p>
<p>"I took this job because the war started and there were no other jobs," 22-year-old Krystyna said. The mine's officials asked Reuters not to give the last names of those who talked to the news service.<br/>
22岁的克雷斯蒂娜说：“我接受这份工作是因为战争开始了，没有其他工作可做。”该矿官员要求路透社不要透露接受采访人员的姓氏。</p>
<p>For five months, Krystyna has worked as a technician 470 meters below ground. She works on the small electric trains that move workers more than four kilometers down the mine.<br/>
克雷斯蒂娜在地下470米的地方做了五个月的技术员。她在小型电动火车上工作，这些火车将工人运送到井下四公里多的地方。</p>
<p>She agreed to take the job after overcoming her fear of leaving her four-year-old son, Denys, at home with her mother. Her hometown of Pavlohrad is 100 kilometers from the front but it is often hit by Russian missiles.<br/>
在克服了把四岁的儿子丹尼斯留在家里和母亲在一起的恐惧后，她同意接受这份工作。她的家乡帕夫洛赫拉德距离前线100公里，但经常被俄罗斯导弹击中。</p>
<p>The work is interesting but difficult, she said. The equipment is heavy and the steam is not easy to deal with. But the pay is good and she feels a sense of duty to stay and do her part for those who have gone to fight.<br/>
她说，这项工作有趣而艰难。设备很重，蒸汽不容易处理。但薪水很高，她觉得有责任留下来，为那些去战斗的人尽自己的一份力量。</p>
<p>Her older brother worked in the same mine. He joined the army two weeks after the start of the invasion, Krystyna said. She added she worries greatly about him.<br/>
她的哥哥在同一个矿井工作。克雷斯蒂娜说，他在入侵开始两周后参军。她补充说，她非常担心他。</p>
<p>She said, "Our boys were taken to the front, and now we need to support them: there is no one else to work in the mine now."<br/>
她说：“我们的小伙子们被带到了前线，现在我们需要支持他们：现在没有其他人在矿井里工作了。”</p>
<p>Ukraine's coal industry was once one of the largest in Europe. It has suffered many years of decline since the collapse of the Soviet Union. The government-controlled market which it supplied suddenly was not there.<br/>
乌克兰的煤炭工业曾经是欧洲最大的工业之一。自苏联解体以来，它经历了多年的衰落。由它供应的政府管制市场突然不存在了。</p>
<p>Russia-backed militias in eastern Ukraine took over many coal-rich areas in 2014. After the 2022 invasion, Russia occupied even more mines.<br/>
2014年，俄罗斯支持的乌克兰东部民兵占领了许多煤炭丰富的地区。2022年入侵后，俄罗斯占领了更多的煤矿。</p>
<p>DTEK is the mine's owner and Ukraine's largest private energy company. It says nearly 3,000 of its 20,000 mineworkers are fighting.<br/>
顿巴斯煤炭能源有限公司是该矿的所有者，也是乌克兰最大的私营能源公司。该公司表示，其20000名矿工中有近3000人正在战斗。</p>
<p>Of the thousand miners at this mine and its nearby other mine who went to fight, 42 have been killed.<br/>
在这座矿井和附近另一座矿井的数千名矿工中，有42人被杀。</p>
<p>Although some women worked in the mines before the war, they were barred from doing jobs underground by the government. The work was considered too physically demanding. The policy had been in place since the Soviet times.<br/>
尽管一些妇女战前就在矿场工作，但政府禁止她们在地下工作。人们认为这项工作对体力要求太高。这项政策从苏联时代就开始实行了。</p>
<p>The ban was removed during the war. Now, about 400 women work underground at DTEK's mines. That is only 2.5 percent of the underground workforce.<br/>
这项禁令在战争期间被取消了。现在，大约有400名妇女在顿巴斯煤炭能源有限公司的矿井地下工作。这只占地下劳动力的2.5%。</p>
<p>"We do everything on the same level as the men – unless it's something very heavy that we can't lift," 43-year-old Natalia said. She also works as a technician who looks after the trains.<br/>
43岁的纳塔利娅说：“我们做任何事情都和男人们在同一水平上——除非是我们抬不起来的重物。”她还是一名技术员，负责照管火车。</p>
<p>Natalia used to work in a shop selling electronics until she lost that job when Ukrainian businesses closed their doors at the beginning of the invasion. When she decided to work in the mine, her 19-year-old son had already worked in a neighboring mine for a year.<br/>
纳塔利娅曾在一家销售电子产品的商店工作，直到入侵开始时乌克兰企业关门，她才失去了这份工作。当她决定去矿井工作时，她19岁的儿子已经在附近的一个矿井工作了一年。</p>
<p>"Actually I had been convincing him not to go and work there," she remembered. But she said she was now happily working in the mine and planned to stay, even after the war.<br/>
“事实上，我一直在说服他不要去那里工作，”她回忆道。但她说，她现在很高兴在矿井里工作，并计划留下来，即使在战争结束后。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sugar Prices Rise after El Nino Damages Crops  (2023/11/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/sugar-prices-rise-after-el-nino-damages-crops.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The sudden and large increase in sugar prices left Ishaq Abdulraheem with few choices. Raising the cost of bread would mean decreasing sales, so the Nigerian <strong>baker</strong> decided to cut his production by half.</p>
<p>For other struggling bakers in the West African nation, it was the latest of many problems they have faced. Many bakers just closed their shops.</p>
<p>Sugar is needed to make bread, the daily food for Nigeria's 210 million people. For many, bread offers a less costly source of calories, or energy. Rising sugar prices — an increase of 55 percent in two months — means fewer bakers and less bread.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Abba Usman sells granulated sugar at his shop inside a market in Abuja, Nigeria on Oct. 27, 2023. The same 50-kilogram bag of sugar that Usman bought a week ago for $66 now costs $81. As prices rise, his customers are dwindling. (AP Photo/Chinedu Asadu)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5d02c78b-0292-465b-b314-0ca3b9f76f88_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Abba Usman sells granulated sugar at his shop inside a market in Abuja, Nigeria on Oct. 27, 2023. The same 50-kilogram bag of sugar that Usman bought a week ago for $66 now costs $81. As prices rise, his customers are dwindling. (AP Photo/Chinedu Asadu)</span></div>
<p>"It is a very serious situation," Abdulraheem said.</p>
<p><strong>Increases worldwide</strong></p>
<p>Sugar is trading at the highest prices since 2011, mainly due to lower supplies around the world.</p>
<p>The increase followed the unusually dry weather that damaged harvests in India and Thailand, the world's second- and third-largest exporters.</p>
<p>This is just the latest problem for developing nations already dealing with shortages of rice and bans on some food trade. Others include the effects of the weather system El Nino and the war in Ukraine. And, increasingly, sugar is being used for biofuels, so worldwide <strong>reserves</strong> of sugar are at their lowest since 2009.</p>
<p>Brazil is the biggest sugar exporter, but its harvest will only help supply later in 2024. Until then, sugar-importing countries — like most of those in sub-Saharan Africa — remain at risk.</p>
<p>Abba Usman is a trader in the Nigeria capital of Abuja. He said a 50-kilogram bag of sugar that cost $66 a week ago now costs $81. As prices rise, his customers are decreasing.</p>
<p>"The price keeps increasing every day, and we don't know why," Usman said.</p>
<p><strong>El Nino</strong></p>
<p>It is partly due to El Nino, a natural event that shifts the weather around the world and can cause extreme weather conditions like <strong>drought</strong> or flooding. Scientists believe climate change is making El Nino stronger.</p>
<p>India experienced its driest August in over a century. Crops in the western state of Maharashtra, which accounts for over a third of its <strong>sugarcane</strong> production, did not grow properly.</p>
<p>The Indian Sugar Mills Association said India's sugar production is likely to decrease by 8 percent this year. The world's most populated nation is also the biggest user of sugar and is now restricting sugar exports.</p>
<p>El Nino affected both the amount and quality of the harvest in Thailand, said Naradhip Anantasuk, leader of the Thailand Sugar Planters Association. He expects only 76 million metric tons of sugarcane in the 2024 harvest season, compared with 93 million metric tons this year.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Kelly Goughary, a senior researcher at Gro Intelligence, said Brazil's harvest is predicted to be 20 percent bigger than last year. But since the country is in the Southern Hemisphere, the increase in supply will not come until March.</p>
<p>Data from the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) shows that the world now has less than 68 days of sugar in reserves to meet its needs.</p>
<p>Some countries, including Indonesia and Kenya, have cut back their sugar imports. China was forced to release sugar from its reserves for the first time in six years to offset high prices.</p>
<p>Back in Nigeria, Africa's largest economy, the struggle of bakers is an example of the effects of rising food, fuel costs and the large impact of high sugar prices.</p>
<p>Bread is often the only food poor families have enough money to buy. When bakers raise bread prices, as they did by 15 percent earlier this year, some people go hungry.</p>
<p>Not passing along higher costs is not possible, said Mansur Umar, president of the Nigerian Bakers' Association.</p>
<p>"There is no way you can buy high and you sell low," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Aniruddha Ghosal and Chinedu Asadu reported this story for the Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>baker</strong>–<em>n</em>. a person who makes bread for a living</p>
<p><strong>reserves</strong>–<em>n</em>. something that is being saved for the future</p>
<p><strong>drought</strong>–<em>n</em>. a long period of time without enough water</p>
<p><strong>sugarcane</strong>–<em>n</em>. a tall grass used for sugar production</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Black, Latino Students Have Reduced Chances for Success  (2023/11/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/black-latino-students-have-reduced-chances-for-success.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A federal study of all public schools says that America's Black and Latino students have reduced chances of success.</p>
<p>The data came from the Civil Rights Data Collection, which is a <strong>survey</strong> by The U.S. Education Department. It aims to examine measures of educational <strong>opportunity</strong>.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> reported on some of the findings.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - New York state has the most segregated public schools in the nation, with many black and Latino students attending schools with virtually no white classmates, according to a report by the University of California at Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Bebeto Matthews)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/07200837-782f-4de5-972a-ee4f2f09e976_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - New York state has the most segregated public schools in the nation, with many black and Latino students attending schools with virtually no white classmates, according to a report by the University of California at Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Bebeto Matthews)</span></div>
<p>The study said Black and Latino students were less likely to be in higher-level classes and to receive teaching from <strong>certified</strong> teachers. The findings suggested effects that have a lasting influence on students' ability to learn and finish college.</p>
<p>The Education Department gathered data during the 2020-2021 school year. That year most public schools were at least partially closed, and teaching took place online because of COVID-19 restrictions.</p>
<p>Speaking about the survey results, U.S. Education Secretary Miguel Cardona said, "...<strong>access</strong> to educational opportunity in this country remains unequal."</p>
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court declared segregation in public schools unlawful nearly 70 years ago. However, information in the federal survey said Black and Latino students were more likely to attend schools with lower percentages of certified teachers.</p>
<p>The data also suggested that Black and Latino students are more likely to be in schools that have security guards or police officers but no counselor.</p>
<p>Cardona called this "appalling," because of rising rates of mental health difficulties for young people.</p>
<p>The new data also showed barriers to higher level, or advanced, classes. Taking advanced classes improves a student's chances of going to college, studies suggest. But Black and Latino students were far less likely to take such classes.</p>
<p>Black students represented 15 percent of all high school students, but they made up just eight percent of students in Advanced Placement (AP) science and six percent in AP math. Latino students represented 27 percent of all high school students but made up 20 percent in AP science and 19 percent in AP math classes.</p>
<p>Sonya Thomas is the executive director of Nashville PROPEL, an activist organization that works with minorities. She said children should have the best and the government should be <strong>accountable</strong>. "It's so disheartening," she added.</p>
<p>Catherine E. Lhamon is Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights at the Department of Education. She called differences between students in the Civil Rights Data Collection information "troubling."</p>
<p>The data showed that in 5,500 public high schools where Black and Latino students make up 75 percent of all students, there were not as many math, science and computer classes as at other schools.</p>
<p>In 35 percent of schools with a high number of Black and Latino students, calculus was not offered. It was available at 54 percent of schools with low Black and Latino numbers.</p>
<p>The Education Department found that students with disabilities and those learning English also faced problems. Fewer students in both groups took math and science classes compared to all students.</p>
<p>The Civil Rights Data Collection is an effort by the U.S. Department of Education to gather information about American public schools. The department's website says the survey started in 1968. It started to include all public schools in the 2009-2010 school year and is required by the government agency.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Collin Binkley and Annie Ma reported this story for the Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>survey</strong> –<em>n</em>. a study in which people are asked to answer questions about a subject</p>
<p><strong>opportunity</strong>–<em>n</em>. situations that make something possible</p>
<p><strong>certified</strong>—<em>adj</em>. recognized for completing the requirements of a government or organization</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> –<em>n</em>. the ability to get or enter something</p>
<p><strong>accountable</strong> –<em>adj</em>. to be responsible or take responsibility for something; to be required to explain something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Clergy Connects with Young People through Music  (2023/11/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/clergy-connects-with-young-people-through-music.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Guilherme Peixoto, a religious official in northern Portugal, has been busy this month. He celebrated religious services, watched over remembrances for the dead, and prepared electronic music for his next international DJ performance.</p>
<p>DJ, short for disc jockey, is a person who plays recorded music on the radio or at a gathering.</p>
<p>For this 49-year-old Catholic <strong>priest</strong>, music has become an important way to reach people at a time when religion is becoming less popular — especially among young people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Roman Catholic priest Guilherme Peixoto, on video screen, plays techno music to help pilgrims wake up at Parque Tejo in Lisbon on Aug. 6, 2023, where Pope Francis will preside over a mass celebrating the 37th World Youth Day later in the day. (AP Photo/Ana Brigida)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ad2cd7f0-9c2e-49d8-8642-0617f8c9dd4d_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Roman Catholic priest Guilherme Peixoto, on video screen, plays techno music to help pilgrims wake up at Parque Tejo in Lisbon on Aug. 6, 2023, where Pope Francis will preside over a mass celebrating the 37th World Youth Day later in the day. (AP Photo/Ana Brigida)</span></div>
<p>"With electronic music, I can take some message, I can be where young people are," Peixoto said recently. "They can think, ‘If it's possible for a priest to be DJ, it's possible for me to like music, and festivals, and be Christian.'"</p>
<p>Peixoto became more well known when the organizers of World Youth Day in Lisbon asked him to "wake up the <strong>pilgrims</strong>" at 7 a.m. before Pope Francis' open-air Mass in August.</p>
<p><strong>Past </strong></p>
<p>When Peixoto was first sent to the village of Laúndos in the mid-2000s, the area needed money to pay for work done on the main church. But local people were tired of normal activities such as bake sales and door-knocking campaigns to raise money. So Peixoto called on the youth music groups to start <strong>karaoke</strong> events for support.</p>
<p>Within a few years, debts were paid off, church repairs were completed, and Peixoto was taking professional DJ classes</p>
<p>"In the beginning it was strange, but now it's the norm. They understood the priest is also a person," said Tania Campos, who was born and raised in Laúndos.</p>
<p>Food and drink sales, as well as other <strong>donations</strong>, all go back to the church, which is readying for a big building project: a new center for youth activities.</p>
<p>"This is why I'm happy to be here," said Andreia Flores, who belongs to Peixoto's second parish in the nearby village of Amorim. "<strong>Faith </strong>is to make others happy."</p>
<p>For Peixoto, DJing has become an important way to spread religious messages.</p>
<p>"I'm making these messages arrive where the church is not," he said of performances such as one at a recent Halloween festival with some 30,000 people. There, he re-mixed electronic dance beats with words from Pope Francis' statements about protecting the environment.</p>
<p>Peixoto added with a laugh, "It's not so much — two-three sentences from the Pope — but if I wasn't there, it's no sentence. It's like a small seed, and the Holy Spirit will do his work."</p>
<p>In fact, it was another document from Pope Francis, telling religious officials to go find "the lost sheep," that pushed Peixoto to work harder on his music skills. The hope was that music could become a way to reach those who might never step inside a church.</p>
<p><strong>The future </strong></p>
<p>In Portugal, about half of young people say they have no religion. Most participate less in services, have less confidence in the Church, and pray less than older generations, says a recent study by the Catholic Portuguese University in Braga.</p>
<p>Peixoto plans to continue to develop his DJ skills to bring a Christian message to people who might have never heard of Jesus — while remaining committed to all regular church activities.</p>
<p>"It's very important to me to not only be the priest DJ, but be the <strong>shepherd </strong>of the community," Peixoto said recently. "The world is not so closed to Jesus. But you need to speak the language."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Giovanna Dell'Orto reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>priest</strong> <em>– n.</em> a person who has the authority to lead or perform ceremonies in some religions and especially in some Christian religions</p>
<p><strong>pilgrim </strong>–<em> n.</em> someone who travels to a holy place</p>
<p><strong>karaoke </strong><em>– n.</em> a form of entertainment in which people sing the words to the songs they choose</p>
<p><strong>donation </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as money or food) that you give in order to help an organization</p>
<p><strong>faith</strong> <em>– n.</em> strong religious feelings or beliefs</p>
<p><strong>shepherd </strong>–<em> n.</em> a person who takes care of sheep — sometimes used figuratively</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Take a Moment to 'Count Your Blessings'  (2023/11/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/take-a-moment-to-count-your-blessings.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Now, the VOA Learning English program <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>There are certain times of the year when we stop and think about all the things that make us happy or bring us joy. Some people even make a list of these things. In English, we have a saying for this: <strong>to count your blessings.</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Pen Pu (center) and Chelsea Peng play with their three-year-old son Dore Peng at the Chinese Garden of Friendship in Sydney, Australia, 2015. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/82606A80-476E-4F79-9774-DFE10DC21F7E_cx0_cy0_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Pen Pu (center) and Chelsea Peng play with their three-year-old son Dore Peng at the Chinese Garden of Friendship in Sydney, Australia, 2015. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)</span></div>
<p>When we count our blessings, we note all the wonderful things in our lives. This helps us to <strong>appreciate</strong> how good life is.</p>
<p>Thanksgiving is a time when many Americans count their blessings. The United States observes this holiday on the fourth Thursday in November.</p>
<p>Counting your blessings is important. It shows that you are <strong>grateful</strong>. <strong>Gratitude</strong> is a feeling of appreciation or thanks. When people count their blessings, they can say it like this: "I am thankful for my family. I am thankful for my friends. I am thankful for my health."</p>
<p>It is better to be grateful for our blessings than to <strong>take them for granted</strong>. When we take something for granted, we do not appreciate<strong> </strong>it. Sometimes we are not appreciative of our good fortune and blessings until they are gone.</p>
<p>But now, let's take a step back. What exactly is a blessing?</p>
<p>In English, the word "blessing" has at least two meanings. As we said, a blessing is something that brings you happiness or helps you. To religious people, a blessing is approval and help from a higher <strong>source</strong> -- God.</p>
<p>A blessing can also be a sign of approval. It gives you permission to do something. For example, a traditional marriage custom involves a blessing. If a young man wants to marry a young woman, he may want to first get her family's blessing.</p>
<p><strong>Give thanks for small blessings</strong></p>
<p>Now, when we want to show our recognition of all the little things that prove helpful, we sometimes say "<strong>give thanks for small blessings</strong>." We often say this expression in the middle of a troubling or difficult time.</p>
<p>So, let's say a friend of yours is angry about a flat <strong>tire</strong> on his car. But then he stops and thinks for a minute and says, "Well, at least I have a car. I should count myself lucky and give thanks for small blessings."</p>
<p>Now, not all blessings are simple and easy to recognize. Some are more complex than others. That brings us to the expression "<strong>mixed blessing</strong>."</p>
<p><strong>Mixed blessing</strong></p>
<p>A mixed blessing is something that is both good and bad. For example, being really beautiful can be a mixed blessing. On one hand, you look great and may be treated really well by <em>some</em> people. On the other hand, you look great and may be treated badly by <em>other </em>people. So, when we use this expression, we often use the terms "on one hand" and "on the other hand."</p>
<p><strong>B</strong><strong>lessing in disguise</strong></p>
<p>Here is another blessing expression. It is a little more complicated: <strong>a blessing in disguise. </strong></p>
<p>First of all, a <strong>disguise</strong> hides something that you do not want seen or noticed. For example, a secret agent might wear a disguise to hide her identity. Or a bottle of <strong>perfume</strong> might disguise an unpleasant smell.</p>
<p>So, a blessing in disguise is a bad event or situation. But the outcome or result is actually good.</p>
<p>Here's how to use the expression <strong>blessing in disguise</strong>.</p>
<em>So how was your high school reunion?</em>
<em>Oh, I got sick and couldn't go. </em>
<em>Oh, I'm sorry to hear that. </em>
<em>Actually, it was a blessing in disguise. It turns out my two best friends from high school couldn't go either. So, we're going to take another trip together next month. </em>
<em>That sounds like even more fun.</em>
<em>It will be! They are the only people I wanted to see anyway. </em>
<em>Hey, how's everything going? I haven't seen you in a while.</em>
<p><em>Things are great! For starters, I got fired last month.</em></p>
<p><em>Oh. Sorry. So, why are things great? Getting fired is terrible.</em></p>
<p><em>Well, yes. But this time it was truly a blessing in disguise. You see, after I was fired I found a new job -- a better job that I really love. And it pays more.</em></p>
<p><em>Good for you! I'm glad you're able to count your blessings!</em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have this week for <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>Now it's time for you to "count your blessings." What are you thankful for? You can tell us in the Comments Section.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>When I am worried and I can't sleep<br/>
I count my blessings instead of sheep<br/>
And I fall asleep </em><em>counting my blessings...</em></p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. George Grow was the editor. The song at the end is "Count Your Blessings (Instead of Sheep) sung by Krista Branch.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>appreciate </strong>– <em>v. </em>to understand the worth or importance of (something or someone) : to admire and value (something or someone) : to be grateful for (something)</p>
<p><strong>grateful </strong>– <em>adj. </em>feeling or showing thanks : feeling or showing thanks to someone for some helpful act</p>
<p><strong>gratitude </strong>– <em>n. </em>the state of being grateful</p>
<p><strong>take them for granted </strong>– <em>expression </em> to never think about something because you believe it will always be available or stay exactly the same</p>
<p><strong>source</strong> – <em>n.</em> a cause or starting point</p>
<p><strong>tire</strong> – <em>n.</em> a rubber cushion that usually contains compressed air and fits around a wheel (as of an automobile</p>
<p><strong>perfume </strong>– <em>n. </em>a substance that emits a pleasant odor</p>
<p><strong>reunion </strong>– <em>n. </em>an organized gathering of people who have not been together for some time</p>
<p><strong>fired </strong>– <em>adj. </em>dismissed from a job</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Jimmy Carter: Outsider  (2023/11/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/americas-presidents-jimmy-carter.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Jimmy Carter. His given name was James, but he liked to be called Jimmy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Jimmy Carter" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/aee13bc0-e63e-4430-b9e9-ea19f42e4499_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Jimmy Carter</span></div>
<p>Carter was elected president in 1976. Until he campaigned for the office, few Americans knew who he was.</p>
<p>But Carter said his lack of experience with the federal government made him the best candidate. After witnessing years of problems in the White House, many voters appeared to agree with him.</p>
<p>However, Carter's inexperience also became a problem. Some of the issues he faced were complex and, at times, they seemed <strong>overwhelming</strong>.</p>
<p>After only one term, Carter failed to get re-elected.</p>
<p>But in time, his public image improved. His years after leaving the White House are generally considered more successful than his time in office.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Jimmy Carter was born in the southern state of Georgia. He was the oldest of four children. His father was a businessman. His mother was a <strong>nurse</strong>. The family owned a store, as well as a peanut farm and warehouse.</p>
<p>Although the businesses did well, Jimmy Carter grew up very modestly. His family's house did not have electricity or running water.</p>
<p>But he was hardworking and wanted to be successful. As a boy, he saved enough money to buy four houses. He earned more money by <strong>renting</strong> them to other people.</p>
<p>He also decided to attend college at the United States Naval Academy. And in time, he did so.</p>
<p>Carter was an excellent student. And he became a fine Naval officer. As a midshipman, Carter worked on one of the country's first nuclear submarines. He later taught nuclear engineering to other crewmembers.</p>
<p>But Carter's promising career in the Navy ended after only seven years.</p>
<p>His father was dying. And the family farm was in trouble.</p>
<p>Carter, his wife, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/rosalynncarter" target="_blank">Rosalynn</a>, and their three sons, decided to return to Georgia and try to save it.</p>
<p>The first years back on the farm were difficult. But in time, the business became successful again.</p>
<p>Carter began to turn his attention to other issues. He became involved in his church, local school, hospitals and libraries. When he had a chance to compete for a position in the state senate, he took it.</p>
<p>As a politician, Carter developed an image as an independent thinker who tried to save the government money. He also acted and spoke strongly against racial discrimination.</p>
<p>In Georgia at the time, many voters did not agree with Carter's support of racial equality. In 1966, even his own Democratic Party did not choose him to be its candidate to represent Georgia in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>So Carter began campaigning for the office of state governor instead. In 1970, he was elected. As Georgia's governor, Carter was known as a social and political reformer.</p>
<p>However, historian Robert Strong notes that Carter did not always work well with others in his party.</p>
<p>Strong teaches at Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/carter/life-before-the-presidency">writes</a> that some Georgia lawmakers believed Carter was "arrogant." He could appear to think he was morally right, and they were morally wrong.</p>
<p>Carter's difficulty in getting along with other officials proved to be one of the problems he would later face.</p>
<p>But in the presidential election of 1976, many Americans seemed to like this quality. The little-known governor from Georgia defeated the sitting president, Gerald Ford.</p>
<p>Carter won, in part, by saying that he was different than other politicians. He was, he said, a Washington outsider.</p>
<p>Then suddenly, Carter was the biggest insider of all: the American president.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>One of the things Carter wanted to do was change the image of the president.</p>
<p>Earlier leaders, such as<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-richard-nixon/4107568.html" target="_blank"> Richard Nixon</a> and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-lyndon-johnson/4095890.html" target="_blank">Lyndon Johnson</a>, had increased the power of the presidency. Nixon had also been shown to be dishonest, and resigned from office.</p>
<p>Carter promised never to lie to the American people. And on the day of his swearing-in as president, he purposefully tried to keep things simple. He walked to the White House from the U.S. Capitol building instead of riding in the back of an automobile.</p>
<p>His wife, Rosalynn, wore clothes that she had worn in public before. The National First Ladies' Library <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.firstladies.org/FirstLadiesandFashion.aspx">notes</a> that her choice of clothing sent a message of "an old American value of thrift – or respecting money, and not spending it needlessly."</p>
<p>What she wore was meaningful because the country was going through difficult economic times. The Carters wanted to show that the new government would work to cut costs. They also wanted to show that they were there to help the American people, not enjoy the powers of the White House.</p>
<p>But in the end, the Carter administration received poor ratings in surveys of public opinion.</p>
<p>President Carter had trouble dealing with U.S. lawmakers, even when his party was in control of Congress. One result was that Carter could not <strong>advance</strong> many of his ideas for legislation. He appeared ineffective.</p>
<p>Many historians point out that, in fact, Carter had a number of successes. He helped reduce the country's dependence on foreign oil. He took steps to make the federal government more efficient, and to improve the environment. He appointed a number of women and racial minorities to top government jobs -- an important move at a time when many were pressing for women's rights and civil rights. And, in many cases, Carter supported human rights causes, both in the United States and around the world.</p>
<p>But the public generally did not see Carter for his successes. Instead, many Americans blamed him for the country's economic problems.</p>
<p>Some also disliked the way he spoke to them. In one speech, Carter blamed the country's troubles on what he called a crisis of <strong>confidence</strong>. Some listeners were offended.</p>
<p>He also decided that the U.S. would not attend the 1980 Olympic Games in Moscow. The move was meant to punish the Soviet Union for its involvement in Afghanistan. But many Americans believed the move mostly hurt young American Olympians.</p>
<p>The administration also faced other problems. The president was never accused of wrongdoing. But other high-level officials were. So was the president's brother, Billy. As a result, Jimmy Carter's public image for honesty suffered.</p>
<p>Then came the Iran hostage crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Iran hostage crisis</strong></p>
<p>The conflict between the United States and Iran had a long history. One part involved the Shah of Iran. The U.S. government had supported his rise to power, partly because American interests wanted to control Iran's oil.</p>
<p>But the Shah severely abused his power. Many Iranians resisted. Some wanted a leader who would more closely obey Islamic teachings.</p>
<p>In 1979, under pressure from those Iranians and others, the Shah fled the country. By now, he was suffering from cancer.</p>
<p>So, as a humanitarian act, President Carter permitted the Shah to come to the United States for medical treatment.</p>
<p>The move made many Iranians angry. In protest, a group of students seized the U.S. embassy in Tehran, the capital of Iran. They took 90 people, including 66 Americans, hostage.</p>
<p>Carter worked hard to get the hostages released. He tried diplomatic negotiations and economic restrictions.</p>
<p>But his efforts did not work.</p>
<p>Finally, he tried a secret military operation. He sent eight helicopters and a team of special forces to enter the embassy and rescue the hostages.</p>
<p>But that operation failed, too. The weather was bad. Three of the helicopters crashed. Eight Americans were killed.</p>
<p>And the public's approval of Jimmy Carter dropped even more.</p>
<p>After 444 days, the remaining hostages were released. In exchange, the U.S. government agreed to end some of its economic sanctions against Iran and promised not to interfere in the country's affairs.</p>
<p>None of the hostages had been seriously hurt. But the crisis was the final blow to Carter's presidency. A few months before they were released, his effort to seek re-election failed.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>As president, Carter did not meet the high expectations he had set for himself. And he faced some unusually difficult situations. His presidency also suffered from his problems communicating effectively with Congress, the media, and the American people.</p>
<p>But his four years as president did leave several marks on the office. For one, he showed that the U.S. president could help other nations and sides resolve their disputes.</p>
<p>Carter's best-known success as president was his help negotiating the <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/camp-david-accords-signed">Camp David Accords</a>.</p>
<p>The accords were a peace agreement between Egypt and Israel. Carter led the talks at Camp David in Maryland.</p>
<p>Carter's efforts to protect human rights overseas also influenced the foreign policy of later presidents.</p>
<p>In time, his work as a defender of human rights has become his most important <strong>legacy</strong>.</p>
<p>Several years after leaving the presidency, he founded the Carter Presidential Center at Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia. The center "seeks to prevent and resolve conflicts, enhance freedom and democracy, and improve health."</p>
<p>In addition to his work there, Carter has helped build houses for people who need them, written books, and negotiated with world leaders to take steps toward peace.</p>
<p>In 2002, Carter received the Nobel Peace Prize for his efforts.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em><span style="font-size: 9pt;"></span></p>
<p>____________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>overwhelming</strong> - <em>adj.</em> something that is so confusing or difficult that you feel unable to do it</p>
<p><strong>nurse</strong> -<em> n.</em> a person who is trained to care for sick or injured people</p>
<p><strong>rent</strong> - <em>v. </em>to allow someone to use (something) in return for payment</p>
<p><strong>advance</strong> -<em> v. </em>to move forward</p>
<p><strong>confidence</strong> -<em> n. </em>a feeling or belief that someone or something is good or has the ability to succeed at something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Pastoralists Modernizing to Deal With Climate Change, New Lifestyles  (2023/11/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/pastoralists-modernizing-to-deal-with-climate-change-new-lifestyles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>More than 50 million people in Asia, Africa, the Middle East and elsewhere follow <strong>pastoralism </strong>as a way of life. They keep animals and move with them to find lands from which their animals can eat. They often sell some of their animals as meat also.</p>
<p>Pastoralism has supported these populations for much of history. But it faces pressure from worsening environments, reductions of pastoral lands, and new generations who seek a less difficult life. At the same time, pastoralism is modernizing, with groups using new technologies.</p>
<p>The practice has survived for so long because it is designed to change with the environment. Pastoralists move with animals to find new lands and water, leaving behind eaten plants to regrow.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A neighboring herder talks to Agvaantogtokh, left, sitting on a livestock fence in the Munkh-Khaan region of the Sukhbaatar district in southeast Mongolia, May 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Manish Swarup)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a0af-08dbe72c6b7c_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A neighboring herder talks to Agvaantogtokh, left, sitting on a livestock fence in the Munkh-Khaan region of the Sukhbaatar district in southeast Mongolia, May 16, 2023. (AP Photo/Manish Swarup)</span></div>
<p>Experts say pastoralism can teach those that keep animals in industrial numbers to change with the climate and reduce their effects on the environment. Pastoralists are not only trying to keep up with climate change; they are fighting it.</p>
<p><strong>Mongolian herders</strong></p>
<p>Mongolia is well known for its pastoralism. The practice is even included in the nation's constitution. It calls its 80 million animals, including camels, yaks, cows, sheep, goats, and horses, as "national wealth" protected by the state.</p>
<p>Agvaantogtokh and his family are <strong>herders. </strong>On horseback, he rides with nearly a thousand sheep and goats to help them find water. Sometimes, he and his wife, Nurmaa, stop to help struggling young ones, weak after a difficult winter.</p>
<p>For families like Agvaantogtokh's, pastoralism is more than a profession. It is a cultural identity that connects generations. At its heart is the human connection to animals.</p>
<p>Agvaantogtokh and his family sell animals for meat. They also sell <strong>dairy </strong>products such as yogurt and hard cheeses. While they consider the animals as their property, they also see them as living beings working alongside them.</p>
<p>Researchers say herders believe in "animal agency." Agvaantogtokh lets his animals choose the food they eat and where they find water. To him, restricting an animal's movement and asking it to eat the same thing each day is like putting a person in prison.</p>
<p>In Mongolia, weather extremes are a part of life. When Agvaantogtokh thinks about climate change, he is concerned about humans and animals.</p>
<p>Continuous dry and warm weather affects Mongolia. Since 1940, the government says, average temperatures have risen 2.2 degrees Celsius. Dzuds – natural disasters special to Mongolia caused by dry weather and severe snowy winters – have grown <strong>harsher</strong> and happen more often.</p>
<p>A dzud pushed Agvaantogtokh and his family to move out after a disastrous winter killed 400 of their animals.</p>
<p><strong>Ancient practice, new methods</strong></p>
<p>To keep their practice alive, pastoralists seek ways to modernize.</p>
<p>In Mongolia, Lkhaebum recently began using a small vehicle to more easily search for horses. The family uses electricity and has other technologies including a television and clothes washing machine. They also use a cellphone to follow the weather and <strong>access</strong> social media where herders share information.</p>
<p>One of the biggest threats to pastoralism comes from within, as the next generation chooses other paths.</p>
<p>Nurmaa and Agvaantogtokh's 18-year old daughter studies medicine. Their son spoke about becoming a herder when he was a child, but not anymore.</p>
<p>"I won't regret anything if my child won't be a herder," Nurmaa said. She added, "I would like them to do what they <strong>aspire</strong> to do."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pastoralism </strong>– <em>n</em>. livestock raising</p>
<p><strong>herder </strong>– <em>v</em>. to gather and move (a group of animals)</p>
<p><strong>diary </strong>– <em>n</em>. milk or food made from milk (such as ice cream, cheese, or yogurt)</p>
<p><strong>harsh </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having an unpleasant or harmful effect because of great strength or force: too intense or powerful</p>
<p><strong>aspire </strong>– <em>v</em>. to want to have or achieve something (such as a particular career or level of success)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ukrainians in Israel Face War Conditions Again  (2023/11/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/ukrainians-in-israel-face-war-conditions-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thousands of Ukrainians decided to flee war in their country and head to Israel after Russian forces invaded in 2022. But now those people are facing war conditions again as Israeli forces continue battling Hamas militants.</p>
<p>Tatyana Prima fled to southern Israel from the southeastern Ukrainian city of Mariupol 18 months ago with her husband and young daughter. The 38-year-old was thankful to arrive safely to Israel and thought she and her family had finally left the bombs behind.</p>
<p>But Prima's sense of safety and calmness disappeared when Hamas militants invaded Israel on October 7. "All these sounds of war that we hear now, they sometimes work as a<strong> trigger </strong>that brings back memories of what we've gone through in Mariupol," she said.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Tatyana Prima, who fled Mariupol, Ukraine, poses for a portrait with her national flag and the Israeli flag she displays outside of her apartment window in Ashkelon, southern Israel, Wednesday, Nov. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Maya Alleruzzo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-32c3-08dbebb5a0a2_cx0_cy17_cw88_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Tatyana Prima, who fled Mariupol, Ukraine, poses for a portrait with her national flag and the Israeli flag she displays outside of her apartment window in Ashkelon, southern Israel, Wednesday, Nov. 8, 2023. (AP Photo/Maya Alleruzzo)</span></div>
<p>The Israeli government estimates more than 45,000 Ukrainians have fled to Israel since Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022. Most of the refugees were trying to deal with war <strong>trauma</strong> experienced back in Ukraine when conflict broke out in Israel.</p>
<p>Some have left Israel, but many remain and are refusing to again flee a war. Most have lost in-person support systems because of restrictions in Israel involving gatherings. Others have lost hope of reuniting with loved ones they left behind in Ukraine.</p>
<p>When Hamas militants attacked on October 7, they killed about 1,200 people and took about 240 hostages. On that day, Prima awoke to the sound of alarms. She lives in the coastal city of Ashkelon, a few kilometers from the Gaza Strip. The crash of airstrikes and shelling has been continuous, as Israel pushes forward with its offensive against Hamas. Prima describes the situation as "<strong>deja vu</strong>," bringing back similar memories from Ukraine.</p>
<p>Mariupol was one of Ukraine's hardest-hit cities in the war with Russia. The city was cut off and bombarded for weeks as people struggled for food, water and heat. During the war's early weeks, Prima cooked over an outdoor fire, used snow for drinking water and sheltered with other relatives just outside the city.</p>
<p>As the shelling intensified, rockets fell around where Prima and her family stayed. After an incident in which her husband's hand was blown off while he searched for water, she decided to leave. The family arrived in Ashkelon in April 2022 and joined relatives of her husband there.</p>
<p>Israeli defense systems block most incoming missiles from Hamas. But at least 80 have landed in populated areas or empty fields in Israel since the war began, the <em>Armed Conflict Location &amp; Event Data Project</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://acleddata.com/">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Prima said the conflict has intensified her feelings of <strong>isolation</strong>. This is because her community support groups have moved most activities online because of government restrictions on gatherings in public.</p>
<p>Koen Sevenants is a mental health specialist who has worked with refugees and displaced people in several conflict areas. He told The Associated Press (AP) he finds such individuals often experience "hopelessness." Experts warn that if people who have not fully recovered from one traumatic incident are victimized again by a new one, the event that caused the trauma can seem worse.</p>
<p>Refugee organizations have offered financial and food assistance to people in Israel who do not feel safe leaving their homes. But Olya Weinstein said these groups are not equipped to help all those in need. Her organization, Project Kesher, has been helping about 6,000 people who fled Ukraine, mostly with food.</p>
<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy said an unknown number of Ukrainians remain trapped in Gaza. Ukraine said at least 160 of them have been safely removed. Gaza's Health Ministry has estimated more than 12,700 Palestinians – most of them women and minors – have been killed since the war began. That number includes both civilian and Hamas militant deaths.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>trigger </strong><em>– n. </em>an event or situation that makes something else happen</p>
<p><strong>trauma </strong><em>– n. </em>severe shock caused by a bad experience</p>
<p><strong><em>deja vu</em></strong><strong> </strong><em>– n. </em>a feeling that you have already experienced a particular thing at another time</p>
<p><strong>isolate</strong><em> – v. </em>to separate someone or something from other people or things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Danger vs. Hazard  (2023/11/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/danger-vs-hazard.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between the words "danger" and "hazard."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello friends,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Danger vs. Hazard " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-61d1-08dbeb95460e_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Danger vs. Hazard </span></div>
<p>I'm Roberto, and I live in S<i></i>227;o Paulo, Brazil. I have a question. What's the difference between "danger" and "hazard"? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for your question, Roberto. Both "danger" and "hazard" are nouns that can mean a dangerous or life-threatening situation. But each can refer to a more specific possibility of harm that separate meanings.</p>
<p>Let's start with "danger."</p>
<p><strong>Danger</strong></p>
<p>"Danger" has a few meanings. It can be used as a substitute for risk, for example.</p>
<p><em>Ellie's job is in danger since she protested the pay changes at her workplace.</em></p>
<p><em>The danger of wrecking a car is greater when it begins to rain because the water spreads the oil on the roads before it washes it away.</em></p>
<p>A "danger" is something or someone that can hurt you.</p>
<p><em>The escaped prisoner was a danger to the area surrounding the prison.</em></p>
<p>Dangers usually involve immediacy.</p>
<p>This is different from "hazard," in which the <strong>exposure</strong> might be extremely low, but there is a higher chance of great harm or death.</p>
<p>Let's look more closely at "hazard" now.</p>
<p><strong>Hazard</strong></p>
<p>A "hazard" is a source of danger or harm to a person or environment.</p>
<p><em>Deep frying turkeys on Thanksgiving is a fire hazard.</em></p>
<p><em>Radiation exposure is a hazard to our health.</em></p>
<p>"Hazard" is a known threat. Yet, there is an unpredictable element to a "hazard."</p>
<p>Take for example a volcano. Volcanoes are a hazard to not only the people that live near them, but they are also a hazard to the environment. Volcanoes have a great possiblity of harm and the possibility of eruptions is difficult to predict.</p>
<p>As a plural noun, "hazards" are special lights on cars that <strong>flash</strong> on and off to warn other drivers. They are used when a vehicle is either not working properly or if the road or weather conditions are hazardous.</p>
<p><em>Drivers often turn on their hazards when there is thick fog to make it easier for other drivers to see them.</em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Roberto.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>exposure</strong> <em>– n.</em> the fact or condition of being affected by something or experiencing something</p>
<p><strong>flash </strong>– <em>n</em>. a sudden burst of light</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>These Coral Reefs Are Doing Well in Gulf of Mexico  (2023/11/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/these-coral-reefs-are-doing-well-in-gulf-of-mexico.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) says changes in ocean temperature are the leading cause of <a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/coral_bleach.html">coral bleaching</a> around the world.</p>
<p>From Australia's Great Barrier Reef to the waters of Florida, it happens when warm water causes corals to expel their colorful <strong>algae</strong> and turn white.</p>
<p>Derek Manzello is the head of Coral Reef Watch, which is part of NOAA. He said at least 35 countries and territories across five oceans and seas reported coral bleaching.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Andy Lewis positions to photograph brain coral at the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary, off the coast of Galveston, Texas, Friday, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9baf1318-4076-4c37-aa83-4b69cf6ffb9e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Andy Lewis positions to photograph brain coral at the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary, off the coast of Galveston, Texas, Friday, Sept. 15, 2023. (AP Photo/LM Otero)</span></div>
<p>He said that by the year 2040, all of the world's coral will suffer from bleaching if water temperatures do not cool. He said coral needs extended periods of cooler water to recover from bleaching. If the water does not cool, he said, "the corals aren't going to have a chance to recover."</p>
<p><strong>Gulf of Mexico corals</strong></p>
<p>But in the Gulf of Mexico, about 160 kilometers south of Galveston, Texas, a large <strong>coral</strong> <strong>reef</strong> is still doing well.</p>
<p>The reef is part of the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary. The reef formation covers over 400 square kilometers. It started with just two reef areas, called banks, in 1992. It now has 17 banks. It is described as undersea mountains of yellow, orange and pink coral as far as the eye can see.</p>
<p>Michelle Johnston oversees the protected marine area for the federal government. She said seeing that much coral in one place is "<strong>magnificent</strong>" and rare.</p>
<p>Johnston said fishermen used to tell the story of a colorful area in the Gulf of Mexico far from shore 100 years ago. But, scientists were uncertain that a coral reef could exist in such deep water. When divers finally reached the reef in the 1960s, they were surprised to find marine life. Johnston said the plants and animals do so well because the reef formed on top of mountain-like salt <strong>domes</strong>, high enough to catch sunlight.</p>
<p>During the recent summer of record-breaking heat, Johnston said, the reef did experience some bleaching but nothing as serious as in other parts of the world. But that does not mean the reef in the Gulf of Mexico is not <strong>vulnerable</strong> to climate change. She is concerned about the area getting too hot and the coral dying off.</p>
<p>Officials who watch over Flower Garden Banks say the reef has suffered more serious bleaching in the past, but its depth and health helped it recover. The reef is deeper – 18 meters - than many others that are often just offshore.</p>
<p>Andy Lewis of Houston, Texas first saw the reef about 10 years ago. He loved it so much that he became an expert diver and started a company that leads dives to Flower Garden Banks.</p>
<p>"It's just a real adventure," he said.</p>
<p>Scientists are working to help the reefs stay healthy. For example, boats are not permitted to <strong>anchor</strong> themselves to the reefs. They must connect to special floating cables to stay in one place. Other workers help remove <strong>invasive</strong> fish and creatures from the area.</p>
<p>Kelly Drinnen is an education and outreach specialist for the Flower Garden Banks. She said, "because coral reefs are declining all over the <strong>globe</strong>, when we find ones that are healthy, we want to keep them that way." Drinnen added that they could also provide information that can help other reefs stay healthy or recover from bleaching.</p>
<p>In 2010, the Flower Garden Banks corals were not damaged by the large oil spill that followed the Deepwater Horizon explosion. Other reefs in the Gulf of Mexico were. So, researchers are using data from the reef to help guide the restoration of the damaged ones.</p>
<p>Researchers are also comparing the genetics of Flower Garden Banks corals to corals in other parts of the world. And they hope to grow and possibly replant them in other places.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>algae </strong><em>–n.</em> simple plants that grow in or near water</p>
<p><strong>coral reef </strong><em>–n.</em> a long line of coral that lies in warm, often shallow, water</p>
<p><strong>magnificent </strong><em>–adj.</em> used to describe something that is unusual and very impressive</p>
<p><strong>dome </strong><em>–n.</em> something tall and with a rounded top, like the rounded top of a building</p>
<p><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>–adj.</em> having the possibility of being hurt or injured</p>
<p><strong>anchor </strong><em>–v.</em> to connect something such as a boat to the ocean floor or another object so that it will not move</p>
<p><strong>invasive </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is living in an area where it does not belong and has no other predators</p>
<p><strong>globe </strong><em>–n.</em> the world, Earth</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Automakers Seek to Produce EV Vehicles with Fewer Rare Earths  (2023/11/24) | 汽车制造商寻求生产无稀土电机</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/automakers-seek-to-produce-ev-vehicles-with-fewer-rare-earths.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Major automakers are seeking new ways to make electric vehicle (EV) motors that depend less on rare earth minerals.<br/>
主要汽车制造商正在寻找新的方法来制造对稀土矿物依赖较少的电动汽车发动机。</p>
<p>China controls most mining and processing of a group of 17 metals known as rare earths. These minerals are used to produce permanent magnets. Many experts consider permanent magnets to be the most effective way to power EVs.<br/>
中国控制着17种稀土金属的大部分开采和加工。这些矿物被用来制造永磁体。许多专家认为永磁体是驱动电动汽车最有效的方式。</p>
<p>But new motor designs show that permanent magnets are not necessary to produce a commercially successfully EV. And some Western EV makers are finding new solutions to produce motors that avoid rare earth minerals.<br/>
但新的电机设计表明，生产商业上成功的电动汽车并不需要永磁体。一些西方电动汽车制造商正在寻找新的解决方案来生产不含稀土矿物的电机。</p>
<p>EV market leader Tesla announced earlier this year it planned to remove rare earths from its next-generation EVs.<br/>
电动汽车市场领导者特斯拉今年早些时候宣布，计划从下一代电动汽车中去除稀土。</p>
<p>Other automakers are also in the process of researching or developing EV motors that use little or no rare earth minerals. These include General Motors, Jaguar Land Rover and BMW.<br/>
其他汽车制造商也在研究或开发几乎不使用稀土矿物的电动汽车发动机。其中包括通用汽车、捷豹路虎和宝马。</p>
<p>Nissan says it plans to develop newer motors with low rare earth content, as well as permanent magnet motors that will one day no longer need the minerals.<br/>
日产表示，计划开发低稀土含量的新型电机，以及有朝一日不再需要稀土的永磁电机。</p>
<p>German technology supplier ZF has developed a new kind of motor the company says is very similar to the size and performance of permanent magnet motors. This kind of motor, known as EESM, uses electricity to produce a magnetic field.<br/>
德国技术供应商采埃孚开发了一种新型电机，该公司表示，这种电机的尺寸和性能与永磁电机非常相似。这种被称为EESM的电机利用电力产生磁场。</p>
<p>ZF's Chief Technology Officer, Otmar Scharrer, told Reuters news agency such development is "an important contribution to making us a little more independent of China."<br/>
采埃孚首席技术官奥特玛·绍尔告诉路透社，这类研制成果是“使我们更加独立于中国的重要贡献”。</p>
<p>ZF is in talks with U.S., European and Chinese automakers to supply the motor and could start producing EV models within two years, Scharrer said.<br/>
绍尔表示，采埃孚正在与美国、欧洲和中国的汽车制造商就供应这款电机进行谈判，并可能在两年内开始生产电动汽车。</p>
<p>Besides being mostly controlled by China, some rare earth development produces poisonous waste that can harm people and the environment. The problem could also be helped by using motors that do not depend on rare earth minerals.<br/>
除了主要由中国控制外，一些稀土开发项目还产生有毒废物，可能危害人类和环境。这个问题也可以通过使用不依赖稀土矿物的电机来解决。</p>
<p>"If you get it right, you've got a much more sustainable product," said Ben Chiswick. He directs engineering business development for Detroit-based Drive System Design. The company is working to create rare earth-free motors with three different automakers.<br/>
本·奇西克说：“如果实现了，就会得到一种更可持续的产品。”他在底特律驱动系统设计公司指导工程业务开发。该公司正与三家不同的汽车制造商合作开发无稀土电机。</p>
<p>Some companies, like BMW, say they have already made great progress after years of research. "It was not a home run... but it works very well without rare earths," said Uwe Deuke of BMW's latest development efforts. He leads engineering efforts for the company's EESM motor planned for its next-generation EVs.<br/>
宝马等一些公司表示，经过多年的研究，他们已经取得了巨大进展。乌韦·德乌卡在谈到宝马的最新开发工作时说：“这不是一次本垒打……但它在没有稀土的情况下运行得很好。”他领导该公司计划用于下一代电动汽车的EESM电机的工程工作。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Serena Williams, Ruby Bridges to Be Honored at Women’s Hall of Fame  (2023/11/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/serena-williams-ruby-bridges-to-be-honored-at-women-s-hall-of-fame.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Serena Williams and Ruby Bridges will be <strong>inducted</strong> into the National Women's Hall of Fame in March of next year. The American organization in Seneca Falls, New York made the announcement Thursday.</p>
<p>The tennis great and the civil rights leader were added to a list to be honored during Women's History Month in March.</p>
<p>"The 2024 inductee class has broken barriers, <strong>challenged</strong> the <strong>status quo</strong>, and left an <strong>impact</strong> on history," the Hall of Fame said in its announcement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Serena Williams, of the United States, reacts during a match at the U.S. Open tennis championships, Sept. 2, 2022, in New York. Williams and Ruby Bridges will be inducted into the National Women's Hall of Fame next year. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, file)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5fd74681-46fc-458e-8bf9-de7f3ad1a997_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Serena Williams, of the United States, reacts during a match at the U.S. Open tennis championships, Sept. 2, 2022, in New York. Williams and Ruby Bridges will be inducted into the National Women's Hall of Fame next year. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, file)</span></div>
<p>Eight other honorees were announced in the spring. Williams and Bridges became available after the ceremony plans changed, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 42-year-old Williams has won major events in tennis, called Grand Slam events, 23 times. She holds the record for the longest <strong>ranking</strong> as the top competitor. She retired from tennis last year. Earlier this month, Williams became the first athlete to win the Fashion Icon award from the Council of Fashion Designers of America.</p>
<p>The 69-year-old Bridges was six years old when she became the first Black student at a Louisiana public school where non-whites had been barred. The event took place in 1960. In 1963, painter Norman Rockwell recreated the scene in his painting, T<em>he Problem We All Live With</em>. Bridges established the Ruby Bridges Foundation in 1999. It offers educational programs and resources to guide and support younger generations toward a peaceful future.</p>
<p>Others to be inducted include Peggy McIntosh, an activist known for her explorations of <strong>privilege</strong>; Kimberlé Crenshaw who helped develop the <strong>academic </strong>idea called critical race theory; and Judith Plaskow, considered by some people as the first Jewish feminist <strong>theologian</strong> for criticizing the lack of female ideas in Jewish history.</p>
<p>The founder of the National Center for Human Rights Education in Atlanta, Loretta Ross, will also be inducted. So will Allucquére Rosanne "Sandy" Stone, a transgender woman born in 1936 and considered a founder of transgender studies in colleges.</p>
<p>Three women will be inducted <strong>posthumously</strong>. Dr. Patricia Bath was an early leader of laser eye operations and the first Black woman doctor to receive a medical patent. Dr. Anna Wessels Williams made a disease discovery that led to a treatment for diphtheria. And Elouise Pepion Cobell, known as Yellow Bird Woman, started the first bank established by a Native American tribe on a reservation in Browning, Montana.</p>
<p>For the first time, the induction ceremony will be broadcast nationally in prime time from New York City, the Hall of Fame said. The past 30 ceremonies have taken place in places around Seneca Falls, New York. The town was the site of the first Women's Rights Convention and is home to the National Women's Hall of Fame.</p>
<p>"The 2024 class of inductees are scientists, activists, performers, and athletes who are changemakers of today and <strong>inspiration</strong> for the women of tomorrow," said National Womens Hall of Fame chief, Jennifer Gabriel.</p>
<p>The American public nominates women to be considered for the Hall of Fame. A group of experts examines those nominations and makes the final decision.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Carolyn Thompson reported this story for the Associated Press. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>induct </strong><em>–v.</em> to accept into something</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>–v.</em> to question authority</p>
<p><strong>status quo </strong><em>–n.</em> the way things are now</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>–n.</em> influence</p>
<p><strong>rank </strong><em>–v.</em> to place things in order of where they place in a competition</p>
<p><strong>privilege </strong><em>–n.</em> having something that others do not or cannot have</p>
<p><strong>academic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to teaching in universities but not in normal life</p>
<p><strong>theologian </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who is an expert in religious matters</p>
<p><strong>posthumously </strong><em>–adv.</em> after someone has died</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Aims to Increase Battery Production  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/us-aims-to-increase-battery-production.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The United States Department of Energy (DOE) is making an effort to increase <strong>battery</strong> production in the country.</p>
<p>The DOE recently announced it would provide $3.5 billion to companies that produce batteries and the important minerals that go into them.</p>
<p>Officials see batteries as an important climate solution. The devices can power cars and store clean electricity made from solar <strong>panels</strong> or wind <strong>turbines</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A truck is parked between brine evaporation ponds at Albemarle Corp.'s Silver Peak lithium facility, Oct. 6, 2022, in Silver Peak, Nev. (AP Photo/John Locher, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c7b49a98-a4f1-4b8c-9f52-af4a543e1a16_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A truck is parked between brine evaporation ponds at Albemarle Corp.'s Silver Peak lithium facility, Oct. 6, 2022, in Silver Peak, Nev. (AP Photo/John Locher, File)</span></div>
<p>The idea is to use fewer <strong>fossil fuels</strong> for cars and power plants.</p>
<p>Lithium ion is currently the favored battery for electric vehicles and clean electrical storage. The DOE wants to strengthen the supply. The agency estimates that by 2030 demand for lithium batteries will increase by as much as 10 times.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden's administration has set a goal of lowering the pollution that causes climate change to zero by 2050. It also wants electric automobiles to represent half of all new car sales by 2030.</p>
<p>Some officials, industry experts and others are concerned that the supply of battery materials will not keep up with the demand. Others worry that too much of the industry is located in Asia.</p>
<p>Jodie Lutkenhaus of the Texas A&amp;M University said she is closely watching U.S. battery production and manufacturing. "I'm worried that we may not catch up and end up in the same situation we're in now with the <strong>semiconductor</strong> industry," she said. Pandemic closings and suspensions slowed manufacturing in Asia. A microchip shortage resulted, affecting the availability of vehicles and electronic products.</p>
<p>"The same thing can happen with batteries if we don't diversify where batteries are made and where materials are sourced," Lutkenhaus said. She said the U.S. must take part in battery production and manufacturing to avoid possible worldwide shortages in the future.</p>
<p>A measure called the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $6 billion in total financing for battery manufacturing, including the processing of materials needed to make them.</p>
<p>So far, 15 projects are receiving the assistance. They include companies that mine minerals like graphite and nickel that are used in lithium batteries. Later, contracts will go to other companies, including finance and chemistry businesses.</p>
<p>Here's how it works: A company might want to build a factory to make special materials for electric cars. It estimates the cost of building the facility and commits to covering half of the cost. If the company is selected for the program, the government payment would cover the other half.</p>
<p>Albemarle, a major lithium producer, received financing for a factory in Kings Mountain, North Carolina. The factory processes lithium from ore collected around the world. The company said that in addition to EVs, demand for lithium also comes from electronics like medical devices and smartphones. Without the DOE financial support, the project "would have likely progressed along a different time scale,"Albemarle said in an email.</p>
<p>Matthew McDowell is with the Georgia Institute of Technology. He said the law has changed U.S. battery manufacturing in the past three years. He is excited, he said, about the new batteries for clean energy storage, including solid state batteries, which could possibly hold more energy than lithium ion.</p>
<p>Tom Moerenhout of Columbia University's Center on Global Energy Policy said it will be difficult to increase the worldwide supply of minerals for the predicted battery demand in 2030. "It's pretty huge," he said, noting that a new mine on average takes 16 years to begin commercial production.</p>
<p>But with the price of lithium rising, Moerenhout said, different battery types become more interesting. One he hopes to see increase is sodium ion batteries to help with the electrical grid. "The potential is quite huge," he said, because they are safe and not costly.</p>
<p>Companies can officially request financing through mid-March.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Isabella O'Malley reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>battery</strong> <em>– n.</em> a device that is placed inside a machine to supply it with electricity</p>
<p><strong>panel</strong> –<em> n. </em>a flat surface</p>
<p><strong>turbine </strong><em>– n.</em> an engine that has blades that are caused to spin by wind</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel</strong> <em>-- n.</em> a fuel such as coal, oil, or natural gas</p>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– n.</em> an object that allows some electricity to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Indian Cloud-seeding Project Aims to Produce Rain to Clear Pollution  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/indian-cloud-seeding-project-aims-to-produce-rain-to-clear-pollution.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Indian scientists plan to add substances to clouds above the capital New Delhi in an effort to produce rain to reduce pollution.</p>
<p>The method to <strong>artificially</strong> produce rain is called cloud seeding. The process involves adding different chemicals to clouds to cause rain. When rain falls from the sky, water droplets can attach to pollution particles and bring them down to the ground.</p>
<p>New Delhi has been rated the city with the most air pollution in the world. Reports say the problem has worsened across the city in recent weeks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Commuters make their way along a road amid heavy smoggy conditions in New Delhi, Nov. 5, 2023. (Photo by Arun SANKAR / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-adbd-08dbdecc68ab_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Commuters make their way along a road amid heavy smoggy conditions in New Delhi, Nov. 5, 2023. (Photo by Arun SANKAR / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Air quality decreases in the city ahead of winter each year. During this time, cold air can trap many pollutants, including gases from vehicles, industry, building projects and agricultural burning.</p>
<p>Scientists expect some clouds over the city around November 20. They hope the clouds will result in heavy rainfall – when sprayed with a <strong>salt</strong> mixture.</p>
<p>The project is being led by Manindra Agrawal, a scientist at the Indian Institute of Technology in the central city of Kanpur. He told Reuters news agency the salt mixture will include silver iodine to help produce rain. It is to be sprayed on clouds over a 100 square kilometer area. Agrawal said the project will cost about $120,000.</p>
<p>The local government in New Delhi, a city of 20 million people, has already closed schools, stopped building activities, and said it will place restrictions on vehicle use to control pollution.</p>
<p>The air quality index in the city was 506 on November 9. This level is considered "hazardous" by <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iqair.com/">IQAir</a>, a Swiss company that describes itself as an "air quality solutions" business.</p>
<p>Gufran Beig is head of the Indian government's air-quality measuring agency SAFAR. He told Reuters the city needs heavy and widespread rain to wash away the pollutants. Beig added that light rain could worsen the situation.</p>
<p>The SAFAR head said current airflow is carrying smoke from crop burning in the states of Punjab and Haryana to Delhi. This smoke adds to the city's existing pollution sources. "So, unless a huge pressure is established by intense rain, this chain of transport from Punjab to Delhi will not be broken," Beig said.</p>
<p>About 38 percent of pollution in the capital has been caused by <strong>stubble</strong> burning in Punjab and Haryana, a recent government statement said. Farmers carry out stubble burning to clear material left behind from rice harvests so they can plant other crops. Indian officials directed leaders in both states to "take effective actions" to identify and limit stubble burning, the statement added.</p>
<p>Officials in New Delhi are seeking approval for the project from the Supreme Court, Reuters reported.</p>
<p>Several countries have used cloud seeding in an effort to produce rain, improve air quality and water crops in times of extreme dryness. These include Mexico, the United States, China, Indonesia and Malaysia.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>artificial </strong><em>– adj. </em>not natural, but made by people</p>
<p><strong>salt </strong><em>–n.</em> a word for one of many chemical combinations of two elements; sodium chloride</p>
<p><strong>stubble </strong><em>– n. </em>small pieces of dried plant stems left behind in a field after it has been cut</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Children in South Africa Walk a Long Way to School  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/children-in-south-africa-walk-a-long-way-to-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Fourteen-year-old Luyanda Hlali walks 10 kilometers to school. She lives in the little village of Stratford in South Africa's KwaZulu-Natal <strong>province</strong>.</p>
<p>There are no school buses. There is only the long road where robbers and bad men can harm her.</p>
<p>Luyanda is one of tens of thousands of children in South Africa who live a long way from their public school. The communities they live in are mostly rural and poor.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Luyanda Hlali, left, and her friend Mimi Dubazane embark on their routine 2 hour-long walk from the village of Stratford to their school in Dundee, South Africa, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. (AP Photo/ Mogomotsi Magome)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-1a20-08dbea9eaef1_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Luyanda Hlali, left, and her friend Mimi Dubazane embark on their routine 2 hour-long walk from the village of Stratford to their school in Dundee, South Africa, Thursday, Oct. 26, 2023. (AP Photo/ Mogomotsi Magome)</span></div>
<p>Observers say students having to travel long distances to public schools shows the country's inequality when it comes to attending school. It has been nearly 30 years since the nation ended its <strong>apartheid</strong> system and the African National Congress party took power bringing democratic change.</p>
<p>There is a lack of school transportation paid for by the government.</p>
<p>Girls face the threat of attack and robberies are common. Parents, local leaders, and activists say the situation increases existing inequalities. The World Bank says South Africa is the most unequal country in the world.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal, campaigners and activists are pressing government officials to provide transportation for over 200,000 schoolchildren. The children have to walk three kilometers or more to school.</p>
<p>President Cyril Ramaphosa's government policy requires officials to provide transportation for the students who have to walk that distance. But school buses are not a concern in an area where unemployment is over 25 percent and people are poor.</p>
<p>A 2020 Amnesty International report said a child's experience in South Africa "still very much depends on where they are born, how wealthy they are, and the color of their skin."</p>
<p>South Africa's education system, the report said, "has deep roots in the <strong>legacy</strong> of apartheid, but which are also not being effectively <strong>tackled</strong>" by the government.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal, more than 30 percent of the province's 12.4 million people are unemployed. Many say they have to choose between buying food or paying $19 a month for public transportation.</p>
<p>"Sometimes these children go to school without eating breakfast," said Bongiwe Nhlangothi, Luyanda's grandmother.</p>
<p>She is the most scared when her grandchildren are traveling.</p>
<p>"There are drug <strong>addicts</strong> around here, when they come across the children in the early hours of the morning, they rob them of their phones, threaten them with knives and try to rape them," Nhlangothi said.</p>
<p>A school <strong>principal</strong> in a village about 50 kilometers from the coalmining town of Dundee, told of his struggle to get more school buses approved. The principal said some of the school's female students had been raped by local criminals.</p>
<p>The school has two old buses, but they can only carry about 65 children. There are more than 400 students at the school. The principal said he fears one of the buses could permanently break down or crash.</p>
<p>In September 2022, reports said 18 students were killed in the province when their overcrowded minivan crashed on the way to school in the town of Pongola.</p>
<p>Some parents have decided to pay to have their children to live closer to their schools. But boarding a student is costly and leaves parents without help at home.</p>
<p>Activist Tebogo Tshesane works for the nonprofit organization Equal Education. He said the campaign for better school transportation across KwaZulu-Natal started back in 2014. It started after students wrote letters because they were walking for up to two hours to school.</p>
<p>Government information says 1,148 schools in KwaZulu-Natal are on a waiting list for school transportation paid for by the government.</p>
<p>The provincial department of education did not wish to talk to <em>The Associated Press</em> for this story.</p>
<p>The answer from the education department is that there is no money, so the children keep walking.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>province </strong><em>— n. </em>a large part or division of a country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>apartheid </strong><em>— n. </em>the system of racial separation in South Africa which was legal until it was abolished in the early 1990s</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>legacy </strong><em>— n. </em>what people leave to their children after they die</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tackle </strong><em>–v. idiom </em>to deal with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>addict </strong>–n. a person who cannot stop taking drugs</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>principal </strong><em>— n.</em><strong> </strong>the leader of a grade school or secondary school</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving: An American Tradition  (2023/11/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/thanksgiving-american-tradition-2017.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Ashley Thompson</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American holiday of Thanksgiving is celebrated every year on the fourth Thursday in November. The holiday is during autumn -- the main season for harvesting crops. Thanksgiving is an autumn harvest <strong>festival</strong> like those found in many cultures around the world.</p>
<p>On this day, most Americans gather with friends and family. Many take time to think about what they are thankful for, cook <strong>up a storm</strong>, and eat.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A VOA Learning English Thanksgiving" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1acdaeb8-5890-43e7-9251-a0272d935591_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A VOA Learning English Thanksgiving</span></div>
<p>A lot.</p>
<p>The star of most Thanksgiving dinners is a <strong>roasted </strong>turkey. Turkeys are large birds native to North America.</p>
<p>The turkey is cooked in an oven for many hours, often with a mix of celery, bread, onions and spices inside the bird. This mix becomes <strong>stuffing </strong>-- another star of the Thanksgiving dinner table.</p>
<p>Anna Matteo here at Learning English says the smell of turkey and stuffing roasting together is the quintessential smell of Thanksgiving. "Quintessential" means the perfect example of something.</p>
<p>After the bird is cooked, the stuffing is taken out and served as a side dish.</p>
<p>One of <em>many </em>side dishes. Families often make other foods like mashed potatoes, sweet potatoes, cranberry sauce and vegetable casseroles. A casserole is a dish that cooks slowly in an oven.</p>
<p>And do not forget about the gravy. This rich sauce is made from the fatty liquid that comes off the turkey as it cooks. People cover their turkey meat, stuffing and mashed potatoes with gravy.</p>
<p>The meal does not end with the turkey, stuffing, and side dishes, though. For some people, the best part of the meal is dessert.</p>
<p>The quintessential Thanksgiving dessert is pie. Pumpkin, cherry, apple or pecan pie are all great ways to finish off a Thanksgiving meal...if you are not too full of food by that point!</p>
<p><strong>Thanksgiving travel </strong></p>
<p>Some Americans must travel long distances to be with their families. In fact, the Sunday after Thanksgiving is the busiest travel day of the entire year. This is usually when people return home from family gatherings.</p>
<p>Not everyone can make the return home each Thanksgiving. So, young people living in cities away from their hometowns sometimes celebrate "Friendsgiving" -- a Thanksgiving meal with their friends instead of their family. They gather at someone's apartment or house and have a "<strong>potluck</strong>." This is a meal where everyone who is invited brings food to share with others.</p>
<p><strong>Beyond the table</strong></p>
<p>Thanksgiving is a big day for television, games and other entertainment.</p>
<p>One tradition is the television broadcast of Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade. It takes place each year in New York City. Workers of the Macy's store on Herald Square organized the first parade in 1924. Many of the workers were immigrants and wanted to hold a big parade like the ones in Europe. So, they dressed in costumes and borrowed some animals from the zoo. They also carried small balloons that floated just overhead.</p>
<p>Many professional American football games are also played on Thanksgiving. Fans of the sport enjoy relaxing and watching a game or two after eating a big Thanksgiving meal.</p>
<p>Some start Thanksgiving Day early - and in a healthy way. So-called "Turkey <strong>Trot</strong>" races take place in many towns and cities. These events involve runners dressing up in a Thanksgiving-related costume and running a short distance -- usually five kilometers.</p>
<p>Many Turkey Trots urge runners to bring canned food to donate to local food banks -- non-profit organizations that give food to poor people in a community.</p>
<p><strong>Serving those less fortunate</strong></p>
<p>Certainly, not everyone in America has an easy Thanksgiving. The United States is home to many poor and homeless people. Some cannot afford a Thanksgiving dinner. Others are without friends or families. Many religious and service organizations around the country try to fill these needs. Some provide community dinners at churches and other centers. Some groups also deliver Thanksgiving meals to people too sick or old to leave their homes.</p>
<p>The writer O. Henry called Thanksgiving the one holiday that is purely American. It is not linked to a religion or a certain group. Anyone in the United States on the fourth Thursday of November is welcome to celebrate Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>And I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Ashley Thompson wrote this story for Learning English. It was first published in 2017.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>festival</strong> - <em>n</em>. a special time or event when people gather to celebrate something</p>
<p><strong>up a storm</strong> - <em>idiom</em>. used to say that something is being done with a lot of energy or enthusiasm</p>
<p><strong>roasted </strong>- <em>adj</em>. cooked with dry heat in an oven or over a fire</p>
<p><strong>stuffing</strong> - <em>n</em>. a seasoned mixture of food that is put inside another food and cooked</p>
<p><strong>potluck</strong> - <em>n</em>. a meal to which everyone who is invited brings food to share</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers: Report Cards Unclear about Students Knowledge, Learning  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/researchers-report-cards-unclear-about-students-knowledge-learning.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>A recent opinion study says a big majority of parents in the United States believe their child is performing at grade level in school. However, standardized tests show far fewer students are <strong>on track</strong>.</p>
<p>Polling company Gallup and the nonprofit group Learning Heroes released the public opinion <strong>poll</strong> this month.</p>
<p>Report cards show students' school performance. Parents depend on them to understand their child's progress. But report cards do not show all of a student's performance, researchers say. Without more knowledge about their child's learning, parents might not seek extra support for their children if it is needed.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Students work in the library during homeroom at D.H.H. Lengel Middle School in Pottsville, Pa., March 15, 2022. (Lindsey Shuey/Republican-Herald via AP, File) " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-eb5e-08dbea15e985_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Students work in the library during homeroom at D.H.H. Lengel Middle School in Pottsville, Pa., March 15, 2022. (Lindsey Shuey/Republican-Herald via AP, File) </span></div>
<p>Bibb Hubbard is the founder and president of Learning Heroes, based in Arlington, Virginia. Report cards are "the number one <strong>indicator</strong> that parents turn to to understand that their child is on grade level, yet a grade does not equal grade-level <strong>mastery</strong>. But nobody's told parents that."</p>
<p>In the Gallup poll, 88 percent of parents believed their child was on grade level in reading, and 89 percent of parents believed their child was on grade level in math. However, a federal survey of school officials said half of all U.S. students started the last school year behind grade level in at least one subject.</p>
<p>One report examined <strong>grade point averages</strong> and test scores in the state of Washington over the past 10 years. Researchers found grades increased during the COVID-19 pandemic. Many school systems had eased their grading policies because of the difficulties students were experiencing.</p>
<p>Some of those policies could still be in place, <strong>masking</strong> the lack of learning that is showing up in standardized tests, but not in grades, said Dan Goldhaber. He is a co-author of the report and the director of the Center for Analysis of Longitudinal Data in Education Research, in Arlington, Virginia.</p>
<p>School systems across the U.S. have spent federal aid money from the COVID-19 crisis on programs to get students back on track. For example, school systems have introduced more <strong>tutoring</strong> and summer academic programs. But Goldhaber said fewer students attended these programs than the system had planned.</p>
<p>For programs like summer school or online tutoring, the family chooses whether to <strong>participate</strong>. "What we see is that it's only a <strong>fraction</strong> of the students that are invited or <strong>eligible</strong> that are actually participating," he said.</p>
<p>The Gallup poll findings suggest that parents might not know they could be taking action to help their child's school performance.</p>
<p>The poll involved more than 2,000 parents of students from kindergarten to twelfth grade. Half the respondents said they have discussed their child's academic progress with a teacher. Among parents who know their child is behind grade level in math, the percentage greatly increases: 74 percent have spoken with a teacher.</p>
<p>Report cards do not give enough information, said Sarah Carpenter. She is director of The Memphis Lift, an education activist group in Tennessee.</p>
<p>"A report card is really tricky in our opinion, because you're just looking at A's and B's and C's," Carpenter said. She said a report card does show whether a child's reading or math level is where it should be and added that parents do not understand this.</p>
<p>Trenace Dorsey-Hollins is a parent and founder of another activist group Parent Shield Fort Worth in Texas. She said if educators spoke to parents about issues like reading and grading, families would be better able to support their children.</p>
<p>She said, "Parents don't know what they don't know. So, we don't want them to blame themselves. But now that you have the information, use the information to demand better and ensure that your child and all children get exactly what they need."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>on track </strong><em>–phrase</em> happening in a way that is expected or planned</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>poll </strong><em>— n. </em>a study in which researchers as people their opinions about a subject to learn what people think about it</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>indicator </strong><em>–n.</em> a sign that shows the condition or the existence of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mastery </strong><em>— n. </em>being able to do something expertly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grade point average </strong>–n. a number that shows the average grade that a student has in school</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mask </strong><em>— v. </em>to hide something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor</strong><em> –v. </em>to teach either one or a small group of students outside of normal class time</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>participate </strong><em>— v.</em><strong> </strong>to take part in something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fraction </strong><em>–n.</em> a part of a whole</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>eligible </strong><em>— adj. </em>able to join something or receive something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Did Thanksgiving 'Turkey' Get Its Name?  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/thanksgiving-turkey-name-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Ashley Thompson and Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Thanksgiving holiday is <strong>symbolized </strong>by its traditional food, a large bird we call a turkey. But turkey is certainly not from Turkey.</p>
<p>In fact, its English name is based on one big mistake. We could say it is a case of mistaken identity.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="President Joe Biden speaks after pardoning the national Thanksgiving turkey, Liberty, during a pardoning ceremony at the White House in Washington, Monday, Nov. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-b0b6-08dbea009118_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">President Joe Biden speaks after pardoning the national Thanksgiving turkey, Liberty, during a pardoning ceremony at the White House in Washington, Monday, Nov. 20, 2023. (AP Photo/Susan Walsh)</span></div>
<p>Let's set the record straight.</p>
<p>The word "Turkey" has meant "the land of the Turks" since ancient times. The word "turkey" as it refers to the bird first appeared in the English language in the mid-1500s.</p>
<p>The misunderstanding over the word happened because of two similar-looking kinds of birds.</p>
<p>There is an African bird called the guinea fowl. It has dark feathers with white spots and a patch of brown on the back of its neck. Portuguese traders brought the guinea fowl to Europe through North Africa.</p>
<p>This foreign bird came to Europe through Turkish lands. So, the English thought of the bird as a "Turkish chicken."</p>
<p>When Europeans came to North America, they saw a bird that looked like the guinea fowl. This bird was native to the North American continent.</p>
<p>Orin Hargraves is a lexicographer, someone who writes dictionaries. Hargraves explains what happened.</p>
<p>"Some Europeans saw an American turkey, thought that it was the guinea fowl, which at that time was called the ‘turkey cock,' and so gave it the same name."</p>
<p>Hundreds of years later, we continue to call this North American bird "turkey," even though it has no connection at all with the country Turkey, or even with Europe.</p>
<p>But English is not the only language with interesting -- and even questionable -- names for this North American bird.</p>
<p>The Turkish, for their part, call turkey "hindi," the Turkish name for India<em>.</em> The reference to India probably comes from the old, wrong idea that the New World was in Eastern Asia.</p>
<p>The French call it "dinde," a name that also connects the bird to India. "D'Inde" means "from India" in the French language. "Turkey" has similar names in several other languages.</p>
<p>So, what do they call this North American bird in India? Well, in the Hindi language, "turkey" is "tarki."</p>
<p>But wait, there's more. In Portuguese, the same bird is called "Peru," after the South American nation.</p>
<p>Thanks to our VOA Learning English Facebook friends, we have a few more names for "turkey" to share with you.</p>
<p>The Vietnamese word for the bird is "gà t<i></i>226;y" or western chicken. Our Facebook friend Nguyen Duc explains that "local chicken is smaller than western chicken."</p>
<p>A Facebook friend in Myanmar explained that the Burmese word for "turkey" is "kyat sin." The name <strong>translates </strong>to "elephant chicken" in English.</p>
<p>"That animal looks like a big chicken," Zaw Myo Win explained.</p>
<p>The Dari language name for the bird, "fel murgh" also translates to "elephant chicken."</p>
<p>Abdulla Kawer explained to us that "here in Afghanistan this name represents the size of this delicious meal." He adds that he thinks the descriptive name "elephant chicken" is "better than a country name."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Ashley Thompson and Anna Matteo wrote this report for Learning English. It was first published in 2017.</em></p>
<p><em>How do you say 'turkey' in your language? Let us know in the comments section!</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>symbolize </strong><em>- v. </em>to represent or express a particular idea or quality</p>
<p><strong>translate<em> </em></strong><em>- v. </em>to change words from one language into another language</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Poor’ New Hampshire Man Leaves Millions to Small Town  (2023/11/22)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/poor-new-hampshire-man-leaves-millions-to-small-town.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">21 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>When Geoffrey Holt of Hinsdale, New Hampshire died earlier this year at 82, not many people knew he had over $1 million.</p>
<p>He wore worn-out clothes. He did not do jobs that paid a lot of money. He rode a bicycle instead of owning a car, and he had a small home.</p>
<p>But when he had extra money, he invested it well. One friend said he put money into a mutual fund that held stock in communications companies. This was in the days before mobile phones.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by Ed Smith, Geoffrey Holt rests his leg on top of his riding mower in Hinsdale, N.H., on April 4, 2020. Holt left the town of Hinsdale nearly $4 million when he died last June. (Ed Smith via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/732da797-835b-461f-b5cf-e59fe821829b_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by Ed Smith, Geoffrey Holt rests his leg on top of his riding mower in Hinsdale, N.H., on April 4, 2020. Holt left the town of Hinsdale nearly $4 million when he died last June. (Ed Smith via AP)</span></div>
<p>Holt told one friend, Edwin Smith, that the money had grown more than he expected.</p>
<p>Holt died with $3.8 million.</p>
<p>He left all the money to the town of Hinsdale.</p>
<p>The town has about 4,200 people and is about 160 kilometers northwest of Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>In Holt's will, the document he left when he died, he said the money should be used for education, health, recreation and culture.</p>
<p>Steve Diorio is one of the town leaders. He called the money "a <strong>tremendous</strong> gift."</p>
<p>No determination has been made yet about how the town will use the money. However, it seems as if the money will go into a special <strong>fund</strong>, and organizations can submit their ideas for approval.</p>
<p>Some have suggested upgrading the town hall clock, others have talked about repairing <strong>civic</strong> buildings or buying a vote-counting machine.</p>
<p>Kathryn Lynch is another town leader. She said Hinsdale will use the money carefully, or "<strong>frugally,</strong>" which is how Holt lived.</p>
<p>Smith, Holt's friend, said "he seemed to have what he wanted, but he didn't have much."</p>
<p>Holt would ride his bicycle or his lawn mower around town. He would go to a small store to buy a newspaper and he would sit on the lawn mower reading it or watching cars pass.</p>
<p>When he was younger, he worked as a manager for a grain production center. After the center closed, he did small jobs around town – helping people fix things in their homes or teaching teenagers how to drive. He did not have a television, and his friend said his home was not in perfect condition – the legs of his bed made holes in the floor.</p>
<p>But Smith said Holt studied financial magazines and carefully decided how to invest his money. He also liked reading about history – some of his favorite topics included World War II and learning about the auto manufacturer Henry Ford. He also enjoyed listening to classical music and had a record collection that included works by Handel and Mozart.</p>
<p>Holt's sister, Alison, is 81. She lives in California. She said she knew her brother invested his money and did not like to spend wastefully. She said their father passed the ideas along to his children.</p>
<p>Alison said her brother had a learning disability called dyslexia, so he had trouble reading and writing. "But he was very smart in certain ways."</p>
<p>She thought that Geoffrey was disappointed he could not succeed in education, so "maybe <strong>socking</strong> <strong>away</strong> all that money was a way to compete."</p>
<p>The Holts grew up nearby in Springfield, Massachusetts. Geoffrey Holt went to Marlboro College in Vermont and also served in the U.S. Navy.</p>
<p>Neither Geoffrey nor his sister had any children. Alison said her brother did not need a lot to be happy. But she is sad he never used the money to "<strong>indulge</strong> himself a little bit."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based a story by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tremendous </strong><em>–adj.</em> very large or great</p>
<p><strong>fund </strong><em>–n.</em> an amount of money that is meant to be used for or serves a specific purpose</p>
<p><strong>civic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to a city or town</p>
<p><strong>frugally </strong><em>–adv.</em> being careful not to spend money when it is not necessary; the careful use of money</p>
<p><strong>sock</strong> <strong>away </strong><em>–v. </em>(phrasal, informal) to save a supply of something, often money, by putting it in a safe place</p>
<p><strong>indulge </strong><em>–v.</em> to permit yourself or someone else to do something purely for the pleasure of it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Workers Trapped in Tunnel in India Given Hot Meal  (2023/11/22) | 印度受困隧道工人吃上热饭</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/workers-trapped-in-tunnel-in-india-given-hot-meal.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The 41 workers who have been trapped in a collapsed tunnel in northern India for over a week are finally getting hot meals on Tuesday. The meals of rice and lentils are sent through a newly placed steel pipe as rescuers are working on a plan to dig them out vertically.<br/>
被困在印度北部一条坍塌隧道中超过一个星期的41名工人终于在周二吃到了热饭。大米和扁豆通过一根新放置的钢管输送，救援人员正在制定垂直挖掘将他们救出的计划。</p>
<p>For the last nine days, the workers survived with dry food sent through a smaller pipe. They also received a supply of oxygen through another one.<br/>
在过去的九天里，工人们靠一根较小的管道输送的干粮生存了下来。他们还通过另一根管道获得了氧气供应。</p>
<p>Officials released a video on Tuesday showing the workers in their safety hats moving around the blocked tunnel. It also showed them communicating with rescuers on the ground through small radio equipment called walkie-talkies. Family members said they felt better after seeing images of their loved ones.<br/>
官方周二发布了一段视频，显示工人们戴着安全帽，在被堵塞的隧道附近走动。视频还显示工人们通过被称为对讲机的小型无线电设备与地面救援人员进行通信。家属们表示，看到亲人的影像后，他们感觉好多了。</p>
<p>The tunnel collapsed in Uttarakhand state. It is a mountainous area that has been difficult for the drilling machine. It broke down as rescuers attempted to dig horizontally toward the trapped workers. Movement from the machine has also caused more rocks to fall. After more rocks fell, officials suspended rescue operations for a moment.<br/>
北阿坎德邦的隧道坍塌。这是一个对钻机来说很困难的山区。当救援人员试图向被困工人水平挖掘时，它发生了故障。机器的移动也导致了更多的岩石掉落。在更多的岩石掉落后，官方暂停了救援行动。</p>
<p>Currently, rescuers are creating a path to the top of the hill from where they will dig vertically. Officials said Monday that from the vertical direction, drilling to the tunnel will take a few days and rocks could fall during the digging. Rescue teams will need to dig 103 meters downwards to reach the trapped workers, nearly double the distance.<br/>
目前，救援人员正在开辟一条通往山顶的道路，从那里他们将进行垂直挖掘。官员们周一表示，从垂直方向钻通隧道需要数天时间，在挖掘过程中可能会有岩石掉落。救援队需要向下挖掘103米才能找到被困工人，这几乎是距离的两倍。</p>
<p>Officials said they would also continue digging horizontally from the mouth of the tunnel toward the workers.<br/>
官员们表示，他们还将继续从隧道口向工人方向进行水平挖掘。</p>
<p>The workers have been trapped since November 12. A landslide may have caused part of the tunnel they were building to collapse 200 meters from the opening.<br/>
这些工人自11月12日以来一直被困。一场山体滑坡可能导致他们正在修建的隧道在距离洞口200米处坍塌。</p>
<p>Mahmood Ahmed is head of the state-run National Highways and Infrastructure Development Corporation. He said, "We might be able to get a breakthrough in the next 30-40 hours."<br/>
马哈茂德·艾哈迈德是国营国家公路和基础设施发展公司的负责人。他说：“我们可能会在接下来的30-40小时内取得突破。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Top Leadership Changes at ChatGPT Maker OpenAI  (2023/11/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/top-leadership-changes-at-chatgpt-maker-openai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) system developer OpenAI was under new leadership Monday after a series of recent changes that included the removal of former chief executive Sam Altman.</p>
<p>OpenAI said on Friday it had dismissed Altman after a "breakdown of communications," with the company's board of directors, several news services reported. Altman's "behavior and lack of <strong>transparency</strong>" had limited "the board's ability to effectively supervise the company," the <em>New York Times</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/20/technology/openai-altman-ceo-not-returning.html">reported</a> a non-public company document as saying.</p>
<p>OpenAI announced it had replaced Altman with Emmett Shear, a technology executive who formerly led live video gaming service Twitch.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Sam Altman, left, appears onstage with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at OpenAI's first developer conference, on Nov. 6, 2023, in San Francisco. Microsoft hired Altman after his sudden departure from OpenAI. (AP Photo/Barbara Ortutay, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-786c-08dbea0b4fe7_cx7_cy16_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Sam Altman, left, appears onstage with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella at OpenAI's first developer conference, on Nov. 6, 2023, in San Francisco. Microsoft hired Altman after his sudden departure from OpenAI. (AP Photo/Barbara Ortutay, File)</span></div>
<p>Greg Brockman, a president and co-founder of OpenAI, along with several company leaders, quit after Altman's removal. Some wrote on X, "OpenAI is nothing without its people."</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press</em> reported that several hundred OpenAI employees also signed a letter calling for the board to step down and Altman to return.</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft investment</strong></p>
<p>Microsoft has invested billions of dollars in OpenAI in recent years. The company has supported the AI developer's machine learning models with its knowledge and experience in building powerful computing machines. Both Microsoft chief Satya Nadella and OpenAI's Shear said they remain committed to their existing business partnership.</p>
<p>Microsoft also announced on Monday that it had hired Altman, along with Brockman, to lead a new specialized AI research team at the company.</p>
<p>Nadella wrote on X that he was "extremely excited" to bring on the former executives of OpenAI and looked "forward to getting to know" Shear and the rest of the leadership team. Altman wrote on X, "the <strong>mission</strong> continues," while Brockman promised, "We are going to build something new &amp; it will be incredible."</p>
<p>Altman became the face of a new generation of AI systems, called chatbots, that have captured a flood of media attention in recent years. Chatbots are designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. The technology is also known as "generative AI." The launch and widespread popularity of OpenAI's ChatGPT tool started a wave of development in the field.</p>
<p>In a statement on X, Shear dismissed media reports suggesting Altman's removal came because of disputes between top OpenAI leaders over the safety of the company's AI methods. Shear promised to hire an independent investigator to look into what led to Altman's ouster and offered to give a report within 30 days.</p>
<p>"It's clear that the process and communications around Sam's removal has been handled very badly, which has seriously damaged our trust," wrote Shear. He noted he also plans in the coming weeks to "reform the <strong>management</strong> and leadership team in light of recent departures into an effective force" and speak with employees, investors and users of OpenAI products.</p>
<p>Shear noted the reason behind the board removing Altman was not a "specific disagreement on safety." Media reports have suggested disputes within OpenAI's leadership about the company's stated plans to safely build AI that is "generally smarter than humans."</p>
<p>On a podcast in June, Shear said he is generally <strong>optimistic</strong> about technology. But he noted he has serious concerns about a possible path to create systems that are "a lot smarter than us" and could endanger humans.</p>
<p>Shear wrote that he had accepted the job "because I believe that OpenAI is one of the most important companies currently in existence."</p>
<p>Richard Windsor heads the British-based financial research company Radio Free Mobile. He told Reuters there had been conflicts between OpenAI's mission to build technology to help people and that of its investors, who have expected a financial return on their investments in the company.</p>
<p>"This weekend was simply the <strong>detonation</strong> of a bomb that has been waiting to go off," Windsor said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transparent </strong><em>– adj. </em>clear and easy to understand or recognize</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>an important job or task, often involving travel to somewhere</p>
<p><strong>management </strong><em>– n. </em>being in control of a company or organization</p>
<p><strong>optimistic</strong><em> – n. </em>thinking in a positive way about something</p>
<p><strong>detonate</strong><em> – v. </em>to blow up</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Drug Trials Often Do Not Include Overweight People  (2023/11/21)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/drug-trials-often-do-not-include-overweight-people.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">20 November 2023</span><br/>
<p>More than 40 percent of American adults are considered obese, or medically overweight. But the medications many of these individuals take are rarely tested in bigger bodies.</p>
<p>Obese people are currently not required to be included in drug studies. Often, they are purposefully left out.</p>
<p>This is a problem because the amount of drugs an obese person should take to be safe is unknown, says Christina Chow. She is a researcher who has sought to bring attention to the need to include obese people in drug development and testing. "There's no real <strong>emphasis</strong> for them to be studied at all," Chow told <em>The Associated Press.</em></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Tablets of ibuprofen are arranged for a photograph in New York on Thursday, Nov. 2, 2017. Even a drug as common as ibuprofen, sold as Advil, may not relieve pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows. (AP Photo/Patrick Sison, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6b82de11-6031-43a4-afd6-338dc037edb7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Tablets of ibuprofen are arranged for a photograph in New York on Thursday, Nov. 2, 2017. Even a drug as common as ibuprofen, sold as Advil, may not relieve pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows. (AP Photo/Patrick Sison, File)</span></div>
<p>Medications can work differently in people who are obese, but exactly how and at what amount is not clear. Research suggests this includes antibiotics and antifungal drugs, medications used to treat serious infections. It even includes ibuprofen, a commonly used painkiller that can be bought without a doctor's orders.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the National Institutes of Health (NIH) are the agencies that control and provide money for drug testing. At a gathering last year, FDA Commissioner Dr. Robert Califf noted a "deficit of evidence" about how medicines act in patients who are obese. The NIH now asks researchers to think about the results of not including obese people in their studies, an agency spokesperson said.</p>
<p>At a recent medical conference, Chow presented a review of more than 200 studies for new drugs in the U.S. last year. Nearly two-thirds of the studies failed to include weight or body mass index, a numerical value noting if a person is obese.</p>
<p>Historically, some populations have not been included in drug testing to avoid harm, including pregnant women and children. In the past, women, racial and ethnic minorities and aged people have also not been included.</p>
<p>Dr. Caroline Apovian is a researcher at Brigham and Women's Hospital in Boston. She is the co-author of Chow's study. Apovian told the AP there are many reasons people who are obese are not included in drug tests.</p>
<p>She noted that people who volunteer for trials are often thin and healthy and this does not effectively represent the general population. Obese individuals can have many health difficulties, and researchers often worry this will affect results of their work.</p>
<p>"Sometimes patients with obesity have many more <strong>comorbidities</strong> than others. They'll have more diabetes, more heart disease, more strokes," Apovian said.</p>
<p>But if drugs are not studied in a condition that affects 42 percent of the U.S. population, the real-world effects can be <strong>dire</strong>, experts say.</p>
<p>Some drugs remain in the body longer in obese people. That could result in harmful drug interactions if another medication is added too soon. There can also be less medication in the blood, leading to undertreatment, Apovian said.</p>
<p>Rexulti is a drug often used to treat people with <strong>schizophrenia</strong> or depression, Chow noted. Research has shown that in obese patients it may take much longer to reach the amount of Rexulti needed to be effective. As a result, many patients and their doctors may stop treatment too early or believe the drug does not work.</p>
<p>"Not treating or undertreating schizophrenia may be dangerous to themselves and the people around them," Chow said.</p>
<p>Even a drug as common as ibuprofen may not reduce pain in people at higher weights when taken as directed, research shows.</p>
<p>But without testing and clear directions, doctors won't know the amount of medicine needed for obese people, said Dr. Colleen Tenan. She is a board member of the Association of Clinical Research Professionals. Tenan said it is very hard to be a doctor and direct patients to take amounts of medication that have not been tested.</p>
<p>Change is coming, but progress is slow, said Dr. Alison Edelman. She is an obstetrician and researcher at Oregon Health &amp; Science University. She told the AP that in 2019, the FDA suggested that researchers permit obese women in studies on birth control. Even though the suggestions are not required, they have already changed how she and other researchers structure their studies.</p>
<p>"Because unless we see representation in our study population, we don't end up with treatments that work well for individuals," Edelman said.</p>
<p>Apovian, from Brigham and Women's Hospital, said patients can ask their doctors about whether the usual amount of a medication is acceptable for their weight. Even if the doctors do not know, the question could start an important discussion about the most effective treatments.</p>
<p>"This is a big issue," Apovian said. "It can be important for patients to speak up."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Jonel Aleccia reported this story for The Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>emphasis </strong>–<em>n</em>. special importance</p>
<p><strong>comorbidities - </strong><em>n</em>. two or more diseases or medical conditions in a patient</p>
<p><strong>dire </strong>– <em>adj</em>. extremely serious or urgent</p>
<p><strong>schizophrenia </strong>– <em>n</em>. a disease that affects the way the brain processes information and causes a loss of touch with reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Argentine’s President Must Deal with Inflation, Weak Economy  (2023/11/21) | 阿根廷新总统上任面临高通胀和经济低迷</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202311/new-argentine-s-president-must-deal-with-inflation-weak-economy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Libertarian Party politician Javier Milei has won Argentina's presidential election with 56 percent of the vote.<br/>
自由党政治家哈维尔·米莱以56%的选票赢得了阿根廷总统大选。</p>
<p>Now President-elect Milei must face the South American country's economic problems.<br/>
现在，当选总统米莱必须面对这个南美国家的经济问题。</p>
<p>Inflation has been measured at over 140 percent. The country lacks foreign currency for international trade, people who aim to save are selling the Argentine Peso, and a recession appears likely. About 40 percent of Argentines live in poverty.<br/>
通货膨胀率已超过140%。该国缺乏用于国际贸易的外汇，旨在储蓄的人们正在出售阿根廷比索，经济衰退似乎很可能发生。大约40%的阿根廷人生活在贫困之中。</p>
<p>Milei is promising to close Argentina's central bank. He also supports dollarization. Dollarization means Argentina would stop using its peso and instead use the U.S. dollar for money.<br/>
米莱承诺关闭阿根廷央行。他还支持美元化。美元化意味着阿根廷将停止使用比索，转而使用美元作为货币。</p>
<p>Milei won a second-round of voting on Sunday with about 56 percent against opponent Sergio Massa's 44 percent.<br/>
米莱在周日的第二轮投票中以56%的得票率战胜了对手塞尔吉奥·马萨的44%。</p>
<p>Now he will try to turn around the economy once he takes office on December 10. Failure could lead to the country's tenth debt default, increased poverty, and possible social unrest.<br/>
现在，他将在12月10日上任后努力扭转经济形势。失败可能导致该国第十次债务违约，加剧贫困，并可能引发社会动荡。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Inflation<br/>
通货膨胀</span></p>
<p>Argentina's high inflation rate creates huge problems in its markets and for consumers. Prices change weekly. Economic experts predict a yearly rate of 185 percent inflation by the end of the year.<br/>
阿根廷的高通胀率给其市场和消费者带来了巨大的问题。价格每周都会变化。经济专家预测，到今年年底，年通货膨胀率将达到185%。</p>
<p>To reduce inflation, Argentina's central bank has increased the interest rate to 133 percent, which pushes people to save Argentine pesos. However, this move makes it too costly to borrow money and hurts economic growth.<br/>
为了降低通货膨胀，阿根廷央行将利率提高到133%，这促使人们储蓄阿根廷比索。然而，此举使借贷成本过高，并损害了经济增长。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Peso controls<br/>
比索控制</span></p>
<p>Capital controls have harmed the value of Argentina's peso since a stock market crash there in 2019. However, different exchange rates for currencies of other nations have led to problems. For example, the U.S. dollar's official exchange rate is about 350 pesos per dollar, but news reports say it can trade for a far higher price under different controls.<br/>
自2019年阿根廷股市崩盘以来，资本管制损害了阿根廷比索的价值。然而，其他国家货币的不同汇率导致了问题。例如，美元的官方汇率约为每美元350比索，但新闻报道称，在不同的控制下，美元的交易价格可能会高得多。</p>
<p>Milei has promised to quickly undo capital controls and to dollarize the country's economy.<br/>
米莱承诺将迅速取消资本管制，并使该国经济美元化。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Central bank reserves<br/>
中央银行准备金</span></p>
<p>Argentina's central bank reserves of foreign currency are near their lowest level since 2006. A major drought affected the exports of important crops like soy, corn, and wheat, which used to bring in enough foreign exchange money.<br/>
阿根廷央行的外汇储备接近2006年以来的最低水平。一场严重的干旱影响了大豆、玉米和小麦等重要作物的出口，这些作物过去可以带来足够的外汇。</p>
<p>Low reserves threaten the country's ability to repay its debts to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and private bondholders. It will also be difficult to pay for imported goods.<br/>
低储备威胁到该国偿还国际货币基金组织和私人债券持有者债务的能力。进口商品的付款也将很困难。</p>
<p>The government has agreed on an extended currency swap with China to help enable it to carry out foreign trade. Argentina also had to delay some payments to important trade partners like neighboring Brazil.<br/>
政府已同意延长与中国的货币互换，以帮助其开展对外贸易。阿根廷还不得不推迟向邻国巴西等重要贸易伙伴支付部分款项。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Recession<br/>
经济衰退</span></p>
<p>Argentina is Latin America's third-largest economy. But it is expected to shrink by two percent this year, the central bank predicted. The recession is partly being blamed on the drought that cut corn and soy crops in half.<br/>
阿根廷是拉丁美洲第三大经济体。但央行预测，今年其经济预计将萎缩2%。经济衰退的部分原因是干旱导致玉米和大豆作物减产一半。</p>
<p>With very high inflation, poverty will likely increase as workers' pay and savings decrease.<br/>
在通货膨胀非常高的情况下，随着工人工资和储蓄的减少，贫困可能会增加。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Possible improvement<br/>
可能的改进</span></p>
<p>Argentina, rich in important grains, natural gas, and lithium, could see an increase next year as improved weather helps crops. A new gas pipeline will reduce dependence on costly imports, and demand is rising for the lithium needed for electric vehicle batteries.<br/>
阿根廷拥有丰富的重要谷物、天然气和锂，随着天气改善有助于作物生长，明年的产量可能会增加。一条新的天然气管道将减少对昂贵进口的依赖，电动汽车电池所需的锂需求正在上升。</p>
<p>Soy and corn are expected to have stronger harvests, which will bring in much-needed foreign currency.<br/>
大豆和玉米预计将有更强劲的收成，这将带来急需的外汇。</p>
<p>Eugenio Marí is head economist at Libertad y Progreso Foundation. He said agriculture and oil and gas from rocks, called shale, can help the economy. The "harvest will help bring a greater flow of income in the economy, as will the greater production of (shale oil formation)," he said.<br/>
欧赫尼奥·马里是利伯塔德·普罗格雷索基金会的首席经济学家。他说，农业和来自页岩的石油和天然气可以帮助经济发展。他说：“农业丰收将有助于为经济带来更大的收入流，页岩油产量也将增加。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
