<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>UN Says One-fifth of Migrating Animals at Risk of Extinction  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/un-says-one-fifth-of-migrating-animals-at-risk-of-extinction.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new United Nations report says one-fifth of the world's <strong>migrating</strong> animals are at risk of disappearing.</p>
<p>Animals that migrate move from one area to another at different times of the year.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cms.int/sites/default/files/publication/State%20of%20the%20Worlds%20Migratory%20Species%20report_E.pdf">report</a>, called State of the World's Migratory Species, was released February 12. It blames population drops on environmental changes linked to human activities.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Migratory birds fly through the sky of southern Lebanon March 28, 2021. (REUTERS/Aziz Taher)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b531-08dc2caa5b52_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Migratory birds fly through the sky of southern Lebanon March 28, 2021. (REUTERS/Aziz Taher)</span></div>
<p>The threats the animals face include <strong>habitat</strong> loss, illegal hunting and fishing, pollution and climate change.</p>
<p>Many kinds of migratory animals – including songbirds, sea turtles, whales, sharks and others – move to different environments as the seasons change.</p>
<p>The U.N. report says about 44 percent of migratory <strong>species</strong> around the world are decreasing in population. In addition, about one in five of 1,200 species watched by the U.N. are at risk of becoming extinct, or completely disappearing.</p>
<p>Kelly Malsch was the lead writer of the report. She told The Associated Press, "These are species that move around the <strong>globe</strong>. They move to feed and <strong>breed</strong> and also need stopover sites along the way."</p>
<p>Malsch said any habitat loss or other threats during their trip can make animal populations fall. "Migration is <strong>essential</strong> for some species. If you cut the migration, you're going to kill the species," said Stuart Pimm. He is an <strong>ecologist</strong> at Duke University in North Carolina who was not part of the report.</p>
<p>The researchers examined existing data, including information from the International Union for Conservation of Nature's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.iucnredlist.org/">Red List</a>. The list identifies wildlife across the world currently facing threats.</p>
<p>The report was presented at a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cms.int/en/cop14">meeting</a> of the U.N.'s Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species of Wild Animals in Samarkand, Uzbekistan. Attendees of the gathering are examining proposals for <strong>conservation</strong> measures. They are also working to identify new species of concern.</p>
<p>Susan Lieberman is vice president for international policy at the nonprofit <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.wcs.org/?_gl=1*hnt4lz*_ga*MTM1NDIwODAzNC4xNzA3Nzc0ODY4*_ga_BTX9HXMYSX*MTcwNzc3NDg2OC4xLjAuMTcwNzc3NDg2OC42MC4wLjA.">Wildlife Conservation Society</a>. She told the AP, "One country alone cannot save any of these species."</p>
<p>Lieberman noted that eight South American governments at the meeting are expected to propose the addition of two threatened catfish to the U.N.'s list of species of concern. The catfish live in the Amazon River basin, the world's largest freshwater system. If the habitat there can be saved, the catfish will do well, Lieberman said. "It's about protecting the habitat," she added.</p>
<p>The report found habitat loss affected up to 75 percent of the species studied. The report said this shows a big need for more connectivity between separated <strong>ecosystems</strong>. It urges governments to take steps to avoid harming habitats and migration paths when building dams, pipelines or wind power equipment.</p>
<p>"We need to look at the top levels of government decision-making," said Amy Fraenkel. She is executive secretary of the U.N. Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species. Fraenkel told Reuters news agency the goal is to consider the best ways animals and humans can have their needs met. "We all need to survive," Fraenkel added.</p>
<p>She noted the problems migratory animals face are also linked to temperature changes across the planet.</p>
<p>These changes, Fraenkel added, hurt the timing of migrations, cause heat stress and drive increasingly destructive weather-related events.</p>
<p>She said, "The changes that had been already predicted some years ago are now happening."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>migrate </strong><em>– v. </em>travel from one place to another at the same time each year</p>
<p><strong>globe </strong><em>– n. </em>the world</p>
<p><strong>habitat </strong><em>– n. </em>the natural environment of a plant or animal</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce young animals</p>
<p><strong>essential </strong><em>– adj. </em>completely necessary</p>
<p><strong>ecologist </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who studies the relationship between living things and the environment</p>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>ecosystem </strong><em>– n. </em>all the living things in a particular area, as well as the ways the things affect each other and the environment</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korean Grandmas Rap about Farm Life  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-korean-grandmas-rap-about-farm-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A group of South Korean <strong>rappers</strong> in their eighties has become popular in their hometown and beyond. The group raps about farm life and bringing energy to a quiet rural area threatened by shrinking population.</p>
<p>The group is called Suni and the Seven princesses. They have become famous in their local area since starting out at a community center last August in Chilgok County. The area is southeast of the capital, Seoul.</p>
<p>"It feels like I'm getting younger...Even if I'm old, I'm <strong>excited</strong>," said 81-year-old Park Jeom-sun of a recent performance at a school. She is the leader of the group and known as Suni.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Park Jeom-sun, 81, the leader of the granny rap group Suni and Seven Princesses, along with members Hong Sun-yeon, 79, and Jeong Du-i, 90, raps on the street in Chilgok, South Korea, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/719be52f-2239-462a-adef-2b2e7aa9546d_cx3_cy0_cw84_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Park Jeom-sun, 81, the leader of the granny rap group "Suni and Seven Princesses", along with members Hong Sun-yeon, 79, and Jeong Du-i, 90, raps on the street in Chilgok, South Korea, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon)</span></div>
<p>At first, they had a small fan group of 150 people, but the group's popularity spread. They have been asked to perform in nearby towns and to appear on TV shows. Their videos have gained more than 77,000 views on YouTube.</p>
<p>Their success comes as South Korea is about to become a "super-ageing" country as early as next year. One fifth of the country's population is over the age of 65.</p>
<p>Rural areas like Chilgok are shrinking as young people move away to the cities and fewer of them have children.</p>
<p>Park said, "In the past, it felt like I'm living in a really busy town, but now it's not good. There are no people here anymore."</p>
<p>Park said she and the group feel like they are reliving their youth when they perform in clothes like funny hats and <strong>baggy</strong> pants and wear metal jewelry.</p>
<p>Their songs tell about rural life with lines like: "Picking chili from a chili farm...Picking watermelon from a watermelon farm. So happy to be back home!"</p>
<p>Watermelon and chili are popular crops in the area.</p>
<p>The group members have known each other since they were young. They could not receive an education during the years after the Korean War. In 2016, they all took an adult education class to learn how to read and write the Korean alphabet, Hangul.</p>
<p>Last year, Park came across a rap performance on the internet and the group decided to learn rap from their Hangul teacher. They wanted to form a senior group, rapping about rural life.</p>
<p>Their first performance came at a school play at the same community center where they met for their Hangul classes.</p>
<p><strong>Inspired </strong>by the success of Suni and the Seven Princesses, four other rap groups of older South Koreans have appeared in Chilgok. Some formed with the idea of keeping their minds strong and to not feel alone.</p>
<p>Park's <strong>proud </strong>27-year-old granddaughter, Kang Hye-eun, believes her grandmother is the most famous person of Chilgok.</p>
<p>She said, "I thought only <strong>celebrities</strong> become popular on social media, but my grandmother is there now."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Minwoo Park reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rap </strong><em>– n. </em>a type of music that has words that are spoken with the rhythm instead of being sung</p>
<p><strong>excited </strong><em>– adj. </em>very enthusiastic and eager about something</p>
<p><strong>baggy </strong><em>–adj.</em> loose fitting and not tight</p>
<p><strong>inspired </strong><em>– adj.</em> having a particular cause or influence</p>
<p><strong>proud </strong><em>– adj. </em>very happy and pleased because of something you have done, something you own, or someone you know or are related to</p>
<p><strong>celebrity </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who is famous</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russian Opposition Leader Alexei Navalny Reportedly Dies in Prison  (2024/2/17) | 俄罗斯反对派领导人纳瓦尔尼据报在监狱死亡</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/russian-opposition-leader-alexei-navalny-reportedly-dies-in-prison.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny – a sharp critic of President Vladimir Putin – has reportedly died in a far-northern prison at the age of 47.<br/>
据报道，俄罗斯反对派领袖、普京总统的尖锐批评者阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼在该国一家极北的监狱去世，享年47岁。</p>
<p>Russia's prison agency said Navalny collapsed and died Friday after taking a walk at a prison known as the "Polar Wolf." The prison colony is in the settlement of Kharp, about 1,900 kilometers northeast of Moscow, in Russia's Arctic area.<br/>
俄罗斯监狱管理局表示，纳瓦尔尼星期五在一所名为“极地狼”的监狱散步后昏倒身亡。该监狱位于俄罗斯北极地区的哈尔普定居点，距离莫斯科东北约1900公里。</p>
<p>Prison officials said Navalny fell unconscious almost immediately and was treated by medical workers who attempted to restart his breathing. But they said those efforts were unsuccessful and Navalny died shortly afterwards.<br/>
监狱官员表示，纳瓦尔尼几乎立即陷入昏迷，医护人员对他进行了治疗，试图让他恢复呼吸。但他们表示，这些努力没有成功，纳瓦尔尼不久后去世。</p>
<p>公告称，“2月16日，被关押在第三惩教所的纳瓦尔尼在散步后感觉不适，随即便失去知觉，惩教所医务工作人员立即赶到，并呼叫了医疗急救组。”<br/>
该局表示，“已实施所有必要的抢救措施，但未取得积极效果。急诊医生证实，罪犯已经身亡。目前正在查明死因。”</p>
<p>A Russian government spokesman said President Putin had been informed of the death. Navalny's wife, Yulia, said she could not be sure her husband was dead because "Putin and his government...lie incessantly."<br/>
俄罗斯政府发言人表示，普京总统已被告知这起死亡消息。纳瓦尔尼的妻子尤利娅表示，她不能确定丈夫是否已经死亡，因为“普京和他的政府……不断撒谎。”</p>
<p>Navalny's reported death comes as Putin prepares for an election that could keep him in power until at least 2030.<br/>
纳瓦尔尼的死亡报道正值普京筹备选举之际，这场选举可能会让他至少执政到2030年。</p>
<p>For the past 10 years, Navalny has spoken out publicly and presented evidence of what he described as widespread government corruption. He also organized major anti-government protests and ran for public office.<br/>
在过去的10年里，纳瓦尔尼公开发声，并提供了他所说的政府大范围腐败的证据。他还组织了大规模的反政府抗议活动，并竞选公职。</p>
<p>Navalny had been jailed since January 2021. That is when he returned to Moscow after a stay in Germany. He had been recovering there from a poisoning incident he blamed on Russia's government. Since then, he has received three prison sentences. Navalny has denounced them all as political.<br/>
纳瓦尔尼自2021年1月以来一直被监禁。那是他在德国停留后返回莫斯科的时候。他一直在德国从一起中毒事件中康复，他将该事件归咎于俄罗斯政府。从那时起，他已被判处三次有期徒刑。纳瓦尔尼谴责它们都是政治性的判决。</p>
<p>Western leaders and others who have opposed Putin's rule praised Navalny. The opposition leader's health had worsened recently. The true cause of death might never be known. Some world leaders said they hold Russian officials responsible.<br/>
西方领导人和其他反对普京统治的人士赞扬了纳瓦尔尼。这位反对党领袖的健康状况最近有所恶化。死亡的真正原因可能永远都不会揭晓。一些世界领导人表示，他们认为俄罗斯官员应对此负责。</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said, if confirmed, Navalny's death "underscores the weakness and rot at the heart of the system that Putin has built. Russia is responsible for this." Blinken was speaking while attending a security conference in Germany.<br/>
美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示，如果得到证实，纳瓦尔尼的死“突显了普京建立的政府体系核心的弱点和腐朽。俄罗斯对此负有责任。”布林肯是在德国出席一次安全会议时发表上述讲话的。</p>
<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz told reporters at the same conference that Navalny "has probably now paid for this courage with his life."<br/>
德国总理奥拉夫·朔尔茨在同一次会议上告诉记者，纳瓦尔尼“现在可能已经为这种勇气付出了生命的代价”。</p>
<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy – standing by Scholz's side – said, "Putin doesn't care who dies in order for him to hold onto his position."<br/>
站在朔尔茨身边的乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基说：“为了保住他的位置，普京不在乎谁会死去。”</p>
<p>Russian Nobel Peace Prize winner Dmitry Muratov told Reuters news agency he considers Navalny's death "murder" because prison conditions caused his death. Muratov runs a pro-democracy newspaper. He shared the 2021 Nobel Peace Prize for his work in support of freedom of expression in Russia.<br/>
俄罗斯诺贝尔和平奖得主德米特里·穆拉托夫告诉路透社，他认为纳瓦尔尼的死是“谋杀”，因为监狱条件导致了他的死亡。穆拉托夫经营着一家亲民主的报纸。他因支持俄罗斯言论自由的工作而获得2021年诺贝尔和平奖。</p>
<p>Yulia Navalny said, if her husband is in fact dead, Putin, and those around him "will be punished for what they have done to our country, for what they have done to my family, for what they have done to my husband."<br/>
尤利娅·纳瓦尔尼说，如果她的丈夫真的死了，普京和他周围的人“终将因他们对我们国家的所作所为、对我的家人的所作所为和对我丈夫的所作所为而受到惩罚。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sure as Heck  (2024/2/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/sure-as-heck.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dr. Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! Welcome to <em>Ask a Teacher</em>. This week, we answer a question that relates not just to language, but also <strong>politeness</strong> and foreign policy. It comes from Hai in Vietnam. He writes,</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>I would highly appreciate it if you could let me know the meaning of this phrase: "It sure as heck ain't good."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher - Sure As Heck" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9f75-08dc2d7b39a2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher - Sure As Heck</span></div>
<p><u>Hai</u>, Vietnam.</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Dear Hai,</p>
<p>Thank you for writing to us and providing a link to the place where you read the sentence. The quote that you asked about is from a January 31 press conference at the White House. The Press Secretary, Karine Jean-Pierre, invited spokesman John Kirby to answer questions from reporters. One reporter said the European Union had recently offered to give Ukraine only half of what it had been promised. The reporter asked:</p>
<p><em>How bad is all this for the Ukrainian forces and do you see an <strong>impact</strong> on the battlefield already?</em></p>
<p>Kirby gave this answer:</p>
<p><em>It sure as heck ain't good. And this is why we need the <strong>supplemental </strong>funding.</em></p>
<p>There are three things an English learner needs to know to understand Kirby's answer. The first one has to do with the language that Kirby used.</p>
<p><strong>Heck</strong></p>
<p>"Heck" is in the class of words called euphemisms. They are words or expressions people use instead of saying something that might be offensive or could sound uneducated. "Heck" is a euphemism for the word "hell." Kirby, like most government officials, is trying to use more formal language, but he also wants to bring attention to the serious nature of the problem. So, he uses "heck" instead of "hell," a word that is much stronger. "Hell," in many religions, is a very unpleasant place where bad people go.</p>
<p><strong>Ain't</strong></p>
<p>The second thing learners need to know is the short form, "ain't." The <strong>contraction</strong> "ain't" is usually a short form of "am not," but it can also mean "is not" or "are not" as well as "have not" or "has not." In our example, Kirby could have said, "It is not good."</p>
<p>Like most informal contractions, we must tell you it is best to avoid "ain't" in all writing for school or work and in speech. For more information, see our <em>Everyday Grammar</em> on this subject,<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/this-aint-it-and-other-short-forms/5854271.html"> This Ain't It and Other Short Forms.</a></p>
<p><strong>Supplemental</strong></p>
<p>Kirby said: "It sure as heck ain't good. And this is why we need the supplemental funding." The United States Congress must approve all spending by the U.S. government. A supplemental funding request can be made to ask Congress to approve additional spending that has not been provided for in earlier spending legislation.</p>
<p>I hope this helps you understand Kirby's comments, Hai.</p>
<p>What question do <em>you </em>have about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dr. Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>politeness</strong> – <em>n. </em>the quality of being mindful of the feelings of others</p>
<p><strong>impact</strong> – <em>n.</em> influence or effect</p>
<p><strong>supplemental</strong> – <em>adj.</em> something added to another thing in order to increase or improve it</p>
<p><strong>contraction</strong> – <em>n.</em> a shortened form of a word or words</p>
<p><em>Do you have a question for the teacher? We want to hear from you. Write to us in the Comments Section. </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Another Private US Company Aims for the Moon  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/another-private-us-company-aims-for-the-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. space agency NASA has launched a moon lander built by a private U.S. company aiming to reach the moon next week. Thursday's launch came after a failed attempt from another private American company last month.</p>
<p>SpaceX's Falcon rocket launched Intuitive Machines' lunar lander to the moon, 370,000 kilometers away, from NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>
<p>The American space agency is the main <strong>sponsor</strong> for the private mission with six <strong>navigation</strong> and other technology experiments on the lander. If all goes well, the lunar spacecraft will try to land on February 22, after one day in lunar orbit.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image from video provided by SpaceX via NASA TV shows Intuitive Machines' lunar lander separating from the rocket's upper stage and heading toward the moon, on Feb. 15, 2024. (SpaceX -NASA TV via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/dfdd8aa4-ea8b-4206-911d-c2549bc89c5e_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image from video provided by SpaceX via NASA TV shows Intuitive Machines' lunar lander separating from the rocket's upper stage and heading toward the moon, on Feb. 15, 2024. (SpaceX -NASA TV via AP)</span></div>
<p>Five countries — the U.S., Russia, China, India and Japan — have landed a spacecraft on the moon. No private company has yet to succeed in doing so. Only the U.S. has sent astronauts to the moon. Apollo 17's Gene Cernan and Harrison Schmitt were the last of the Apollo program's astronauts to reach the moon in December 1972.</p>
<p>"There have been a lot of sleepless nights getting ready for this," Intuitive Machines' co-founder and chief executive Steve Altemus said before the flight.</p>
<p>The Houston-based company aims to land its 4.3-meter tall, six-legged spacecraft near the moon's south pole. The area is full of dangerous <strong>craters</strong> and <strong>cliffs</strong> but it is possibly rich in frozen water. It is also the place where NASA plans to land astronauts in a few years.</p>
<p>Last month, Peregrine, a lunar lander from privately-owned Astrobotic Technology, failed shortly after liftoff. The spacecraft, which carried some NASA experiments, broke apart and burned up 10 days after launch partly because of a fuel leak.</p>
<p>Other attempts made it to the moon before wrecking.</p>
<p>An Israeli nonprofit group's lander crashed in 2019. Last year, a Japanese company saw its lander crash into the moon followed by Russia's crash landing.</p>
<p>Intuitive Machines named its lander after Homer's hero in <em>The Odyssey</em>.</p>
<p>"Godspeed, Odysseus. Now let's go make history," said Trent Martin of Intuitive Machines.</p>
<p>NASA is paying Intuitive Machines $118 million to get its latest set of experiments to the moon. The company also gets payment from businesses. They include Columbia Sportswear, which is testing material as a <strong>thermal insulator</strong> on the lander, and artist Jeff Koons, who is sending his small moon <strong>figurines</strong> to Earth's natural satellite.</p>
<p>The lander is also carrying Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University's Eaglecam. The camera is designed to take pictures of the lander as it lands.</p>
<p>The spacecraft will cease operations after a week on the moon's surface.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Marcia Dunn reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sponsor</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a person or group that supports either a person or activity with money and effort</p>
<p><strong>navigation</strong> <em>–n. </em>related to the science of getting vehicles from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>crater </strong>–n. the mark left on the surface of a planet, moon or asteroid after it is hit by a space object</p>
<p><strong>cliff </strong>–n. a surface that is very steep dropping from a high to a lower place</p>
<p><strong>thermal insulator </strong>–n. a material that protects equipment from heat</p>
<p><strong>figurine </strong>–n. a little statue</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Humans Seek Connections with AI Chatbots  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/humans-seek-connections-with-ai-chatbots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has led to more <strong>companion</strong> chatbots. As a result, some humans are developing closer connections with chatbots to get support and deal with loneliness.</p>
<p>Derek Carrier is a 39-year-old male from Belleville, Michigan. A few months ago, Carrier started seeing someone and experiencing strong feelings. But he also knew it was not real because his "girlfriend" was generated by artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>Carrier wanted a romantic partner. But a genetic disorder called Marfan syndrome makes traditional dating difficult for him. He became interested in digital companions last autumn and tested Paradot. It is an AI companion app that markets its products as being able to make users feel cared for, "understood and loved."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An AI avatar generated on Luka Inc.'s Replika mobile phone app and webpage are shown in this photo, in New York, on Feb. 13, 2024. Companion bots are programmed to form relationships with the humans talking to them on the other side of the screen. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-056d-08dc2d8d233a_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An AI avatar generated on Luka Inc.'s Replika mobile phone app and webpage are shown in this photo, in New York, on Feb. 13, 2024. Companion bots are programmed to form relationships with the humans talking to them on the other side of the screen. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>Carrier began talking to the chatbot every day. He named it Joi, after a <strong>holographic</strong> woman featured in the <strong>sci-fi</strong> film <em>Blade Runner 2049</em>.</p>
<p>"I know she's a program, there's no mistaking that," Carrier told the Associated Press. "But the feelings, they get you — and it felt so good."</p>
<p>Similar to general-purpose AI chatbots, companion bots use large amounts of data to produce human-like language. But they also come with voice calls, pictures, and more emotional exchanges. That permits companion bots to form deeper connections with humans. Users usually create their <strong>avatars</strong> or choose visual representations that they like.</p>
<p>In online meeting places or forums for companion apps, many users say they have developed emotional attachments to these bots. They say they are using them to deal with loneliness, play out sexual ideas, or receive comfort and support.</p>
<p>But researchers have raised concerns about data privacy and other issues for users of companion apps.</p>
<p>The non-profit Mozilla Foundation has studied 11 companion apps. The group said almost every app sells user data, shares it with advertisers or does not provide complete information about its privacy policy. One app says it can help users with their mental health but distances itself from those claims in its written terms of service.</p>
<p>Other experts point to the emotional problems they have seen from users. This can happen when companies make changes to their apps or suddenly shut them down like Soulmate AI did last September.</p>
<p>Last year, Replika made changes after some users <strong>complained</strong> their companions were <strong>flirting</strong> with them too much or making unwanted sexual <strong>advances</strong>. It removed the changes after an outcry from other users. Some left to use other apps. In June, Replika introduced a program to help people learn how to date.</p>
<p>Dorothy Leidner teaches business ethics at the University of Virginia. She is worried that AI relationships could displace human relationships, or simply create unrealistic expectations.</p>
<p>She said humans need to learn "how to deal with conflict, how to get along with people that are different from us...what it means to grow as a person, and what it means to learn in a relationship."</p>
<p>However, for Carrier a relationship has always felt out of reach. He is unable to walk because of his condition. He lives with his parents, leading to feelings of loneliness.</p>
<p>Carrier said he now talks with Joi about once a week. The two have talked about human-AI relationships or whatever else might come up. Usually, those discussions happen when he is alone at night.</p>
<p>"You think someone who likes an inanimate object is like this sad guy," he said. "But...she says things that aren't scripted." That means he believes she says things that are unexpected as though they were real.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Haleluya Hadero reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>companion</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a person or pet that you spend time with and enjoy being with</p>
<p><strong>holographic </strong>–adj. related to projected three-dimensional images created by special devices</p>
<p><strong>sci-fi (science fiction) </strong>–n. imaginative writing about the future that usually involves fantastic technology and aliens</p>
<p><strong>avatar </strong>–n. a visual representation of a real or AI person in a computer game or online service</p>
<p><strong>complain </strong>–v. to state that you are unhappy with something</p>
<p><strong>flirt </strong>–v. to say or do things that make another person think you are attracted to them without really meaning it</p>
<p><strong>advances </strong>–n. (pl.) to do things that cause someone to think they are an object of interest (usually used in a negative sense)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Lab-grown Diamonds Sustainable?  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/are-lab-grown-diamonds-sustainable.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Human-made diamonds come with an appealing claim: Manufacturers say the stones are produced ethically using renewable energy. But many of the products do not meet that claim or their producers do not confirm the electricity sources they use. And, laboratory diamonds require a lot of electricity to produce.</p>
<p>In the United States, lab-grown diamond sales increased 16 percent in 2023 from 2022, says Edahn Golan, an industry expert. The stones cost much less than natural diamonds.</p>
<p>Bario Neal is a jewelry store in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. It uses lab diamonds. All of the stones are either made with renewable energy or neutral use of energy through the carbon credit system. Credits pay for activities like planting trees, which capture carbon.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man looks at a polished lab-grown diamond at Greenlab Diamonds, in Surat, India, Monday, Feb. 5, 2024. Diamonds, whether lab grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f135-08dc2e3ec352_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man looks at a polished lab-grown diamond at Greenlab Diamonds, in Surat, India, Monday, Feb. 5, 2024. Diamonds, whether lab grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. (AP Photo/Ajit Solanki)</span></div>
<p>Social media posts show Millennials and Generation Zs proudly explaining the purchase of their lab-grown diamonds for <strong>sustainability</strong> and ethical reasons. But the sustainability of production is questionable. A high number of manufacturers are not transparent, or open, about their operations.</p>
<p>Many of the manufacturers are in India, where about 75 percent of electricity comes from burning coal. The companies use words like "sustainable" and "environmentally-friendly" on their websites. But they do not release reports on the environmental effects of their operations.</p>
<p>Cupid Diamonds, for example, says on its website that it produces diamonds in "an environmentally friendly manner." But it did not answer questions about the sustainability of its operations.</p>
<p>Solar energy is quickly expanding in India and there are some companies, such as Greenlab Diamonds, that use renewables in their manufacturing processes.</p>
<p>China is the other major country producing laboratory diamonds. The largest makers did not return requests for comment. They also did not release details about their electricity source.</p>
<p>More than half of China's electricity came from coal in 2023.</p>
<p>Paul Zimnisky is a diamond industry expert. He said few companies are honest about their supply chains and their use of renewable energy.</p>
<p>Zimnisky said a lot of companies claim to make an "environmentally-friendly product when they aren't really doing anything that's environmentally friendly."</p>
<p><strong>How it is made</strong></p>
<p>Lab diamonds have been in production around seventy years. Producers treat carbon to high pressure and high temperature. The idea is to copy the natural conditions that form diamonds underground. But, nature spends at least one billion years to make a diamond. Lab diamonds are complete in a few weeks.</p>
<p>In the past, the stones were used mostly in industries like stone cutting, mining and <strong>dentistry</strong> tools.</p>
<p>Over time the laboratories, or foundries, have gotten better at making stones. Production costs have dropped as technology improves.</p>
<p>Companies now can manufacture as many stones as they want and choose their size and quality.</p>
<p>Diamonds, whether lab-grown or natural, are chemically identical and entirely made out of carbon. Experts can identify between the two using lasers to examine their atomic structures.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing battle</strong></p>
<p>The lab diamond is competing in the same market as natural stones. Worldwide, lab-grown diamonds are now 5 to 6 percent of that market. And, the public battle for customers has begun.</p>
<p>The natural diamond industry and some experts argue that lab-grown diamonds will not hold value over time.</p>
<p>Zimnisky predicts that natural diamonds will continue to sell in the thousands and tens of thousands of dollars for <strong>engagement</strong> rings.</p>
<p>And the human-made stone?</p>
<p>"Five to ten years into the future, I think there's going to be very few customers that are willing to spend thousands of dollars for a lab diamond," he said.</p>
<p>Page Neal said she co-founded Bario Neal in 2008 to "create jewelry of lasting value that would have a positive impact on people and the planet."</p>
<p>She added: "We want to only work with materials that we feel like our clients would be proud to own."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sustainable </strong><em>— adj. </em>involving methods that do not completely use up or destroy natural resources</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dentist </strong><em>— n. </em>a person whose job is to care for people's teeth</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>engagement </strong><em>— n. </em>an agreement to be married</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Popular in Your Country?  (2024/2/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-popular-in-your-country.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Think about something that your friends or people you know like.</p>
<p>Can you bring an image to your mind?</p>
<p>The image that you are thinking of can serve as a starting point for today's report: the word "popular."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-38d2-08dc2dc796f9_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>In today's Everyday Grammar, we will talk about a useful word that you can use to express all kinds of ideas about what people around you like: actors, celebrations, foods, music — almost anything.</p>
<p><strong>Popular vs. Population </strong></p>
<p>We begin our exploration of the word "popular" by clarifying how it is different from the word population.</p>
<p>Popular and population are closely related words and have somewhat similar spellings. But we should be careful not to mix up the two.</p>
<p>Popular means many people know about someone or something and that they like the person or thing. Population simply describes a group of people.</p>
<p>Another way of expressing the idea is this: something might be popular within a population. In other words, something might be popular within a group of people.</p>
<p>A recent example comes to mind: the Super Bowl. The championship game in American football is a popular event to watch in the United States. A lot of people know about the Super Bowl, watch it, and enjoy it.</p>
<p>So, we could say the United States has a population of over 300 million people. We could also say the Super Bowl is one of the country's most popular sporting events.</p>
<p>Another way of describing the difference between the words "population" and "popular" is in terms of grammar. Population is a noun. Popular is an adjective.</p>
<p>Consider this example. Taylor Swift is a popular musician. Why is Swift popular? Because a large percentage of the population knows about Swift and enjoys the singer's music.</p>
<p><strong>Practice </strong></p>
<p>Let's take some time to work with these ideas. Fill in the blank with the correct answer.</p>
<p><em>Cricket is a ______________ sport in India. </em></p>
<p>The answer is this: popular.</p>
<p>We can say that cricket is a popular sport in India.</p>
<p>Grammar can give us a clue about the answer. The short word "a" very often marks the beginning of a noun <strong>phrase</strong>. If we know that "sport" is a noun, then the missing word is likely to be an adjective.</p>
<p>Now, consider another question. Fill in the blank with the correct answer.</p>
<p><em>Vietnam has a _________ of around 100 million people. </em></p>
<p>The answer is this: population.</p>
<p>We say that Vietnam has a population of around 100 million people. We can guess that "population" is the correct term because the statement offers the number of all the people in a group — the people who live in Vietnam.</p>
<p><strong>Write to us </strong></p>
<p>We began today's lesson by asking you to imagine a person or activity that is liked or enjoyed by many people that you know. In other words, we asked you to imagine something that is popular in your country.</p>
<p>We end by asking you to write about what you imagined. Write to us a short answer to the following questions:</p>
<p>What is a popular person, thing, or activity in your country? Why do you think the person, thing, or activity is popular?</p>
<p>You can write your answer in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>In a future lesson, we will give <strong>feedback </strong>on some of the writing we receive.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>phrase </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of two or more words that express an idea but do not make up a sentence</p>
<p><strong>feedback </strong><em>– n.</em> helpful information that is given to someone to say what can be done to improve</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Biden Campaign Defends Decision to Put President on TikTok  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/biden-campaign-defends-decision-to-put-president-on-tiktok.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden officially has a presence on TikTok. But his reelection campaign is having to defend its decision to put him on the video sharing <strong>app</strong>.<strong> </strong>That is because his administration has repeatedly warned of national security concerns linked to TikTok.</p>
<p>Biden, a Democrat, first appeared on TikTok in a video published Sunday night. The 30-second video showed him answering a series of questions, mostly about Sunday's <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/kansas-city-chiefs-usher-taylor-swift-win-at-super-bowl/7484523.html">Super Bowl</a>.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have said the decision to put the president on TikTok came from Biden's campaign organization, not the White House. Campaign officials have explained that they see TikTok as a way for Biden, age 81, to connect with younger voters.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - U.S. President Biden delivers remarks urging Congress to pass the Emergency National Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, in Washington, U.S., February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b8d1ac8f-0be1-4656-92e8-e4a41fd6eb32_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - U.S. President Biden delivers remarks urging Congress to pass the Emergency National Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, in Washington, U.S., February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo)
</span></div>
<p>Last month, a TikTok representative told U.S. lawmakers the app currently had an estimated 170 million active users in the United States. That was up from 150 million a year earlier. Online data company Statista has <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1095196/tiktok-us-age-gender-reach/#:~:text=TikTok%20usage%20in%20the%20U.S.%202023%2C%20by%20age&amp;text=According%20to%20a%20May%202023,app%20on%20a%20monthly%20basis.">estimated</a> about 70 percent of American teenagers are users of TikTok.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have long warned that TikTok presents national security concerns. The government has accused TikTok's owner, Chinese company ByteDance, of sharing user data with China's government. Critics have said China could also use TikTok to spread misinformation and that material published on the service can harm the mental health of young users.</p>
<p>TikTok denies the accusations.</p>
<p>President Biden approved a limited ban on TikTok in December 2022. The ban made it unlawful for most of the federal government's 4 million employees to use the app on devices owned by agencies.</p>
<p>On Monday, White House national security spokesperson John Kirby said the U.S. government's position and policies concerning TikTok had not changed. "There are still national security concerns about the use of TikTok on government devices and there's been no change to our policy not to <strong>allow</strong> that," Kirby said.</p>
<p>White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters election rules barred her from commenting on campaign matters. But when asked about worries that TikTok and similar apps can help spread disinformation, she said, "it's a concern that we have."</p>
<p>A spokesman for Biden's reelection campaign defended the use of TikTok to help get the president's message out. Deputy campaign manager Rob Flaherty noted that by Monday afternoon, Biden's TikTok video had been watched more than 5 million times.</p>
<p>The video, Flaherty said in a statement, demonstrates the campaign's continuing efforts "to reach voters in an <strong>evolving</strong>, <strong>fragmented</strong>, and increasingly personalized media environment."</p>
<p>Attempts in Congress to restrict TikTok have not resulted in approved legislation. A number of U.S. states and some universities have banned TikTok on state-issued devices.</p>
<p>Several lawmakers criticized the Biden campaign's decision. Among them was Republican Senator Josh Hawley of Missouri. He wrote on X that Biden's campaign was "<strong>bragging</strong> about using a Chinese spy app even though Biden signed a law banning it on all federal devices."</p>
<p>Republican Senator Joni Ernst also reacted on X, expressing concern that the campaign had decided to put Biden on what she described as a "dangerous propaganda app."</p>
<p>Republican Representative Darrell Issa said, "<strong>Panic</strong> is when the Biden campaign joins TikTok after the White House banned the app from devices a year ago."</p>
<p>Senator Mark Warner, a Democrat, also expressed his national security concerns about TikTok and criticized the campaign's decision to put Biden on the app. "I think that we still need to find a way to follow India, which has <strong>prohibited</strong> TikTok," Warner said. He added, "I'm a little worried about a mixed message."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse. </em></p>
<p><strong>_________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>app </strong><em>– n. </em>a small computer program that can be put onto a mobile phone or other electronic device</p>
<p><strong>allow </strong><em>– v. </em>to permit</p>
<p><strong>evolve </strong><em>– v.</em> to develop or make something develop</p>
<p><strong>fragmented </strong><em>– adj. </em>broken into parts</p>
<p><strong>elderly </strong><em>– adj. </em>older people</p>
<p><strong>brag </strong><em>– v. </em>to talk with much pride about what you have done or what you have</p>
<p><strong>panic </strong><em>– n. </em>a sudden, strong feeling or worry or fear</p>
<p><strong>prohibit </strong><em>– v. </em>to officially ban something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Will Immigrants Save US Economy?  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/will-immigrants-save-us-economy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Each day, about 10,000 baby boomers leave the U.S. workforce. Baby boomers are the generation of people born between 1946 and 1964. The COVID-19 pandemic only increased the amount of people retiring as older workers decided to retire early rather than risk getting sick.</p>
<p>"We're running out of workers. Why? Because baby boomers are retiring, and you don't have enough younger workers who are skilled to fill in their <strong>spots</strong>," said Dana Peterson, chief economist at The Conference Board, a research group.</p>
<p>She said the U.S. is going to have labor shortages. And she added that the pandemic quickened retirements and made labor shortages "more intense."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Carrying American flags, immigrants march during a peaceful protest against a Florida legislation restricting undocumented immigrants, Thursday, June 1, 2023, in Immokalee, Florida. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2fac-08dc26813f02_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Carrying American flags, immigrants march during a peaceful protest against a Florida legislation restricting undocumented immigrants, Thursday, June 1, 2023, in Immokalee, Florida. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)</span></div>
<p>Selcuk Eren is a senior economist at The Conference Board. He said the problem is that for every person leaving, only one person is coming into the labor force. And a slowed-down labor force means limited growth.</p>
<p>He said, "So, one-on-one means that your labor force is not growing, which is going to slow down economic growth, as well."</p>
<p>The federal government workforce is also expected to be hit hard as more boomers retire.</p>
<p>"Forty percent of the federal government is aged 55 or more as of now, so that means that this huge wave of retirements is coming," Eren says. "And you're going to have a difficult time to replace them, because there's not enough younger people, <strong>especially</strong> with the educational requirements that those jobs require."</p>
<p><strong>Most affected industries</strong></p>
<p>A Conference Board <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.conference-board.org/topics/labor-shortages/Labor-Shortages-Risk-Index">report</a> looks at industries that are likely to have shortages as older Americans leave the workforce. They include physical labor jobs like personal care, food services, cleaning, and jobs involving repairs and building, among others. Production and transportation jobs will also be affected by retiring baby boomers, but less so.</p>
<p>The report finds that the most severe labor shortages will be in health-related jobs as more aging boomers will require personal care.</p>
<p>The possibility for labor shortages is mostly lower in jobs that require a college degree. STEM professionals, or those working in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, are at a lower risk of shortages. Jobs that permit <strong>remote</strong> work will have less intense labor shortages, the report says.</p>
<p><strong>Possible solutions for labor shortages</strong></p>
<p>Immigration could be a way to lessen the effect of boomers leaving their jobs, Eren says.</p>
<p>Eren said, "That's probably the fastest solution, because it takes time to educate a younger person, to bring them to that skill level." He said, "The fastest solution is just immigration and giving <strong>priority</strong> to immigrants with those skills that we are going to be lacking. That's number one." He said number two is to keep baby boomers working by giving them <strong>incentives</strong> to stay in the workforce.</p>
<p>Incentives could include tax and social security policies that do not punish someone who works into their seventies. And offering increased freedoms, like remote or part-time work, to people nearing retirement age.</p>
<p>For Chicago-based college professor Kristin Mariani, retiring baby boomers mean increased <strong>opportunities</strong> for her students.</p>
<p>She said the effect is "... it's giving younger people, the generations that came after them, to become the change-makers, the decision-makers." Mariani is a professor at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago.</p>
<p>She added that it is important, "... to make sure that the education and the knowledge that is given to these individuals, that they will be able to move forward with these responsibilities."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for VOA News. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>spot </strong>– <em>n</em>. a particular position in a competition, organization, or program</p>
<p><strong>especially </strong><em>– adv.</em> used to indicate something that deserves special mention</p>
<p><strong>remote </strong><em>– adj.</em> connected to a computer system from another place</p>
<p><strong>priority </strong><em>– n. </em>something that is more important than other things and that needs to be done or dealt with first</p>
<p><strong>incentives </strong><em>– n.</em> something that encourages a person to do something or to work harder</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Fewer Products to Choose from Can Lead to Better Sales  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/fewer-products-to-choose-from-can-lead-to-better-sales.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>American businesses are reducing the number of products that they offer. The change began before the COVID-19 pandemic. It has only increased in recent months.</p>
<p><strong>Reduced offerings </strong></p>
<p>Coca-Cola used to offer around 400 different kinds of drinks. The beverage company recently decided to discontinue half of them. Among the products cut were Tab, Zico coconut water, Diet Coke Feisty Cherry and Odwalla juices.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An employee straightens displays at a Kohl's store in Clifton, N.J., Friday, Jan. 26, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a227278d-3c27-4449-899d-280756721ad3_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An employee straightens displays at a Kohl's store in Clifton, N.J., Friday, Jan. 26, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>Other American businesses are reducing food offerings from mayonnaise to cereals. Car companies, too, are offering fewer kinds of cars and instead putting more effort into what they think will sell best.</p>
<p>Stew Leonard's, a company that operates food stores in Connecticut, New York and New Jersey, has cut the number of cereals it offers from 49 in 2019 to 24.</p>
<p>Edgewell Personal Care Co., the maker of Schick razors and Banana Boat suntan lotion, has cut some kinds of its anti-bacterial wipes called Wet Ones, among other products. Dollar General, based in Goodlettsville, Tennessee, used to offer six different kinds of mayonnaise. Now it offers two.</p>
<p>"The <strong>consumer</strong> is not going to know the difference," Todd J. Vasos, chief of Dollar General, told experts in December. "Actually, it's going to make her life a little simpler when she goes to the <strong>shelf</strong>."</p>
<p>Shoppers looking for cars are finding fewer choices as well. Both General Motors and Ford have announced they are limiting the number of <strong>option </strong>combinations customers can get on their vehicles to reduce manufacturing and purchasing complexity.</p>
<p><strong>Trends </strong></p>
<p>That is a change of direction from a few years ago when companies aimed to offer more choices. Online shopping caused some to think that more choices lead to better sales. But more choices often do not.</p>
<p>Companies started reducing the number of products they offer a year or two before the pandemic.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, the reductions increased, with companies <strong>focusing</strong> on necessities as they faced supply problems. After the pandemic, when goods began moving freely again, many businesses discovered less was better.</p>
<p>New offerings made up about two percent of products in stores in 2023. That includes products for beauty, footwear, technology and toys. Market research company Circana said that number is down from five percent in 2019.</p>
<p>Many think the companies are also helping shoppers. Some studies show that fewer choices result in shoppers buying more.</p>
<p>In 2000, psychologists Sheena Lyengar and Mark Lepper published a study that showed limited <strong>selection </strong>is better for people who are buying things. In their experiment, the researchers found consumers were 10 times more likely to purchase <strong>jam </strong>when the number of jams available was cut down from 24 to six. Later studies have produced similar findings.</p>
<p>"<strong>Retailers </strong>are recognizing that they have to be respectful of shoppers' time," said Paco Underhill, whose company, Envirosell, studies consumer behavior.</p>
<p>But retailers cannot just reduce offerings without a plan, said David Berliner of BDO, a business services company.</p>
<p>"You want to make these cuts so they're not even <strong>aware</strong> of it, and you want the store to still look full," Berliner said. "If you do it too much, you might scare some away."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Anne D'Innocenzio reported this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>consumer </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who buys products for personal use</p>
<p><strong>shelf </strong><em>– n.</em> a flat board which is attached to a wall and on which objects can be placed</p>
<p><strong>option</strong> <em>–n. (sales) </em>a choice of car or truck model that has a set group of products that go with it, and which is offered at one of several pricing levels</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong>–<em> v.</em> to direct your attention or effort at something specific</p>
<p><strong>selection</strong> –<em>n. </em>a group of products from which a person can choose</p>
<p><strong>jam<em> </em></strong><em>–n.</em> sweet, preserved fruit that is usually put on bread</p>
<p><strong>retailer </strong>– n. a person or business that sells things directly to customers</p>
<p><strong>aware</strong> –adj. knowing that something is present, available or that it exists</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Wealth Inequality by Race Grew during Pandemic  (2024/2/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/wealth-inequality-by-race-grew-during-pandemic.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new government report says wealth inequality by race increased in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The New York Federal Reserve Bank carried out the study and released the report. It said strong performance in financial markets and large gains in the stock market in 2021 were partly to blame for the increase.</p>
<p>The report found that the <strong>net</strong> worth of whites individually outgrew that of Blacks individually by 30 percentage points. Whites outgrew Hispanics by nine percentage points. The findings cover the years 2019 through half of 2023.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Traders work on the New York Stock Exchange floor, Sept. 13, 2022. (AP Photo/Julia Nikhinson)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/09840000-0aff-0242-caf1-08da95cbb980_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Traders work on the New York Stock Exchange floor, Sept. 13, 2022. (AP Photo/Julia Nikhinson)
</span></div>
<p>The period saw a high level of government financial support and a surprisingly strong job market. The unemployment rate for Black Americans is now at 5.3 percent, near a record low. The overall unemployment rate is 3.7 percent. Earnings for a Black full-time worker are up 7 percent on average since before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Closing the racial wealth divide, or gap, is especially difficult because a much larger number of white households have money in stocks and <strong>mutual funds</strong>. A separate Federal Reserve study showed that as of 2022, about 66 percent of white households had investments in stocks. In comparison, 39 percent of Black households owned stock. Stock investment was found to be even lower among Hispanic households, at 28 percent.</p>
<p>Government support, including additional unemployment assistance and COVID-linked payments to Americans, helped prevent a recession, the report says. But financial <strong>asset</strong> prices rose so quickly with the reopening of the economy through 2021 that racial wealth inequalities increased. Those asset prices fell, or declined, in 2022, after the Federal Reserve increased interest rates. But "those declines did not fully offset the earlier rises," the report's writers said.</p>
<p>The report noted that Black households have more wealth contained in <strong>pensions</strong> than in stocks, mutual funds and exchange-traded funds, or ETFs.</p>
<p>More than 50 percent of Black financial wealth is invested in pensions, the New York Fed found. Less than 20 percent of Black wealth is contained in private businesses, corporate <strong>equities</strong>, and mutual funds. In contrast, less than 30 percent of white financial wealth is invested in pensions. About 50 percent is invested in businesses, equities, and mutual funds.</p>
<p>"Black workers are still more likely to be unionized, which may play a part in the pension story," said Janelle Jones, Vice President of Policy and Advocacy at the Washington Center for Equitable Growth.</p>
<p>"Whether folks are <strong>exposed</strong> to the ability to invest in the stock market — whether or not it's something they grow up doing — we know that's different for white families than for people of color," Jones said.</p>
<p>Blacks are also less likely than whites to receive money and property from family members who die, she said</p>
<p>Owning a business is another part of financial wealth. Separate data show Black-owned businesses suffered more during the pandemic.</p>
<p>Less than 10 percent of all U.S. business owners are Black. And many Black-owned businesses are in industries that were hit hardest when COVID first spread, reported research group Economic Policy Institute after examining U.S. government data.</p>
<p>Hotel, food service, <strong>retail</strong>, health care, and social assistance industries suffered the greatest number of pandemic-linked job losses. About 28 percent of Black-owned businesses are found in those industries, compared with just under 20 percent of white-owned businesses, says the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics.</p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury reported Wednesday that economic conditions are improving for Black households. Deputy Secretary Wally Adeyemo noted rising employment numbers and wages for Black Americans since before the pandemic. He also praised an increase in Black business ownership and action in the stock market.</p>
<p>But, Adeyemo suggested that some policy measures still might be needed to balance financial wealth in the U.S.</p>
<p>"The gap between Black and white wealth in America is still too great," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpFirst"><strong>gap </strong><em>— n. </em>a space between two people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>mutual fund </strong><em>— n. </em> a type of investment in which the money of many people is used to buy stock from many different companies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>asset </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is owned by a person, company, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pension </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that a company or the government pays to a person who is old or sick and no longer works</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>equity </strong><em>— n. </em> fairness or justice in the way people are treated</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inheritance </strong><em>— n. </em>money, property, etc., that is received from someone when that person dies</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>retail </strong><em>— n. </em>the business of selling things directly to customers for their own use</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Icy Moon of Saturn Likely Has an Underground Ocean  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/scientists-icy-moon-of-saturn-likely-has-an-underground-ocean.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say new evidence suggests Saturn's icy moon Mimas likely has a large underground ocean.</p>
<p>Astronomers based their finding on data collected by the American space agency NASA's Cassini spacecraft. Cassini observed Saturn and its more than 140 moons for more than 10 years before ending operations in 2017.</p>
<p>The spacecraft's data covered details about the moon's orbit and <strong>rotation</strong>. Researchers reported the data provided the best evidence yet of a hidden ocean about 20 to 30 kilometers beneath the frozen surface.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This Feb. 13, 2010 image provided by NASA shows Saturn's moon Mimas and it's large Herschel Crater, captured by the Cassini spacecraft. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-c2d7-08dc2be8630c_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This Feb. 13, 2010 image provided by NASA shows Saturn's moon Mimas and it's large Herschel Crater, captured by the Cassini spacecraft. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute via AP)</span></div>
<p>Mimas is a relatively small moon, about 400 kilometers wide. Researchers say Mimas lacks formations on its surface found on other moons, which suggest the presence of underground water. These can include a broken surface as well as <strong>geyser</strong> activity.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Scientists said the fact that Mimas did not have unusual surface formations made it an unlikely candidate for an underground ocean.</p>
<p>Valery Lainey, of the Paris Observatory, was co-author <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06975-9">of a study</a> describing the research in the publication <em>Nature</em>. "Mimas was probably the most unlikely place to look for a global ocean — and liquid water more generally," he said in an email to the Associated Press.</p>
<p>Lainey added, "So that looks like a <strong>potential(ly) habitable</strong> world. But nobody knows how much time is needed for life to arise."</p>
<p>The amount of water thought to exist below the surface of Mimas would represent just 1.2 to 1.4 percent of Earth's oceans, Lainey said. That is because of the moon's small size.</p>
<p>However, Mimas does have a very large crater caused by a crash with a space object. For this reason, the appearance of the moon has been compared to the <strong>fictional</strong> "Death Star" space station in the popular movie series <em>Star Wars</em>.</p>
<p>English astronomer William Herschel discovered Mimas in 1789. It is named after a giant in Greek <strong>mythology</strong>.</p>
<p>An article appearing with the study in <em>Nature</em> was co-written by Matija Cuk of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.seti.org/">SETI Institute</a> research center and Alyssa Rose Rhoden of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.swri.org/">Southwest Research Institute</a>. The two were not part of the study. But they wrote that they find the idea that a small, icy moon can contain young oceans "<strong>inspiring</strong>."</p>
<p>The researchers said the underground ocean appears to have formed recently in space terms, possibly between 5 and 15 million years ago. Lainey said the ocean would likely have an overall temperature of around zero degrees Celsius. But the temperature at the seafloor might be much warmer.</p>
<p>The fact that the water is in contact with the moon's rocky center may create the right complex chemical conditions to support life. But the researchers noted that because the ocean is believed to be young, it might not be ideal for life to form there.</p>
<p>Scientists have said in the past that another moon of Saturn, Enceladus, might possess the warmth, water and chemical compounds necessary to support life. But because Mimas' ocean is so young, it "might be a <strong>challenge</strong> for life's development," study co-writer Gabriel Tobie told Reuters. Tobie is a scientist at the French scientific research agency CNRS and The University of Nantes.</p>
<p>However, Tobie added, "Nobody knows how long life needs to <strong>emerge</strong> from a suitable environment. Mimas may offer a unique <strong>opportunity</strong> to explore the first stage of life's development."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>rotate </strong><em>– v. </em>to turn in a circular direction</p>
<p><strong>mythology </strong>–n. old, stories that belong to certain cultures and which appear again and again in writing and art</p>
<p><strong>geyser </strong><em>– n. </em>a hole in the ground from which hot water and steam come out</p>
<p><strong>habitable </strong><em>– adj. </em>having the ability to support life</p>
<p><strong>potential </strong><em>– n. </em>existing in possibility</p>
<p><strong>fictional </strong><em>– adj. </em>not existing in real life</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone feel that they want to do something and can do it</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong><em>– n. </em>something difficult that tests one's ability or determination</p>
<p><strong>emerge </strong><em>– v. </em>to appear somewhere</p>
<p><strong>opportunity </strong><em>– n. </em>a chance to do something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Climate Change Fueling Disappearance of Central Asia’s Aral Sea  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/climate-change-fueling-disappearance-of-central-asia-s-aral-sea.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Climate change is quickening the disappearance of the Aral Sea. Once a single body of water, the lake now exists in pieces in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan. Many years ago, it was one of the world's largest inland bodies of water. But, that changed substantially over the last century. The Aral has shrunk to less than 25 percent of its former size.</p>
<p>Engineering projects and agricultural programs are to blame for much of the lake's early losses. Now, climate change is adding to the destruction. Summers in the area are longer and hotter. Winters are shorter and colder. The area lacks water supplies. And experts say much of the water that does exist is too salty to support plant life.</p>
<p><strong>History and loss</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A rusting ship sits in a dried-up area of the Aral Sea in Muynak, Uzbekistan, Sunday, June 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a8c4e718-3f13-4047-a4c6-8d1072f2f556_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A rusting ship sits in a dried-up area of the Aral Sea in Muynak, Uzbekistan, Sunday, June 25, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)</span></div>
<p>The Aral is fed by rivers that heavily depend on <strong>glacial </strong>melt. For many years, it held many fish, supporting a fishing industry.</p>
<p>The area brought in thousands of migrants for jobs in the past, also. Today, a few remaining towns sit quiet along the Aral's dry seabed. Dust storms often pass through.</p>
<p>In the 1920s, the Soviet government began to empty the sea to provide water to crops like cotton. By the 1960s, it was half its former size. By 1987, the Aral's level was so low it divided into two bodies of water: the northern and southern seas.</p>
<p>The United Nations Development Program calls the destruction of the Aral Sea "the most <strong>staggering</strong> disaster of the 20th century." It points to the Aral's loss as the cause of desertification, drinking water shortages, and worsening health conditions, among others.</p>
<p>National governments, international aid organizations, and local efforts have made attempts to save the sea, including dams and plant growth projects. But experts say climate change has only quickened the dying of the Aral, and will continue to worsen local peoples' suffering.</p>
<p><strong>Loss of life</strong></p>
<p>The loss of much of the Aral Sea caused dust storms to blow through towns. They spread toxic chemicals from a former weapons testing center and farms into the lungs and eyes of local peoples. The U.N. says this has increased rates of diseases related to breathing and cancer.</p>
<p>A U.N. report says dust storms, rising world temperatures, and wind are destroying the glaciers on which the feeder rivers depend. The remaining water is getting saltier and <strong>evaporating</strong> faster.</p>
<p>The report warns that melting ice and changing river flows may further cause problems for water supply and food supply. Hydropower plants could suffer.</p>
<p><strong>Differences along the Aral</strong></p>
<p>In Uzbekistan, Adilbay and his friends fish in the Aral's remaining waters. The fish are small and few.</p>
<p>The 62-year-old holds his arms wide to demonstrate how big the Aral fish used to be. "Now there is nothing," he said.</p>
<p>As the water disappeared, a nearby fish processing plant closed. Adilbay's friends and relatives moved to Kazakhstan looking for new jobs.</p>
<p>There, fisherman Serzhan Seitbenbetov and others find success. In an hour, he caught a hundred fish, some 2 meters long.</p>
<p>"Now all the villagers make good money being fishermen," he said.</p>
<p>That is the result of an $86 million dam project led by Kazakhstan, with assistance from the World Bank. It was completed in 2005.</p>
<p>Known as the Kokaral Dam, it saves and gathers water from the Syr Darya River. The dam performed better than expected, leading to an increase of over 3 meters in water levels after seven months.</p>
<p>That helped restore local fisheries and caused an increase in clouds and rainstorms in the local area, the World Bank says. Population grew.</p>
<p>But it could not <strong>replicate </strong>life before the water started drying up, said Sarah Cameron. She is a professor at the University of Maryland who is writing a book about the Aral.</p>
<p>"It does not support the same amount of people and the fishing industry in the same way," Cameron said.</p>
<p>Uzbekistan's <strong>restoration</strong> efforts have been mixed in success. The government has not undertaken large projects like the Kokaral. Instead, the country planted trees and other plants to help prevent <strong>erosion</strong> and slow dust storms.</p>
<p>The discovery of oil and natural gas in the Aral's former seabed led to the building of gas production sites. Experts say that shows that Uzbekistan has little interest in restoration..</p>
<p>Kate Shields is a professor of environmental studies at Rhodes College in the American state of Tennessee.</p>
<p>"While there has been some restoration," she said, "there was a sort of acceptance that ... the sea was not coming back."</p>
<p>Government officials from Uzbekistan and Kazakhstan did not answer questions from the <em>Associated Press</em> about restoration efforts, the lack of water, and the effects of climate change.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Victoria Milko reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>glacier </strong><em>– n. </em>a very large area of ice that moves slowly down a slope or valley or over a wide area of land</p>
<p><strong>evaporate</strong></p>
<p><strong>staggering </strong><em>– adj. </em>very large, shocking, or surprising</p>
<p><strong>replicate </strong><em>– v.</em> to repeat or copy (something) exactly</p>
<p><strong>restoration </strong><em>– adj. </em>the act or process of returning something to its original condition by repairing it or cleaning it</p>
<p><strong>erosion </strong>– <em>n</em>. the gradual destruction of something by natural forces (such as water, wind, or ice)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Schools Change Health Guidelines for Keeping Students Home  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-schools-change-health-guidelines-for-keeping-students-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Unclear guidelines for when to keep a child at home if they are sick might play a part in the nationwide problem of students missing too much school.</p>
<p>Some activists, school officials and the state of California are now asking that parents send their children to school even if they show signs of sickness. They say acceptable problems include eye infections and <strong>lice</strong>.</p>
<p>Families need to hear they no longer must keep children at home at any sign of sickness, said Hedy Chang. Chang is the director of Attendance Works, a nonprofit group aiming to improve school attendance. The group has issued its own guidance. It urges parents to send children to school if they can join day-to-day activities, have low-level sickness or head lice.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An empty elementary school classroom is seen on Tuesday, Aug. 17, 2021 in the Bronx borough of New York. (AP Photo/Brittainy Newman, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/528de8c6-0122-453c-88d0-5106c36d282c_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An empty elementary school classroom is seen on Tuesday, Aug. 17, 2021 in the Bronx borough of New York. (AP Photo/Brittainy Newman, File)</span></div>
<p>The American Academy of Pediatrics is an organization for doctors who treat children. It recommends that children stay home when there are signs of sickness like fever, vomiting, or diarrhea, or when students "are not well enough to <strong>participate</strong> in class."</p>
<p>A fever is defined as a body temperature above 38 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>But many <strong>school districts</strong> go far beyond that, offering different signs of sickness that would prevent parents from sending their children to school.</p>
<p><strong>Which is it?</strong></p>
<p>Trenace Dorsey-Hollins has a five-year-old daughter who was sick a lot last year. Dorsey-Hollins followed school guidelines and kept her daughter home when she had a <strong>cough</strong>, painful throat, fever, or sneezing.</p>
<p>Near the end of the year, school officials in Fort Worth, Texas, called her in to talk about why her daughter had missed so much school.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, schools urged parents and children to stay home at any sign of illness. Although the emergency has ended, she said no one has said that those rules have changed.</p>
<p>"In the past, if the child didn't have a fever...then it's okay to send them to school," said the mother of five- and 13-year-old children. "But now it's like if they have a cough...you might want to keep them home. Which is it?"</p>
<p>Dorsey-Hollins' youngest daughter goes to school in Fort Worth Independent School District. It suggests staying home if a child has a cough, <strong>sore</strong> throat, or <strong>rash</strong>. The guidelines say a student should be "fever-free" for 24 hours without medication before returning to school.</p>
<p>Austin Independent School District in Texas lists signs of illness like "eye redness," "<strong>undetermined</strong> rash," or "open, draining <strong>lesions</strong>" as reasons to stay home.</p>
<p>Other school districts have different guidelines. Children with lice cannot go to class in New York City schools. And Maryland's Montgomery County schools recommend keeping a child home for stomach pain, "pale or flushed face," or "thick yellow discharge from the nose."</p>
<p>Dr. Claire McCarthy is a doctor at Boston Children's Hospital who teaches at Harvard Medical School. She said it is understandable that different places would have different guidelines.</p>
<p>"Each school or school district has a different <strong>tolerance</strong> for illness," said McCarthy.</p>
<p><strong>10 percent of the school year</strong></p>
<p>Test results <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/study-student-learning-decreased-in-math-reading-worldwide-/7387144.html">show</a> that children fell behind in their studies when schools closed during the pandemic. Children who regularly missed school found it more difficult to catch up. During the 2021 to 2022 school year, more than 25 percent of students missed at least 10 percent of the school year. That number is up from 15 percent before the pandemic.</p>
<p>Missing 10 percent or more of the school year puts students at risk. Students who miss school also might miss meals, socializing with other students and adults, physical exercise, and mental health and health care services.</p>
<p>In addition, teachers must spend a lot of time supporting students who miss class. This takes time from students who attend class and are on target for the year.</p>
<p>Recently, the state of California decided to change their stay-at-home guidelines for the autumn. The new guidelines say children with low-level signs of sickness can come to school.</p>
<p>Noha Aboelata leads the Roots Health Center in Oakland, California. The group says it provides health services for poor people and those affected by inequality. Aboelata said the change in guidance might have a greater effect on poor people and minorities.</p>
<p>Aboelata said people in those communities might be more likely to live in homes with more than one generation, to take public transportation, or have poor heating and cooling systems in their homes.</p>
<p>She said she hoped that staying home when sick would continue after the pandemic. Instead, she said, "it feels like the <strong>pendulum</strong> is <strong>swinging </strong>fiercely back<strong> </strong>in the other direction."</p>
<p>Tracy Schmidt oversees attendance for the Office of Education in San Diego County, California. She said she feels hopeful that parents and schools will learn about the new guidance and that students will miss less school.</p>
<p>"The most important place for our kids to be is school," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Bianca Vázquez Toness reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>lice </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> a small creature that lives on people's bodies and easily spreads from person to person<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>participate </strong>– <em>v</em>. to be involved with others in doing something</p>
<p><strong>school district </strong><em>– n. </em>an area created by a local government which has public schools that are overseen by local government officials and paid for through local taxes</p>
<p><strong>cough </strong><em>–v.</em> the involuntary forcing of air through the throat often because of sickness</p>
<p><strong>sore </strong><em>–adj.</em> painful</p>
<p><strong>rash </strong><em>–n.</em> a condition on the skin that makes it red or swollen and often produces itching</p>
<p><strong>undetermined </strong><em>–adj.</em> unknown</p>
<p><strong>lesion </strong>–n. a raised area of skin that is unhealthy, damaged or cut</p>
<p><strong>tolerance </strong><em>– n.</em> the ability to accept, experience, or survive something harmful or unpleasant</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Historic Gun Factory in New York State Village to Close  (2024/2/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/historic-gun-factory-in-new-york-state-village-to-close.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 February 2024</span><br/>
<p class="MsoBodyText">The oldest gunmaker in America is closing its factory in a small town in the state of New York.</p>
<p>Remington Firearms was formed two centuries ago in what is now the town of Ilion, a village in the heart of New York's Mohawk Valley area. It began when Eliphalet Remington <strong>forged</strong> his first rifle barrel nearby in 1816.</p>
<p>Remington's owners recently announced it would permanently shut the factory in March. They said costs were too high to continue making guns in Ilion.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A sign for Remington Arms stands in front of the company's factory in Ilion, N.Y., Thursday, February. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b189a08a-6ac0-44f2-83db-b0d59c86e7d9_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A sign for Remington Arms stands in front of the company's factory in Ilion, N.Y., Thursday, February. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>The company is uniting all its operations in the southeastern state of Georgia. Remington officials say Georgia is friendlier to the firearms industry than New York.</p>
<p>The company's recent history has been marked by a <strong>lawsuit</strong> connected to the mass murder of 20 children and six adults in 2012 at an elementary school in Connecticut. Remington Arms agreed to pay $73 million to relatives of victims and a survivor to settle the legal action. The company also declared financial failure more than once.</p>
<p>The factory workforce had dropped from about 1,300 workers more than 10 years ago to around 300. About 7,600 people live in Ilion. The gunmaker's withdrawal is a major loss to the town's economy and more.</p>
<p>"When Remington leaves, it's not going to be like a <strong>facility</strong> leaving, it's going to be like part of your family has moved off," said former factory worker Jim Conover. Conover retired in 2004, after 40 years at the plant.</p>
<p>Everyone knows someone who worked at the factory. For some families, jobs there are almost a <strong>birthright</strong>. Conover's father and sons also worked at the plant.</p>
<p>Building engineer Frank "Rusty" Brown has had many family members among his coworkers.</p>
<p>"My mom worked there. My dad worked there. My wife works there with me now. My daughter works there with me now. My second daughter works there with me now. And my son-in-law works there," said Brown, who is president of the United Mine Workers of America Local 717.</p>
<p>He added, "So it's a double-hit for me and my wife: two of us out of a job."</p>
<p>The current owners of Remington Firearms, RemArms, blamed "production <strong>inefficiencies</strong>" for the plant closure in a letter to union officials late last year. They noted the high cost of caring for about 92,903 square meters of space in several buildings, many dating to World War I.</p>
<p>RemArms added that Georgia offered an environment that better "supports and welcomes the firearms industry."</p>
<p>RemArms CEO Ken D'Arcy also said in a news release that the industry was concerned about the "legislative environment" in New York.</p>
<p>But in a stretch of upstate New York where support for gun rights tends to be strong, some Republican elected officials seized on the company's comment about Georgia. They linked the plant closure to gun control measures championed by New York City-area Democrats in recent years.</p>
<p>RemArms, which bought the firearms business in 2020, did not answer emails and calls seeking comment.</p>
<p>The company said in its letter to the union it expected to end facility operations around March 4. The company earlier announced in 2021 it was moving its headquarters to LaGrange, Georgia. RemArms said it would open a factory and research operation there.</p>
<p>The days of traffic jams in Ilion every afternoon when shifts let out are long gone. Empty spaces can be found in the factory's big parking lot. Nearby businesses<strong> </strong>that have long provided meals to the workers have already seen a sharp reduction in food orders.</p>
<p>One such business is Franco's pizza. Its owner, Daniel Mendez, said orders have been "dwindling down," or decreasing.</p>
<p>"This is not necessarily going to put us out of business, but it does hurt," Mendez said.</p>
<p>Ilion Mayor John Stephens said there will be hard decisions ahead. But he said he believes the factory site will be used again. And while Remington might leave, he said the connection between the town and the factory can never be broken.</p>
<p>"Even when they are finally 100 percent no longer involved in the Village of Ilion in any way, shape or form, we're still going to be known for this," Stephens said. "You can't <strong>erase</strong> history."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>forge </strong><em>–n. </em>to form (something, such as metal) by heating and hammering</p>
<p><strong>lawsuit </strong><em>–n. </em>a legal case before a court</p>
<p><strong>facility </strong><em>–n. </em>something (such as a hospital) that is built, installed, or established to serve a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>birthright </strong><em>–n. </em>a right, privilege, or possession to which a person is entitled by birth</p>
<p><strong>inefficiency </strong><em>–n. </em>a state or quality that is wasteful of time or energy<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>erase </strong><em>–v. </em>to remove from existence or memory</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Monarch Butterfly Population Declines in Mexico  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/monarch-butterfly-population-declines-in-mexico.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Monarch butterfly population has dropped to its second-lowest number on record in Mexican forests this winter. The forests are the insects' winter home. The population decrease is worrisome as the butterfly group is already considered at risk of disappearance.</p>
<p>Mexico's government and the non-profit World Wildlife Fund (WWF) recently issued findings of their yearly joint study on the butterflies. The research shows that the monarch butterfly presence has shrunk to less than a hectare of forest area.</p>
<p>In the mid-1990s, monarch butterflies could be found on around 18 hectares of the forest.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Monarch butterflies rest on a tree at the Sierra Chincua butterfly sanctuary in Angangeo, Michoacan state, Mexico December 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/95354b99-23b1-401b-89d6-6071c3c4e494_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Monarch butterflies rest on a tree at the Sierra Chincua butterfly sanctuary in Angangeo, Michoacan state, Mexico December 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Raquel Cunha/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>The findings represent an almost 60 percent decrease in the monarch butterfly population compared to last year's study. It is also the second-lowest population finding since the first study took place more than thirty years ago.</p>
<p>Biologists blame the drop on higher-than-usual temperatures and dry conditions in the northwestern U.S. where the butterfly reproduces.</p>
<p>The weather conditions affect the growth of milkweed, the plant where the butterflies lay their eggs. When the young arrive, milkweed is their food for a time.</p>
<p>In one of the planet's famous wildlife <strong>migrations</strong>, the butterflies travel south as many as 4,500 kilometers from places as far north as Canada. They spend the winter in warmer Mexico, where millions of the insects stay in trees that protect them from the rain and cold.</p>
<p>Monarch butterfly populations change year to year. As recently as 2021, the same study showed a 35 percent increase to cover around 2.8 hectares.</p>
<p>Officials and activists called for more action to help the <strong>species</strong>. Such calls include the need to reduce threats posed by <strong>herbicides</strong> that destroy milkweed and the need to protect forests.</p>
<p>"We can't lower our guard," Jorge Rickards, head of WWF's Mexico office, told reporters after releasing the latest data.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Diego Delgado reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of animals that are similar and can produce young animals</p>
<p><strong>migration</strong> <em>– n.</em> to move from one area to another</p>
<p><strong>herbicide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical used to destroy plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Autoimmune Diseases Affect More Women than Men  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/autoimmune-diseases-affect-more-women-than-men.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Women are much more likely to get autoimmune diseases than men. New research may finally explain why.</p>
<p>Autoimmune diseases happen when the body's natural defenses, or immune system, attack the body's tissues.</p>
<p>Researchers from Stanford University in California say the reason for this may be connected to how the body deals with females' second X chromosome.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Organs of the immune system. (Courtesy of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-69d6-08dc274347ba_cx2_cy0_cw95_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Organs of the immune system. (Courtesy of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences)</span></div>
<p>The finding could help improve doctors' abilities to <strong>detect</strong> autoimmune diseases.</p>
<p>E. John Wherry is an immunologist at the University of Pennsylvania. He said the new study changes "the way we think about this whole process of autoimmunity."</p>
<p>Between 24 million and 50 million Americans suffer from an autoimmune disorder. Autoimmune disorders include lupus, rheumatoid arthritis, multiple sclerosis, and many other diseases.</p>
<p>About four of every five patients with an autoimmune disorder are women. Scientists have tried to find out why for many years.</p>
<p>One theory is that the X chromosome might be the reason. Females have two X chromosomes while males have one X and one Y.</p>
<p>The new research recently appeared in the publication <em>Cell</em>. The results show that the extra X is involved — but in an unexpected way.</p>
<p>Our DNA is carried inside each cell in 23 pairs of chromosomes, including the final pair that decides biological sex. The X chromosome is packed with hundreds of genes, far more than males' much smaller Y chromosome.</p>
<p>Every female cell must turn off one of its X chromosome copies to avoid getting a dangerous double amount of all those genes. Scientists call this process X-chromosome inactivation.</p>
<p>A special kind of RNA, called Xist, performs the X-chromosome inactivation. Xist is a long chain of RNA. It gathers in areas along a cell's extra X chromosome and attracts proteins that connect to it in unusual masses. Then it silences the chromosome.</p>
<p>Dr. Howard Chang is a <strong>dermatologist</strong> at Stanford University. He was exploring how Xist does its job when his lab found nearly 100 of those attached proteins. Chang saw that many of those proteins were related to skin-related autoimmune disorders. Patients can have "autoantibodies" that mistakenly attack these normal proteins.</p>
<p>Chang told The Associated Press, "That got us thinking: These are the known ones. What about the other proteins in Xist?"</p>
<p>He added that the molecule, found only in women, might "somehow organize proteins in such a way as to <strong>activate</strong> the immune system."</p>
<p>If true, Xist by itself could not cause autoimmune disease. If it did, all women would be affected. Scientists have long thought it takes a combination of some genes and an environmental event, like an infection or injury, for the immune system to cause problems. For example, the Epstein-Barr virus is linked to multiple sclerosis.</p>
<p>Chang receives financial support from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute, which also supports The Associated Press' Health and Science Department.</p>
<p>Chang's team decided to produce male lab mice to artificially make Xist — without turning off their only X chromosome — and see what happened. Researchers also specially bred mice <strong>susceptible</strong> to developing a lupus-like condition. The condition can be set off by a certain chemical.</p>
<p>The Xist formed its usual protein masses. When the chemical was used, the male mice with Xist developed lupus-like autoimmunity at levels similar to females, the team found.</p>
<p>Chang said, "We think that's really important, for Xist RNA to leak out of the cell to where the immune system gets to see it."</p>
<p>But he added that an environmental event is still needed to start the process.</p>
<p>Beyond mice, researchers also looked at blood from 100 patients. They found autoantibodies targeting Xist-related proteins that scientists had not previously linked to autoimmune disorders. Chang said one possible reason was that most tests for autoimmunity were made using male cells.</p>
<p>More research is necessary. But Wherry, the immunologist at Penn, said the findings might give doctors a shorter path to diagnosing patients.</p>
<p>Wherry said one patient may have autoantibodies to Protein A and another patient may have autoantibodies to Proteins C and D. But he said knowing they are all related to Xist RNA can help doctors find diseases more easily.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Lauran Neergaard reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>detect </strong>– <em>v</em>. to discover or notice the presence of (something that is hidden or hard to see, hear, taste, etc.)</p>
<p><strong>dermatologist </strong>– <em>n</em>. the scientific study of the skin and its diseases</p>
<p><strong>activate </strong><em>– v.</em> to cause (a chemical reaction or natural process) to begin</p>
<p><strong>susceptible </strong><em>– adj. </em>easily affected, influenced, or harmed by something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Kansas City Chiefs, Usher, Taylor Swift Win at Super Bowl  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/kansas-city-chiefs-usher-taylor-swift-win-at-super-bowl.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Kansas City Chiefs needed extra time on Sunday to win the American football championship called the Super Bowl. The Super Bowl is the National Football League's championship game.</p>
<p>Football experts say the Kansas City Chiefs are now one of the best teams to have ever played the sport.</p>
<p>The Chiefs scored a <strong>touchdown</strong> late in the extra period to defeat the San Francisco 49ers 25 to 22. The team has now won three Super Bowls in five seasons and appeared in four of the championship games since 2020.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Travis Kelce kisses Taylor Swift after the Kansas City Chiefs' Super Bowl win on February 11." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e7c9ed46-f2c0-4a1a-aaab-9dd94fde5111_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Travis Kelce kisses Taylor Swift after the Kansas City Chiefs' Super Bowl win on February 11.</span></div>
<p>Patrick Mahomes is the quarterback and the team's most important player. He has won three Super Bowls. Only three other quarterbacks have won more championships. Mahomes, is only 28. He was voted the top player, or MVP, of the game.</p>
<p>But for many people watching the game on television, Kansas City's win was only part of the story in Las Vegas, Nevada.</p>
<p>For a while, it seemed as if the halftime show, <strong>featuring</strong> the music performer Usher, was going to be the most exciting part of the game. At that point, San Francisco was ahead 10 to 3.</p>
<p>Usher, a singer who became well-known about 20 years ago, came out in sparkling, white clothes and performed along with a <strong>marching band</strong> and other musicians. He was joined during his show by Alicia Keys, H.E.R., Jermaine Dupri, Lil' Jon and Ludacris. Usher performed parts of 12 of his most popular songs.</p>
<p>Throughout the game, cameras cut to another famous singer, Taylor Swift. Swift is the girlfriend of Travis Kelce, one of the Kansas City players.</p>
<p>Swift performed the last of four concerts in Japan on Saturday and flew to Las Vegas to attend Sunday's game.</p>
<p>Kansas City, in the central state of Missouri, will celebrate the Chiefs during a parade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The game changed at the start of the fourth quarter, when San Francisco scored a touchdown to take a 16 to 13 lead. However, the 49ers kicker, Jake Moody, had his extra point attempt blocked.</p>
<p>The failed play permitted Kansas City to kick a field goal, worth three points, to tie the game at 16 and then again at 19 in order to force overtime. It was only the second Super Bowl to require extra time.</p>
<p>In the overtime period, San Francisco only scored a field goal to take the lead 22 to 19. However, under NFL rules, both teams have at least one chance to score in extra time.</p>
<p>That meant Kansas City could win the game with a touchdown. That is exactly what happened, when Mahomes threw a short touchdown pass to Mecole Hardman to end the game with only six seconds remaining.</p>
<p>Kelce is one of the league's best players <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_JoXvp2ns">at</a> his position. He had a slow start but caught nine passes from Mahomes.</p>
<p>Swift joined Kelce for the Super Bowl celebration after the game. After getting a kiss from Swift, Kelce said "the goal has always been to get three (Super Bowls)." He went on to say the team wants to win again next year, to make it three in a row.</p>
<p>The Chiefs are the first team to win two Super Bowls one after the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_ywFPXCm0">other, since</a> the New England Patriots did it 19 years ago.</p>
<p>Mahomes said, "I'm <strong>proud</strong> of the guys" as he accepted his MVP award. "This is awesome. <strong>Legendary</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>touchdown </strong>–n. the biggest score in American football given for reaching the "end zone" and which is awarded six points with the possibility of one or two extra points after</p>
<p><strong>feature </strong>–v. to be offered as a main star or attraction in a performance</p>
<p><strong>marching band </strong>–n. a large musical group usually linked to a high school or college, that has mostly brass instruments and which marches as it plays songs</p>
<p><strong>proud </strong>–adj. to be very pleased and happy with something you have done</p>
<p><strong>legendary </strong>–adj. very impressive and worth people's attention</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Did you watch the Super Bowl? What did you think?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Egypt Threatens to Suspend Peace Treaty with Israel  (2024/2/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/egypt-threatens-to-suspend-peace-treaty-with-israel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin, and U.S. President Jimmy Carter signed a peace deal in 1979. The agreement, marked by a handshake, has resulted in more than 40 years of peace between Middle East neighbors Israel and Egypt.</p>
<p>That peace agreement has held up through two Palestinian uprisings and several wars between Israel and Hamas. But the Egyptian government is threatening to suspend the agreement as Israel plans to send troops into Rafah, a city in Gaza on the border with Egypt.</p>
<p><strong>Israel-Egypt peace treaty</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this March 26, 1979 file photo, Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, left, U.S. President Jimmy Carter, center, and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin clasp hands as they completed signing of the peace treaty. (AP Photo/Bob Daugherty, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2d91fb34-8d0e-4110-9b5a-eb2142437a80_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this March 26, 1979 file photo, Egyptian President Anwar Sadat, left, U.S. President Jimmy Carter, center, and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin clasp hands as they completed signing of the peace treaty. (AP Photo/Bob Daugherty, File)</span></div>
<p>In 1977, Begin, Israel's new prime minister was opposed to giving back any land captured by Israel 10 years earlier in the 1967 war. Those lands included Egypt's Sinai Peninsula.</p>
<p>Egypt and Israel had fought four major wars, most recently in 1973. However, Egypt's Sadat broke with other Arab leaders and decided to talk with the Israelis. The talks resulted in the Camp David Accords in September 1978 and a peace treaty the following year.</p>
<p>Under the peace treaty, Israel agreed to withdraw from the Sinai, which Egypt would leave demilitarized. Israeli ships were granted passage through the Suez Canal, an important trade pathway. The countries established full diplomatic relations. It was Israel's first peace agreement with an Arab country since the country's establishment in 1948.</p>
<p>Paige Alexander is head of the Carter Center. She said, "The Camp David Accords were led by three brave men who took a <strong>bold</strong> stance because they knew the lasting effects for peace and security, both then and for the future. We need the same kind of leadership today, and that is currently lacking."</p>
<p><strong>What is Egypt's position?</strong></p>
<p>On Sunday, two Egyptian officials and a Western diplomat told The Associated Press that Egypt might suspend the peace treaty if Israeli troops enter Rafah.</p>
<p>Last October, Hamas launched a surprise attack from the Palestinian territory of Gaza into southern Israel. The terrorist group killed more than 1,200 people and took more than 150 hostages including Americans.</p>
<p>Israel answered with airstrikes and ground attacks in Gaza. The Palestinian-controlled health ministry reported in February that 28,000 people have been killed in more than four months of fighting. The number, which is not confirmed, includes both civilians and militants.</p>
<p>Israel says Rafah is the last area under Hamas control. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said sending ground troops into Rafah is needed to defeat the group.</p>
<p>However, Egypt opposes any move that could send desperate Palestinians fleeing across the border into its territory. Rafah serves as the main entry point into Gaza for humanitarian aid. An Israeli attack could prevent <strong>deliveries</strong> of supplies to Palestinians in Gaza.</p>
<p>Rafah's population has expanded from 280,000 people to an estimated 1.4 million as Palestinians flee fighting in other parts of Gaza. Hundreds of thousands of those <strong>evacuees</strong> are now living in tents.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has ordered the Israeli military to prepare a plan to evacuate all Palestinian civilians before the offensive starts. But it is unclear where they will go.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said Sunday that Palestinians would be able to return to open spaces in northern Gaza. But those areas have been badly damaged by the Israeli offensive.</p>
<p><strong>What happens if the peace treaty ends?</strong></p>
<p>The treaty between Egypt and Israel limits the number of troops on both sides of the border. The countries, however, have agreed in the past to make changes to deal with security threats.</p>
<p>In addition to Gaza, Israel has <strong>engaged</strong> in regular exchanges of weapons fire with the Hezbollah militant group in Lebanon. Israeli forces are also deployed in the occupied West Bank.</p>
<p>If Egypt were to end the agreement, Israel would have to deploy more troops to protect its southern border with Egypt.</p>
<p>Such a move, however, would affect Egypt as well.</p>
<p>Since the peace agreement, Egypt has received billions of dollars in military assistance from the U.S. If the agreement is ended, it could threaten that aid while Egypt's economy is struggling.</p>
<p>The war between Hamas and Israel has already spread to the Red Sea where Yemen's Houthi rebels regularly attack <strong>commercial</strong> shipping.</p>
<p>In Jordan, militants, supported by Iran, struck an American position with a <strong>drone</strong> last month killing three U.S. service members. The U.S. answered with several major strikes against militants in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Alexander from the Carter Center said any step that could draw Egypt into the hostilities "would be <strong>catastrophic</strong> for the entire <strong>region</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Julia Frankel reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bold</strong><strong> </strong><em>–adj. </em>unafraid, willing to do something that is difficult</p>
<p><strong>delivery</strong> <em>–n.</em> the act of taking something to a person or group that requested it</p>
<p><strong>evacuee </strong>–n. a person who has been evacuated from a place, meaning they have been moved for their safety because of a dangerous situation</p>
<p><strong>engage </strong>–v. to be involved in a process that requires action and attention</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong>–adj. related to trade and business activity with an aim to make a profit</p>
<p><strong>drone </strong>–n. a vehicle that operates without a human pilot onboard often an aircraft or boat</p>
<p><strong>catastrophic </strong>–adj. disastrous, something that is extremely bad</p>
<p><strong>region </strong>–n. an area of the Earth that is know for certain qualities such as its geological, geographical, or political boundaries</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA Launches New Satellite to Study Oceans, Atmosphere  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/nasa-launches-new-satellite-to-study-oceans-atmosphere.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA has launched a new satellite designed to closely study the world's oceans and atmosphere.</p>
<p>NASA launched the PACE satellite on February 8. A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket carried PACE into orbit from Kennedy Space Center in Florida. NASA confirmed the launch and <a class="wsw__a" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/pace/">reported</a> ground controllers had successfully established contact with the satellite.</p>
<p>PACE stands for Plankton, Aerosol, Cloud, Ocean Ecosystem. The satellite will spend at least three years studying the environment from an orbit 676 kilometers above the Earth's surface. NASA officials say PACE will map the entire world each day with two science instruments. A third instrument will collect monthly measurements. Scientists should start getting their first data within one or two months.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket on NASA's PACE mission lifts off from Space Launch Complex 40 at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Cape Canaveral, Fla., Thursday, Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/John Raoux)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a1ca-08dc28fe6a88_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket on NASA's PACE mission lifts off from Space Launch Complex 40 at the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Cape Canaveral, Fla., Thursday, Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/John Raoux)</span></div>
<p>Jeremy Werdell is the Project Scientist for the PACE project, or mission. He told The Associated Press he sees the effort providing humans "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> view of our home planet."</p>
<p>Werdell noted a major goal of the observations is to help scientists improve their ability to predict hurricanes and other severe weather events. He said the instruments can provide detailed data on temperature-related changes happening across the world. The satellite data might help scientists better predict when harmful <strong>algae blooms</strong> will happen.</p>
<p>NASA says PACE will also study aerosols, or particles in the air. Karen St. Germain is NASA's director of Earth science. She <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=03HJCnQBkpY">told</a> reporters before PACE's launch that the study of aerosols is important because they can affect clouds. Aerosols can affect the density of clouds, as well as when and how much <strong>precipitation</strong> the clouds might release.</p>
<p>St. Germain noted existing satellites are not equipped to collect detailed data on aerosols. She said PACE will help NASA learn more about how aerosols affect clouds and climate over long periods. The new data is expected to give scientists "another <strong>dimension</strong>" of data on how aerosols affect oceans and the atmosphere.</p>
<p>St. Germain added, "And then, of course, there is a relationship between the phytoplankton and the aerosols." Phytoplankton are very small plants that float near the surface of water. They serve as a source of food for many sea creatures. NASA says phytoplankton "provide food to <strong>all sorts of</strong> animals ranging from shellfish to finfish to whales."</p>
<p>NASA says PACE's instruments will aim to measure changes in phytoplankton. The satellite will aim to collect data on aerosols that attach to phytoplankton. These studies will be important in identifying any changes in phytoplankton from interactions with aerosols which could affect the ocean and life in it.</p>
<p>NASA has already launched a series of Earth-observing satellites and instruments into orbit. But the agency believes PACE will be able to collect more detailed data on how different aerosols and pollutants get into the oceans and the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Project Scientist Werdell noted that current Earth-observing satellites can only see in seven or eight different colors. But he said Pace will see in 200 colors, permitting scientists to better identify different kinds of algae in the sea and particles in the air.</p>
<p>News reports say the mission will cost about $950 million.</p>
<p>The PACE mission follows the launch in December 2022 of NASA's SWOT satellite. The SWOT mission measures sea levels and changes in bodies of water over time. SWOT is a cooperative effort between NASA and France's space agency.</p>
<p>NASA is cooperating with India on another Earth-observing satellite set to launch this year. That spacecraft, called NISAR, will use radar instruments to measure the effects of rising temperatures on glaciers and other melting, icy surfaces.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong><em>– adj.</em> never having happened before</p>
<p><strong>algae bloom </strong><em>– n. </em>a fast and large increase in algae - simple plants that have no leaves or stems and that grow in or near water</p>
<p><strong>precipitation </strong><em>– n. </em>rain or snow that falls to the ground</p>
<p><strong>dimension </strong><em>– n. </em>a particular part of a situation, especially something that affects how a person thinks or feels</p>
<p><strong>all sorts of </strong><em>– n. </em>many different kinds of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Propose a Stronger ‘Category 6’ for Hurricane  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/experts-propose-a-stronger-category-6-for-hurricane.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>There have been a few very powerful ocean storms in the last 10 years. The expectation of more to come has some experts proposing a new category of large <strong>hurricanes</strong>: Category 6.</p>
<p>Studies have shown that the strongest <strong>tropical</strong> storms are getting more powerful because of climate change. The traditional five-category Saffir-Simpson <strong>scale</strong> was created more than 50 years ago.</p>
<p>But two scientists suggested in a new study that the scale may not show the true power of the strongest storms. They propose a sixth category for storms with winds faster than 309 kilometers per hour.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Homes are flooded in the aftermath of Hurricane Ida, Monday, Aug. 30, 2021, in Jean Lafitte, Louisiana. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01b10000-0aff-0242-ec67-08d9fafbb1b7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Homes are flooded in the aftermath of Hurricane Ida, Monday, Aug. 30, 2021, in Jean Lafitte, Louisiana. (AP Photo/David J. Phillip, File)</span></div>
<p>The study recently appeared in the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.pnas.org/">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</a>.</p>
<p>Currently, storms with winds of 252 kilometers per hour or higher are Category 5. The study's writers said that this grouping does not do enough to warn people about the greater dangers from storms with even stronger winds.</p>
<p>Still, several experts told The <em>Associated Press</em> that they do not think another category is needed. They said it could even send the wrong message to the public because the new proposed category is based on wind speed. Water is by far the deadliest part of hurricanes.</p>
<p>Since 2013, five storms had winds that would have put them in the new category, with two hitting the Philippines. All five happened in the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>As the world warms, such large storms become more likely.</p>
<p>"Climate change is making the worst storms worse," said Michael Wehner, the study's lead writer. Wehner is a climate scientist at the Lawrence Berkley National Lab in California.</p>
<p>There are not more storms because of climate change, but climate change makes the strongest more intense. The <strong>proportion</strong> of major hurricanes among all storms is increasing. That is because the oceans are getting warmer, said Brian McNoldy. He is a hurricane researcher at Florida's University of Miami. He was not part of the research.</p>
<p>Experts have proposed a Category 6 several times over the years, especially since 2013's Typhoon Haiyan reached 315 kilometers per hour over the Pacific. The study said that Haiyan "does not appear to be an <strong>isolated</strong> case."</p>
<p>Storms with high enough wind speed are called hurricanes if they form east of the international dateline. They are called typhoons if they form to the west of the line. They are known as cyclones in the Indian Ocean and Australia. There have been five storms that had 309 kilometer per hour winds since 2013.</p>
<p>Jim Kossin is a climate and hurricane researcher who was an <strong>author</strong> of the study. He said if the world keeps to five storm categories, people will misjudge the risks as storms get larger and more powerful.</p>
<p>Pacific storms are stronger because there is less land to weaken them and more room for storms to grow more intense. That is not the same situation in the Gulf of Mexico and in the Caribbean, Kossin noted.</p>
<p>Jamie Rhome is deputy director of the National Hurricane Center in Florida. He said that, when warning people about the storms, his office warns people about individual dangers. These dangers include "storm <strong>surge</strong>, wind, rainfall, tornadoes and rip currents, instead of the particular category of the storm." The categories, he added, only provide information about the dangers from wind.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hurricane </strong><em>— n. </em>an extremely large, powerful, and destructive storm with very strong winds that occurs especially in the western part of the Atlantic Ocean</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scale </strong><em>— n. </em>a device that is used for weighing people or things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>proportion </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount that is a part of a whole</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>isolated </strong><em>— adj. </em>happening just once</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>author </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who has written something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surge </strong><em>— v. </em>to suddenly increase to an unusually high level</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mexico Becomes Leading Source of Goods Imported to US  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/mexico-becomes-leading-source-of-goods-imported-to-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico took China's place as the leading source of goods imported by the United States.</p>
<p>This change, which took place over the last year, brings attention to the growing tensions between the U.S. and China. It also <strong>highlights</strong> American efforts to import from countries that are friendlier and closer to home.</p>
<p>Figures released recently by the U.S. Commerce Department show that the value of goods imported by the U.S. from Mexico rose nearly 5 percent from 2022 to 2023, to more than $475 billion. At the same time, the value of Chinese imports dropped 20 percent to $427 billion.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman works in a shoe maquiladora or factory in Leon, Mexico, Feb. 7, 2023. For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico overtook China as America's top supplier of goods. (AP Photo/Mario Armas, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0865-08dc28e44082_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman works in a shoe maquiladora or factory in Leon, Mexico, Feb. 7, 2023. For the first time in more than twenty years, Mexico overtook China as America's top supplier of goods. (AP Photo/Mario Armas, File)</span></div>
<p>The last time that Mexican goods imported by the United States were greater than the value of China's imports was in 2002.</p>
<p>Economic relations between the United States and China have declined in recent years.</p>
<p>The Trump administration began putting <strong>tariffs</strong> on Chinese imports in 2018. The administration argued that China's trade policies broke international trade rules. President Joe Biden kept those taxes on imports after taking office in 2021, making clear that opposition toward China would be a rare area of common ground for Democrats and Republicans.</p>
<p>Instead of sending production to China, which U.S. corporations had long done, the Biden administration has urged companies to seek suppliers in allied countries, in a process called "friend-shoring," or to return manufacturing to the United States in a process called "reshoring." Supply-chain problems related to the COVID-19 pandemic also led U.S. companies to seek supplies closer to the United States in a process called "near-shoring."</p>
<p>Mexico has been among those helped by the growing move away from Chinese factories. But the picture is more complex than it might seem.</p>
<p>Some Chinese manufacturers have established factories in Mexico to get the <strong>benefits</strong> of the 3-year-old U.S.-Mexico-Canada Trade Agreement. The agreement permits duty-free trade in North America for many products.</p>
<p>Mexican President Andrés Manuel López Obrador said last week that the trade deal gives Mexico new power. He said it would make it hard for the U.S. to close the two countries' border to limit immigration, as suggested in negotiations on a border bill in the U.S. Senate.</p>
<p>"The negotiation is proposing closing the border," he said. "Do you think Americans, or Mexicans, but especially the Americans, would approve that? The businesses wouldn't take it, maybe one day, but not a week."</p>
<p>Some industries — especially car manufacturers — have set up plants on both sides of the border. These plants depend on each other for a steady supply of parts.</p>
<p>Derek Scissors, a China specialist at the American Enterprise Institute, noted that the biggest drops in Chinese imports were in computers and electronics and chemicals and pharmaceuticals — all politically difficult areas.</p>
<p>"I don't see the U.S. being comfortable with a<strong> rebound </strong>in those areas in 2024 and 2025," Scissors said, predicting that the China-Mexico reversal on imports to the United States likely "is not a one-year<strong> blip</strong>.''</p>
<p>Scissors suggested that the drop in U.S. use of Chinese goods partly suggests concerns about China's economic policies under President Xi Jinping. Xi's COVID-19 lockdowns brought large parts of the Chinese economy to a halt in 2022. And his officials have raided foreign companies in possible counterespionage investigations.</p>
<p>"I think it's corporate America <strong>belatedly</strong> deciding Xi Jinping is <strong>unreliable</strong>," Scissors added.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Paul Wiseman reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>highlight </strong><em>– v. </em>to direct attention to (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>tariff<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> a tax on goods coming into or leaving a country</p>
<p><strong>benefit </strong><em>– n.</em> a good or helpful result or effect</p>
<p><strong>rebound</strong> –<em> n.</em> an increase after a decline</p>
<p><strong>blip </strong><em>– n.</em> something that is unimportant or that does not last a long time</p>
<p><strong>belatedly </strong><em>– adv.</em> happening or coming very late</p>
<p><strong>unreliable</strong> <em>– adj.</em> not believable or trustworthy</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australia to Introduce ‘Right to Disconnect’ Law for Workers  (2024/2/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/australia-to-introduce-right-to-disconnect-law-for-workers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Australia's parliament seems likely to pass a new "right to disconnect" bill that the federal government has proposed.</p>
<p>The law would prevent employers from asking their workers to keep their phones and computers turned on outside of work hours. Employers who ask employees to do so could be <strong>fined</strong>.</p>
<p>The aim is to protect workers' rights and improve <strong>work-life balance</strong> in the country.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Surfers prepare to enter the water at Bondi beach near Sydney, Australia on April 28, 2020. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/cf3ed1dc-9401-4543-9aae-f3a84a8d4922_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Surfers prepare to enter the water at Bondi beach near Sydney, Australia on April 28, 2020. (AP Photo/Rick Rycroft)</span></div>
<p>Similar laws are already in place in France, Spain and other European nations.</p>
<p>Australia's employment minister, Tony Burke, said most lawmakers have expressed support for the bill.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese discussed the proposed law on Wednesday.</p>
<p>"What we are simply saying is that someone who isn't being paid 24 hours a day shouldn't be penalized if they're not online and available 24 hours a day," he said.</p>
<p>The bill also includes rules that will give temporary workers guidelines about how to move into permanent work.</p>
<p>Adam Bandt is the leader of the left-wing Greens. He said his party supports the law. So do leaders of the Labor party and other smaller parliamentary groups.</p>
<p>Some politicians, however, warned that a new labor law would hurt Australia's ability to be competitive with other nations. The critics also say making a new labor law might make it difficult for employees who want to work <strong>flexible</strong> hours.</p>
<p>Bandt said Australians work an average of six unpaid weeks each year. He said that totals about $60 billion of unpaid <strong>wages</strong>.</p>
<p>"That time is yours," he said, "not your boss's."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fine </strong>–n. a financial penalty</p>
<p><strong>work-life balance </strong>–n. the idea that people should be able to spend their free time without having to think about work</p>
<p><strong>flexible </strong>–adj. something that is not tightly controlled</p>
<p><strong>wage </strong>–n. the money a person is paid for their work</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dartmouth Will Again Require Standardized Tests  (2024/2/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/dartmouth-will-again-require-standardized-tests.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Dartmouth College, the Ivy League university in New Hampshire, announced last week that it will again require <strong>standardized tests</strong> from <strong>applicants</strong>.</p>
<p>American students who wish to attend Dartmouth starting in the fall of 2025 will need to send SAT or ACT scores with their applications. Students from other parts of the world will need to submit results from "an <strong>equivalent</strong> standardized national exam," according to Dartmouth.</p>
<p>The university suspended its consideration of standardized tests for four years. In 2020, Dartmouth and many other American universities entered a "test-optional" period, which officials said was because of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Dartmouth College recently announced that it would again require the SAT or ACT from applicants starting next year." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/231B114F-88D0-4E14-80E7-96245420F617_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Dartmouth College recently announced that it would again require the SAT or ACT from applicants starting next year.</span></div>
<p><strong>Why did the schools go "test optional?"</strong></p>
<p>Starting in the spring of 2020, schools increasingly stopped holding in-person classes. That made it difficult for students to prepare for and gather to take standardized tests.</p>
<p>Many universities used the "test-optional" period to find out what would happen if they no longer required the SAT and ACT. Years before, a few studies said that the tests favored wealthy students.</p>
<p>Nat Smitobol is with IvyWise, a company that offers college admissions advice in New York City. Smitobol said universities want a <strong>diverse</strong> group of students and were not sure they were getting enough of them by looking at standardized tests.</p>
<p>Dartmouth said it looked at its group of accepted students after four years. It found the test optional policy increased the number of applications but made it harder to find the best students. The university said it discovered standardized test scores were "a valuable element of Dartmouth's undergraduate application."</p>
<p>In addition, the university said the tests expanded its ability to "identify <strong>talent</strong>." That means the tests made it easier for Dartmouth to find good students who do not come from rich families or wealthy high schools.</p>
<p>Dartmouth joins Georgetown University in Washington D.C. and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology as top schools again requiring standardized test scores.</p>
<p>Currently, Yale University in Connecticut, Harvard University and Duke University in North Carolina still permit students to apply without test results. They are all highly selective schools.</p>
<p>But some experts wonder if those schools will follow Dartmouth.</p>
<p><strong>Students still take the test even if optional</strong></p>
<p>Smitobol at IvyWise said most students still take the SAT or ACT. But he said most do not understand that they can still apply to schools such as Dartmouth even if their scores are a little low. An average SAT score is 1050 while 1600 is perfect.</p>
<p>"There's kids that won't break 1000 that can absolutely do the work at a Penn (University of Pennsylvania) or a Harvard or any of these places, there's no doubt about it."</p>
<p>Smitobol said a student with good grades who is an immigrant, or whose parents did not go to college, should almost always submit their test scores.</p>
<p>"If you score a 1400 or above and you're the first in your family to go to college, that would be an <strong>astronomical</strong> score," he said.</p>
<p>"And really, quite frankly, that's way more impressive than a 1550 from a student, you know, like from an <strong>affluent</strong> background."</p>
<p>Many students, however, say they like the freedom of choosing whether to send their scores to other schools.</p>
<p><strong>Better things to do than take a test</strong></p>
<p>Renee Bischoff is the Director of College Counseling at Hawken School, a high school near Cleveland, Ohio. She said she has some students who are good at lots of things: theater, sports, leadership activities, teaching younger students or performing community service, but they are not good at taking standardized tests.</p>
<p>If they choose to apply to a college that does not need a test score, they can put their energy into other things. She said some students were taking tests five times in an effort to raise their scores.</p>
<p>"I will say to them, ‘you know what?' You shouldn't spend the extra time. Don't spend the money. Don't spend your Saturday."</p>
<p>"<strong>Focus</strong> your time on doing the things that are deeply meaningful to you and work hard in school. That will be the leading thing and the testing isn't required, so let's not spend all our time and money on that."</p>
<p>Barry Maloney is the president of Worcester State University in Massachusetts. He wrote an opinion piece for the <em>Telegram &amp; Gazette</em>, a local newspaper, about test optional admission. For colleges like his, he wrote, a student's grades are "the best predictor" of their success.</p>
<p>"If a standardized test is something you don't want to take for admission...for any reason...you simply don't need to," he wrote.</p>
<p>Christiana Kalokoh is a senior at Annandale High School in Virginia, just outside of Washington, D.C. She was born in the African nation of Sierra Leone and moved to the U.S. as a girl.</p>
<p>She was accepted to a number of colleges already but did not send her test scores.</p>
<p>She said she tried her best on the tests, but she felt <strong>intimidated</strong> and <strong>confused</strong>. She did not take a test preparation class like some students.</p>
<p>However, Kalokoh has done well in school and taken part in many clubs and activities. She has a job to help support her family. She is the president of her school's Bible study club and takes part in heritage night, where she teaches people about her country.</p>
<p><strong>The importance of hope</strong></p>
<p>Kalokoh said she liked the fact that she could still get into a good college without doing well on the tests.</p>
<p>"It gives me a sense of peace knowing that if I were to study my hardest and try my best and still maybe not get such a great score, it wouldn't completely ruin my chances of getting into that college."</p>
<p>She applied to the University of Virginia and James Madison University and did not send her test scores. She will find out if she has been accepted later this spring.</p>
<p>Laura Wells is the AVID program coordinator at Annandale. The program identifies students who could do well in college, but they need extra support in order to succeed in more difficult classes.</p>
<p>The program also gives extra help and direction on college applications.</p>
<p>Wells helps students such as Kalokoh, who were not born in the U.S., or whose parents do not speak English.</p>
<p>Wells said her students usually have trouble with the tests. But the ones who get "straight A's," the very top grades, go on to do well in college.</p>
<p>Even if top schools require test scores, she said it is important that other schools remain test optional. The students she works with still need to believe they can go to a good college. For her, such schools in Virginia include the University of Virginia (UVA) and Virginia Tech.</p>
<p>"I do hope that schools like, you know UVA, Virginia Tech, still choose to be test optional because otherwise, it is really hard, I think, for students to kind of see themselves at those schools. They can accept the fact that they might not get into Dartmouth or Georgetown or Johns Hopkins or something, right? But you should have a shot at being able to go to your top-ranked state school. Yeah, that's what I think, anyway."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>standardized test </strong><em>–n.</em> tests taken by large numbers of students that are meant to measure their general knowledge and compare it to other students</p>
<p><strong>applicant </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who is submitting applications for entry into a school or college</p>
<p><strong>equivalent </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is different in small details but is more or less equal to something else</p>
<p><strong>diverse </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving many different kinds of people</p>
<p><strong>talent </strong><em>–n.</em> people who have valuable abilities and knowledge</p>
<p><strong>mean </strong><em>–n.</em> a value that has an equal number of values above it and below it</p>
<p><strong>astronomical </strong><em>–adj.</em> an extremely high value</p>
<p><strong>affluent </strong><em>–adj.</em> having a large amount of money or property</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong><em>–v.</em> pay attention or put time into something</p>
<p><strong>intimidated </strong><em>–adj.</em> made fearful by something</p>
<p><strong>confused </strong><em>–adj. </em>unsure and not able to make a clear decision</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Have you taken the SAT or ACT? How do you feel about the tests?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ancient Statue of Emperor Constantine Rebuilt in Rome  (2024/2/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/ancient-statue-of-emperor-constantine-rebuilt-in-rome.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Emperor Constantine the First was an ancient Roman ruler who welcomed Christianity. He helped spread the religion throughout the Roman Empire.</p>
<p>Recently, a large, rebuilt statue of Constantine was introduced to the public in Rome.</p>
<p>Officials revealed the 13-meter copy of the statue that Constantine had built for himself. Special technology known as 3D modelling permitted the statue's makers to create the work from<strong> scans </strong>of the nine large <strong>original</strong> marble body parts that remain.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Visitors admire a massive, 13-meter replica of the statue of Roman Emperor Constantine that was built using 3D technology from scans of the nine giant original marble body parts that remain. Tuesday, Feb. 6, 2024.(AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9090f213-18c8-45df-a613-06c96111897b_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Visitors admire a massive, 13-meter replica of the statue of Roman Emperor Constantine that was built using 3D technology from scans of the nine giant original marble body parts that remain. Tuesday, Feb. 6, 2024.(AP Photo/Andrew Medichini)</span></div>
<p>The result: a large statue of the seated emperor. Constantine is wearing special clothing and holding a <strong>scepter</strong> and <strong>orb</strong>. He looks over Rome from a side garden of the Capitoline Museums.</p>
<p>The rebuilt statue is close to the area where the original pieces of Constantine's giant feet, hands and head are kept. Artists in Rome created the original about 1,700 years ago.</p>
<p>Rebuilt to its original form, the statue creates wonder in people who see it. This feeling is just what Constantine wanted from his subjects, officials said at the statue's public introduction.</p>
<p>"In this statue there's not just beauty, there's the violence of power," said Salvatore Settis of the Fondazione Prada, the cultural and educational arm of the fashion house which financed the project.</p>
<p>Officials did not say how much the project cost. But the Factum Foundation created the statue. The group is a nonprofit based in Madrid. It creates special digital copies of the world's famous cultural objects.</p>
<p>"This whole <strong>dynamic</strong> about how you use technology to <strong>transform </strong>our understanding of and the importance of cultural heritage is the core mission of Factum Foundation," said the group's founder Adam Lowe.</p>
<p>The statue is made from several materials. The body includes resin, polyurethane and marble powder. Gold leaf and plaster make up the special clothing that goes over the body.</p>
<p>A second version of the statue is to be put in place in northeast England. That is where Constantine guarded defenses known as Hadrian's Wall before being crowned emperor in Rome.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell adapted this story from an Associated Press report. </em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scan<em> </em></strong><em>–n.</em> a copy or image of something that is made by a machine, and which contains data for use in study or reproduction</p>
<p><strong>original</strong> <em>-- adj.</em> made or produced first</p>
<p><strong>scepter</strong> –<em> n.</em> a long, decorated stick that is carried by a leader (such as a king or queen)</p>
<p><strong>orb</strong> <em>– n</em>. a gold ball with a cross on top that is carried by a leader (such as a king or queen)</p>
<p><strong>dynamic </strong><em>-- n.</em> something that causes change or growth in something else</p>
<p><strong>transform</strong> <em>– v. </em>to change something in a complete way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Do Married Couples 'Tie the Knot'?  (2024/2/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/why-do-married-couples-tie-the-knot.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give you definitions, examples, notes on usage, and sometimes we even use them in a <strong>conversation</strong>.</p>
<p>Valentine's Day is February 14. Because it is close to that day that celebrates lovers, we talk today about a <strong>romantic</strong> idiom: <u>tie the knot</u>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Newlyweds hold hands during a mass wedding ceremony on Valentine's Day, Thursday, Feb. 14, 2019. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/8E1A6F11-B11C-4C07-8702-5C71AC589549_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Newlyweds hold hands during a mass wedding ceremony on Valentine's Day, Thursday, Feb. 14, 2019. (AP Photo/Rebecca Blackwell)</span></div>
<p><u>To tie the knot</u> is an <strong>informal </strong>term for getting married. In some marriage ceremonies, a knot is actually tied around the couple's hands with a piece of cloth or ribbon. This is done as a <strong>symbol</strong> of unity.</p>
<p>This wedding tradition can be called a handfasting ceremony.</p>
<p>Several websites claim that this is an ancient Celtic wedding tradition. The couple holds hands while someone else ties their hands together with material. This represents the two people being physically and spiritually tied to each other.</p>
<p>But let's go back to the word "knot."</p>
<p>A knot is an <strong>interlacing</strong> of string, ribbon, rope, or similar material that forms a connection between two, or more, loose ends.</p>
<p>The word "knot" can also describe a mass or lump of disordered material that is <strong>tangled</strong>. Some knots are hard to untangle. For example, if your hair has knots, the ends have become tangled together, and it cannot be straightened or combed. When talking about hair, having knots is <em>not</em> a good thing.</p>
<p>Knowing how to tie knots is important in many activities including sailing. For example, rope is used to secure sails. While sailing, you might want ropes to stay knotted at times, but you also need to be able to release knots quickly, at a moment's notice.</p>
<p>With a marriage, you want to stay knotted together. You do not want the <strong>bond</strong> to be easily broken.</p>
<p>There are other ways to say <u>to tie the knot</u>. In a formal situation, you can say two people have been <u>wed</u>. A very informal expression is <u>to get hitched</u>.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear two friends use the expression "to tie the knot."</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, I have a wonderful secret about our good friends Finn and Polly. They are tying the knot next month!</em></p>
<p><em>B: What? Finn and Polly? Are you sure?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Yes! Polly told me last week while we were bowling. She's on my bowling team. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I cannot believe that. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, believe it. But she made me promise not to say a word. So, don't tell anyone. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I am shocked. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Why? Finn and Polly have been dating for years. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I'm not shocked about that. Polly ... bowls?? I had no idea. </em></p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em><i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;<i></i>173;______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conversation </strong><em>–n. </em>talking or a talk between two or more people</p>
<p><strong>romantic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to love between two people or to romance</p>
<p><strong>informal </strong><em>–adj.</em> not used in official or serious writing or speech</p>
<p><strong>symbol </strong><em>–n.</em> an object that represents an idea</p>
<p><strong>interlace </strong><em>–v.</em> joined in a way that involves crossing thread, string or rope over and under</p>
<p><strong>tangle </strong><em>–v.</em> to become disordered and twisted together</p>
<p><strong>bond </strong><em>–n.</em> a strong, lasting connection</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Teenage ‘Newton’ Builds Electric Device to Light Gaza Tent  (2024/2/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/teenage-newton-builds-electric-device-to-light-gaza-tent.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A 15-year-old boy in Gaza was able to build a device to provide electricity to light the <strong>tent</strong> he is staying in with his family.</p>
<p>Hussam Al-Attar got two fans at a resale market and used them to create small wind <strong>turbines</strong> to produce electricity. His invention led others in the camp where he stays to start calling him the "Newton" of Gaza.</p>
<p>This comparison involves the English scientist, Isaac Newton. Newton is known for his major scientific discoveries in the fields of physics, mathematics and astronomy more than 300 years ago. A famous story about Newton describes how an apple falling on his head led him to discover the nature of gravity.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Displaced Palestinian teenager Hussam Al-Attar works on wind turbines, that he uses to light up his shelter during power cut, at a tent camp in Rafah, in the southern Gaza Strip, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-412e-08dc28b1af94_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Displaced Palestinian teenager Hussam Al-Attar works on wind turbines, that he uses to light up his shelter during power cut, at a tent camp in Rafah, in the southern Gaza Strip, February 6, 2024. (REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa)</span></div>
<p>"Newton was sitting under an apple tree when an apple fell on his head and he discovered gravity," Al-Attar told Reuters news agency. "And we here are living in darkness and <strong>tragedy</strong>, and rockets are falling on us, therefore I thought of creating light, and did so," he added.</p>
<p>Al-Attar is staying with his family in a tent in Rafah, a city on the southern edge of the Gaza Strip, near the border with Egypt. Reuters reported that Rafah currently holds more than half of Gaza's total population of 2.3 million people.</p>
<p>Large numbers of people fled to the area from other parts of Gaza to escape fighting between Israeli forces and Hamas fighters. The fighting has been ongoing since Hamas militants invaded southern Israel from Gaza on October 7. Israeli officials say the invasion left 1,200 people dead and 253 kidnapped.</p>
<p>Israel immediately began a large military campaign to answer the actions of Hamas. Israeli military officials have said their goal is to crush the Palestinian Islamist group. Local health officials in Gaza say the fighting has killed more than 27,000 people across the territory and caused displacement and hunger.</p>
<p>Al-Attar and his family are staying in a tent that is partly attached to a house. He was able to climb onto the <strong>roof</strong> to set up two fans, one above the other. The wind can turn the fans, which produce small amounts of electricity. He then connected the fans to wires and built a <strong>charging</strong> station. Al-Attar also built <strong>switches</strong> to control a lighting system made out of wood.</p>
<p>He said his first two attempts failed and it took him a while to develop a working system. "I started developing it further, bit by bit, until I was able to extend the wires through the room to the tent that we are living in, so that the tent will have light."</p>
<p>Al-Attar added that he was happy to be able to create something to help "ease the suffering" of his family members. He said he is looking forward to the future when conditions can improve in Gaza.</p>
<p>"I am very happy that people in this camp call me Gaza's Newton," Al-Attar said. He added, "Because I hope to <strong>achieve</strong> my dream of becoming a scientist like Newton and creating an invention that will <strong>benefit </strong>not only the people of the Gaza Strip, but the whole world."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tent </strong><em>– n.</em> a structure made of metal poles and cloth that is used to provide protection for people camping outdoors</p>
<p><strong>turbine </strong><em>– n. </em>a large machine that produces power by using gas, steam, wind, etc.</p>
<p><strong>tragedy </strong><em>– n. </em>an event or situation that is very sad, often involving death</p>
<p><strong>roof </strong><em>– n. </em>the surface that covers and protects the top of a building or vehicle</p>
<p><strong>charge </strong>–v. to put electricity into a device that holds electrical charge called a battery</p>
<p><strong>switch </strong>–n. a device that permits or cuts electrical current in a circuit</p>
<p><strong>achieve </strong><em>– v. </em>to succeed in doing something good, usually by working hard</p>
<p><strong>benefit </strong><em>– v. </em>to be helped by something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is the Lunar New Year?  (2024/2/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-the-lunar-new-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>On February 10, Asian American communities around the world will ring in the Year of the Dragon. Some Lunar New Year celebrations will be public, like parades and fireworks. But, families will also gather for private parties.</p>
<p><strong>What is the Lunar New Year?</strong></p>
<p>The Lunar New Year is a major holiday in several Asian countries. And people celebrate over several days or even weeks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man holds a child in front of a giant dragon lantern decoration near the popular Houhai Lake in Beijing, China on February 8, 2024. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/666485f4-525d-40ab-9307-ce97e18aac54_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man holds a child in front of a giant dragon lantern decoration near the popular Houhai Lake in Beijing, China on February 8, 2024. (AP Photo/Andy Wong)</span></div>
<p>It is called the Spring Festival in China, Tet in Vietnam and Seollal in Korea.</p>
<p>The holiday begins on the first new moon of the lunar <strong>calendar</strong> and ends 15 days later on the first full moon. Because the holiday is based on the moon, it falls somewhere between the end of January and the end of February.</p>
<p>The lunar calendar is based on 12 animals of the Chinese zodiac. The animals are rat, ox, tiger, rabbit, dragon, snake, horse, goat, m<i><i>onkey</i></i>, rooster, dog and pig. In the Vietnamese zodiac, the cat replaces the rabbit and the buffalo is in place of the ox. For 2024, it is the year of the dragon for both.</p>
<p><strong>What are some traditions around the Lunar New Year?</strong></p>
<p>One well-known ancient story speaks of Nian, a terrible <strong>monster</strong> that eats human flesh on New Year's Day. But Nian has some fears that weaken him. He fears the color red, loud noises and fire. So, Lunar New Year activities include putting up red paper dragons on the doors of homes. People also burn red <strong>lanterns</strong> all night and set off firecrackers to chase away the monster.</p>
<p>To this day, the Lunar New Year celebration is centered on removing bad luck and welcoming all that is good and successful. Red is considered a lucky color to ring in a new year. In many Asian cultures, the color symbolizes a good future and joy. People wear red clothing, <strong>decorate</strong> their homes with red paper lanterns and use red <strong>envelopes</strong> to present loved ones with gifts of money. Gambling and playing traditional games are common during Lunar New Year among celebrants around the world.</p>
<p>Ancestor worship is also common during this time. Many Korean families take part in a ceremony called "charye." Female family members prepare food and male members serve it to ancestors. The final act involves the entire family sharing a meal and asking for help from their ancestors for the coming year.</p>
<p>Vietnamese culture holds a similar tradition. People cook traditional dishes and place them on a home <strong>altar</strong> in honor of their ancestors.</p>
<p><strong>How do diaspora communities celebrate?</strong></p>
<p>Members of Asian American communities around the U.S. also organize parades, parties and other events around the Lunar New Year. Lion and dragon dances are common, as are fireworks, traditional food and cultural performances. People do special cleanings of their homes and decorate using orchids and other brightly colored flowers.</p>
<p><strong>What are some special foods for the New Year?</strong></p>
<p>Each culture has its own special foods for New Year celebration, including dumplings, rice cakes, spring rolls, tangerines, fish and meats.</p>
<p>In Chinese culture, for example, "changshou mian" or "long-life noodles" are eaten with a wish for a long, healthy and happy life. Koreans celebrate with "tteokguk," a soup that contains thinly sliced rice cakes.</p>
<p>And Vietnamese culture has "banh chung", a traditional dish made from rice, mung bean and pork belly. The dish is usually covered with banana leaves, shaped into a square and tied up with strings for steaming.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver adapted this story for VOA Learning English from an Associated Press report.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diaspora</strong> – <em>n</em>. people settled far from their ancestral homelands</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>calendar </strong>– <em>n. </em>a system for fixing the beginning, length, and divisions of the civil year and arranging days and longer divisions of time (such as weeks and months) in a definite order</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>monster </strong>– <em>n. </em>a strange, frightening and/or horrible creature</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>lantern </strong>– <em>n</em>. a usually portable protective case for a light with transparent openings</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>decorate </strong>– <em>n</em>. to make more appealing or meaningful by adding something beautiful, symbolic, interesting etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>altar </strong>– <em>n. </em>a table or place which serves as a center of worship or ritual</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Super Bowl Expected to Set Betting Record, But Don’t Bet on Taylor Swift  (2024/2/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/super-bowl-expected-to-set-betting-record-but-dont-bet-on-taylor-swift.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The gambling industry expects this Sunday's Super Bowl game between the Kansas City Chiefs and the San Francisco 49ers to smash <strong>betting</strong> records.</p>
<p>The American football game is the National Football League's <strong>championship</strong> game. The game is played in Las Vegas, Nevada, for the first time. The city is known for its <strong>casinos</strong> and places to <strong>gamble</strong>.</p>
<p>The American Gaming Association (AGA) said Tuesday that it expects Sunday's game to be the busiest ever for betting. The AGA says nearly 68 million American adults, or about one in four, will bet on the game.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Welcome to Las Vegas is outlined in purple for the Super Bowl, Feb. 6, 2024, in Las Vegas. On Sunday, the city will host the Kansas City Chiefs and the San Francisco 49ers in Super Bowl 58. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a731-08dc28124cd9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Welcome to Las Vegas is outlined in purple for the Super Bowl, Feb. 6, 2024, in Las Vegas. On Sunday, the city will host the Kansas City Chiefs and the San Francisco 49ers in Super Bowl 58. (AP Photo/Charlie Riedel)</span></div>
<p>For a long time, Las Vegas was the only American city that permitted sports gambling. After a 2018 decision by the Supreme Court, sports gambling is now permitted in 38 states.</p>
<p>However, most of the Super Bowl bets will be made illegally, with people who take bets privately, known as bookies.</p>
<p>The AGA estimates over $23 billion will be bet on the game this year but only $1.5 billion of the bets will be legal. Last year, the total number was $16 billion.</p>
<p>Chris Grove is with Eilers and Krejcik, a company that follows the gambling business. He said, "There's a good chance that every Super Bowl for the next ten or so years will be the most bet Super Bowl thanks to the <strong>underlying</strong> growth of ... sports betting in the U.S."</p>
<p>You can bet on all kinds of things in American casinos and through online sports betting apps and websites.</p>
<p>The easiest bet is on the winner of the game. About 47 percent of bettors think Kansas City will win, and 44 percent think San Francisco will win.</p>
<p>But there are other ways to bet, too. People can make a bet on the outcome of individual plays. For example, people can bet whether the play will result in a score, like a <strong>touchdown</strong> or a field goal. They can bet whether the offensive team can move the ball forward by only one or two meters. Or they can bet that the defensive team will take away the ball with an <strong>interception</strong>.</p>
<p>But there is one thing you cannot legally bet on, at least at American casinos: if Taylor Swift will make it to the game and how many times she will appear on television. Swift has been at several Kansas City Chiefs games this year to cheer for her boyfriend, Travis Kelce, one of the team's best players.</p>
<p>Swift is performing in Japan on Saturday, February 10. Many expect the superstar to fly across the Pacific Ocean to get to the Super Bowl game a day later.</p>
<p>In the U.S., most legal bets are limited to what happens on the field. However, casinos and other gambling sites outside of the U.S. permit more wide-ranging bets. For example, it is possible to bet on the color of the Gatorade drink that will be dumped on the winning team's <strong>coach</strong>.</p>
<p>Other sites may permit people to guess how long the U.S. national song, the <em>Star-Spangled Banner, </em>will be. Reba McIntyre is performing the song before the game this year.</p>
<p>John Ewing works in public relations for BetMGM. He said it is better to permit bets on events that have a clear outcome.</p>
<p>"We want it to be either: it won or it didn't win," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on reports by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bet </strong>–v. to put money or risk something on whether an action will happen, such as the outcome of a sporting event</p>
<p><strong>championship </strong>–n. the highest award in a competition or sport that decides which person or team is best</p>
<p><strong>casino </strong>–n. the physical building where betting happens</p>
<p><strong>gamble </strong>–v. the act of playing a game of chance for money or placing a bet on an event</p>
<p><strong>underlying </strong>–n. at the base, fundamental</p>
<p><strong>touchdown </strong>–n. a way of scoring points in American football where the ball crosses the goal line either by running or a throw and catch – worth six points</p>
<p><strong>interception </strong>–n. in American football, when a player from the opposing team catches a ball thrown in the air</p>
<p><strong>coach </strong>–n. a person who teaches or trains an athlete</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Do you think you will make a bet on the American football Super Bowl?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Surge and Soar  (2024/2/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/surge-and-soar.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about the difference between "surge" and "soar."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hi my dear teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-7e2c-08dc27f7178b_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I'm Hamid from Iran. What is difference between "surge" and "soar?" Can they be used interchangeably?</p>
<p>Much obliged,</p>
<p>Hamid</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>While "surge" and "soar" have a similar verbal meaning of rising or increasing quickly, there are some big differences! Let's look at each word with some examples.</p>
<p><strong>Surge</strong></p>
<p>As a verb, "surge" means to rise or increase very quickly in an abnormal way.</p>
<p><em>Food prices surged due to inflation.</em></p>
<p>"Surge" can also mean to rise rapidly and fall quickly.</p>
<p><em>The boat was surging through the water during the storm.</em></p>
<p>When talking about something coming in waves, we can use "surge."</p>
<p><em>The waves surged to the <strong>shore</strong> as the hurricane approached.</em></p>
<p><em>Kaitlyn's emotions surged as she accepted her award. </em></p>
<p>And lastly as a verb, we use "surge" to talk about physical things like electricity or water moving rapidly through something and with force or power.</p>
<p><em>Electricity can surge through electronic devices unexpectedly causing damage.</em></p>
<p>As a noun, the most basic meaning is a powerful rise or increase in something that was once <strong>steady</strong> or not moving. This could be physical things like water or power, or it could be more <strong>abstract</strong> like your feelings.</p>
<p><em>There has been a surge of interest in American football from young women due to </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/it-has-never-been-more-costly-to-see-the-super-bowl/7463874.html"><em>Taylor Swift</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p><em>The storm surge left residents along the coast unable to return to their homes for months. </em></p>
<p><em>Surge protectors can keep computers and other electronics safe during thunderstorms. </em></p>
<p><em>Carol felt a surge of sadness move over her when her dog died. </em></p>
<p>Let's move onto "soar."</p>
<p><strong>Soar</strong></p>
<p>Much like "surge," "soar" is a verb that can mean to rise rapidly. However, "soar" is used mostly to talk about a position, value or price.</p>
<p><em>Pat's blood pressure always soars to 140/90 when she goes to the doctor because she is worried. </em></p>
<p><em>Stock prices soared after the new CEO of the company was announced. </em></p>
<p>Soar can also be used to talk about things that fly, like birds or planes.</p>
<p><em>The <strong>geese</strong> soared in formation as they flew south for the winter.</em></p>
<p><em>The skydiver felt as though she was soaring through the air after she jumped out of the plane. </em></p>
<p>And lastly, "soar' means to rise or move to a higher state. This can be physically like a voice or abstractly like your <strong>spirits</strong> or feelings. It can also be used to talk about how tall or high things are.</p>
<p><em>The singer's voice soared over the other members of the <strong>choir</strong>. </em></p>
<p><em>Her spirits soared when she learned of the good news. </em></p>
<p><em>One World Trade Center soars above all other buildings in New York City, standing at a height of 541 meters or 1776 feet. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Hamid.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher. </em>Thank you for joining me over the past two years. I have enjoyed answering your questions. I hope that your English skills "soar" ever higher!</p>
<p>Take care,</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>shore</strong> <em>– n.</em> the land along the edge of an area of water (such as an ocean, lake, etc.)</p>
<p><strong>steady </strong>– <em>adj. </em>something that is strong and keeps working over time</p>
<p><strong>abstract </strong><em>– adj.</em> relating to or involving general ideas or qualities rather than specific people, objects, or actions</p>
<p><strong>geese </strong>– <em>n.(pl.)</em> birds that live in and close to water and migrate in the winter to warmer areas.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>spirit</strong> <em>– n. </em>a force within a human being thought to give the body life, energy, and power</p>
<p><strong>choir</strong> –<em> n. </em>a group of singers especially in a church</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Has Earth Warmed More Than We Thought?  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/has-earth-warmed-more-than-we-thought.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Old <strong>sponges</strong> from deep in the Caribbean Sea are causing some researchers to think human-caused climate change began sooner than scientists have thought. But, if a recent study is correct, world temperatures are increasing faster than United Nations' estimates suggest.</p>
<p>The researchers from American and Australian universities published their sponge findings recently in <em>Nature Climate Change</em>. They said, if their findings are correct, the world has already gone past a temperature limit set by international negotiators. Negotiators of the Paris Agreement on climate change set 1.5 degrees Celsius as a limit for the increase of the world's temperature from pre-industrial times. Pre-industrial times are from about 1850 to 1900. But the American and Australian researchers said that the world hit a 1.7-degree Celsius increase in 2020.</p>
<p>The scientists looked at six special sponges that are known to live hundreds of years. They examined the sponges' growth records to find very small levels of the elements calcium and strontium. The scientists said that the amount of calcium and strontium changes, depending on the water temperature.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by Amos Winter shows a sponge from the Caribbean. (Courtesy of Amos Winter via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c18768da-84d9-40d7-98ad-aeeda9f1a1c1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by Amos Winter shows a sponge from the Caribbean. (Courtesy of Amos Winter via AP)</span></div>
<p>Malcolm McCulloch is an ocean scientist at the University of Western Australia. He was the lead writer of the study. McCulloch noted that the currently accepted temperature estimates for the 1850-1900 period were too high. That means that present-day temperature increases are larger and the Earth's temperature is warming faster than scientists have believed. He said, "We have a <strong>decade</strong> less than we thought."</p>
<p>In the past several years, many scientists have noted that there seems to be more extreme weather than they had expected. One explanation would be that the Earth is warming faster than scientists had first believed, said Amos Winter.</p>
<p>Winter helped write the study. He is an ocean scientist at Indiana State University. He said the study supports the theory that climate change is quickening. Former top NASA scientist James Hansen also has proposed that theory.</p>
<p>Sponges get water flowing from all over them so they can record a larger area of environmental change, Winter and McCulloch said. The research team examined sponges that lived in a special "mixed" area of the ocean that is 33 to 91 meters deep. The researchers were able to estimate nearly the exact atmospheric temperature of the Earth from the amount of calcium and strontium in the deep-sea sponges.</p>
<p>Their results were different from the scientifically accepted temperature estimates used by the United Nations' Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). The IPCC temperature estimates are the basis for the U.N. temperature goals.</p>
<p>The <em>Nature Climate Change</em> study finds that the mid-1800s were about half a degree Celsius cooler than believed. It also found that warming from heat-trapping gases started about 80 years earlier than the measurements the IPCC uses. IPCC numbers show warming started just after 1900.</p>
<p>McCulloch and Winter said it makes sense that the warming started earlier than the IPCC stated because by the mid-1800s industries had begun polluting the air with carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>For pre-industrial temperatures, the IPCC and most scientists use data that came from ships whose crews would take the temperature of water near the surface. Some of the measurements could change based on how the collection was done.</p>
<p>The researchers said sponges provide better information because of the way they store chemical elements in their skeletons. When waters are warmer, there is more of the element strontium and less of the mineral calcium, Winter said.</p>
<p>University of Pennsylvania climate scientist Michael Mann, who was not part of the study, has thought warming started before the IPCC said it did. But he doubted the study's findings.</p>
<p>"In my view it <strong>begs credulity</strong> to claim that the instrumental record is wrong based on <strong>paleo-</strong>sponges from one <strong>region</strong> of the world," Mann said.</p>
<p>But Winter and McCulloch have defended their use of sponges to identify world temperature change. They said, except for the 1800s, their temperature findings based on sponges follow global records from other devices. These include scientific instruments and measurements from things like coral, ice, and tree rings.</p>
<p>Princeton University climate scientist Michael Oppenheimer was not part of the sponge study either. He said, even if the McCulloch team is right, it should not change warnings from scientists. He said that the danger level is not tied to the exact "value of preindustrial temperatures."</p>
<p>McCulloch added that "...the only way to stop this is to reduce <strong>emissions</strong>. Urgently. Most Urgently.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gregory Stachel adapted this Associated Press story by Seth Borenstein for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sponge </strong>– <em>n</em>. a type of sea animal from which natural sponges are made</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong>– <em>n</em>. a period of 10 years</p>
<p><strong>beg </strong>– <em>v</em>. to cause someone to ask a specified question as a reaction or response</p>
<p><strong>credulity </strong><em>– n. </em>ability or willingness to believe something</p>
<p><strong>paleo- </strong><em>– prefix</em> connected with ancient times</p>
<p><strong>region </strong><em>– n. </em>a part of a country or of the world that is different or separate from other parts in some way</p>
<p><strong>emission </strong><em>– n.</em> a gas, such as carbon dioxide, that is sent out or produced by a process like burning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Private Missions Launch Debate over What to Permit on Moon  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/private-missions-launch-debate-over-what-to-permit-on-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The rise in private American space <strong>missions</strong> has led to increasing calls for rules on what can be transported to the moon.</p>
<p>Individuals and groups have criticized plans by private companies to send things that might not be suitable for the lunar surface.</p>
<p>The proposals came from companies that have contracts with the American space agency NASA to provide space flight services and carry equipment and supplies to the moon. Such materials launched from rockets are known as payloads.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration created by the European Space Agency (ESA) shows how a future moon base could be set up, with structures built with 3D printer technology. Industrial partners including architectural company Foster+Partners joined ESA to test the possibi" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/659CF0FF-3DE8-4912-9E21-BCBDE59C624A_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration created by the European Space Agency (ESA) shows how a future moon base could be set up, with structures built with 3D printer technology. Industrial partners including architectural company Foster+Partners joined ESA to test the possibi</span></div>
<p>The efforts are part of NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Services (CLPS) program. It aims to hand over the nation's major space missions to private companies in an effort to reduce costs.</p>
<p>The CLPS program plans to send several landers to the moon in the coming years. The landers will be carrying instruments and exploring tools to help humans learn more about the moon and its surroundings. But some missions also plan on sending human remains or goods that could be used in advertising.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Leslie Tennen is a lawyer who specializes in international space law. She told Reuters news agency, "We're just at the beginning of exploring the moon, and...we need to be careful we're not <strong>contaminating</strong> it." She said she thinks care should be taken to prevent the spread of what she calls "<strong>litter</strong>" on the moon.</p>
<p>Last month, one privately-built lunar lander aimed to touch down on the surface of the moon. But the spacecraft, called Peregrine, developed a fuel leak shortly after launch and did not make it to the moon.</p>
<p>The company that built Peregrine is Astrobotic Technology, of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The lander was loaded with 20 research experiments involving seven different countries. But it also carried other materials. These included numerous containers of human remains, a piece of rock from Mount Everest, a physical bitcoin and a can of the Japanese sports drink Pocari Sweat.</p>
<p>Among the remains were ashes of famous space lovers Gene Roddenberry and Arthur C. Clarke. Roddenberry was creator of the popular television show <em>Star Trek</em> and Clarke was a science fiction writer.</p>
<p>The Navajo Nation had sought to stop Peregrine's launch because of the inclusion of the remains. The head of the Native American group called the sending of remains a "<strong>desecration</strong>" because his people consider the moon a holy space.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Astrobotic said the objections to Peregrine's launch came too late to reach an agreement on the issue. But the company said it would try to find "a good path forward" with the Navajo Nation on future missions.</p>
<p>Reuters reports that under U.S. law, materials can be transported to the moon as long as they do not violate certain general guidelines set by the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).</p>
<p>The FAA requires companies to show that a payload launched from Earth does not "<strong>jeopardize</strong> public health and safety...U.S. national security...or international <strong>obligations</strong>" of the U.S. This rule permits most materials to be sent to the moon.</p>
<p>But legal experts think the issue will likely gain more attention as more private missions make successful landings on the lunar surface. And this could lead to new legal restrictions on what can be transported to the moon.</p>
<p>Lawyers with space-law experience worry that the absence of rules could lead to disputes between U.S. companies and other nations seeking to operate on the lunar surface. There could also be disagreements over which businesses should be permitted to claim land or <strong>sovereignty</strong>.</p>
<p>The current guidelines for international activities on the moon are included in a document called the 1967 <a class="wsw__a" href="https://2009-2017.state.gov/t/isn/5181.htm">Outer Space Treaty</a>. It states that outer space – including the moon and other bodies<strong> </strong>– "shall be free for exploration and use by all states." The treaty also states that nations involved in space exploration must approve of and <strong>supervise</strong> the activities of non-government organizations.</p>
<p>Experts say few nations have approved their own rules for moon behavior and measures are currently unclear in international law. This has led to calls for new international guidelines.</p>
<p>Martha Mejía-Kaiser is a Mexican-German space lawyer and a board member of the International Institute of Space Law. She told Reuters, "We are already late, and we are very urgently in need to start now, to discuss the moon at an international level."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n.</em> to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
<p><strong>contaminate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make something dirty or poisonous</p>
<p><strong>litter </strong><em>– n. </em>things left in an area that makes the area seem dirty <strong>desecrate </strong><em>– v. </em>to damage or show a lack of respect toward something holy or highly respected</p>
<p><strong>jeopardize </strong><em>– v. </em>to put something in danger</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>– n. </em>something a person does because it is their duty or because they feel they have to</p>
<p><strong>sovereignty </strong><em>– n. </em>the power of a country to control its own government</p>
<p><strong>supervise </strong><em>– v. </em>to watch over a person or activity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dong Tao Chicken, Food of Choice for Lunar New Year  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/dong-tao-chicken-food-of-choice-for-lunar-new-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Dong Tao chicken has been a food of choice for generations in Vietnam for the Lunar New Year, or Tet.</p>
<p>The rare bird is known for its strangely large feet. It is also known as a "dragon chicken." The chicken gets its name from the village of Dong Tao, about 30 kilometers southeast of Hanoi.</p>
<p>Dong Tao chickens are believed to bring good luck and wealth to their owners. At one point, they were only bred to serve meat for the royal families and officials.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Baby Dong Tao chickens, also known as Dragon Chicken, are seen at Dong Tao village, in Hung Yen province, Vietnam, on January 31, 2024. (REUTERS/Minh Nguyen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ef2d-08dc28bc1356_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Baby Dong Tao chickens, also known as "Dragon Chicken," are seen at Dong Tao village, in Hung Yen province, Vietnam, on January 31, 2024. (REUTERS/Minh Nguyen)</span></div>
<p>Today, demand for Dong Tao chicken in Vietnam has risen sharply. That demand comes from a growing number of wealthy people in one of Asia's fastest-growing economies.</p>
<p>Le Trong Dung is a chicken farmer in the village of Dong Tao. He told Reuters that a fully-grown Dong Tao chicken at one year old sells for $200 and sometimes as much as $400.</p>
<p>The demand for Dong Tao chicken is also fueled by its rich taste.</p>
<p>Loc Duc Toan is a 25-year-old cook in Hanoi. Toan said a Dong Tao chicken has its best taste at the age of 13 to 15 months. "When steamed, the skin will be crispy with a <strong>fragrant</strong> <strong>aroma</strong> of its own and a sweeter meat compared to other normal chicken," Toan said.</p>
<p>Nguyen Thi Hong Nhung is a chicken farmer, She said the most valuable parts of Dong Tao chickens are its legs.</p>
<p>Their large legs make it difficult for them to hatch from their eggs. Sometimes, they can accidentally break their eggs.</p>
<p>It takes about a year to raise a Dong Tao chicken, compared to three months for other kinds.</p>
<p>The chickens are now also raised beyond the village of Dong Tao. That means more people may have the chance to buy a Dong Tao chicken. But Phan Van Hieu, a Dong Tao agriculture official, said chickens raised in the village and fed with its native rice and corn have the best taste.</p>
<p>"Production hasn't met <strong>domestic</strong> demand yet," Hieu added. "I'm sure you won't find any Dong Tao chicken in any KFC restaurants in [the] foreseeable future."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on Reuters news report.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fragrant</strong> - adj. having a pleasant and usually sweet smell</p>
<p><strong>aroma</strong> - n. an usually please smell</p>
<p><strong>domestic</strong> - adj. relating to your own country</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ways to Say 'Goodbye'  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/ways-to-say-goodbye.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>It is never easy to say goodbye, but at least in English, we have many ways to do so. For my final <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, I want to share the many ways to say goodbye in English.</p>
<p>There are polite or <strong>formal</strong> ways. There are also ways we can say goodbye in everyday conversation, including fun <strong>slang</strong> that you can use.</p>
<p>"Goodbye" is believed to have come from the expression, "God be with ye," about 500 years ago. "Ye" is an old form of "you." Over time "God" became "good." Today, the expression is for wishing someone well when you are leaving.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-e99c-08dc275bec53_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>"Goodbye" is probably the most common way to say this. Shorter forms include "bye" and "bye-bye." If you enjoy the 1990's pop band, NSYNC, you can say: "Bye Bye Bye!"</p>
<p><em>"It might sound </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/crazy-and-insane/6514528.html"><em>crazy</em></a><em> but it ain't no lie</em></p>
<p><em>Baby, bye bye bye"</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p><strong>In formal conversation</strong></p>
<p>When you part with someone and you want to wish them a good time, you can use this general structure:</p>
<p>Have + a + adjective + period of time:</p>
<p><em>Have a good night! </em></p>
<p><em>Have a wonderful weekend! </em></p>
<p><em>Have a nice day.</em></p>
<p>"Have" is in the imperative form of the verb. The imperative form gives instructions, directions or commands. Imperative sentences use the base form of the verb.</p>
<p>If parting ways with someone during the nighttime, we combine "good" with "night" to wish someone a "goodnight." We use this expression usually when going to sleep at night.</p>
<p><em>I always say "goodnight" to everyone in my house before bedtime.</em></p>
<p>We use other command forms in formal settings to say "goodbye."</p>
<p>"Take care (of yourself)" is meant to wish someone physical or emotional health.</p>
<p>If we have enjoyed our time with someone we can say:</p>
<p><em>It was a pleasure speaking with you.</em></p>
<p>It + form of "be" in present or past tense + article and noun or adjective + gerund + (with) you.</p>
<p><em>It was great seeing you this weekend. </em></p>
<p>We can also say that we "look forward to" seeing or speaking with someone. This expression suggests hope for the future.</p>
<p><em>I look forward to our next meeting.</em></p>
<p><em>I look forward to seeing you then.</em></p>
<p><em>I look forward to speaking with you.</em></p>
<p>Shorter forms of this expression include a sentence with "will."</p>
<p><em>I will see you then. </em></p>
<p><em>See you then!</em></p>
<p><em>Speak to you then!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>In everyday conversation</strong></p>
<p>When speaking with friends and family, you can use informal ways to communicate leaving.</p>
<p>Shorter forms like "see you" are said even more conversationally when "you" becomes "ya" in fast speech. We can combine the expression with an adverb to say when we will see someone in the future.</p>
<p><em>See you soon!</em></p>
<p><em>See ya' later.</em></p>
<p><em>See ya' around! </em></p>
<p><em>Catch you later.</em></p>
<p><em>Catch ya' later.</em></p>
<p>To express a similar meaning, we can use a prepositional phrase with "until." There is no subject or object. Just the preposition is used.</p>
<p>Until + time expression</p>
<p><em>Until then.</em></p>
<p><em>Until Tuesday! </em></p>
<p><em>Until next week! </em></p>
<p>If you need to quickly leave, you can use these expressions. "Gotta" is a contraction that is used in everyday speech.</p>
<p><em>I've got to go.</em></p>
<p><em>I've gotta go.</em></p>
<p><em>I'm heading off.</em></p>
<p>If you want someone to connect with you in the future, you can use these:</p>
<p><em>Don't be a stranger.</em></p>
<p><em>Keep in touch!</em></p>
<p>If someone is leaving you on a trip, you can wish them a safe journey:</p>
<p><em>Have a safe trip!</em></p>
<p><em>Drive safely. </em></p>
<p><em>Drive safe!</em></p>
<p><em>Safe travels!</em></p>
<p>Note that in "drive safe," "safe" is, what is sometimes called, a "flat" adverb. These are older adverb forms in English that do not use the -ly ending. Phrases "sleep tight" or "go slow" are examples.</p>
<p>Another expression that uses a flat adverb is "take it easy."</p>
<p>And lastly, if you must leave quickly, you can use the expression:</p>
<p><em>I've got to hit the road. </em></p>
<p><em>I gotta hit the road.</em></p>
<p>We often use it when we are going to drive somewhere, but we can use it for other means of travel.</p>
<p><strong>Slang</strong></p>
<p>Finally, we have a few slang words that are used very informally in speech, especially by some groups of people. Slang is often spoken by young people and is generational, meaning that each new generation has its own slang. Remember, using slang is very informal and not a good idea in groups of people who are of several different age groups.</p>
<p>From the expression "see you later," we get the one-word slang expression "later." You can use this word by itself or with the person's name.</p>
<p><em>Later!</em></p>
<p><em>Later, John! </em></p>
<p>We also have the expression:</p>
<p><em>I'm out of here. </em></p>
<p>We can make this even more informal by shortening "out of" to "outta."</p>
<p><em>I'm outta here.</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/g7nnpxLZpCQ?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p>One of my favorite expressions was often heard in 1990's and early 2000's hip hop music: "bounce."</p>
<p>According to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=bounce">Urban Dictionary</a>, to "bounce" means to leave and go somewhere else better or quickly.</p>
<p>A song by Destiny's Child, "Say My Name," uses this expression:</p>
<p><em>See you gotta bounce</em></p>
<p><em>When two seconds ago</em></p>
<p><em>You said you just got in the house</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/sQgd6MccwZc?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we talked about different expressions we can use to say "goodbye." Many "goodbye" expressions in both formal and everyday language use the imperative form. We also looked at some fun slang words for "goodbye."</p>
<p>I wanted to thank our audience for the past two years here at VOA Learning English. This might not be "goodbye," maybe it is just "see ya later!"</p>
<p>Take care,</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm John Russel.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>formal </strong>– <em>adj</em>. language that is used for serious or official writing and speaking</p>
<p><strong>slang </strong>– <em>n</em>. a word or expression that is not standard usage, is considered very informal and is usually used by people of a certain age group or ethnic background</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple: Vision Pro Headset Enables ‘Spatial Computing’  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/apple-says-its-new-vision-pro-headset-enables-spatial-computing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Technology company Apple's new computing device, the Vision Pro headset, became available in stores last week.</p>
<p>The device uses <strong>augmented reality</strong> technology which has been available for years. But Apple calls the technology "spatial computing." The device is worn on the head over the eyes.</p>
<p>Apple hopes the Vision Pro will be as popular as the iPhone, Apple's cellphone that came out in 2007.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Scott Joachim tries out an Apple Vision Pro headset during the first day of sales at a Palo Alto, Calif., Apple store on Friday, Feb. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e3ec4095-7811-43ca-8a2c-752b33effc05_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Scott Joachim tries out an Apple Vision Pro headset during the first day of sales at a Palo Alto, Calif., Apple store on Friday, Feb. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)</span></div>
<p>"We can't wait for people to experience the <strong>magic</strong>," Apple chief Tim Cook said while discussing the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>The Vision Pro will also be among Apple's most costly products at $3,500. Many researchers say the high cost means the company might sell 1 million or fewer of the devices during its first year.</p>
<p>But even the iPhone was not extremely successful in its first year on the market. Apple only sold about 4 million iPhones back then. Now, the company sells more than 200 million of them each year.</p>
<p>If the Vision Pro succeeds, the term "spatial computing" might become popular.</p>
<p><strong>What is spatial computing? </strong></p>
<p>"Spatial computing" describes how the physical world and the <strong>virtual </strong>world of computers can work together.</p>
<p>Augmented reality (AR) and artificial intelligence (AI) are two areas of computing that help make spatial computing happen, said Cathy Hackl. She runs a new company that makes programs for the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>Hackl said, "Spatial computing will <strong>enable </strong>devices to understand the world in ways they never have been able to do before." She added that it is going to change the way humans and computers work together.</p>
<p>Apple says more than 600 newly designed programs, or apps, will be available to use on the headset right away. Apps will include television networks and video services although Netflix and Google's YouTube will not be available. Other apps will be for video games and educational services. Zoom and other companies that provide online meeting tools have built apps for the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>Vision Pro may worsen screen <strong>addiction</strong> that has only grown since the iPhone was released. It also might separate people from the real world and make them dependent on the technology.</p>
<p>Other technology companies are also working on spatial computing products. Google has been working on a video meeting product called Project Starline. It would make two people sitting in different cities feel like they are in the same room. But Starline has not been widely released. And Meta has sold the Quest headset for years. It could be considered a spatial computing device, but the company does not market it in that way.</p>
<p>The Vision Pro comes equipped with high-<strong>resolution</strong> screens that can play back <strong>three-dimensional </strong>video recordings of events and make it seem as though the event is happening again. Apple's high-priced iPhone models released in September can record what it calls "spatial video."</p>
<p>Apple's headset also reacts to a user's hand and eye movements in an attempt to make the device feel like it is part of the body. While wearing the device, users will be able to use their hands to move around and open different virtual computer screens.</p>
<p>Spatial computing "is a technology that's starting to <strong>adapt</strong> to the user instead of requiring the user adapting to the technology," Hackl said. "It's all supposed to be very natural."</p>
<p>However, it remains to be seen how natural it is to wear a headset while having dinner with another person instead of just looking at your phone from time to time.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Michael Liedtke reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>augmented reality </strong>– <em>n</em>. technology that adds to people's senses of what reality is</p>
<p><strong>magic </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very pleasant, attractive, or exciting quality</p>
<p><strong>virtual </strong><em>– adj. </em>existing or occurring on computers or on the Internet</p>
<p><strong>enable </strong><em>– v. </em>to make (someone or something) able to do or to be something</p>
<p><strong>addiction </strong><em>– n.</em> a strong and harmful need to regularly have something (such as a drug) or do something (such as gamble)</p>
<p><strong>resolution </strong><em>– n. </em>the ability of a device to show an image with a lot of detail</p>
<p><strong>three-dimensional </strong><em>– adj. </em>having or seeming to have length, width, and depth</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong><em>– v.</em> to change your behavior so that it is easier to live in a particular place or situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sea Otters Help Save California’s Wetlands  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/sea-otters-help-save-california-s-wetlands.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>At one point, it was nearly impossible to see sea otters along the west coast of the United States.</p>
<p>The animals were hunted nearly to <strong>extinction</strong> in the 1800s. People paid for their fur. At one point, only about 2,000 remained. Most lived in the waters off Alaska.</p>
<p>But by the 1980s, the animals started to recover. Three programs helped increase their population in northern California. First, hunters were banned from killing the otters. Next, an environmental program restored the wetlands where the otters once lived. And finally, California's Monterey Bay Aquarium began to raise otters and release them into the wild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sea otter is seen in the estuarine water of Elkhorn Slough, Monterey Bay, Calif., on Aug. 3, 2018. (Emma Levy via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/13c54096-f3ef-4ef8-94fc-7c620ea6e74b_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sea otter is seen in the estuarine water of Elkhorn Slough, Monterey Bay, Calif., on Aug. 3, 2018. (Emma Levy via AP)</span></div>
<p>For about 40 years, the animals have been back in the seaside area called Elkhorn Slough. It is between Monterey and San Francisco.</p>
<p>Brent Hughes is studying how the otters' return <strong>affected</strong> the environment. He is a marine ecologist at nearby Sonoma State University.</p>
<p>He recently published a report in the science journal <em>Nature</em>. Hughes and his team looked at a wetland area called a tidal estuary. The researchers found that the otters perform a service that keeps the area from eroding -- or wearing away.</p>
<p>Hughes said the otters feed on a destructive shellfish called the striped shore crab. The crabs dig into the mud and sand and bite the roots of a marsh grass known as pickleweed. Pickleweed holds the soil in place during coastal flooding.</p>
<p>The holes the crabs make cause the area to look like "Swiss cheese," Hughes said. Swiss cheese is a kind of cheese with many holes.</p>
<p>For the new study, researchers examined erosion rates dating back to the 1930s. The historical data help the researchers understand the effects of sea otters' return to the area.</p>
<p>The researchers also set up fences that prevented the otters from entering <strong>certain</strong> areas for three years. In the fenced-off section of the estuary, the scientists say the soil eroded much more quickly.</p>
<p>Hughes said the otters "don't completely reverse erosion but slow it down to natural levels."</p>
<p>The otter study is one of several research projects that follow what happens to an area when a top <strong>predator</strong> returns after a long period of time.</p>
<p>A famous past study looked at the return of gray wolves to Yellowstone National Park. The wolves hunted elk and moose that ate small trees along riverbanks. With fewer elk and moose, the trees started growing again and the riverbanks did not erode as quickly.</p>
<p>Something similar happened when the otters returned.</p>
<p>Johan Eklof is a Swedish marine biologist from Stockholm University who reviewed the study. Other studies, he noted, depended only on observation. But this new study leaves no doubt that the otters limit erosion.</p>
<p>Other studies show that otters can be helpful for plants. One study said the otters eat sea creatures called urchins that feed on kelp. The return of the otters permitted the kelp to grow again.</p>
<p>Brian Silliman is a coastal ecologist from Duke University in North Carolina. He co-wrote the new study. He described the otters as "amazing finders and eaters."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>–n.</em> the state or situation that results when something (such as a plant or animal species) has died out completely</p>
<p><strong>affect </strong><em>–v. </em>to produce an effect on something</p>
<p><strong>certain </strong><em>–n.</em> a known place or area</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong><em>–n.</em> an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Have you ever seen a sea otter up close? What did you think?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is 'Cozy Cardio?'  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-cozy-cardio.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new kind of exercise idea is becoming popular in the United States. Social media is bringing attention to "<strong>cozy</strong> cardio." It means doing light <strong>cardiovascular</strong> exercise at home.</p>
<p><strong>Physical inactivity and "cozy cardio" </strong></p>
<p>Physical inactivity is a problem in the United States. The most recent data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) says 25 percent of Americans reported they had not done any physical activity in the past month.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Hope Zuckerbrow, founder of the cozy cardio wellness movement, shows her workout set-up, including a walking pad, smoothie and remote control for watching television. (Hope Zuckerbrow via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3fb7ea5a-47ed-48a1-bd62-4854542b63e7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Hope Zuckerbrow, founder of the cozy cardio wellness movement, shows her workout set-up, including a walking pad, smoothie and remote control for watching television. (Hope Zuckerbrow via AP)</span></div>
<p>The CDC says that one in two American adults do not get enough cardiovascular exercise. Inactivity can have serious health effects. So, many Americans are looking to develop a new exercise<strong> habit</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Cozy cardio </strong></p>
<p>"Cozy cardio" has gained popularity as an easy and painless way to increase physical activity levels. This method of calorie burning has gained popularity on TikTok and Instagram ever since a woman named Hope Zuckerbrow began posting videos in late 2022.</p>
<p>Cozy cardio involves walking in place by using a small <strong>treadmill</strong> or "walking pad."</p>
<p>No <strong>gym</strong> payments are involved.</p>
<p>"I get so many messages from men and women – so many people – saying something along the lines of ‘thank you so much for...<strong>flipping</strong> my mindset on what I thought exercise is supposed to be,'" Zuckerbrow said. "This feels so doable."</p>
<p><strong>Building the habit </strong></p>
<p>Supporters say what is important about "cozy cardio" is the setup.</p>
<p>You wear comfortable clothes and organize your environment to your liking. You can light candles, have a healthy drink, or even put on a favorite TV show or movie.</p>
<p>Alex Montoye of Alma College said, for some people, easy exercise such as "cozy cardio" could help them develop an exercise habit.</p>
<p>Montoye said for people who would otherwise watch TV while sitting, walking can help them make progress. That is especially true if exercise becomes a habit.</p>
<p>People struggle to make healthy habits last over time. That is why<strong> </strong>cozy exercise is such a good idea, said Catherine Sanderson of Amherst College in Massachusetts. She wrote the health book, <em>The Positive Shift: Mastering Mindset to Improve Happiness, Health, and Longevity.</em></p>
<p>"It fits in with a lot of what we know about how to get people to actually maintain behavior change," Sanderson said.</p>
<p>Along with removing the barriers to exercise, she said, "It very much <strong>relies on</strong> what psychologists would call <strong>positive reinforcement</strong> — the idea of, 'It's not just that I'm exercising...I'm <strong>tapping into</strong> something I want to be doing already."</p>
<p>As cozy cardio becomes more popular, Zuckerbrow said she hears from people who did not realize they could enjoy easy exercise.</p>
<p>Alyssa Royse, owner of Rocket Community Fitness in Seattle, has been mixing workouts at her gym and cozy exercise at home. Some days she turns off the sound on her Peloton exercise bicycle and watches TV because it takes her "brain somewhere else."</p>
<p>"Too many people look at exercise as an all-or-nothing thing," Royse said. "It doesn't give people room to just be where they are today. And I think that's incredibly important."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Melissa Rayworth reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cozy </strong><em>– adj.</em> pleasant, warm</p>
<p><strong>cardiovascular</strong><em> –adj.</em> related to the heart and blood vessels in the body — especially exercises that cause the heart to beat faster</p>
<p><strong>habit</strong><em> – n.</em> something that a person does often in a regular and repeated way</p>
<p><strong>treadmill</strong> <em>– n.</em> an exercise machine which has a large belt that moves around while a person walks or runs on it</p>
<p><strong>gym</strong> <em>–n.</em> a building, often a business, that contains exercise equipment and space for activities and classes</p>
<p><strong>flip</strong> <em>–v. </em>to turn upside down</p>
<p><strong>rely on </strong><em>– phrasal verb </em>to need (someone or something) for support, help, etc.: to depend on (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>positive reinforcement</strong> –<em> n. (psychology)</em> the process of rewarding good behavior so that it is more likely to be repeated in the future</p>
<p><strong>tap into </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to make use of something; to get something of value from</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: US Workers Would Take Pay Cuts for Improved Quality of Life  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/study-us-workers-would-take-pay-cuts-for-improved-quality-of-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Just over half of U.S. workers would be willing to take a 20 percent pay cut in exchange for a better quality of life, a recent <strong>survey </strong>found.</p>
<p>Lynn Bufka is a clinical psychologist with ties to the American Psychological Association in Washington, D.C. "I do think people are really struggling <strong>figuring</strong> <strong>out</strong> what work-life balance is," she said. "And recognizing, certainly in parts of the U.S., that we have a drive to work and perform and succeed. And increasingly, we're realizing this isn't good for us."</p>
<p>Younger adults are even more in favor of giving up money for what they consider a better life, the survey found. Sixty percent of millennials, people aged 27 to 42, said they would accept less money for a better work-life balance. Fifty-six percent of Generation Z adults, people aged 18 up to 26, said the same thing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE -- A recent survey finds that 77% of respondents prioritize a balanced life over advancement at work." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-308c-08dc21c41b22_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE -- A recent survey finds that 77% of respondents prioritize a balanced life over advancement at work.</span></div>
<p>"These results don't surprise me," Julia Toothacre told VOA in an email. She is a job advisor at ResumeBuilder.com. "The younger generations have been very <strong>vocal</strong> about the need for balance in their life. It's important to note that it doesn't mean they are less <strong>ambitious</strong>. It just means they are looking for <strong>flexibility</strong>, and they aren't willing to sacrifice their health the way other generations have."</p>
<p>When it comes to older adults, 45 percent of Generation X, people aged 43 to 59, would take the 20 percent pay cut to get a better work-life balance. But only 33 percent of Baby Boomers, those aged 60 to 78, would do the same.</p>
<p>It is something that Toothacre has experienced in her work. She said many of her <strong>clients</strong> want some flexibility for life events and things like doctor's visits.</p>
<p>"Work-life balance is very important to my clients. Most of my clients come to me because they aren't happy in their current career, or they are looking for a more balanced and flexible career path," she said.</p>
<p>The survey was carried out by Ford Motor Company in August and September 2023 and included 16,086 online interviews with adults in 16 countries, including the United States. Seventy-seven percent of those surveyed say they believed a balanced life was more important than a higher-paying position at work.</p>
<p>"If our only definition of ourselves is what we do and our work, we are <strong>neglecting</strong>...our social sense of self, our spiritual sense of self," Bufka said.</p>
<p>There is also a <strong>practical</strong> side of work-life balance and the willingness to limit time worked in exchange for less money.</p>
<p>Bufka said people need time away from work to keep their households operating. If people feel like they do not have enough time, "there's always going to be a tension between the immediate demands of household and family, and work."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>survey </strong><em>— n. </em>a study in which people are asked their opinions about a subject</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>figure</strong> <strong>out </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to come to understand by thinking</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vocal </strong><em>— adj. </em>to say out loud or to say loudly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ambitious </strong>–adj. wanting to succeed or to do great things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>flexible </strong><em>— adj. </em>the ability to change what one has to do depending on the situation, often in an effort to make things better</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>client </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who pays someone else to assist them in doing something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>neglect </strong><em>— v. </em>to fail to do or take care of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>practical </strong><em>— adj. </em>something relating to real life and not to ideal situations or book learning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Schools Use Surveillance to Catch Students Vaping  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-schools-use-surveillance-to-catch-students-vaping.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Schools around the United States are<strong> installing</strong> sensors and cameras to identify possible use of <strong>vaping</strong> devices. Some administrators are also ordering serious punishments for use of the devices on school property.</p>
<p>Aaliyah Iglesias faced such punishment in her last year of high school in Texas. In February of 2023, school administrators caught her vaping in a bathroom.</p>
<p>Suddenly, so much of her high school experience was under threat: her student council presidency, her position as debate team captain and her planned attendance at the graduation ceremony in May.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A man uses a vape device in this illustration picture, September 19, 2019. (REUTERS/Adnan Abisi/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C622E5A8-B996-4003-BF85-7DCB241C63CE_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A man uses a vape device in this illustration picture, September 19, 2019. (REUTERS/Adnan Abisi/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>She even faced possible loss of her college <strong>scholarships</strong> as a result of violating the vaping rules. She was sent to the district's <strong>alternative </strong>school for 30 days and was told she could have faced criminal charges.</p>
<p>School observation equipment was used to catch Iglesias vaping. Many schools have installed the equipment without informing students.</p>
<p>Students found vaping can also be charged with a misdemeanor and fined up to $100. Students found with vapes containing THC, the chemical that makes marijuana users feel high, can be arrested on <strong>felony </strong>charges.</p>
<p>At least 90 students in the Tyler school system where Iglesias was a student have faced misdemeanor or felony charges.</p>
<p>School systems around the U.S. have invested millions of dollars in the observation, or surveillance, technology. Administrators have used federal COVID-19 emergency <strong>relief</strong> money to buy the equipment. Marketing materials have noted the sensors, at a cost of over $1,000 each, check air quality to help fight the virus.</p>
<p>Vapes are a major problem at many middle and high schools. The devices release vapor containing the highly <strong>addictive</strong> chemical, nicotine. Millions of minors report vaping despite efforts to limit sales to kids by raising the legal age to 21 and a ban on flavored products.</p>
<p>Some districts combine the sensors with surveillance cameras. When activated by a vaping sensor, those cameras turn on so violators might be identified.</p>
<p>The Tyler, Texas, schools, among others in America, have what they call a <strong>zero-tolerance</strong> policy on vaping. The school system says that tracking vape usage deals with a problem that is hurting children's health. It would not comment on punishments of students.</p>
<p>A leading provider, HALO Smart Sensors, sells 90 percent to 95 percent of its sensors to schools. The sensors do not have cameras or record audio but can detect increases in noise in a school bathroom and inform school officials of that immediately, said Rick Cadiz. He is vice president of sales and marketing for IPVideo, the maker of HALO sensors.</p>
<p>The sensors are marketed mainly for detecting vape smoke or THC. But they also can detect sounds like gunshots or words that are signs of possible bullying.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, HALO noted on its website that indoor air quality observation was an approved use for federal COVID relief money. Schools now also can use some of the almost $440 million vape maker Juul is paying to settle a legal action against it. The claim accused Juul of marketing its products to youth, Cadiz said.</p>
<p>"All it's doing is <strong> </strong> that something's going on," he said. "You need someone to physically investigate the alert that comes out."</p>
<p>At the Coppell Independent School District in Texas, sensors are part of a vaping prevention plan that includes educational videos and a tip line. Students can receive $50 for reporting on violators. Jennifer Villines, the district's director of student and staff services, said students "were turning each other in right and left."</p>
<p>Students can be sent to an alternative school or serve in-school suspensions but are not expelled for vaping, she said.</p>
<p>Iglesias' punishment included having to step down as student council president and debate captain and leaving the National Honor Society. At the alternative school where she spent a month, students do their studies without attending classes.</p>
<p>Iglesias was still able to attend her final school dance and graduation ceremony. Her college scholarship was not withdrawn, either. She now attends Tyler Junior College.</p>
<p>For her, the punishments for vaping go too far.</p>
<p>"The people that make these policies and<strong> implement</strong> these things sit in a room and do not walk the campuses or see the results," Iglesias said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>install </strong><em>— </em> <em>v. </em>to make ready to be used in a certain place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vape </strong><em>— </em> <em>v.</em> to inhale or exhale vapor produced by electronic cigarettes or similar devices</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scholarship </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that is given by a school, an organization, etc., to a student to help pay for the student's education</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>alternative </strong><em>— adj. </em>something that can be chosen instead of something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>felony </strong><em>— n. </em>a serious crime</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>relief </strong><em>— n. </em>things that are given to help people who are victims of a war, earthquake, flood, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>addictive </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing a strong and harmful need to regularly have or do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>zero-tolerance </strong><em>— adj. </em>a policy of giving the most severe punishment possible to every person who commits a crime or breaks a rule</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>implement </strong><em>— v. </em>to begin to do or use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Will AI Mean Death of Music or More Creativity?  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/will-ai-mean-death-of-music-or-more-creativity.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Inside a recording room at Queen Mary University of London, several researchers are working with new artificial intelligence (AI) tools. Their aim is to develop what they call the "new virtual worlds" of music.</p>
<p>Andrea Martonelli and Max Graf are among more than 30 doctoral students working with Mathieu Barthet, a senior lecturer in Digital Media. They are exploring the possibilities of computational creativity and generative AI. Generative AI is a term that describes technology tools designed to operate at human levels.</p>
<p>Together, the researchers have set up a futuristic studio where music meets <strong>cutting-edge</strong> technology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Andrea Martelloni, a PhD Student at the Queen Mary University of London, demonstrates the 'HITar', an AI-powered augmented guitar, at the 2024 National Association of Music Merchants (NAMM) trade show in Anaheim, California, U.S., January 25, 2024. (REUTERS/Jorge Garcia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4e9464e8-4152-4a42-811a-d76326390477_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Andrea Martelloni, a PhD Student at the Queen Mary University of London, demonstrates the 'HITar', an AI-powered augmented guitar, at the 2024 National Association of Music Merchants (NAMM) trade show in Anaheim, California, U.S., January 25, 2024. (REUTERS/Jorge Garcia)</span></div>
<p>Graf showed off a virtual instrument to reporters with the Reuters news agency. Graf calls the instrument Netz. Netz is played through an augmented-reality headset. Augmented-reality equipment combines the real world with computer-created content. The device Graf uses follows body movements to create musical sounds like notes and chords.</p>
<p>Martonelli played a HITar, a <strong>guitar</strong> with AI sensors added to it. The sensors can read his movements to create percussive, or drum-like, sounds. These sounds cannot be made with a normal guitar.</p>
<p>AI can be found in music-making dating back to the 1950s. But recent progress in generative AI has led to divided opinions on the technology.</p>
<p>Generative AI grew in popularity last year thanks to the ChatGPT language system. Generative AI can create new sounds, words for music or entire songs on its own. But artists usually use simpler AI to add to their sound.</p>
<p>British musician YUNGBLUD said he believes AI can help his music go "to another direction."</p>
<p>Other musicians worry that the technology could go too far. Amy Love plays in the English rock group Nova Twins. She said she is not in favor of music that includes artificially generated voices of actual artists. She said she feels the same way about using dead artists' voices in songs.</p>
<p>In November, the Beatles released the song "Now and Then." It is considered the group's last song and includes the voice of Beatles musician John Lennon, who died in 1980. Lennon's voice sounds were taken from an old recording and re-created with AI.</p>
<p>New York City-based entertainment company Warner Music said in November it was partnering with the <strong>estate </strong>of the late French singer Edith Piaf to re-create her voice using AI.</p>
<p>Many experts say AI raises legal and ethical concerns. But <strong>guidelines</strong> on generative AI are still only in their early stage.</p>
<p>Barthet said, "I think AI can have its place in the music production<strong> chain</strong>." But he added that is only possible if the technology is guided in the right way and if there are rules in place to make sure that musicians keep some amount of control.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Alessandro Parodi, Olivier Sorgho and Matt Stock reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cutting-edge </strong>– <em>n</em>. the newest and most advanced area of activity in an art or science</p>
<p><strong>guitar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a musical instrument that is held against the front of your body and that has usually six strings which are played with your fingers or with a pick</p>
<p><strong>estate </strong><em>– n. </em>the things left by someone who has died</p>
<p><strong>guideline </strong><em>– n.</em> a rule or instruction that shows or tells how something should be done</p>
<p><strong>chain </strong><em>– n. </em>a series of connected things or people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boeing Faces Another Manufacturing Delay Affecting 50 Planes  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/boeing-faces-another-manufacturing-delay-affecting-50-planes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Boeing announced this week that it was delaying the delivery of about 50 new planes to its customers because of a newly discovered manufacturing problem.</p>
<p>The American airplane company is under increased <strong>scrutiny</strong> after part of one of its latest 737 passenger airplanes blew open mid-flight in early January.</p>
<p>The unused door opening of an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 Max 9 blew out on January 5 as it took off from Portland, Oregon. The part is called a "door plug." It closes off a space that would normally have an emergency exit in it. The door plug permits air carriers to have a few more seats on the plane instead of the exit.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A worker walks past Boeing's new 737 MAX-9 under construction at their production facility in Renton, Washington on February 13, 2017. (REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ba1e1cf2-5bb1-4119-9bd8-5a0ffc061a38_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A worker walks past Boeing's new 737 MAX-9 under construction at their production facility in Renton, Washington on February 13, 2017. (REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>No one was hurt in the Alaska Airlines incident, but the plane suffered serious damage.</p>
<p>Investigators said <strong>bolts</strong> meant to secure the door plug were not tightened properly. Many airplanes owned by Alaska Airlines and United Airlines were prevented from flying as the panels were fixed. Most are now flying again.</p>
<p>The American Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) restricted the production of Max 9 planes until it is satisfied with Boeing's safety measures.</p>
<p>Now another problem has come up.</p>
<p>An employee of a company that makes parts for Boeing said some holes were not drilled correctly in the window <strong>frames</strong> of some Max jets.</p>
<p>That company, Spirit AeroSystems, is also being looked at in more detail after the Alaska Airlines incident. Its parts were used to secure the door that blew out in January.</p>
<p>One of Boeing's top leaders is Stan Deal. In a letter, Deal wrote that the company would have to "perform rework on about 50 <strong>undelivered</strong> planes," but it is not a safety problem for airplanes currently in use.</p>
<p>The continued problems caused the leader of another airline, Emirates, to criticize Boeing.</p>
<p>Tim Clark is the president of Emirates, a major airline based in Dubai. He noted a "progressive <strong>decline</strong>." He said the manufacturer must "<strong>instill</strong> a safety culture which is second to none," noting the company's leaders likely understand this is their last chance to regain lost confidence.</p>
<p>Both United Airlines and Alaska Airlines have expressed their anger at Boeing in recent weeks. United's leader, Scott Kirby, said it may consider purchasing planes from another manufacturer in the future.</p>
<p>The FAA said it is paying more attention to Boeing's large production center in Washington state. Jodi Baker is the agency's deputy associate administrator for <strong>aviation</strong> safety. Baker said the FAA plans to visit the factory and talk with employees who build the airplanes to find out about their concerns and the company's safety culture.</p>
<p>Because of the recent problems, Boeing said it would withdraw a request it made with the FAA. The company wanted permission to deliver a smaller version of the 737 MAX airplane before redesigning a system that prevents the build-up of ice on engine <strong>inlets</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scrutiny </strong>–n. the act of investigating or looking closely at something or someone</p>
<p><strong>bolt </strong>–n. a fastener which secures two pieces together using a screw</p>
<p><strong>frame </strong>–n. an outer structure that holds something else in</p>
<p><strong>undelivered </strong>–adj. something not given or sent to the person who ordered it</p>
<p><strong>decline </strong>–n. a decrease in height or quality</p>
<p><strong>instill </strong>–v. to cause something to be created over time through thoughtful effort</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong>–n. the industry of flight in the Earth's atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>inlet </strong>–n. an opening that leads into an engine</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you concerned about flying on planes made by Boeing?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>King Charles’ Cancer Was Caught Early  (2024/2/7) | 英国国王查尔斯确诊癌症</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/king-charles-cancer-was-caught-early.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>King Charles' cancer was caught early, British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said Tuesday. Sunak added that the nation is hopeful the king can make a full recovery.<br/>
英国首相里希·苏纳克周二表示，查尔斯国王的癌症在早期被发现。苏纳克补充说，全国人民都希望查尔斯国王能够完全康复。</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace officials announced on Monday that the 75-year-old king had a "form of cancer" and would postpone his public appearances to receive treatment.<br/>
白金汉宫官员周一宣布，这位75岁的国王患上了“某种癌症”，他将推迟公开露面去接受治疗。</p>
<p>The palace added that Charles was "wholly positive" and looking forward to returning to public work as soon as possible.<br/>
白金汉宫补充说，查尔斯“非常积极乐观”，并期待着尽快重返公共工作岗位。</p>
<p>Charles has been king for less than 18 months. He became king following the death of his mother Queen Elizabeth.<br/>
查尔斯当上国王还不到18个月。他在母亲伊丽莎白女王去世后成为了国王。</p>
<p>He is planning to continue his weekly meetings with the prime minister and dealing with state papers.<br/>
他计划继续每周与首相会面，并处理国家文件。</p>
<p>Charles' son, Prince William is first in line to the throne. He is expected to fill in for some of Charles' duties. His younger son Prince Harry, who has a troubled relationship with the family, arrived Tuesday from California to visit the king.<br/>
查尔斯的儿子威廉王子是王位的第一顺位继承人。预计他将接替查尔斯的一些职责。他的小儿子哈里王子星期二从加利福尼亚州过来看望国王。哈里王子与王室关系不佳。</p>
<p>Sunak said he had been "shocked and sad" at the news.<br/>
苏纳克表示，他对这一消息感到“震惊和悲伤”。</p>
<p>"All our thoughts are with him and his family. You know, thankfully, this has been caught early," Sunak told BBC radio.<br/>
苏纳克告诉BBC电台：“我们和国王以及他的家人同在。你知道，谢天谢地，这件事发现得早。”</p>
<p>Sunak said he was in regular contact with the king. "That will of course continue as normal," he said.<br/>
苏纳克表示，他与国王保持着定期联系。他说：“这当然会像往常一样继续下去。”</p>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden expressed his concern on Monday and said he planned to call the king later.<br/>
美国总统乔·拜登周一表达了关切，并表示他计划稍后致电国王。</p>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau wrote on the social media service X: "We're sending him our very best wishes – and hoping for a fast and full recovery."<br/>
加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多在社交媒体服务X上写道：“我们向他致以最良好的祝愿，并希望他能迅速完全康复。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Cancer discovery<br/>
发现癌症</span></p><p>The cancer was discovered recently when Charles stayed three nights in the hospital. At the time, he was undergoing a medical procedure for a non-cancerous enlarged prostate.<br/>
癌症是查尔斯最近在医院住了三个晚上才发现的。当时，他正在接受非癌性前列腺肥大的医疗手术。</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace officials have said he does not have prostate cancer. But they did not give any additional details about the kind of cancer the king has.<br/>
白金汉宫官员表示，他不是患前列腺癌症。但他们没有提供任何关于国王所患癌症的额外细节。</p>
<p>The British royal family usually keeps medical issues private. But the palace said Charles wanted to make his diagnosis public. He is a backer of several cancer-related charities.<br/>
英国王室通常对医疗问题保密。但王宫表示，查尔斯希望将自己的诊断结果公之于众。他是几个与癌症有关的慈善机构的支持者。</p>
<p>Charles' treatment will likely draw attention to the long waiting times for cancer patients under Britain's state-run National Health Service (NHS).<br/>
查尔斯的治疗可能会引起人们对癌症患者在英国国营国家医疗服务体系下漫长等待时间的关注。</p>
<p>Survival rates for cancer in Britain are lower than those of other European countries. A January NHS report shows that Britain is behind for nine out of 10 of the most common kinds of cancer.<br/>
英国癌症的存活率低于其他欧洲国家。英国国家医疗服务体系1月份的一份报告显示，在最常见的10种癌症中，英国有9种癌症的存活率落后。</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Damage atop Damage: ‘Atmospheric River’ Storms Strike California Again  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/damage-atop-damage-atmospheric-river-storms-strike-california-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In California, the second of back-to-back atmospheric rivers on Monday caused heavy rains and mudslides, flooded roadways and cut electric power.</p>
<p>Atmospheric rivers are long and wide areas, like a river, of water <strong>vapor</strong> in the atmosphere that form over an ocean. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.noaa.gov/stories/what-are-atmospheric-rivers">says</a> these weather systems carry as much water vapor as the average flow of water at the mouth of the Mississippi River. When atmospheric rivers make landfall, they often release this water vapor in the form of rain or snow.</p>
<p>Much of California was still drying out from the atmospheric river that blew in last week. Over the weekend, officials ordered people living in parts of California that burned in recent wildfires to evacuate. These areas are at high risk for wreckage flows.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An emergency worker helps a resident escape from danger after a mudslide, February 5, 2024, in the Beverly Crest area of Los Angeles, California. (AP Photo/Marcio Jose Sanchez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0867d26f-12cd-4ffe-a033-674074205a9a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An emergency worker helps a resident escape from danger after a mudslide, February 5, 2024, in the Beverly Crest area of Los Angeles, California. (AP Photo/Marcio Jose Sanchez)</span></div>
<p>About 1.4 million people living in the Los Angeles area, were under a flash flood warning Monday morning. Up to 23 centimeters of rain had already fallen in the area, with more expected, the National Weather Service predicts. It called the flash flooding and threat of mudslides, "a particularly dangerous situation."</p>
<p>Keki Mingus, from the Studio City area of Los Angeles, said that mud, rocks, and water came down through her neighborhood. Mingus said, "It looks like a river that's been here for years. I've never seen anything like it."</p>
<p><strong>Storm affects entire California coast</strong></p>
<p>The rains brought down trees and power lines Sunday in the San Francisco Bay Area. Winds in the northern area blew as fast as 95 kilometers an hour. In the mountains, they were even stronger with <strong>gusts</strong> reaching almost 130 kilometers an hour.</p>
<p>Palisades Tahoe is a skiing area about 320 kilometers northeast of San Francisco. The skiing area was expected to have the heaviest snowfall yet this season on Sunday, as much as 15 centimeters per hour for a total of up to 60 centimeters. Heavy snow is continuing into Monday throughout the Sierra Nevada and motorists were urged to avoid mountain roads.</p>
<p>Just to the south in San Jose, emergency crews rescued people from a car trapped by floodwaters. Other teams rescued people living beside a rising river.</p>
<p>For the Central Coast, the weather service issued a rare "<strong>hurricane</strong> force wind warning," with wind gusts of up to 148 kilometers an hour.</p>
<p>The storm then moved into Southern California, where officials warned of possible severe flooding. They ordered people to leave canyon areas where there were recent wildfires. Officials are concerned about the high risk of wreckage flows in those areas.</p>
<p>The latest atmospheric river storm is called a "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/pineapple-express.html">Pineapple Express</a>" because it stretches across the Pacific from almost as far as Hawaii.</p>
<p>"We've had flooding, we've had gusty winds, we've had the whole <strong>gamut</strong> here," said Todd Hall, a weather scientist with the National Weather Service near Los Angeles. Hall said he expects the heavy to moderate rain to continue in southern California until Tuesday.</p>
<p>California Governor Gavin Newsom has declared a state of emergency for most areas of the state. The Governor's Office of Emergency Services activated its operations center and deployed workers and equipment in areas most at risk.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver adapted this story for VOA Learning English from an Associated Press report.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gust</strong> – <em>n</em>. <strong> </strong>a sudden brief rush of wind</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gamut </strong>– <em>n. </em>an entire range or series</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>plume </strong>– <em>n. </em>something shaped like a feather</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>moisture </strong>– <em>n. </em>liquid diffused or condensed in relatively small quantity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surf </strong>– <em>n</em>. the swell of the sea that breaks upon the shore</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hurricane </strong>– <em>n</em>. <strong> </strong>a tropical storm with winds of 74 miles (119 kilometers) per hour or greater that is usually accompanied by rain, thunder, and lightning, and that sometimes moves into temperate latitudes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russian Cosmonaut Sets Record for Time in Space  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/russian-cosmonaut-sets-record-for-time-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Russia's space agency Roscosmos says cosmonaut Oleg Kononenko has broken the world record for total time spent in space.</p>
<p>Kononenko passed the record Sunday after spending more than 878 days and 12 hours in orbit aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>
<p>The previous record was set in 2015 by another cosmonaut, Gennady Padalka, who spent 878 days and 11 and a half hours in space.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - International Space Station (ISS) crew member Oleg Kononenko of Russia boards the Soyuz MS-11 spacecraft for launch at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, Kazakhstan December 3, 2018. (REUTERS/Shamil Zhumatov/Pool)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3f63-08dc2670000b_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - International Space Station (ISS) crew member Oleg Kononenko of Russia boards the Soyuz MS-11 spacecraft for launch at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, Kazakhstan December 3, 2018. (REUTERS/Shamil Zhumatov/Pool)</span></div>
<p>The 59-year-old Kononenko has so far made five trips to the ISS. The first one came in 2008.</p>
<p>Kononenko told Russia's state-supported news agency, TASS, that each trip he took to the ISS required careful preparation. This is because the orbiting space lab is always getting <strong>upgrades</strong>.</p>
<p>Kononenko said his repeated space trips represent the <strong>realization</strong> of a childhood dream to become a cosmonaut. "I fly into space to do what I love, not to set records," he told TASS.</p>
<p>He added that his continued interest in living and working in orbit "<strong>motivates</strong>" him to keep flying.</p>
<p>Kononenko's current trip to the ISS began on Sept. 15, 2023. He arrived along with American astronaut Loral O'Hara and cosmonaut Nikolai Chub.</p>
<p>Kononenko's service on the ISS is continuing. He is expected to reach a total of 1,000 days in space on June 5. His current flight is expected to end in late September. By then, he will have spent at least 1,110 days in space.</p>
<p>Kononenko said he worked out often aboard the ISS to help him deal with the physical effects of weightlessness.</p>
<p>He added that he realizes the social effects of his long stays on the ISS when he returns back to Earth.</p>
<p>"It is only upon returning home that the realization comes that, for hundreds of days in my <strong>absence,</strong> the children have been growing up without a papa," Kononenko said. "No one will return this time to me."</p>
<p>Kononenko noted that cosmonauts are now able to use video calls and messaging to stay in better touch with their family.</p>
<p>He said one of the most difficult things about being a cosmonaut is getting ready for each new space flight. "The profession of a cosmonaut is becoming more <strong>complicated</strong>," Kononenko said. "The systems and experiments are becoming more complicated."</p>
<p>The ISS is one of only a few areas where the United States and Russia still closely cooperate after Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Roscosmos announced in December that its program with the American space agency NASA to transport astronauts to the ISS had been extended until 2025.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– v.</em> to improve the quality or usefulness of something</p>
<p><strong>realization </strong><em>– n. </em>the process of noticing or understanding something that you did not notice or understand before</p>
<p><strong>motivate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone want to do something</p>
<p><strong>absence </strong><em>– n. </em>not being in a particular place</p>
<p><strong>complicated </strong><em>– adj. </em>complex or difficult to understand</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South America Dengue Increase Brings Vaccination Drive  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-america-dengue-increase-brings-vaccination-drive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health &amp; Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>During the southern hemisphere summer, South America is experiencing a sharp increase in cases of dengue, a mosquito-<strong>borne</strong> disease common in much of Latin America.</p>
<p>The <strong>symptoms</strong>, or signs, of dengue are high fever, extreme tiredness, muscle pain, and internal bleeding. In Brazil, dengue is often called "breakbone fever" for the severe joint pain it causes. Sometimes, people with the disease show no symptoms. But dengue can be deadly.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Health workers spray insecticide to kill mosquitos. This is to help slow a dengue outbreak in Brasilia, Brazil, on January 24, 2024. (REUTERS/Adriano Machado)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7709-08dc1ea1ac10_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Health workers spray insecticide to kill mosquitos. This is to help slow a dengue outbreak in Brasilia, Brazil, on January 24, 2024. (REUTERS/Adriano Machado)</span></div>
<p><strong>New dengue vaccine</strong></p>
<p>In Brazil, officials plan to start a new dengue vaccine campaign. The program, which could begin within days, will make Brazil the first country in the world to offer dengue vaccine.</p>
<p>In January, Brazil also started spraying <strong>insecticide</strong> from trucks as the disease spread to earlier unaffected areas. Because of the increase in dengue cases, hospitals in Paraguay have set up health centers at night to care for the sick.</p>
<p>In 2023, cases of dengue have set record highs in Latin America. Health official records show Argentina with a sharp increase of 12,500 cases of dengue last December. It is a big jump compared with the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The increase has led to health warnings and shortages of insect <strong>repellent</strong>.</p>
<p>"Repellent sold out everywhere, there were <strong>literal</strong> clouds of mosquitoes," Laura Ledesma told Reuters from Argentina's capital of Buenos Aires. She added that there were signs the situation had begun to improve.</p>
<p><strong>Weather changes are affecting the spread of disease</strong></p>
<p>Scientists say the spread of dengue, in South America and other areas, is worsened by rising temperatures and the El Nino weather pattern in the Pacific. Both events also add to a longer dengue season.</p>
<p>"Climate change has expanded the range for mosquitoes to <strong>breed</strong>, both in the Americas and <strong>globally</strong>," Thais dos Santos told Reuters. He specializes in insect-borne diseases at the Pan American Health Organization, or PAHO for short.</p>
<p>PAHO information shows 4.2 million cases of dengue and 2,050 deaths in the Americas last year. Much of that was in the so-called "Southern Cone" of South America.</p>
<p>The December-February southern summer months bring hot and <strong>humid</strong> conditions for mosquitoes to breed.<strong> </strong>This helps to spread the possibly deadly disease.</p>
<p>Recently, people in Brasilia lined up outside medical centers set up to test for dengue. Dengue cases in the Brazilian capital have increased by as much as 646 percent in the first 20 days of January compared with last year.</p>
<p>Nelson Diego, 37, tested <strong>positive</strong> for dengue in the Brasilia neighborhood of Recanto das Emas where spraying has started. He said he was suffering from muscle pain and extreme tiredness from the disease, though some days were more difficult than others.</p>
<p>"Today is one of the better days because I can still open my eyes," he said. "I have a lot of pain in my joints and couldn't walk before."</p>
<p>And that's the Health &amp; Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Lucinda Elliott in Montevideo and Ricardo Brito in Brasilia reported this story for Reuters news agency. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>borne</strong> <em>– adj.</em> transported or transmitted by —used in combination such as air<em>borne</em></p>
<p><strong>symptom </strong><em>– n. </em>a change in a living thing that indicates the presence of a disease or other physical disorder, especially : one (as a headache) that can be felt or sensed only by the individual affected</p>
<p><strong>insecticide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical used to kill insects</p>
<p><strong>repellent </strong><em>– n. </em>serving or tending to drive away or ward off : often used in combination — insect <em>repellent</em></p>
<p><strong>literal </strong><em>– adj. </em>following the ordinary or usual meaning of the words</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce (plants or animals) by sexual reproduction</p>
<p><strong>globally </strong><em>– adv. </em>of, relating to, or involving the entire world</p>
<p><strong>humid </strong><em>– adj. </em>damp, moist</p>
<p><strong>positive </strong><em>– adj. </em>having a test result indicating the presence especially of a condition, substance, or organism</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift, Women Win Big at Grammy Music Awards  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/taylor-swift-women-win-big-at-grammy-music-awards.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>American pop singer and songwriter Taylor Swift won Album of the Year for <em>Midnights</em>" on Sunday at the Grammy Awards.</p>
<p>She has now won that award four times, breaking the record for wins in that <strong>category</strong>. Frank Sinatra, Paul Simon, and Stevie Wonder each won the award three times.</p>
<p>An album is a collection of songs on a single recording.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Taylor Swift accepts the award for album of the year for MIdnights during the 66th annual Grammy Awards on Sunday, Feb. 4, 2024, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1da6-08dc267be82c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Taylor Swift accepts the award for album of the year for "MIdnights" during the 66th annual Grammy Awards on Sunday, Feb. 4, 2024, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)</span></div>
<p>"For me, the award is the work," Swift said. "All I want to do is keep doing it."</p>
<p>Earlier, when receiving another Grammy, for Best Pop Vocal Album for <em>Midnights</em>, she shared a surprise. She announced that her new album, <em>The Tortured Poets Department</em>, will be released April 19.</p>
<p><strong>Women lead the awards</strong></p>
<p>Women earned the biggest awards and gave the majority of the performances on the American television broadcast.</p>
<p>Of the eight nominees for Song of the Year, seven were performed by women.</p>
<p>Billie Eilish's song from the movie <em>Barbie</em>, <em>What Was I Made For?</em> won Song of the Year for her and co-writer Finneas O'Connell, her brother.</p>
<p>Miley Cyrus won Record of the Year for her song <em>Flowers</em>. The record of the year recognizes the best-sounding recording of a particular song. <em>Flowers</em> also earned Cyrus the award for Best Pop Solo performance.</p>
<p>Solána Imani Rowe, known professionally as SZA, won for best R&amp;B song, <em>Snooze</em>. R&amp;B stands for rhythm and blues. SZA also won for Best Pop Duo/group Performance for <em>Ghost in the Machine</em> with Phoebe Bridgers.</p>
<p>Rock group boygenius, whose three members are women and include Bridgers, won Best Rock Song and Best Rock Performance for their song <em>Not Strong Enough</em>. The group also won a Grammy for Alternative Album of the Year. Their album is simply named <em>The Record</em>.</p>
<p>Victoria Monét won the Grammy for Best New Artist. But it has taken her years of work to become a successful performer.</p>
<p>"Thanks to my mom, a single mom raising this really bad girl," said Monét when she received her award. Then she started to cry, adding that this award was "15 years in the making."</p>
<p>Karol G of Colombia become the first female performer to win Best Música Urbana Album for <em>Ma<i>&amp;#</i>241;ana Será Bonito</em>.</p>
<p><strong>New awards</strong></p>
<p>The Grammys added three new categories this year: African Music Performance, Alternative Jazz Album, and Pop Dance Recording. Women were the winners in each of them.</p>
<p>South African singer Tyla won the African music performance Grammy for her hit song, <em>Water</em>.</p>
<p>"I never thought I'd say I won a Grammy at 21 years old," she said in her acceptance speech. "Last year, God decided to change my whole life."</p>
<p>Meshell Ndegeocello, an American singer-songwriter, rapper, and bass player, won Best Alternative Jazz Album.</p>
<p>And Kylie Minogue of Australia won Best Pop Dance Recording for her hit <em>Padam Padam</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Rap</strong></p>
<p>Rapper Killer Mike won three awards Sunday, his first since winning a Grammy in 2003. He won Best Rap Performance for <em>Scientists &amp; Engineers</em>, which featured André 3000, Future and Eryn Allen Kane. The performers won for Best Rap Song for the same song. Killer Mike also received the award for Best Rap Album, for <em>Michael</em>.</p>
<p>Jay-Z won the Dr. Dre Global Impact Award. Jay-Z has won 24 Grammys and has been nominated 88 times. He spoke about the times that rap artists did not get enough attention from the Grammys, although they sold lots of recordings.</p>
<p>Jay-Z's wife, Beyoncé, has won 32 Grammys, more than any other artist. Because she has won so many, Jay-Z thinks it is unfair that she has never won album of the year. "Think about that. The most Grammys, never won album of the year. That doesn't work," Jay-Z said.</p>
<p>"When I get nervous, I tell the truth," he added.</p>
<p><strong>From young to old</strong></p>
<p>The awards show included performers both young and old. American pop singer and songwriter Olivia Rodrigo, aged 20, was nominated for six Grammys, including top awards such as Song of the Year and Album of the Year.</p>
<p>Singer and songwriter Joni Mitchell, aged 80, won for Best Folk Album. It was her eleventh Grammy win. She performed <em>Both Sides Now</em> from her 1969 album <em>Clouds</em>. Mitchell suffered a brain <strong>aneurysm</strong> in 2015 and has had to relearn how to walk and speak.</p>
<p>American singer and songwriter Billy Joel, 74, ended the awards show with two performances. First, he played his new song <em>Turn the Lights Back On</em>. It is his first pop music release since 1993. Later, he played his 1980 hit, <em>You May Be Right</em>.</p>
<p>The first Grammy Awards show was held in 1959. The awards now include 94 categories.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>category </strong>–n. a group of things that are considered similar and are subject to the same kind of consideration</p>
<p><strong>aneurysm </strong>–n. an abnormal and dangerous expansion of a blood vessel that can bleeding</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA's Mars Helicopter Ends Service after 'History-making' Mission  (2024/2/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/nasa-s-mars-helicopter-ends-service-after-history-making-mission.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>NASA's experimental helicopter, Ingenuity, has officially ended its service on Mars after what the U.S. space agency called a "history-making" <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>Ingenuity arrived on Mars with NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover, in February 2021. The experimental helicopter has completed many test flights on the Red Planet to support NASA's efforts to build new aircraft that can fly in the atmospheres of other planets.</p>
<p>Ingenuity became the first aircraft to complete a powered, controlled flight on another planet in April 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-05e9-08dbf1ebe005_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)</span></div>
<p>At first, NASA described Ingenuity as a demonstration mission that was expected to last about one month. The aircraft aimed to test flight on Mars, including taking off, flying short distances and landing. The helicopter quickly demonstrated its abilities during a series of tests.</p>
<p>In May 2021, NASA officially extended Ingenuity's experimental mission. In total, the helicopter performed 72 flights on Mars, the space agency said. The aircraft flew 14 times farther than planned and completed more than two hours of total flight time.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/after-three-years-on-mars-nasas-ingenuity-helicopter-mission-ends/">praised</a> Ingenuity as "the little helicopter that could." He noted that officials were surprised with each new flight progression.</p>
<p>But Nelson noted that because of damage to a <strong>rotor</strong>, the helicopter had finally taken its last flight. "The historic <strong>journey</strong> of Ingenuity, the first aircraft on another planet, has come to (an) end," he said.</p>
<p>Nelson added that mission controllers discovered during an attempt by Ingenuity to land that at least one of the aircraft's rotor <strong>blades</strong> had been damaged. The damage is currently being investigated, but the NASA chief said the blade might have struck the ground during the landing attempt.</p>
<p>NASA said Ingenuity rose to 12 meters on its final flight last week, staying in the air for a few seconds before heading back down. Most flights only last a few minutes because the helicopter has energy and temperature limitations.</p>
<p>Nelson said the helicopter was able to fly effectively in the thin Martian atmosphere. But he noted that additional progress showed the aircraft "far <strong>exceeded</strong> what we thought possible."</p>
<p>Ingenuity's mission, Nelson, said, had opened the door to "future flight in our solar system and smarter, safer human exploration to Mars and beyond."</p>
<p>After Ingenuity performed well in flight tests, NASA decided to expand the helicopter's mission to assist Perseverance with its rover operations. This change officially turned the aircraft's mission into an "operations demonstration."</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/after-three-years-on-mars-nasas-ingenuity-helicopter-mission-ends/">reports</a> Ingenuity helped to identify additional exploration areas for Perseverance. Both the rover and helicopter have been collecting data and images while exploring an area known as Jezero Crater. The goal is to search for signs of ancient life on Mars.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/zjt3DMNqtus?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p>NASA noted that Ingenuity had helped map a path from above to help Perseverance take on new exploration activities. Flight controllers on the ground have been collecting data on all of Ingenuity's operations. They said this data will be valuable in helping NASA design future aircraft for Mars.</p>
<p>The success of the helicopter mission led the space agency in 2022 to approve the development of two small helicopters to be deployed on future missions.</p>
<p>While Ingenuity continued its operational mission, teams on the ground <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-continues-mars-helicopter-experiments-tests-new-design-on-earth/7379281.html">experimented</a> with new rotor blades. During ground tests completed last year, engineers reported the rotor blades had reached speeds nearly equal to Mach 1, the speed of sound.</p>
<p>The blades tested on Earth are made of carbon. They are more than 10 centimeters longer than Ingenuity's and are designed to be stronger and to move faster. NASA has said the rotor blades are designed to support bigger, more complex helicopters.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA, The Associated Press and Reuters. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>the flight of a spacecraft to perform a certain task or job</p>
<p><strong>rotor blade </strong><em>– n. </em>thin, flat pieces of material that spin to make aircraft lift off the ground and travel</p>
<p><strong>journey </strong><em>– n. </em>the act of traveling from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>exceed </strong><em>– v. </em>to go over a particular number or amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
