<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Has Earth Warmed More Than We Thought?  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/has-earth-warmed-more-than-we-thought.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Old <strong>sponges</strong> from deep in the Caribbean Sea are causing some researchers to think human-caused climate change began sooner than scientists have thought. But, if a recent study is correct, world temperatures are increasing faster than United Nations' estimates suggest.</p>
<p>The researchers from American and Australian universities published their sponge findings recently in <em>Nature Climate Change</em>. They said, if their findings are correct, the world has already gone past a temperature limit set by international negotiators. Negotiators of the Paris Agreement on climate change set 1.5 degrees Celsius as a limit for the increase of the world's temperature from pre-industrial times. Pre-industrial times are from about 1850 to 1900. But the American and Australian researchers said that the world hit a 1.7-degree Celsius increase in 2020.</p>
<p>The scientists looked at six special sponges that are known to live hundreds of years. They examined the sponges' growth records to find very small levels of the elements calcium and strontium. The scientists said that the amount of calcium and strontium changes, depending on the water temperature.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by Amos Winter shows a sponge from the Caribbean. (Courtesy of Amos Winter via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c18768da-84d9-40d7-98ad-aeeda9f1a1c1_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by Amos Winter shows a sponge from the Caribbean. (Courtesy of Amos Winter via AP)</span></div>
<p>Malcolm McCulloch is an ocean scientist at the University of Western Australia. He was the lead writer of the study. McCulloch noted that the currently accepted temperature estimates for the 1850-1900 period were too high. That means that present-day temperature increases are larger and the Earth's temperature is warming faster than scientists have believed. He said, "We have a <strong>decade</strong> less than we thought."</p>
<p>In the past several years, many scientists have noted that there seems to be more extreme weather than they had expected. One explanation would be that the Earth is warming faster than scientists had first believed, said Amos Winter.</p>
<p>Winter helped write the study. He is an ocean scientist at Indiana State University. He said the study supports the theory that climate change is quickening. Former top NASA scientist James Hansen also has proposed that theory.</p>
<p>Sponges get water flowing from all over them so they can record a larger area of environmental change, Winter and McCulloch said. The research team examined sponges that lived in a special "mixed" area of the ocean that is 33 to 91 meters deep. The researchers were able to estimate nearly the exact atmospheric temperature of the Earth from the amount of calcium and strontium in the deep-sea sponges.</p>
<p>Their results were different from the scientifically accepted temperature estimates used by the United Nations' Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). The IPCC temperature estimates are the basis for the U.N. temperature goals.</p>
<p>The <em>Nature Climate Change</em> study finds that the mid-1800s were about half a degree Celsius cooler than believed. It also found that warming from heat-trapping gases started about 80 years earlier than the measurements the IPCC uses. IPCC numbers show warming started just after 1900.</p>
<p>McCulloch and Winter said it makes sense that the warming started earlier than the IPCC stated because by the mid-1800s industries had begun polluting the air with carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>For pre-industrial temperatures, the IPCC and most scientists use data that came from ships whose crews would take the temperature of water near the surface. Some of the measurements could change based on how the collection was done.</p>
<p>The researchers said sponges provide better information because of the way they store chemical elements in their skeletons. When waters are warmer, there is more of the element strontium and less of the mineral calcium, Winter said.</p>
<p>University of Pennsylvania climate scientist Michael Mann, who was not part of the study, has thought warming started before the IPCC said it did. But he doubted the study's findings.</p>
<p>"In my view it <strong>begs credulity</strong> to claim that the instrumental record is wrong based on <strong>paleo-</strong>sponges from one <strong>region</strong> of the world," Mann said.</p>
<p>But Winter and McCulloch have defended their use of sponges to identify world temperature change. They said, except for the 1800s, their temperature findings based on sponges follow global records from other devices. These include scientific instruments and measurements from things like coral, ice, and tree rings.</p>
<p>Princeton University climate scientist Michael Oppenheimer was not part of the sponge study either. He said, even if the McCulloch team is right, it should not change warnings from scientists. He said that the danger level is not tied to the exact "value of preindustrial temperatures."</p>
<p>McCulloch added that "...the only way to stop this is to reduce <strong>emissions</strong>. Urgently. Most Urgently.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gregory Stachel adapted this Associated Press story by Seth Borenstein for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sponge </strong>– <em>n</em>. a type of sea animal from which natural sponges are made</p>
<p><strong>decade </strong>– <em>n</em>. a period of 10 years</p>
<p><strong>beg </strong>– <em>v</em>. to cause someone to ask a specified question as a reaction or response</p>
<p><strong>credulity </strong><em>– n. </em>ability or willingness to believe something</p>
<p><strong>paleo- </strong><em>– prefix</em> connected with ancient times</p>
<p><strong>region </strong><em>– n. </em>a part of a country or of the world that is different or separate from other parts in some way</p>
<p><strong>emission </strong><em>– n.</em> a gas, such as carbon dioxide, that is sent out or produced by a process like burning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Private Missions Launch Debate over What to Permit on Moon  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/private-missions-launch-debate-over-what-to-permit-on-moon.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The rise in private American space <strong>missions</strong> has led to increasing calls for rules on what can be transported to the moon.</p>
<p>Individuals and groups have criticized plans by private companies to send things that might not be suitable for the lunar surface.</p>
<p>The proposals came from companies that have contracts with the American space agency NASA to provide space flight services and carry equipment and supplies to the moon. Such materials launched from rockets are known as payloads.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration created by the European Space Agency (ESA) shows how a future moon base could be set up, with structures built with 3D printer technology. Industrial partners including architectural company Foster+Partners joined ESA to test the possibi" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/659CF0FF-3DE8-4912-9E21-BCBDE59C624A_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration created by the European Space Agency (ESA) shows how a future moon base could be set up, with structures built with 3D printer technology. Industrial partners including architectural company Foster+Partners joined ESA to test the possibi</span></div>
<p>The efforts are part of NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Services (CLPS) program. It aims to hand over the nation's major space missions to private companies in an effort to reduce costs.</p>
<p>The CLPS program plans to send several landers to the moon in the coming years. The landers will be carrying instruments and exploring tools to help humans learn more about the moon and its surroundings. But some missions also plan on sending human remains or goods that could be used in advertising.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Leslie Tennen is a lawyer who specializes in international space law. She told Reuters news agency, "We're just at the beginning of exploring the moon, and...we need to be careful we're not <strong>contaminating</strong> it." She said she thinks care should be taken to prevent the spread of what she calls "<strong>litter</strong>" on the moon.</p>
<p>Last month, one privately-built lunar lander aimed to touch down on the surface of the moon. But the spacecraft, called Peregrine, developed a fuel leak shortly after launch and did not make it to the moon.</p>
<p>The company that built Peregrine is Astrobotic Technology, of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The lander was loaded with 20 research experiments involving seven different countries. But it also carried other materials. These included numerous containers of human remains, a piece of rock from Mount Everest, a physical bitcoin and a can of the Japanese sports drink Pocari Sweat.</p>
<p>Among the remains were ashes of famous space lovers Gene Roddenberry and Arthur C. Clarke. Roddenberry was creator of the popular television show <em>Star Trek</em> and Clarke was a science fiction writer.</p>
<p>The Navajo Nation had sought to stop Peregrine's launch because of the inclusion of the remains. The head of the Native American group called the sending of remains a "<strong>desecration</strong>" because his people consider the moon a holy space.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Astrobotic said the objections to Peregrine's launch came too late to reach an agreement on the issue. But the company said it would try to find "a good path forward" with the Navajo Nation on future missions.</p>
<p>Reuters reports that under U.S. law, materials can be transported to the moon as long as they do not violate certain general guidelines set by the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).</p>
<p>The FAA requires companies to show that a payload launched from Earth does not "<strong>jeopardize</strong> public health and safety...U.S. national security...or international <strong>obligations</strong>" of the U.S. This rule permits most materials to be sent to the moon.</p>
<p>But legal experts think the issue will likely gain more attention as more private missions make successful landings on the lunar surface. And this could lead to new legal restrictions on what can be transported to the moon.</p>
<p>Lawyers with space-law experience worry that the absence of rules could lead to disputes between U.S. companies and other nations seeking to operate on the lunar surface. There could also be disagreements over which businesses should be permitted to claim land or <strong>sovereignty</strong>.</p>
<p>The current guidelines for international activities on the moon are included in a document called the 1967 <a class="wsw__a" href="https://2009-2017.state.gov/t/isn/5181.htm">Outer Space Treaty</a>. It states that outer space – including the moon and other bodies<strong> </strong>– "shall be free for exploration and use by all states." The treaty also states that nations involved in space exploration must approve of and <strong>supervise</strong> the activities of non-government organizations.</p>
<p>Experts say few nations have approved their own rules for moon behavior and measures are currently unclear in international law. This has led to calls for new international guidelines.</p>
<p>Martha Mejía-Kaiser is a Mexican-German space lawyer and a board member of the International Institute of Space Law. She told Reuters, "We are already late, and we are very urgently in need to start now, to discuss the moon at an international level."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n.</em> to do something considered very difficult or impossible</p>
<p><strong>contaminate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make something dirty or poisonous</p>
<p><strong>litter </strong><em>– n. </em>things left in an area that makes the area seem dirty <strong>desecrate </strong><em>– v. </em>to damage or show a lack of respect toward something holy or highly respected</p>
<p><strong>jeopardize </strong><em>– v. </em>to put something in danger</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>– n. </em>something a person does because it is their duty or because they feel they have to</p>
<p><strong>sovereignty </strong><em>– n. </em>the power of a country to control its own government</p>
<p><strong>supervise </strong><em>– v. </em>to watch over a person or activity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Dong Tao Chicken, Food of Choice for Lunar New Year  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/dong-tao-chicken-food-of-choice-for-lunar-new-year.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Dong Tao chicken has been a food of choice for generations in Vietnam for the Lunar New Year, or Tet.</p>
<p>The rare bird is known for its strangely large feet. It is also known as a "dragon chicken." The chicken gets its name from the village of Dong Tao, about 30 kilometers southeast of Hanoi.</p>
<p>Dong Tao chickens are believed to bring good luck and wealth to their owners. At one point, they were only bred to serve meat for the royal families and officials.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Baby Dong Tao chickens, also known as Dragon Chicken, are seen at Dong Tao village, in Hung Yen province, Vietnam, on January 31, 2024. (REUTERS/Minh Nguyen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ef2d-08dc28bc1356_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Baby Dong Tao chickens, also known as "Dragon Chicken," are seen at Dong Tao village, in Hung Yen province, Vietnam, on January 31, 2024. (REUTERS/Minh Nguyen)</span></div>
<p>Today, demand for Dong Tao chicken in Vietnam has risen sharply. That demand comes from a growing number of wealthy people in one of Asia's fastest-growing economies.</p>
<p>Le Trong Dung is a chicken farmer in the village of Dong Tao. He told Reuters that a fully-grown Dong Tao chicken at one year old sells for $200 and sometimes as much as $400.</p>
<p>The demand for Dong Tao chicken is also fueled by its rich taste.</p>
<p>Loc Duc Toan is a 25-year-old cook in Hanoi. Toan said a Dong Tao chicken has its best taste at the age of 13 to 15 months. "When steamed, the skin will be crispy with a <strong>fragrant</strong> <strong>aroma</strong> of its own and a sweeter meat compared to other normal chicken," Toan said.</p>
<p>Nguyen Thi Hong Nhung is a chicken farmer, She said the most valuable parts of Dong Tao chickens are its legs.</p>
<p>Their large legs make it difficult for them to hatch from their eggs. Sometimes, they can accidentally break their eggs.</p>
<p>It takes about a year to raise a Dong Tao chicken, compared to three months for other kinds.</p>
<p>The chickens are now also raised beyond the village of Dong Tao. That means more people may have the chance to buy a Dong Tao chicken. But Phan Van Hieu, a Dong Tao agriculture official, said chickens raised in the village and fed with its native rice and corn have the best taste.</p>
<p>"Production hasn't met <strong>domestic</strong> demand yet," Hieu added. "I'm sure you won't find any Dong Tao chicken in any KFC restaurants in [the] foreseeable future."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on Reuters news report.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fragrant</strong> - adj. having a pleasant and usually sweet smell</p>
<p><strong>aroma</strong> - n. an usually please smell</p>
<p><strong>domestic</strong> - adj. relating to your own country</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Ways to Say 'Goodbye'  (2024/2/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/ways-to-say-goodbye.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>It is never easy to say goodbye, but at least in English, we have many ways to do so. For my final <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, I want to share the many ways to say goodbye in English.</p>
<p>There are polite or <strong>formal</strong> ways. There are also ways we can say goodbye in everyday conversation, including fun <strong>slang</strong> that you can use.</p>
<p>"Goodbye" is believed to have come from the expression, "God be with ye," about 500 years ago. "Ye" is an old form of "you." Over time "God" became "good." Today, the expression is for wishing someone well when you are leaving.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-e99c-08dc275bec53_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>"Goodbye" is probably the most common way to say this. Shorter forms include "bye" and "bye-bye." If you enjoy the 1990's pop band, NSYNC, you can say: "Bye Bye Bye!"</p>
<p><em>"It might sound </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/crazy-and-insane/6514528.html"><em>crazy</em></a><em> but it ain't no lie</em></p>
<p><em>Baby, bye bye bye"</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p><strong>In formal conversation</strong></p>
<p>When you part with someone and you want to wish them a good time, you can use this general structure:</p>
<p>Have + a + adjective + period of time:</p>
<p><em>Have a good night! </em></p>
<p><em>Have a wonderful weekend! </em></p>
<p><em>Have a nice day.</em></p>
<p>"Have" is in the imperative form of the verb. The imperative form gives instructions, directions or commands. Imperative sentences use the base form of the verb.</p>
<p>If parting ways with someone during the nighttime, we combine "good" with "night" to wish someone a "goodnight." We use this expression usually when going to sleep at night.</p>
<p><em>I always say "goodnight" to everyone in my house before bedtime.</em></p>
<p>We use other command forms in formal settings to say "goodbye."</p>
<p>"Take care (of yourself)" is meant to wish someone physical or emotional health.</p>
<p>If we have enjoyed our time with someone we can say:</p>
<p><em>It was a pleasure speaking with you.</em></p>
<p>It + form of "be" in present or past tense + article and noun or adjective + gerund + (with) you.</p>
<p><em>It was great seeing you this weekend. </em></p>
<p>We can also say that we "look forward to" seeing or speaking with someone. This expression suggests hope for the future.</p>
<p><em>I look forward to our next meeting.</em></p>
<p><em>I look forward to seeing you then.</em></p>
<p><em>I look forward to speaking with you.</em></p>
<p>Shorter forms of this expression include a sentence with "will."</p>
<p><em>I will see you then. </em></p>
<p><em>See you then!</em></p>
<p><em>Speak to you then!</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>In everyday conversation</strong></p>
<p>When speaking with friends and family, you can use informal ways to communicate leaving.</p>
<p>Shorter forms like "see you" are said even more conversationally when "you" becomes "ya" in fast speech. We can combine the expression with an adverb to say when we will see someone in the future.</p>
<p><em>See you soon!</em></p>
<p><em>See ya' later.</em></p>
<p><em>See ya' around! </em></p>
<p><em>Catch you later.</em></p>
<p><em>Catch ya' later.</em></p>
<p>To express a similar meaning, we can use a prepositional phrase with "until." There is no subject or object. Just the preposition is used.</p>
<p>Until + time expression</p>
<p><em>Until then.</em></p>
<p><em>Until Tuesday! </em></p>
<p><em>Until next week! </em></p>
<p>If you need to quickly leave, you can use these expressions. "Gotta" is a contraction that is used in everyday speech.</p>
<p><em>I've got to go.</em></p>
<p><em>I've gotta go.</em></p>
<p><em>I'm heading off.</em></p>
<p>If you want someone to connect with you in the future, you can use these:</p>
<p><em>Don't be a stranger.</em></p>
<p><em>Keep in touch!</em></p>
<p>If someone is leaving you on a trip, you can wish them a safe journey:</p>
<p><em>Have a safe trip!</em></p>
<p><em>Drive safely. </em></p>
<p><em>Drive safe!</em></p>
<p><em>Safe travels!</em></p>
<p>Note that in "drive safe," "safe" is, what is sometimes called, a "flat" adverb. These are older adverb forms in English that do not use the -ly ending. Phrases "sleep tight" or "go slow" are examples.</p>
<p>Another expression that uses a flat adverb is "take it easy."</p>
<p>And lastly, if you must leave quickly, you can use the expression:</p>
<p><em>I've got to hit the road. </em></p>
<p><em>I gotta hit the road.</em></p>
<p>We often use it when we are going to drive somewhere, but we can use it for other means of travel.</p>
<p><strong>Slang</strong></p>
<p>Finally, we have a few slang words that are used very informally in speech, especially by some groups of people. Slang is often spoken by young people and is generational, meaning that each new generation has its own slang. Remember, using slang is very informal and not a good idea in groups of people who are of several different age groups.</p>
<p>From the expression "see you later," we get the one-word slang expression "later." You can use this word by itself or with the person's name.</p>
<p><em>Later!</em></p>
<p><em>Later, John! </em></p>
<p>We also have the expression:</p>
<p><em>I'm out of here. </em></p>
<p>We can make this even more informal by shortening "out of" to "outta."</p>
<p><em>I'm outta here.</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/g7nnpxLZpCQ?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p>One of my favorite expressions was often heard in 1990's and early 2000's hip hop music: "bounce."</p>
<p>According to <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=bounce">Urban Dictionary</a>, to "bounce" means to leave and go somewhere else better or quickly.</p>
<p>A song by Destiny's Child, "Say My Name," uses this expression:</p>
<p><em>See you gotta bounce</em></p>
<p><em>When two seconds ago</em></p>
<p><em>You said you just got in the house</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/sQgd6MccwZc?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we talked about different expressions we can use to say "goodbye." Many "goodbye" expressions in both formal and everyday language use the imperative form. We also looked at some fun slang words for "goodbye."</p>
<p>I wanted to thank our audience for the past two years here at VOA Learning English. This might not be "goodbye," maybe it is just "see ya later!"</p>
<p>Take care,</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm John Russel.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>formal </strong>– <em>adj</em>. language that is used for serious or official writing and speaking</p>
<p><strong>slang </strong>– <em>n</em>. a word or expression that is not standard usage, is considered very informal and is usually used by people of a certain age group or ethnic background</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple: Vision Pro Headset Enables ‘Spatial Computing’  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/apple-says-its-new-vision-pro-headset-enables-spatial-computing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Technology company Apple's new computing device, the Vision Pro headset, became available in stores last week.</p>
<p>The device uses <strong>augmented reality</strong> technology which has been available for years. But Apple calls the technology "spatial computing." The device is worn on the head over the eyes.</p>
<p>Apple hopes the Vision Pro will be as popular as the iPhone, Apple's cellphone that came out in 2007.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Scott Joachim tries out an Apple Vision Pro headset during the first day of sales at a Palo Alto, Calif., Apple store on Friday, Feb. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e3ec4095-7811-43ca-8a2c-752b33effc05_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Scott Joachim tries out an Apple Vision Pro headset during the first day of sales at a Palo Alto, Calif., Apple store on Friday, Feb. 2, 2024. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)</span></div>
<p>"We can't wait for people to experience the <strong>magic</strong>," Apple chief Tim Cook said while discussing the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>The Vision Pro will also be among Apple's most costly products at $3,500. Many researchers say the high cost means the company might sell 1 million or fewer of the devices during its first year.</p>
<p>But even the iPhone was not extremely successful in its first year on the market. Apple only sold about 4 million iPhones back then. Now, the company sells more than 200 million of them each year.</p>
<p>If the Vision Pro succeeds, the term "spatial computing" might become popular.</p>
<p><strong>What is spatial computing? </strong></p>
<p>"Spatial computing" describes how the physical world and the <strong>virtual </strong>world of computers can work together.</p>
<p>Augmented reality (AR) and artificial intelligence (AI) are two areas of computing that help make spatial computing happen, said Cathy Hackl. She runs a new company that makes programs for the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>Hackl said, "Spatial computing will <strong>enable </strong>devices to understand the world in ways they never have been able to do before." She added that it is going to change the way humans and computers work together.</p>
<p>Apple says more than 600 newly designed programs, or apps, will be available to use on the headset right away. Apps will include television networks and video services although Netflix and Google's YouTube will not be available. Other apps will be for video games and educational services. Zoom and other companies that provide online meeting tools have built apps for the Vision Pro.</p>
<p>Vision Pro may worsen screen <strong>addiction</strong> that has only grown since the iPhone was released. It also might separate people from the real world and make them dependent on the technology.</p>
<p>Other technology companies are also working on spatial computing products. Google has been working on a video meeting product called Project Starline. It would make two people sitting in different cities feel like they are in the same room. But Starline has not been widely released. And Meta has sold the Quest headset for years. It could be considered a spatial computing device, but the company does not market it in that way.</p>
<p>The Vision Pro comes equipped with high-<strong>resolution</strong> screens that can play back <strong>three-dimensional </strong>video recordings of events and make it seem as though the event is happening again. Apple's high-priced iPhone models released in September can record what it calls "spatial video."</p>
<p>Apple's headset also reacts to a user's hand and eye movements in an attempt to make the device feel like it is part of the body. While wearing the device, users will be able to use their hands to move around and open different virtual computer screens.</p>
<p>Spatial computing "is a technology that's starting to <strong>adapt</strong> to the user instead of requiring the user adapting to the technology," Hackl said. "It's all supposed to be very natural."</p>
<p>However, it remains to be seen how natural it is to wear a headset while having dinner with another person instead of just looking at your phone from time to time.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Michael Liedtke reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>augmented reality </strong>– <em>n</em>. technology that adds to people's senses of what reality is</p>
<p><strong>magic </strong>– <em>n</em>. a very pleasant, attractive, or exciting quality</p>
<p><strong>virtual </strong><em>– adj. </em>existing or occurring on computers or on the Internet</p>
<p><strong>enable </strong><em>– v. </em>to make (someone or something) able to do or to be something</p>
<p><strong>addiction </strong><em>– n.</em> a strong and harmful need to regularly have something (such as a drug) or do something (such as gamble)</p>
<p><strong>resolution </strong><em>– n. </em>the ability of a device to show an image with a lot of detail</p>
<p><strong>three-dimensional </strong><em>– adj. </em>having or seeming to have length, width, and depth</p>
<p><strong>adapt </strong><em>– v.</em> to change your behavior so that it is easier to live in a particular place or situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Sea Otters Help Save California’s Wetlands  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/sea-otters-help-save-california-s-wetlands.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>At one point, it was nearly impossible to see sea otters along the west coast of the United States.</p>
<p>The animals were hunted nearly to <strong>extinction</strong> in the 1800s. People paid for their fur. At one point, only about 2,000 remained. Most lived in the waters off Alaska.</p>
<p>But by the 1980s, the animals started to recover. Three programs helped increase their population in northern California. First, hunters were banned from killing the otters. Next, an environmental program restored the wetlands where the otters once lived. And finally, California's Monterey Bay Aquarium began to raise otters and release them into the wild.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sea otter is seen in the estuarine water of Elkhorn Slough, Monterey Bay, Calif., on Aug. 3, 2018. (Emma Levy via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/13c54096-f3ef-4ef8-94fc-7c620ea6e74b_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sea otter is seen in the estuarine water of Elkhorn Slough, Monterey Bay, Calif., on Aug. 3, 2018. (Emma Levy via AP)</span></div>
<p>For about 40 years, the animals have been back in the seaside area called Elkhorn Slough. It is between Monterey and San Francisco.</p>
<p>Brent Hughes is studying how the otters' return <strong>affected</strong> the environment. He is a marine ecologist at nearby Sonoma State University.</p>
<p>He recently published a report in the science journal <em>Nature</em>. Hughes and his team looked at a wetland area called a tidal estuary. The researchers found that the otters perform a service that keeps the area from eroding -- or wearing away.</p>
<p>Hughes said the otters feed on a destructive shellfish called the striped shore crab. The crabs dig into the mud and sand and bite the roots of a marsh grass known as pickleweed. Pickleweed holds the soil in place during coastal flooding.</p>
<p>The holes the crabs make cause the area to look like "Swiss cheese," Hughes said. Swiss cheese is a kind of cheese with many holes.</p>
<p>For the new study, researchers examined erosion rates dating back to the 1930s. The historical data help the researchers understand the effects of sea otters' return to the area.</p>
<p>The researchers also set up fences that prevented the otters from entering <strong>certain</strong> areas for three years. In the fenced-off section of the estuary, the scientists say the soil eroded much more quickly.</p>
<p>Hughes said the otters "don't completely reverse erosion but slow it down to natural levels."</p>
<p>The otter study is one of several research projects that follow what happens to an area when a top <strong>predator</strong> returns after a long period of time.</p>
<p>A famous past study looked at the return of gray wolves to Yellowstone National Park. The wolves hunted elk and moose that ate small trees along riverbanks. With fewer elk and moose, the trees started growing again and the riverbanks did not erode as quickly.</p>
<p>Something similar happened when the otters returned.</p>
<p>Johan Eklof is a Swedish marine biologist from Stockholm University who reviewed the study. Other studies, he noted, depended only on observation. But this new study leaves no doubt that the otters limit erosion.</p>
<p>Other studies show that otters can be helpful for plants. One study said the otters eat sea creatures called urchins that feed on kelp. The return of the otters permitted the kelp to grow again.</p>
<p>Brian Silliman is a coastal ecologist from Duke University in North Carolina. He co-wrote the new study. He described the otters as "amazing finders and eaters."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>–n.</em> the state or situation that results when something (such as a plant or animal species) has died out completely</p>
<p><strong>affect </strong><em>–v. </em>to produce an effect on something</p>
<p><strong>certain </strong><em>–n.</em> a known place or area</p>
<p><strong>predator </strong><em>–n.</em> an animal that lives by killing and eating other animals</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Have you ever seen a sea otter up close? What did you think?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is 'Cozy Cardio?'  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-cozy-cardio.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new kind of exercise idea is becoming popular in the United States. Social media is bringing attention to "<strong>cozy</strong> cardio." It means doing light <strong>cardiovascular</strong> exercise at home.</p>
<p><strong>Physical inactivity and "cozy cardio" </strong></p>
<p>Physical inactivity is a problem in the United States. The most recent data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) says 25 percent of Americans reported they had not done any physical activity in the past month.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Hope Zuckerbrow, founder of the cozy cardio wellness movement, shows her workout set-up, including a walking pad, smoothie and remote control for watching television. (Hope Zuckerbrow via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3fb7ea5a-47ed-48a1-bd62-4854542b63e7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Hope Zuckerbrow, founder of the cozy cardio wellness movement, shows her workout set-up, including a walking pad, smoothie and remote control for watching television. (Hope Zuckerbrow via AP)</span></div>
<p>The CDC says that one in two American adults do not get enough cardiovascular exercise. Inactivity can have serious health effects. So, many Americans are looking to develop a new exercise<strong> habit</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Cozy cardio </strong></p>
<p>"Cozy cardio" has gained popularity as an easy and painless way to increase physical activity levels. This method of calorie burning has gained popularity on TikTok and Instagram ever since a woman named Hope Zuckerbrow began posting videos in late 2022.</p>
<p>Cozy cardio involves walking in place by using a small <strong>treadmill</strong> or "walking pad."</p>
<p>No <strong>gym</strong> payments are involved.</p>
<p>"I get so many messages from men and women – so many people – saying something along the lines of ‘thank you so much for...<strong>flipping</strong> my mindset on what I thought exercise is supposed to be,'" Zuckerbrow said. "This feels so doable."</p>
<p><strong>Building the habit </strong></p>
<p>Supporters say what is important about "cozy cardio" is the setup.</p>
<p>You wear comfortable clothes and organize your environment to your liking. You can light candles, have a healthy drink, or even put on a favorite TV show or movie.</p>
<p>Alex Montoye of Alma College said, for some people, easy exercise such as "cozy cardio" could help them develop an exercise habit.</p>
<p>Montoye said for people who would otherwise watch TV while sitting, walking can help them make progress. That is especially true if exercise becomes a habit.</p>
<p>People struggle to make healthy habits last over time. That is why<strong> </strong>cozy exercise is such a good idea, said Catherine Sanderson of Amherst College in Massachusetts. She wrote the health book, <em>The Positive Shift: Mastering Mindset to Improve Happiness, Health, and Longevity.</em></p>
<p>"It fits in with a lot of what we know about how to get people to actually maintain behavior change," Sanderson said.</p>
<p>Along with removing the barriers to exercise, she said, "It very much <strong>relies on</strong> what psychologists would call <strong>positive reinforcement</strong> — the idea of, 'It's not just that I'm exercising...I'm <strong>tapping into</strong> something I want to be doing already."</p>
<p>As cozy cardio becomes more popular, Zuckerbrow said she hears from people who did not realize they could enjoy easy exercise.</p>
<p>Alyssa Royse, owner of Rocket Community Fitness in Seattle, has been mixing workouts at her gym and cozy exercise at home. Some days she turns off the sound on her Peloton exercise bicycle and watches TV because it takes her "brain somewhere else."</p>
<p>"Too many people look at exercise as an all-or-nothing thing," Royse said. "It doesn't give people room to just be where they are today. And I think that's incredibly important."</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Melissa Rayworth reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cozy </strong><em>– adj.</em> pleasant, warm</p>
<p><strong>cardiovascular</strong><em> –adj.</em> related to the heart and blood vessels in the body — especially exercises that cause the heart to beat faster</p>
<p><strong>habit</strong><em> – n.</em> something that a person does often in a regular and repeated way</p>
<p><strong>treadmill</strong> <em>– n.</em> an exercise machine which has a large belt that moves around while a person walks or runs on it</p>
<p><strong>gym</strong> <em>–n.</em> a building, often a business, that contains exercise equipment and space for activities and classes</p>
<p><strong>flip</strong> <em>–v. </em>to turn upside down</p>
<p><strong>rely on </strong><em>– phrasal verb </em>to need (someone or something) for support, help, etc.: to depend on (someone or something)</p>
<p><strong>positive reinforcement</strong> –<em> n. (psychology)</em> the process of rewarding good behavior so that it is more likely to be repeated in the future</p>
<p><strong>tap into </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to make use of something; to get something of value from</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: US Workers Would Take Pay Cuts for Improved Quality of Life  (2024/2/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/study-us-workers-would-take-pay-cuts-for-improved-quality-of-life.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Just over half of U.S. workers would be willing to take a 20 percent pay cut in exchange for a better quality of life, a recent <strong>survey </strong>found.</p>
<p>Lynn Bufka is a clinical psychologist with ties to the American Psychological Association in Washington, D.C. "I do think people are really struggling <strong>figuring</strong> <strong>out</strong> what work-life balance is," she said. "And recognizing, certainly in parts of the U.S., that we have a drive to work and perform and succeed. And increasingly, we're realizing this isn't good for us."</p>
<p>Younger adults are even more in favor of giving up money for what they consider a better life, the survey found. Sixty percent of millennials, people aged 27 to 42, said they would accept less money for a better work-life balance. Fifty-six percent of Generation Z adults, people aged 18 up to 26, said the same thing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE -- A recent survey finds that 77% of respondents prioritize a balanced life over advancement at work." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-308c-08dc21c41b22_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE -- A recent survey finds that 77% of respondents prioritize a balanced life over advancement at work.</span></div>
<p>"These results don't surprise me," Julia Toothacre told VOA in an email. She is a job advisor at ResumeBuilder.com. "The younger generations have been very <strong>vocal</strong> about the need for balance in their life. It's important to note that it doesn't mean they are less <strong>ambitious</strong>. It just means they are looking for <strong>flexibility</strong>, and they aren't willing to sacrifice their health the way other generations have."</p>
<p>When it comes to older adults, 45 percent of Generation X, people aged 43 to 59, would take the 20 percent pay cut to get a better work-life balance. But only 33 percent of Baby Boomers, those aged 60 to 78, would do the same.</p>
<p>It is something that Toothacre has experienced in her work. She said many of her <strong>clients</strong> want some flexibility for life events and things like doctor's visits.</p>
<p>"Work-life balance is very important to my clients. Most of my clients come to me because they aren't happy in their current career, or they are looking for a more balanced and flexible career path," she said.</p>
<p>The survey was carried out by Ford Motor Company in August and September 2023 and included 16,086 online interviews with adults in 16 countries, including the United States. Seventy-seven percent of those surveyed say they believed a balanced life was more important than a higher-paying position at work.</p>
<p>"If our only definition of ourselves is what we do and our work, we are <strong>neglecting</strong>...our social sense of self, our spiritual sense of self," Bufka said.</p>
<p>There is also a <strong>practical</strong> side of work-life balance and the willingness to limit time worked in exchange for less money.</p>
<p>Bufka said people need time away from work to keep their households operating. If people feel like they do not have enough time, "there's always going to be a tension between the immediate demands of household and family, and work."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>survey </strong><em>— n. </em>a study in which people are asked their opinions about a subject</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>figure</strong> <strong>out </strong><em>–v. (phrasal)</em> to come to understand by thinking</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vocal </strong><em>— adj. </em>to say out loud or to say loudly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ambitious </strong>–adj. wanting to succeed or to do great things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>flexible </strong><em>— adj. </em>the ability to change what one has to do depending on the situation, often in an effort to make things better</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>client </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who pays someone else to assist them in doing something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>neglect </strong><em>— v. </em>to fail to do or take care of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>practical </strong><em>— adj. </em>something relating to real life and not to ideal situations or book learning</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Schools Use Surveillance to Catch Students Vaping  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-schools-use-surveillance-to-catch-students-vaping.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Schools around the United States are<strong> installing</strong> sensors and cameras to identify possible use of <strong>vaping</strong> devices. Some administrators are also ordering serious punishments for use of the devices on school property.</p>
<p>Aaliyah Iglesias faced such punishment in her last year of high school in Texas. In February of 2023, school administrators caught her vaping in a bathroom.</p>
<p>Suddenly, so much of her high school experience was under threat: her student council presidency, her position as debate team captain and her planned attendance at the graduation ceremony in May.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A man uses a vape device in this illustration picture, September 19, 2019. (REUTERS/Adnan Abisi/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C622E5A8-B996-4003-BF85-7DCB241C63CE_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A man uses a vape device in this illustration picture, September 19, 2019. (REUTERS/Adnan Abisi/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>She even faced possible loss of her college <strong>scholarships</strong> as a result of violating the vaping rules. She was sent to the district's <strong>alternative </strong>school for 30 days and was told she could have faced criminal charges.</p>
<p>School observation equipment was used to catch Iglesias vaping. Many schools have installed the equipment without informing students.</p>
<p>Students found vaping can also be charged with a misdemeanor and fined up to $100. Students found with vapes containing THC, the chemical that makes marijuana users feel high, can be arrested on <strong>felony </strong>charges.</p>
<p>At least 90 students in the Tyler school system where Iglesias was a student have faced misdemeanor or felony charges.</p>
<p>School systems around the U.S. have invested millions of dollars in the observation, or surveillance, technology. Administrators have used federal COVID-19 emergency <strong>relief</strong> money to buy the equipment. Marketing materials have noted the sensors, at a cost of over $1,000 each, check air quality to help fight the virus.</p>
<p>Vapes are a major problem at many middle and high schools. The devices release vapor containing the highly <strong>addictive</strong> chemical, nicotine. Millions of minors report vaping despite efforts to limit sales to kids by raising the legal age to 21 and a ban on flavored products.</p>
<p>Some districts combine the sensors with surveillance cameras. When activated by a vaping sensor, those cameras turn on so violators might be identified.</p>
<p>The Tyler, Texas, schools, among others in America, have what they call a <strong>zero-tolerance</strong> policy on vaping. The school system says that tracking vape usage deals with a problem that is hurting children's health. It would not comment on punishments of students.</p>
<p>A leading provider, HALO Smart Sensors, sells 90 percent to 95 percent of its sensors to schools. The sensors do not have cameras or record audio but can detect increases in noise in a school bathroom and inform school officials of that immediately, said Rick Cadiz. He is vice president of sales and marketing for IPVideo, the maker of HALO sensors.</p>
<p>The sensors are marketed mainly for detecting vape smoke or THC. But they also can detect sounds like gunshots or words that are signs of possible bullying.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, HALO noted on its website that indoor air quality observation was an approved use for federal COVID relief money. Schools now also can use some of the almost $440 million vape maker Juul is paying to settle a legal action against it. The claim accused Juul of marketing its products to youth, Cadiz said.</p>
<p>"All it's doing is <strong> </strong> that something's going on," he said. "You need someone to physically investigate the alert that comes out."</p>
<p>At the Coppell Independent School District in Texas, sensors are part of a vaping prevention plan that includes educational videos and a tip line. Students can receive $50 for reporting on violators. Jennifer Villines, the district's director of student and staff services, said students "were turning each other in right and left."</p>
<p>Students can be sent to an alternative school or serve in-school suspensions but are not expelled for vaping, she said.</p>
<p>Iglesias' punishment included having to step down as student council president and debate captain and leaving the National Honor Society. At the alternative school where she spent a month, students do their studies without attending classes.</p>
<p>Iglesias was still able to attend her final school dance and graduation ceremony. Her college scholarship was not withdrawn, either. She now attends Tyler Junior College.</p>
<p>For her, the punishments for vaping go too far.</p>
<p>"The people that make these policies and<strong> implement</strong> these things sit in a room and do not walk the campuses or see the results," Iglesias said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>install </strong><em>— </em> <em>v. </em>to make ready to be used in a certain place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vape </strong><em>— </em> <em>v.</em> to inhale or exhale vapor produced by electronic cigarettes or similar devices</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scholarship </strong><em>— n. </em>an amount of money that is given by a school, an organization, etc., to a student to help pay for the student's education</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>alternative </strong><em>— adj. </em>something that can be chosen instead of something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>felony </strong><em>— n. </em>a serious crime</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>relief </strong><em>— n. </em>things that are given to help people who are victims of a war, earthquake, flood, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>addictive </strong><em>— adj. </em>causing a strong and harmful need to regularly have or do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>zero-tolerance </strong><em>— adj. </em>a policy of giving the most severe punishment possible to every person who commits a crime or breaks a rule</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>implement </strong><em>— v. </em>to begin to do or use</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Will AI Mean Death of Music or More Creativity?  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/will-ai-mean-death-of-music-or-more-creativity.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Inside a recording room at Queen Mary University of London, several researchers are working with new artificial intelligence (AI) tools. Their aim is to develop what they call the "new virtual worlds" of music.</p>
<p>Andrea Martonelli and Max Graf are among more than 30 doctoral students working with Mathieu Barthet, a senior lecturer in Digital Media. They are exploring the possibilities of computational creativity and generative AI. Generative AI is a term that describes technology tools designed to operate at human levels.</p>
<p>Together, the researchers have set up a futuristic studio where music meets <strong>cutting-edge</strong> technology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Andrea Martelloni, a PhD Student at the Queen Mary University of London, demonstrates the 'HITar', an AI-powered augmented guitar, at the 2024 National Association of Music Merchants (NAMM) trade show in Anaheim, California, U.S., January 25, 2024. (REUTERS/Jorge Garcia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4e9464e8-4152-4a42-811a-d76326390477_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Andrea Martelloni, a PhD Student at the Queen Mary University of London, demonstrates the 'HITar', an AI-powered augmented guitar, at the 2024 National Association of Music Merchants (NAMM) trade show in Anaheim, California, U.S., January 25, 2024. (REUTERS/Jorge Garcia)</span></div>
<p>Graf showed off a virtual instrument to reporters with the Reuters news agency. Graf calls the instrument Netz. Netz is played through an augmented-reality headset. Augmented-reality equipment combines the real world with computer-created content. The device Graf uses follows body movements to create musical sounds like notes and chords.</p>
<p>Martonelli played a HITar, a <strong>guitar</strong> with AI sensors added to it. The sensors can read his movements to create percussive, or drum-like, sounds. These sounds cannot be made with a normal guitar.</p>
<p>AI can be found in music-making dating back to the 1950s. But recent progress in generative AI has led to divided opinions on the technology.</p>
<p>Generative AI grew in popularity last year thanks to the ChatGPT language system. Generative AI can create new sounds, words for music or entire songs on its own. But artists usually use simpler AI to add to their sound.</p>
<p>British musician YUNGBLUD said he believes AI can help his music go "to another direction."</p>
<p>Other musicians worry that the technology could go too far. Amy Love plays in the English rock group Nova Twins. She said she is not in favor of music that includes artificially generated voices of actual artists. She said she feels the same way about using dead artists' voices in songs.</p>
<p>In November, the Beatles released the song "Now and Then." It is considered the group's last song and includes the voice of Beatles musician John Lennon, who died in 1980. Lennon's voice sounds were taken from an old recording and re-created with AI.</p>
<p>New York City-based entertainment company Warner Music said in November it was partnering with the <strong>estate </strong>of the late French singer Edith Piaf to re-create her voice using AI.</p>
<p>Many experts say AI raises legal and ethical concerns. But <strong>guidelines</strong> on generative AI are still only in their early stage.</p>
<p>Barthet said, "I think AI can have its place in the music production<strong> chain</strong>." But he added that is only possible if the technology is guided in the right way and if there are rules in place to make sure that musicians keep some amount of control.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Alessandro Parodi, Olivier Sorgho and Matt Stock reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>cutting-edge </strong>– <em>n</em>. the newest and most advanced area of activity in an art or science</p>
<p><strong>guitar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a musical instrument that is held against the front of your body and that has usually six strings which are played with your fingers or with a pick</p>
<p><strong>estate </strong><em>– n. </em>the things left by someone who has died</p>
<p><strong>guideline </strong><em>– n.</em> a rule or instruction that shows or tells how something should be done</p>
<p><strong>chain </strong><em>– n. </em>a series of connected things or people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Boeing Faces Another Manufacturing Delay Affecting 50 Planes  (2024/2/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/boeing-faces-another-manufacturing-delay-affecting-50-planes.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Boeing announced this week that it was delaying the delivery of about 50 new planes to its customers because of a newly discovered manufacturing problem.</p>
<p>The American airplane company is under increased <strong>scrutiny</strong> after part of one of its latest 737 passenger airplanes blew open mid-flight in early January.</p>
<p>The unused door opening of an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 Max 9 blew out on January 5 as it took off from Portland, Oregon. The part is called a "door plug." It closes off a space that would normally have an emergency exit in it. The door plug permits air carriers to have a few more seats on the plane instead of the exit.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A worker walks past Boeing's new 737 MAX-9 under construction at their production facility in Renton, Washington on February 13, 2017. (REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ba1e1cf2-5bb1-4119-9bd8-5a0ffc061a38_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A worker walks past Boeing's new 737 MAX-9 under construction at their production facility in Renton, Washington on February 13, 2017. (REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>No one was hurt in the Alaska Airlines incident, but the plane suffered serious damage.</p>
<p>Investigators said <strong>bolts</strong> meant to secure the door plug were not tightened properly. Many airplanes owned by Alaska Airlines and United Airlines were prevented from flying as the panels were fixed. Most are now flying again.</p>
<p>The American Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) restricted the production of Max 9 planes until it is satisfied with Boeing's safety measures.</p>
<p>Now another problem has come up.</p>
<p>An employee of a company that makes parts for Boeing said some holes were not drilled correctly in the window <strong>frames</strong> of some Max jets.</p>
<p>That company, Spirit AeroSystems, is also being looked at in more detail after the Alaska Airlines incident. Its parts were used to secure the door that blew out in January.</p>
<p>One of Boeing's top leaders is Stan Deal. In a letter, Deal wrote that the company would have to "perform rework on about 50 <strong>undelivered</strong> planes," but it is not a safety problem for airplanes currently in use.</p>
<p>The continued problems caused the leader of another airline, Emirates, to criticize Boeing.</p>
<p>Tim Clark is the president of Emirates, a major airline based in Dubai. He noted a "progressive <strong>decline</strong>." He said the manufacturer must "<strong>instill</strong> a safety culture which is second to none," noting the company's leaders likely understand this is their last chance to regain lost confidence.</p>
<p>Both United Airlines and Alaska Airlines have expressed their anger at Boeing in recent weeks. United's leader, Scott Kirby, said it may consider purchasing planes from another manufacturer in the future.</p>
<p>The FAA said it is paying more attention to Boeing's large production center in Washington state. Jodi Baker is the agency's deputy associate administrator for <strong>aviation</strong> safety. Baker said the FAA plans to visit the factory and talk with employees who build the airplanes to find out about their concerns and the company's safety culture.</p>
<p>Because of the recent problems, Boeing said it would withdraw a request it made with the FAA. The company wanted permission to deliver a smaller version of the 737 MAX airplane before redesigning a system that prevents the build-up of ice on engine <strong>inlets</strong>.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scrutiny </strong>–n. the act of investigating or looking closely at something or someone</p>
<p><strong>bolt </strong>–n. a fastener which secures two pieces together using a screw</p>
<p><strong>frame </strong>–n. an outer structure that holds something else in</p>
<p><strong>undelivered </strong>–adj. something not given or sent to the person who ordered it</p>
<p><strong>decline </strong>–n. a decrease in height or quality</p>
<p><strong>instill </strong>–v. to cause something to be created over time through thoughtful effort</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong>–n. the industry of flight in the Earth's atmosphere</p>
<p><strong>inlet </strong>–n. an opening that leads into an engine</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you concerned about flying on planes made by Boeing?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>King Charles’ Cancer Was Caught Early  (2024/2/7) | 英国国王查尔斯确诊癌症</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/king-charles-cancer-was-caught-early.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>King Charles' cancer was caught early, British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said Tuesday. Sunak added that the nation is hopeful the king can make a full recovery.<br/>
英国首相里希·苏纳克周二表示，查尔斯国王的癌症在早期被发现。苏纳克补充说，全国人民都希望查尔斯国王能够完全康复。</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace officials announced on Monday that the 75-year-old king had a "form of cancer" and would postpone his public appearances to receive treatment.<br/>
白金汉宫官员周一宣布，这位75岁的国王患上了“某种癌症”，他将推迟公开露面去接受治疗。</p>
<p>The palace added that Charles was "wholly positive" and looking forward to returning to public work as soon as possible.<br/>
白金汉宫补充说，查尔斯“非常积极乐观”，并期待着尽快重返公共工作岗位。</p>
<p>Charles has been king for less than 18 months. He became king following the death of his mother Queen Elizabeth.<br/>
查尔斯当上国王还不到18个月。他在母亲伊丽莎白女王去世后成为了国王。</p>
<p>He is planning to continue his weekly meetings with the prime minister and dealing with state papers.<br/>
他计划继续每周与首相会面，并处理国家文件。</p>
<p>Charles' son, Prince William is first in line to the throne. He is expected to fill in for some of Charles' duties. His younger son Prince Harry, who has a troubled relationship with the family, arrived Tuesday from California to visit the king.<br/>
查尔斯的儿子威廉王子是王位的第一顺位继承人。预计他将接替查尔斯的一些职责。他的小儿子哈里王子星期二从加利福尼亚州过来看望国王。哈里王子与王室关系不佳。</p>
<p>Sunak said he had been "shocked and sad" at the news.<br/>
苏纳克表示，他对这一消息感到“震惊和悲伤”。</p>
<p>"All our thoughts are with him and his family. You know, thankfully, this has been caught early," Sunak told BBC radio.<br/>
苏纳克告诉BBC电台：“我们和国王以及他的家人同在。你知道，谢天谢地，这件事发现得早。”</p>
<p>Sunak said he was in regular contact with the king. "That will of course continue as normal," he said.<br/>
苏纳克表示，他与国王保持着定期联系。他说：“这当然会像往常一样继续下去。”</p>
<p>U.S. President Joe Biden expressed his concern on Monday and said he planned to call the king later.<br/>
美国总统乔·拜登周一表达了关切，并表示他计划稍后致电国王。</p>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau wrote on the social media service X: "We're sending him our very best wishes – and hoping for a fast and full recovery."<br/>
加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多在社交媒体服务X上写道：“我们向他致以最良好的祝愿，并希望他能迅速完全康复。”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Cancer discovery<br/>
发现癌症</span></p><p>The cancer was discovered recently when Charles stayed three nights in the hospital. At the time, he was undergoing a medical procedure for a non-cancerous enlarged prostate.<br/>
癌症是查尔斯最近在医院住了三个晚上才发现的。当时，他正在接受非癌性前列腺肥大的医疗手术。</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace officials have said he does not have prostate cancer. But they did not give any additional details about the kind of cancer the king has.<br/>
白金汉宫官员表示，他不是患前列腺癌症。但他们没有提供任何关于国王所患癌症的额外细节。</p>
<p>The British royal family usually keeps medical issues private. But the palace said Charles wanted to make his diagnosis public. He is a backer of several cancer-related charities.<br/>
英国王室通常对医疗问题保密。但王宫表示，查尔斯希望将自己的诊断结果公之于众。他是几个与癌症有关的慈善机构的支持者。</p>
<p>Charles' treatment will likely draw attention to the long waiting times for cancer patients under Britain's state-run National Health Service (NHS).<br/>
查尔斯的治疗可能会引起人们对癌症患者在英国国营国家医疗服务体系下漫长等待时间的关注。</p>
<p>Survival rates for cancer in Britain are lower than those of other European countries. A January NHS report shows that Britain is behind for nine out of 10 of the most common kinds of cancer.<br/>
英国癌症的存活率低于其他欧洲国家。英国国家医疗服务体系1月份的一份报告显示，在最常见的10种癌症中，英国有9种癌症的存活率落后。</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Damage atop Damage: ‘Atmospheric River’ Storms Strike California Again  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/damage-atop-damage-atmospheric-river-storms-strike-california-again.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In California, the second of back-to-back atmospheric rivers on Monday caused heavy rains and mudslides, flooded roadways and cut electric power.</p>
<p>Atmospheric rivers are long and wide areas, like a river, of water <strong>vapor</strong> in the atmosphere that form over an ocean. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.noaa.gov/stories/what-are-atmospheric-rivers">says</a> these weather systems carry as much water vapor as the average flow of water at the mouth of the Mississippi River. When atmospheric rivers make landfall, they often release this water vapor in the form of rain or snow.</p>
<p>Much of California was still drying out from the atmospheric river that blew in last week. Over the weekend, officials ordered people living in parts of California that burned in recent wildfires to evacuate. These areas are at high risk for wreckage flows.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An emergency worker helps a resident escape from danger after a mudslide, February 5, 2024, in the Beverly Crest area of Los Angeles, California. (AP Photo/Marcio Jose Sanchez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0867d26f-12cd-4ffe-a033-674074205a9a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An emergency worker helps a resident escape from danger after a mudslide, February 5, 2024, in the Beverly Crest area of Los Angeles, California. (AP Photo/Marcio Jose Sanchez)</span></div>
<p>About 1.4 million people living in the Los Angeles area, were under a flash flood warning Monday morning. Up to 23 centimeters of rain had already fallen in the area, with more expected, the National Weather Service predicts. It called the flash flooding and threat of mudslides, "a particularly dangerous situation."</p>
<p>Keki Mingus, from the Studio City area of Los Angeles, said that mud, rocks, and water came down through her neighborhood. Mingus said, "It looks like a river that's been here for years. I've never seen anything like it."</p>
<p><strong>Storm affects entire California coast</strong></p>
<p>The rains brought down trees and power lines Sunday in the San Francisco Bay Area. Winds in the northern area blew as fast as 95 kilometers an hour. In the mountains, they were even stronger with <strong>gusts</strong> reaching almost 130 kilometers an hour.</p>
<p>Palisades Tahoe is a skiing area about 320 kilometers northeast of San Francisco. The skiing area was expected to have the heaviest snowfall yet this season on Sunday, as much as 15 centimeters per hour for a total of up to 60 centimeters. Heavy snow is continuing into Monday throughout the Sierra Nevada and motorists were urged to avoid mountain roads.</p>
<p>Just to the south in San Jose, emergency crews rescued people from a car trapped by floodwaters. Other teams rescued people living beside a rising river.</p>
<p>For the Central Coast, the weather service issued a rare "<strong>hurricane</strong> force wind warning," with wind gusts of up to 148 kilometers an hour.</p>
<p>The storm then moved into Southern California, where officials warned of possible severe flooding. They ordered people to leave canyon areas where there were recent wildfires. Officials are concerned about the high risk of wreckage flows in those areas.</p>
<p>The latest atmospheric river storm is called a "<a class="wsw__a" href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/pineapple-express.html">Pineapple Express</a>" because it stretches across the Pacific from almost as far as Hawaii.</p>
<p>"We've had flooding, we've had gusty winds, we've had the whole <strong>gamut</strong> here," said Todd Hall, a weather scientist with the National Weather Service near Los Angeles. Hall said he expects the heavy to moderate rain to continue in southern California until Tuesday.</p>
<p>California Governor Gavin Newsom has declared a state of emergency for most areas of the state. The Governor's Office of Emergency Services activated its operations center and deployed workers and equipment in areas most at risk.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver adapted this story for VOA Learning English from an Associated Press report.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gust</strong> – <em>n</em>. <strong> </strong>a sudden brief rush of wind</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gamut </strong>– <em>n. </em>an entire range or series</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>plume </strong>– <em>n. </em>something shaped like a feather</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>moisture </strong>– <em>n. </em>liquid diffused or condensed in relatively small quantity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surf </strong>– <em>n</em>. the swell of the sea that breaks upon the shore</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hurricane </strong>– <em>n</em>. <strong> </strong>a tropical storm with winds of 74 miles (119 kilometers) per hour or greater that is usually accompanied by rain, thunder, and lightning, and that sometimes moves into temperate latitudes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Russian Cosmonaut Sets Record for Time in Space  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/russian-cosmonaut-sets-record-for-time-in-space.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Russia's space agency Roscosmos says cosmonaut Oleg Kononenko has broken the world record for total time spent in space.</p>
<p>Kononenko passed the record Sunday after spending more than 878 days and 12 hours in orbit aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>
<p>The previous record was set in 2015 by another cosmonaut, Gennady Padalka, who spent 878 days and 11 and a half hours in space.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - International Space Station (ISS) crew member Oleg Kononenko of Russia boards the Soyuz MS-11 spacecraft for launch at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, Kazakhstan December 3, 2018. (REUTERS/Shamil Zhumatov/Pool)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-3f63-08dc2670000b_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - International Space Station (ISS) crew member Oleg Kononenko of Russia boards the Soyuz MS-11 spacecraft for launch at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, Kazakhstan December 3, 2018. (REUTERS/Shamil Zhumatov/Pool)</span></div>
<p>The 59-year-old Kononenko has so far made five trips to the ISS. The first one came in 2008.</p>
<p>Kononenko told Russia's state-supported news agency, TASS, that each trip he took to the ISS required careful preparation. This is because the orbiting space lab is always getting <strong>upgrades</strong>.</p>
<p>Kononenko said his repeated space trips represent the <strong>realization</strong> of a childhood dream to become a cosmonaut. "I fly into space to do what I love, not to set records," he told TASS.</p>
<p>He added that his continued interest in living and working in orbit "<strong>motivates</strong>" him to keep flying.</p>
<p>Kononenko's current trip to the ISS began on Sept. 15, 2023. He arrived along with American astronaut Loral O'Hara and cosmonaut Nikolai Chub.</p>
<p>Kononenko's service on the ISS is continuing. He is expected to reach a total of 1,000 days in space on June 5. His current flight is expected to end in late September. By then, he will have spent at least 1,110 days in space.</p>
<p>Kononenko said he worked out often aboard the ISS to help him deal with the physical effects of weightlessness.</p>
<p>He added that he realizes the social effects of his long stays on the ISS when he returns back to Earth.</p>
<p>"It is only upon returning home that the realization comes that, for hundreds of days in my <strong>absence,</strong> the children have been growing up without a papa," Kononenko said. "No one will return this time to me."</p>
<p>Kononenko noted that cosmonauts are now able to use video calls and messaging to stay in better touch with their family.</p>
<p>He said one of the most difficult things about being a cosmonaut is getting ready for each new space flight. "The profession of a cosmonaut is becoming more <strong>complicated</strong>," Kononenko said. "The systems and experiments are becoming more complicated."</p>
<p>The ISS is one of only a few areas where the United States and Russia still closely cooperate after Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Roscosmos announced in December that its program with the American space agency NASA to transport astronauts to the ISS had been extended until 2025.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– v.</em> to improve the quality or usefulness of something</p>
<p><strong>realization </strong><em>– n. </em>the process of noticing or understanding something that you did not notice or understand before</p>
<p><strong>motivate </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone want to do something</p>
<p><strong>absence </strong><em>– n. </em>not being in a particular place</p>
<p><strong>complicated </strong><em>– adj. </em>complex or difficult to understand</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South America Dengue Increase Brings Vaccination Drive  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-america-dengue-increase-brings-vaccination-drive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health &amp; Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>During the southern hemisphere summer, South America is experiencing a sharp increase in cases of dengue, a mosquito-<strong>borne</strong> disease common in much of Latin America.</p>
<p>The <strong>symptoms</strong>, or signs, of dengue are high fever, extreme tiredness, muscle pain, and internal bleeding. In Brazil, dengue is often called "breakbone fever" for the severe joint pain it causes. Sometimes, people with the disease show no symptoms. But dengue can be deadly.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Health workers spray insecticide to kill mosquitos. This is to help slow a dengue outbreak in Brasilia, Brazil, on January 24, 2024. (REUTERS/Adriano Machado)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-7709-08dc1ea1ac10_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Health workers spray insecticide to kill mosquitos. This is to help slow a dengue outbreak in Brasilia, Brazil, on January 24, 2024. (REUTERS/Adriano Machado)</span></div>
<p><strong>New dengue vaccine</strong></p>
<p>In Brazil, officials plan to start a new dengue vaccine campaign. The program, which could begin within days, will make Brazil the first country in the world to offer dengue vaccine.</p>
<p>In January, Brazil also started spraying <strong>insecticide</strong> from trucks as the disease spread to earlier unaffected areas. Because of the increase in dengue cases, hospitals in Paraguay have set up health centers at night to care for the sick.</p>
<p>In 2023, cases of dengue have set record highs in Latin America. Health official records show Argentina with a sharp increase of 12,500 cases of dengue last December. It is a big jump compared with the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The increase has led to health warnings and shortages of insect <strong>repellent</strong>.</p>
<p>"Repellent sold out everywhere, there were <strong>literal</strong> clouds of mosquitoes," Laura Ledesma told Reuters from Argentina's capital of Buenos Aires. She added that there were signs the situation had begun to improve.</p>
<p><strong>Weather changes are affecting the spread of disease</strong></p>
<p>Scientists say the spread of dengue, in South America and other areas, is worsened by rising temperatures and the El Nino weather pattern in the Pacific. Both events also add to a longer dengue season.</p>
<p>"Climate change has expanded the range for mosquitoes to <strong>breed</strong>, both in the Americas and <strong>globally</strong>," Thais dos Santos told Reuters. He specializes in insect-borne diseases at the Pan American Health Organization, or PAHO for short.</p>
<p>PAHO information shows 4.2 million cases of dengue and 2,050 deaths in the Americas last year. Much of that was in the so-called "Southern Cone" of South America.</p>
<p>The December-February southern summer months bring hot and <strong>humid</strong> conditions for mosquitoes to breed.<strong> </strong>This helps to spread the possibly deadly disease.</p>
<p>Recently, people in Brasilia lined up outside medical centers set up to test for dengue. Dengue cases in the Brazilian capital have increased by as much as 646 percent in the first 20 days of January compared with last year.</p>
<p>Nelson Diego, 37, tested <strong>positive</strong> for dengue in the Brasilia neighborhood of Recanto das Emas where spraying has started. He said he was suffering from muscle pain and extreme tiredness from the disease, though some days were more difficult than others.</p>
<p>"Today is one of the better days because I can still open my eyes," he said. "I have a lot of pain in my joints and couldn't walk before."</p>
<p>And that's the Health &amp; Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Lucinda Elliott in Montevideo and Ricardo Brito in Brasilia reported this story for Reuters news agency. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>borne</strong> <em>– adj.</em> transported or transmitted by —used in combination such as air<em>borne</em></p>
<p><strong>symptom </strong><em>– n. </em>a change in a living thing that indicates the presence of a disease or other physical disorder, especially : one (as a headache) that can be felt or sensed only by the individual affected</p>
<p><strong>insecticide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical used to kill insects</p>
<p><strong>repellent </strong><em>– n. </em>serving or tending to drive away or ward off : often used in combination — insect <em>repellent</em></p>
<p><strong>literal </strong><em>– adj. </em>following the ordinary or usual meaning of the words</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce (plants or animals) by sexual reproduction</p>
<p><strong>globally </strong><em>– adv. </em>of, relating to, or involving the entire world</p>
<p><strong>humid </strong><em>– adj. </em>damp, moist</p>
<p><strong>positive </strong><em>– adj. </em>having a test result indicating the presence especially of a condition, substance, or organism</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift, Women Win Big at Grammy Music Awards  (2024/2/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/taylor-swift-women-win-big-at-grammy-music-awards.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>American pop singer and songwriter Taylor Swift won Album of the Year for <em>Midnights</em>" on Sunday at the Grammy Awards.</p>
<p>She has now won that award four times, breaking the record for wins in that <strong>category</strong>. Frank Sinatra, Paul Simon, and Stevie Wonder each won the award three times.</p>
<p>An album is a collection of songs on a single recording.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Taylor Swift accepts the award for album of the year for MIdnights during the 66th annual Grammy Awards on Sunday, Feb. 4, 2024, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1da6-08dc267be82c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Taylor Swift accepts the award for album of the year for "MIdnights" during the 66th annual Grammy Awards on Sunday, Feb. 4, 2024, in Los Angeles. (AP Photo/Chris Pizzello)</span></div>
<p>"For me, the award is the work," Swift said. "All I want to do is keep doing it."</p>
<p>Earlier, when receiving another Grammy, for Best Pop Vocal Album for <em>Midnights</em>, she shared a surprise. She announced that her new album, <em>The Tortured Poets Department</em>, will be released April 19.</p>
<p><strong>Women lead the awards</strong></p>
<p>Women earned the biggest awards and gave the majority of the performances on the American television broadcast.</p>
<p>Of the eight nominees for Song of the Year, seven were performed by women.</p>
<p>Billie Eilish's song from the movie <em>Barbie</em>, <em>What Was I Made For?</em> won Song of the Year for her and co-writer Finneas O'Connell, her brother.</p>
<p>Miley Cyrus won Record of the Year for her song <em>Flowers</em>. The record of the year recognizes the best-sounding recording of a particular song. <em>Flowers</em> also earned Cyrus the award for Best Pop Solo performance.</p>
<p>Solána Imani Rowe, known professionally as SZA, won for best R&amp;B song, <em>Snooze</em>. R&amp;B stands for rhythm and blues. SZA also won for Best Pop Duo/group Performance for <em>Ghost in the Machine</em> with Phoebe Bridgers.</p>
<p>Rock group boygenius, whose three members are women and include Bridgers, won Best Rock Song and Best Rock Performance for their song <em>Not Strong Enough</em>. The group also won a Grammy for Alternative Album of the Year. Their album is simply named <em>The Record</em>.</p>
<p>Victoria Monét won the Grammy for Best New Artist. But it has taken her years of work to become a successful performer.</p>
<p>"Thanks to my mom, a single mom raising this really bad girl," said Monét when she received her award. Then she started to cry, adding that this award was "15 years in the making."</p>
<p>Karol G of Colombia become the first female performer to win Best Música Urbana Album for <em>Ma<i>&amp;#</i>241;ana Será Bonito</em>.</p>
<p><strong>New awards</strong></p>
<p>The Grammys added three new categories this year: African Music Performance, Alternative Jazz Album, and Pop Dance Recording. Women were the winners in each of them.</p>
<p>South African singer Tyla won the African music performance Grammy for her hit song, <em>Water</em>.</p>
<p>"I never thought I'd say I won a Grammy at 21 years old," she said in her acceptance speech. "Last year, God decided to change my whole life."</p>
<p>Meshell Ndegeocello, an American singer-songwriter, rapper, and bass player, won Best Alternative Jazz Album.</p>
<p>And Kylie Minogue of Australia won Best Pop Dance Recording for her hit <em>Padam Padam</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Rap</strong></p>
<p>Rapper Killer Mike won three awards Sunday, his first since winning a Grammy in 2003. He won Best Rap Performance for <em>Scientists &amp; Engineers</em>, which featured André 3000, Future and Eryn Allen Kane. The performers won for Best Rap Song for the same song. Killer Mike also received the award for Best Rap Album, for <em>Michael</em>.</p>
<p>Jay-Z won the Dr. Dre Global Impact Award. Jay-Z has won 24 Grammys and has been nominated 88 times. He spoke about the times that rap artists did not get enough attention from the Grammys, although they sold lots of recordings.</p>
<p>Jay-Z's wife, Beyoncé, has won 32 Grammys, more than any other artist. Because she has won so many, Jay-Z thinks it is unfair that she has never won album of the year. "Think about that. The most Grammys, never won album of the year. That doesn't work," Jay-Z said.</p>
<p>"When I get nervous, I tell the truth," he added.</p>
<p><strong>From young to old</strong></p>
<p>The awards show included performers both young and old. American pop singer and songwriter Olivia Rodrigo, aged 20, was nominated for six Grammys, including top awards such as Song of the Year and Album of the Year.</p>
<p>Singer and songwriter Joni Mitchell, aged 80, won for Best Folk Album. It was her eleventh Grammy win. She performed <em>Both Sides Now</em> from her 1969 album <em>Clouds</em>. Mitchell suffered a brain <strong>aneurysm</strong> in 2015 and has had to relearn how to walk and speak.</p>
<p>American singer and songwriter Billy Joel, 74, ended the awards show with two performances. First, he played his new song <em>Turn the Lights Back On</em>. It is his first pop music release since 1993. Later, he played his 1980 hit, <em>You May Be Right</em>.</p>
<p>The first Grammy Awards show was held in 1959. The awards now include 94 categories.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and other sources. </em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>category </strong>–n. a group of things that are considered similar and are subject to the same kind of consideration</p>
<p><strong>aneurysm </strong>–n. an abnormal and dangerous expansion of a blood vessel that can bleeding</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>NASA's Mars Helicopter Ends Service after 'History-making' Mission  (2024/2/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/nasa-s-mars-helicopter-ends-service-after-history-making-mission.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>NASA's experimental helicopter, Ingenuity, has officially ended its service on Mars after what the U.S. space agency called a "history-making" <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>Ingenuity arrived on Mars with NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover, in February 2021. The experimental helicopter has completed many test flights on the Red Planet to support NASA's efforts to build new aircraft that can fly in the atmospheres of other planets.</p>
<p>Ingenuity became the first aircraft to complete a powered, controlled flight on another planet in April 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-05e9-08dbf1ebe005_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration, made available by NASA, depicts the Ingenuity helicopter on Mars after launching from the Perseverance rover, shown in the background left. (NASA/JPL-Caltech via AP)</span></div>
<p>At first, NASA described Ingenuity as a demonstration mission that was expected to last about one month. The aircraft aimed to test flight on Mars, including taking off, flying short distances and landing. The helicopter quickly demonstrated its abilities during a series of tests.</p>
<p>In May 2021, NASA officially extended Ingenuity's experimental mission. In total, the helicopter performed 72 flights on Mars, the space agency said. The aircraft flew 14 times farther than planned and completed more than two hours of total flight time.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/after-three-years-on-mars-nasas-ingenuity-helicopter-mission-ends/">praised</a> Ingenuity as "the little helicopter that could." He noted that officials were surprised with each new flight progression.</p>
<p>But Nelson noted that because of damage to a <strong>rotor</strong>, the helicopter had finally taken its last flight. "The historic <strong>journey</strong> of Ingenuity, the first aircraft on another planet, has come to (an) end," he said.</p>
<p>Nelson added that mission controllers discovered during an attempt by Ingenuity to land that at least one of the aircraft's rotor <strong>blades</strong> had been damaged. The damage is currently being investigated, but the NASA chief said the blade might have struck the ground during the landing attempt.</p>
<p>NASA said Ingenuity rose to 12 meters on its final flight last week, staying in the air for a few seconds before heading back down. Most flights only last a few minutes because the helicopter has energy and temperature limitations.</p>
<p>Nelson said the helicopter was able to fly effectively in the thin Martian atmosphere. But he noted that additional progress showed the aircraft "far <strong>exceeded</strong> what we thought possible."</p>
<p>Ingenuity's mission, Nelson, said, had opened the door to "future flight in our solar system and smarter, safer human exploration to Mars and beyond."</p>
<p>After Ingenuity performed well in flight tests, NASA decided to expand the helicopter's mission to assist Perseverance with its rover operations. This change officially turned the aircraft's mission into an "operations demonstration."</p>
<p>NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/after-three-years-on-mars-nasas-ingenuity-helicopter-mission-ends/">reports</a> Ingenuity helped to identify additional exploration areas for Perseverance. Both the rover and helicopter have been collecting data and images while exploring an area known as Jezero Crater. The goal is to search for signs of ancient life on Mars.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
renderExternalContent("https://www.youtube.com/embed/zjt3DMNqtus?&amp;&amp;&amp;fs=1&amp;enablejsapi=1")



<p>NASA noted that Ingenuity had helped map a path from above to help Perseverance take on new exploration activities. Flight controllers on the ground have been collecting data on all of Ingenuity's operations. They said this data will be valuable in helping NASA design future aircraft for Mars.</p>
<p>The success of the helicopter mission led the space agency in 2022 to approve the development of two small helicopters to be deployed on future missions.</p>
<p>While Ingenuity continued its operational mission, teams on the ground <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/nasa-continues-mars-helicopter-experiments-tests-new-design-on-earth/7379281.html">experimented</a> with new rotor blades. During ground tests completed last year, engineers reported the rotor blades had reached speeds nearly equal to Mach 1, the speed of sound.</p>
<p>The blades tested on Earth are made of carbon. They are more than 10 centimeters longer than Ingenuity's and are designed to be stronger and to move faster. NASA has said the rotor blades are designed to support bigger, more complex helicopters.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA, The Associated Press and Reuters. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>the flight of a spacecraft to perform a certain task or job</p>
<p><strong>rotor blade </strong><em>– n. </em>thin, flat pieces of material that spin to make aircraft lift off the ground and travel</p>
<p><strong>journey </strong><em>– n. </em>the act of traveling from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>exceed </strong><em>– v. </em>to go over a particular number or amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Research Suggests Bright Lights Confuse Insects  (2024/2/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/research-suggests-bright-lights-confuse-insects.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many people have long believed that bright lights draw, or attract, flying insects.</p>
<p>But that is not exactly what is going on, a new study suggests.</p>
<p>Researchers believe that artificial lights at night may cause problems with flying insects' natural navigation systems. As a result, the creatures fly in confusion around porch lamps, street lights and other artificial lights.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This photo 2022 photo provided by Samuel Timothy Fabian shows an Atlas Moth (Attacus lorquinii) used to test the interaction of flying insects with artificial light is photographed at Imperial College London. (Samuel Timothy Fabian via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/ccdd807a-5e8f-42ef-a737-ae5141a0627e_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This photo 2022 photo provided by Samuel Timothy Fabian shows an Atlas Moth (Attacus lorquinii) used to test the interaction of flying insects with artificial light is photographed at Imperial College London. (Samuel Timothy Fabian via AP)</span></div>
<p>"Insects have a navigational problem," said Tyson Hedrick of the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill. Hedrick was not involved in the research. He added, "They're<strong> accustomed to</strong> using light as a<strong> cue</strong> to know which way is up."</p>
<p>Insects do not fly directly toward a light source, but actually "<strong>tilt</strong> their backs toward the light," said Sam Fabian of Imperial College London. Fabian was a co-writer of the study that appeared recently in Nature Communications.</p>
<p>This tilting action would make sense if the strongest light source was in the sky. But in the presence of artificial lights, the result is midair confusion.</p>
<p>For the study, researchers attached very small sensors to moths and dragonflies in a laboratory. They then filmed "motion-capture" video of flight — similar to how filmmakers attach sensors to actors to follow their movements.</p>
<p>Researchers also used high-resolution cameras to film insects flying around lights at a field in Costa Rica.</p>
<p>Such films permitted researchers to study in detail how dragonflies circle endlessly around light sources, positioning themselves with their backs facing the light. Researchers also documented that some insects fly upside down — and often crash land — in the presence of lights that shine straight upward like search lights.</p>
<p>Insect flight was least disrupted by bright lights that shine straight downward, the researchers found.</p>
<p>"For millions of years, insects oriented themselves by sensing that the sky is light, the ground is dark" — until people invented artificial lights, said Avalon Owens of Harvard University. Owens was not involved in the research.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>accustomed to </strong><em>– expression </em>familiar with something so that it seems normal or usual</p>
<p><strong>cue </strong><em>– n.</em> something that indicates the nature of what you are seeing, hearing, etc.</p>
<p><strong>tilt</strong> <em>– v.</em> to lift or move (something) so that one side is higher than another side</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Part-time Detectives Find Problems in Medical, Scientific Research  (2024/2/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/part-time-detectives-find-problems-in-medical-scientific-research.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A major cancer hospital and research center recently announced it is asking for withdrawals or corrections to at least 37 research papers.</p>
<p>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute in Boston is taking action after its research included false images.</p>
<p>The cancer hospital is connected with Harvard University's medical school. Harvard's last president, Claudine Gay, recently left her position after being accused of plagiarism. Plagiarism is when a person claims someone else's work as their own.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A sign hangs from the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Aug. 18, 2022, in Boston. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/22bf9480-3cf2-4cb0-be28-39fde9dafe75_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A sign hangs from the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Aug. 18, 2022, in Boston. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa, File)</span></div>
<p>In the Dana-Farber case, a blogger from Wales in Britain, said the cancer center published documents that had <strong>manipulated</strong> images. Sholto David is a 32-year-old blogger who investigates scientific reports in his free time.</p>
<p>On January 2, David wrote on his blog that he found <strong>suspicious</strong> images in 30 papers published by four Dana-Farber scientists, including top leaders Laurie Glimcher and William Hahn. He said some of the images made the research look stronger. The papers discussed how cells work. Another documented <strong>samples</strong> of bone marrow from human volunteers.</p>
<p><strong>When did the problem surface?</strong></p>
<p>Similar investigators found problems with some of the Dana-Farber papers and pointed them out on a website called PubPeer. Reporters from Harvard's student newspaper started writing about the problems on January 12.</p>
<p>Dana-Farber answered the news coverage by saying it had already been looking into the problems. On January 22, the center said it asked for six of the papers to be retracted, or withdrawn from publication, because of problems. It also asked for corrections in 31 other papers.</p>
<p>Dr. Barrett Rollins is the research <strong>integrity</strong> officer at Dana-Farber. He said the center and its scientists took "<strong>prompt</strong> and decisive action in (most) cases" that David pointed out.</p>
<p><strong>Community of "sleuths"</strong></p>
<p>David is not the only person who studies scientific research and looks for errors. Elisabeth Bik is a microbiologist in California. She has been looking at journals and papers for 10 years. Based on her work over 1,000 articles have been pulled back. Over 1,000 have been corrected and 153 times journals have printed their concerns about previously published work.</p>
<p>She has seen manipulated images of bacteria, cells and more.</p>
<p>Bik wrote about her work in a paper published by the <em>American Society for Microbiology</em> in 2016. "Science should be about finding the truth," she said.</p>
<p>Bik does get some money for her work. Some people who like her work subscribe to a journal she writes. She earns about $2,300 per month for the work she does. David said he earns just over $200 a month for his work.</p>
<p><strong>Why do they do it?</strong></p>
<p>Ivan Oransky is an expert on the science <strong>sleuths</strong>. He teaches medical <strong>journalism</strong> at Columbia University in New York City. He said some of the detectives use software tools to look for problems in scientific writing. Many do not use their names when they write about their findings.</p>
<p>Oransky said the sleuths "want science to do and be better." He said they are upset that people in publishing and at universities do not seem interested in correcting mistakes. Some of the bloggers are worried that the number of people who trust science is falling.</p>
<p>Bik said the problem that leads to false research is that many doctors and scientists feel pressure to get published. And they make mistakes because they are in a hurry.</p>
<p>Oransky, the journalism teacher at Columbia, said pressure to publish means: if the images do not match the story the paper is trying to tell, "you <strong>beautify</strong> them."</p>
<p><strong>What next?</strong></p>
<p>Scientific journals look at errors brought to their attention but do not often do a public investigation. They keep the process quiet and then release their decision. Usually, they will ask for a correction or withdraw the paper.</p>
<p>Some journals told <em>The Associated Press</em> they were looking into the issues that David raised.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>manipulate </strong>–v. to change in a way that is meant to affect people in a certain way or to deceive people</p>
<p><strong>suspicious </strong>–adj. causing concern that there is something wrong</p>
<p><strong>sample </strong>–n. a small amount of a substance that is taken for study or research</p>
<p><strong>integrity </strong>–n. the quality of being honest, fair, complete or good</p>
<p><strong>prompt </strong>–adj. quick, done in a timely way</p>
<p><strong>sleuth </strong>–n. someone who looks for clues to solve crimes or problems</p>
<p><strong>journalism </strong>–n. the job of finding, writing and editing news stories for newspapers, magazines, TV and radio</p>
<p><strong>beautify </strong>–v. to make something beautiful or to increase its beauty</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan's Cafés Where People Can Pet Pigs  (2024/2/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/japan-s-cafes-where-people-can-pet-pigs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In Japan's big cities, small restaurants that serve coffee, called cafés, are known for starting <strong>trends</strong>. First there were pet cafés, then cat cafés. The latest trend<strong> </strong>in Japan is a café that has pigs.</p>
<p>"It was wonderful. Very relaxing and enjoyable," said Brad Loomis. He is a software engineer from the city of Pullman, in the U.S. state of Washington. He was talking about his recent visit to Tokyo's Mipig Café with his 21-year-old daughter, Paige.</p>
<p>On a recent morning in late January, the father and daughter were among many people in the café, smiling and taking <strong>selfies</strong> with the pigs.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Customers play with micro pigs at a mipig cafe on Jan. 24, 2024, in Tokyo. The pigs, a miniature breed, moved about the room, looking for a cozy lap to cuddle up. Customers pay $15 for the first 30 minutes and a reservation is required. (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1f5c-08dc236a9911_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Customers play with micro pigs at a mipig cafe on Jan. 24, 2024, in Tokyo. The pigs, a miniature breed, moved about the room, looking for a cozy lap to cuddle up. Customers pay $15 for the first 30 minutes and a reservation is required. (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko)</span></div>
<p>The pigs are very small. They move around the room, looking for a comfortable place. They are surprisingly quiet, making little <strong>snorts</strong> now and then. Unlike the<strong> stereotype</strong>, they are very clean and do not smell bad.</p>
<p>The pigs do not like to be alone. So, this makes them good company for people. <strong>Customers</strong> pay $15 for the first 30 minutes of time with a pig. Customers must contact the café to set a time for the experience.</p>
<p>"Each pig is <strong>unique</strong>. Each one has his or her own <strong>personality.</strong> You may notice one may be strong-headed, and another may be gentle," said Shiho Kitagawa. She is an executive at Mipig Café. She calls the pigs "buta-san," or "Mr. and Mrs. Pig."</p>
<p>The Mipig Café in the trendy Harajuku neighborhood. It is among 10 such pig cafes the owner has opened around Japan. The first one opened in Tokyo in 2019. Two more are planned for later this year.</p>
<p>The animals are known as "micro pigs." Micro means very small. The pigs do not grow to be bigger than a small dog, even when they are fully grown.</p>
<p>Pig lovers say they make great pets. They can be bought for $1,350 from Mipig. The pigs sold at Mipig have been house-trained and are used to being with people. Micro pig food is also for sale. Mipig says it has sold about 1,300 pigs as pets.</p>
<p>Foreign visitors to the café said they found out about it on the service Instagram and other social media platforms. The café does not pay for advertising.</p>
<p>Australian Ben Russell smiled when a pig finally climbed onto him. Although this was the first time he touched a real pig, he said they have always been his favorite animal.</p>
<p>A visitor from New Zealand, Sophie Mo'unga, was in Japan with her husband and two children. She was very popular with the pigs, with several of them fighting over her.</p>
<p>"They were <strong>cute," </strong>she said. "I think they were all keeping each other warm."</p>
<p>The pig café is the latest in a series of coffee shops with animals that have appeared in Japan. There are coffee shops that have owls, hedgehogs, birds, and even snakes.</p>
<p>Some people have raised questions about whether the animals enjoy the experience as much as humans do.</p>
<p>"It must be <strong>stressful </strong>to be touched...by a bunch of strangers," said Sachiko Azuma. She is head of Tokyo-based animal rights group called PEACE.</p>
<p>"The animals have become tools for a money-making business," she said.</p>
<p>Her group opposes animal experiments and "petting zoos." Azuma said cafés are small and do not provide enough of a natural environment for cats or small pigs. She added that businesses that entrap wildlife are abhorrent, or extremely bad. However, she said she approves of cafés run by shelters that try to find homes for homeless animals.</p>
<p>Some people believe that such interactions are good for human health.</p>
<p>Dr. Bruce Kornreich teaches at Cornell University's College of Veterinary Medicine in Ithaca, New York. He said that interacting with animals can reduce headaches and lower a person's blood pressure and risk of <strong>cardiovascular</strong> disease. It can also increase a sense of well-being and help people deal with stress, he said.</p>
<p>"How they do these things, I'm not sure we know the answer," said Kornreich. He is also part of the Cornell Feline Health Center, which supports the study and well-being of cats.</p>
<p>He told the Associated Press that there is growing evidence that being around pets can help people both mentally and physically.</p>
<p>Even with dogs, it is not clear if walking a dog helps its owner's health or being around a friendly animal does. Whatever it is, people seem to be calm and happy around their animals.</p>
<p>"Very cute and very sleepy," Paige Loomis said of the pigs. "They made me sleepy."</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Yuri Kageyama reported this story in Tokyo for the Associated Press. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>trend </strong>–n. something new that gets increasingly popular</p>
<p><strong>selfie </strong>–n. a picture taken of oneself with a mobile phone that is shared on social media</p>
<p><strong>snort </strong>–n. a short sound made through the nose</p>
<p><strong>stereotype </strong>–n. a person's idea of what something or someone is, does or looks like which is transferred to all similar things</p>
<p><strong>customer </strong>–n. a person, or group, that pays for goods or services</p>
<p><strong>unique </strong>–adj. unlike anything else, one-of-a-kind</p>
<p><strong>personality </strong>–n. the sum of all qualities that make up a person</p>
<p><strong>cute </strong>–adj. having a pleasing appearance</p>
<p><strong>stressful </strong>–adj. causing tension or worry</p>
<p><strong>cardiovascular </strong>–adj. related to the heart or blood vessels in the body</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Webb Telescope Captures Images of 19 Spiral Galaxies  (2024/2/4) | 韦伯太空望远镜拍下19个螺旋星系图片</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/webb-telescope-captures-images-of-19-spiral-galaxies.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Newly released images captured by the James Webb Space Telescope show 19 spiral galaxies relatively close to our Milky Way. The images offer new information on star formation, galaxy structure and evolution.<br/>
詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜最新发布的图像显示了距离我们银河系相对较近的19个螺旋星系。这些图像提供了关于恒星形成、星系结构和演化的新信息。</p>
<p>The images were made public on Monday by a team of scientists involved in a project called Physics at High Angular resolution in Nearby GalaxieS (PHANGS). The project operates across several major astronomical observatories.<br/>
周一，一个名为“邻近星系高角分辨率物理学”的项目下的科学家团队公开了这些图像。该项目在几个主要的天文台运行。</p>
<p>The closest of the 19 galaxies is called NGC5068. It is about 15 million light years from Earth. The most distant is NGC1365, about 60 million light years from Earth. A light year is the distance light travels in a year, which is equal to about 9.5 trillion kilometers.<br/>
19个星系中距离最近的一个被称为NGC50068。它距离地球大约1500万光年。最遥远的是NGC1365，距离地球约6000万光年。一光年是光在一年中传播的距离，约等于9.5万亿公里。</p>
<p>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) was launched in 2021 and began collecting data in 2022. It has shaped understanding of the early universe while taking pictures of space.<br/>
詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜于2021年发射，并于2022年开始收集数据。它在拍摄太空照片的同时，塑造了人们对早期宇宙的理解。</p>
<p>The orbiting telescope looks at the universe mainly in the infrared. The Hubble Space Telescope, which was launched in 1990 and is still in use, has examined the universe mostly at optical and ultraviolet wavelengths.<br/>
轨道望远镜主要在红外波段观察宇宙。哈勃太空望远镜于1990年发射，目前仍在使用中，主要在光学和紫外线波长下对宇宙进行了探测。</p>
<p>Spiral galaxies are a common galaxy type. Our Milky Way is one.<br/>
螺旋星系是一种常见的星系类型。我们的银河系就是其中之一。</p>
<p>The new observations came from Webb's Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) and Mid-Infrared Instrument (MIRI). They show about 100,000 star clusters and millions, or even billions, of individual stars.<br/>
这一新的观测结果来自于韦伯太空望远镜的近红外相机和中红外仪器。它们展示了大约10万个星团和数百万甚至数十亿颗恒星。</p>
<p>"These data are important as they give us a new view on the earliest phase of star formation," said University of Oxford astronomer Thomas Williams. He led the team's data processing on the images.<br/>
牛津大学天文学家托马斯·威廉姆斯说：“这些数据很重要，它们让我们对恒星形成的最早阶段有了新的认识。”他领导团队对图像进行数据处理。</p>
<p>Williams added, "Stars are born deep within dusty clouds that completely block out the light at visible wavelengths - what the Hubble Space Telescope is sensitive to - but these clouds light up at the JWST wavelengths. We don't know a lot about this phase."<br/>
威廉姆斯补充道，“恒星诞生在尘土飞扬的云层深处，这些云层完全阻挡了可见光波长的光线——哈勃太空望远镜对此很敏感——但这些云层以JWST波长发光。我们对这个阶段了解不多。”</p>
<p>About half of spiral galaxies have a straight structure, called a bar, coming out from the center. The spiral arms attach to this structure.<br/>
大约一半的螺旋星系有一个直的结构，称为棒，从中心出来。螺旋臂连接到该结构上。</p>
<p>Williams said the commonly held thought is that galaxies form from the inside out. That way, they "get bigger and bigger over their lifetimes."<br/>
威廉姆斯说，人们普遍认为星系是由内而外形成的。这样，它们“在生命中变得越来越大”。</p>
<p>The images let scientists for the first time determine the structure of the clouds of dust and gas from which stars and planets form at a high level of detail.<br/>
这些图像使科学家首次能够以高水平的细节确定恒星和行星形成的尘埃和气体云的结构。</p>
<p>The images are in galaxies beyond the Large Magellanic Cloud and Small Magellanic Cloud. Those two galaxies are near the Milky Way.<br/>
这些图像属于大麦哲伦星系和小麦哲伦星系之外的星系。那两个星系在银河系附近。</p>
<p>Webb's observations build on Hubble's.<br/>
韦伯太空望远镜的观测建立在哈勃望远镜的基础上。</p>
<p>Erik Rosolowsky is an astronomer at Canada's University of Alberta. He said, "Using Hubble, we would see the starlight from galaxies, but some of the light was blocked by the dust of galaxies."<br/>
Erik Rosolowsky是加拿大阿尔伯塔大学的天文学家。他说：“使用哈勃望远镜，我们可以看到来自星系的星光，但有些光被星系的尘埃阻挡了。”</p>
<p>Rosolowsky added, "This limitation made it hard to understand parts of how a galaxy operates as a system. With Webb's view in the infrared, we can see through this dust to see stars behind and within the enshrouding dust."<br/>
Rosolowsky补充道，“这种限制使得人们很难理解星系作为一个系统是如何运作的。根据韦伯太空望远镜在红外波段的观测，我们可以透过这些尘埃，看到尘埃背后和内部的恒星。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Student Academy Awards Provide ‘Momentum’ for Young Filmmakers  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/student-academy-awards-provide-momentum-for-young-filmmakers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>While most people know about the Academy Awards in Hollywood — the awards known as the Oscars — few know about the Student Academy Awards.</p>
<p>But to those who know about the industry, they are a big deal.</p>
<p>A top-three finish at the Student Academy Awards can lift a young filmmaker's <strong>career</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A replica of the Academy Awards statuette on display prior to the 96th Academy Awards nominations announcement on Tuesday, Jan. 23, 2024, at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Beverly Hills. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7a200008-d55b-475b-92c8-d63b86d48a8d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A replica of the Academy Awards statuette on display prior to the 96th Academy Awards nominations announcement on Tuesday, Jan. 23, 2024, at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Beverly Hills. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>Freddy Macdonald knows this.</p>
<p>His short movie, <em>Shedding Angels</em>, placed third in the <strong>narrative</strong> film category in 2022. It was his thesis film after two years of study at the American Film Institute (AFI) in Los Angeles. A thesis is a big project that is needed to complete a study program.</p>
<p>Just being selected as a finalist was a dream come true, Macdonald said.</p>
<p>"Having that <strong>stamp</strong> from the Academy helped give me so much <strong>momentum</strong> to create my first feature film."</p>
<p>Macdonald is 23. He said the recognition from the Academy helped launch his career. After the award, he said, investors paid more attention to him, and he was able to create excitement for a full-length movie.</p>
<p>That movie is a longer version of another one of his short films called <em>Sew Torn</em>. He directed it when he was 19.</p>
<p><em>Sew Torn</em>, he said, tells the story of a <strong>seamstress</strong> who gets involved in a violent drug deal.</p>
<p>The full-length movie will be shown at film festivals this year and Macdonald hopes it will be shown in theaters sometime in the near future.</p>
<p><strong>History of success</strong></p>
<p>Macdonald could be one of the more recent filmmakers to go on to a successful career in Hollywood after receiving a student award from the Academy.</p>
<p>The awards program celebrated its 50<sup>th</sup> year in 2023. Some of the past winners include Spike Lee, known for his movies, <em>Do the Right Thing</em>, <em>Malcolm X</em>, <em>He Got Game</em> and others. Lee won an Oscar in 2019 for <em>BlacKkKlansman.</em></p>
<p>Lee won his student award in 1983 when he was studying at New York University (NYU). His film was <em>Joe's Bed-Stuy Barbershop: We Cut Heads</em>.</p>
<p>Other student winners include Robert Zemeckis, who won an Oscar for directing <em>Forrest Gump</em> in 1994. Pete Docter won a student award, too. He later earned Oscars for his <strong>animated</strong> films <em>Up</em>, <em>Inside Out</em> and <em>Soul</em>.</p>
<p>Kendra Carter is a Vice President at the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, which runs both awards programs. She said the Academy hopes to open the film industry to people from many different backgrounds and "create a pool of highly skilled, <strong>diverse</strong> talent."</p>
<p><strong>Serious exposure</strong></p>
<p>In 2023, 640 members of the Academy voted on the awards, which means the student work was seen by hundreds of people in Hollywood. In addition to the award, many students come away from the event with a business agent who can help them get more work.</p>
<p>But that's not all. The gold-medal winners can choose to have their work submitted for the Academy Awards. Last year, an animated short film by a student from Australia, <em>An Ostrich Told Me the World Is Fake and I Think I Believe It</em>, was considered for an Oscar.</p>
<p>"Once your name is tied to a Student Academy Award, it just opens all of these doors," the Academy's Carter said. "It's so <strong>transformative</strong> for <strong>emerging</strong> filmmakers."</p>
<p>The program is now open to young filmmakers from around the world. Giorgio Ghiotto of Italy is a student at NYU. He won the gold medal in October for his documentary short film <em>Wings of Dust</em>.</p>
<p>"Everyone thinks it's impossible to be a documentary filmmaker unless you're rich, or super lucky," Ghiotto said. He called his success "an impossible dream."</p>
<p>Macdonald said the opportunity to compete with student filmmakers from around the world was both "extremely <strong>daunting</strong> and exciting." He said it was a great experience to go to the awards ceremony and meet so many creative people from around the world.</p>
<p><strong>School experience</strong></p>
<p>He would not have gotten that experience without going to film school. Macdonald said he thought about going to an undergraduate film program first.</p>
<p>"And then towards the end of high school, kind of, I knew I wanted to be a filmmaker, but the big question came what college am I gonna go to? Where should I be <strong>applying</strong>? And so, I started looking at all the different paths in terms of film school and the American Film Institute always jumped off the page to me...But I didn't think that would be a possibility because it is a graduate program, and I was applying as a high school senior."</p>
<p>Macdonald applied and was the youngest person ever accepted into the directing program. He was qualified because by then, he had already made a short film and done other directing jobs. But because he did not have a college degree, AFI gave him a "certificate of completion" at the end.</p>
<p>While in school, he learned more about the business side of filmmaking than he expected. He learned how to write a proposal that aimed to make investors excited to finance a film.</p>
<p>"And that was really helpful for me to kind of wrap my head around the different ways you can make movies."</p>
<p><strong>‘An honor'</strong></p>
<p>Before being nominated for a Student Academy Award, Macdonald had everything he needed to enter the film industry. He had strong experience before attending AFI. He learned even more in school. He even got attention from some film studios. But the Student Academy Award experience gave him something more. It gave him the sense that other people believed in what he was doing.</p>
<p>"The Academy recognizing it (my film) really gave me belief in myself that the stories that I want to tell are worth telling and that I should keep <strong>pursuing</strong> them."</p>
<p>The lesson, Macdonald added, was that the Academy liked his work and he, in his words, "should keep fighting to make movies."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press and his interview with Macdonald.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>career </strong><em>–n.</em> a job or profession that a person has for a long time</p>
<p><strong>narrative </strong><em>–adj.</em> telling a story</p>
<p><strong>stamp </strong><em>–n.</em> a mark of approval</p>
<p><strong>momentum </strong><em>–n.</em> a push that continues movement into the future</p>
<p><strong>seamstress </strong><em>–n. </em>a woman who sews or repairs clothing</p>
<p><strong>animated </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving moving pictures or cartoons rather than live-action film</p>
<p><strong>diverse </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving many different examples of something</p>
<p><strong>transformative </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing complete change</p>
<p><strong>emerging </strong><em>–adj.</em> just beginning to develop into something fully</p>
<p><strong>pursue </strong><em>–v.</em> to chase, follow or simply continue doing something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Do You Have a 'Doppelgänger'?  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/do-you-have-a-doppelganger.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>English borrows from many other languages. And today we talk about a word that comes from German – doppelganger.</p>
<p>The word "doppelganger" comes from German <strong>folklore</strong>. The online dictionary <em>Merriam-Webster </em>describes the old story. All living creatures have a <strong>spirit</strong> who is <strong>invisible</strong> but exactly the same as the living person. But just because you can't see them, doppelgangers are not <strong>ghosts</strong>. They are sometimes described as "the spiritual opposite or <strong>negative</strong> of their human <strong>counterpart</strong>."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this photo provided by Zooparc de Beauval, twin panda cubs Yuandudu and Huanlili take their first steps in public, at the Beauval Zoo in Saint-Aignan-sur-Cher, France, Dec. 11, 2021. (Zooparc de Beauval via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/BB0D17A2-D48D-49F1-9AF0-9B7BB7E2F378_cx5_cy11_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this photo provided by Zooparc de Beauval, twin panda cubs Yuandudu and Huanlili take their first steps in public, at the Beauval Zoo in Saint-Aignan-sur-Cher, France, Dec. 11, 2021. (Zooparc de Beauval via AP)</span></div>
<p>Even though the word comes from spiritual folklore, we use it in a very real way. When two people look very similar, we can call them doppelgangers.</p>
<p>English has other expressions that have a similar meaning. If someone looks like someone else, you can call them a look-alike, spitting image or mirror image.</p>
<p>Let's hear two friends use some of these expressions.</p>
<p><em>A: Were you at the airport yesterday?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. I haven't been to the airport in over a year. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Are you sure about that? </em></p>
<p><em>B: I think I would know if I were at the airport. Why do you ask?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, if you weren't there, then I ran into your doppelganger. She was a mirror image of you!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Wow, I've heard about doppelgangers. But I didn't think I really had a look-alike out there in the world. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, you do. And they are on their way to Costa Rica. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I wish I could trade places with my doppelganger!</em></p>
<p>If you know someone who looks exactly like another person, you can also call them a dead ringer.</p>
<p>Experts say this expression comes from American horse racing, and usage began in the late 19<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>Sometimes, racehorse owners would race a horse under a false name and <strong>pedigree</strong>. They did this to trick people who bet money on race results. These horses were called "ringers."</p>
<p>Here is how to use this expression in a sentence: My best friend in college is a dead ringer for George Clooney. When we're out in public, he gets asked for his autograph all the time.</p>
<p>In the expression "dead ringer," the word "dead" does not mean lifeless. In this case, it means exact or <strong>precise</strong>. It is a way to add <strong>emphasis, </strong>or highlight something. For example, if I am sure that my friend is right about something, I can say she is dead right. We can also say someone is "dead wrong" if they are most certainly wrong.</p>
<p>The next time you want to describe two people who look the same, you can choose any of these expressions.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>folklore </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>customs, beliefs, stories, and sayings of a people handed down from generation to generation</p>
<p><strong>spirit</strong> <em>– n. </em>a force within a human being thought to give the body life, energy, and power</p>
<p><strong>invisible </strong><em>– adj. </em>incapable by nature of being seen<strong>: </strong>not perceptible by vision</p>
<p><strong>ghost </strong><em>– n. </em>the soul of a dead person believed to be an inhabitant of the unseen world or to appear to the living in bodily likeness</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong> <em>– adj. </em>extending or measured in a direction opposite to one chosen as positive</p>
<p><strong>counterpart </strong><em>– n. </em>one remarkably similar to another: a thing that fits another perfectly</p>
<p><strong>pedigree </strong><em>– n. </em>lineage or line of ancestors of a person or animal: purity of breed recorded by an ancestral line</p>
<p><strong>precise </strong><em>– adj. </em>exactly or sharply defined or stated</p>
<p><strong>emphasis </strong><em>– n. </em>the act or fact of giving stress to a word or syllable when speaking: special attention or importance given to something</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is Elon Musk Worth $55.8 Billion to Tesla?  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/is-elon-musk-worth-55-8-billion-to-tesla.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Tesla chief Elon Musk wants to move the company's incorporation, or registration, from the American state of Delaware to Texas. Musk said he will ask Tesla shareholders to vote on the move after a Delaware judge ruled against his 2018 pay deal valued at $55.8 billion.</p>
<p>"Never incorporate your company in the state of Delaware," Musk posted on social media service X shortly after the ruling.</p>
<p>Tesla and many major companies, including Amazon, Google, Disney, and Walmart, keep their headquarters in other states. But they all register in the small eastern state of Delaware because of its tax laws and business courts.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Tesla Chief Executive Officer Elon Musk gets in a Tesla car as he leaves a hotel in Beijing, China May 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Tingshu Wang)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2351c59a-5972-4a74-b6c7-314047701fd5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Tesla Chief Executive Officer Elon Musk gets in a Tesla car as he leaves a hotel in Beijing, China May 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Tingshu Wang)</span></div>
<p>The financial publication <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/business/incorporating-in-delaware/"><em>Forbes </em>reports</a> that 68 percent of the top American businesses are incorporated in Delaware. Companies that are registered in Delaware do not pay corporate income tax if they do not do business in the state. Even if they do business in the state, companies can also avoid paying corporate tax by setting up what is called a "shell" company. A shell company legally owns property but does not carry out any business.</p>
<p>Dan Coatsworth is an expert at AJ Bell, a British investment company. He told Reuters that Musk's plan is the kind of behavior from someone "who always looks for an <strong>alternative</strong> if he can't get what he wants."</p>
<p>Musk's idea, should he go through with the vote, is not without risk. Legal experts said investors might take legal action if he tried to move the state of incorporation to Texas. Legal action is even more likely if it was seen as a move to get his pay deal rather than to help Tesla.</p>
<p><strong>Musk's pay package</strong></p>
<p>In 2022, the research firm Equilar carried out a study for <em>The Associated Press.</em> The study said that the <strong>median</strong> pay deal for a chief executive officer, or CEO, of a company in the Standard &amp; Poor 500, an index of top companies, was valued at $14.8 million.</p>
<p>It would take an average worker at one of those companies more than 185 years to earn what their chief executive gets in just 12 months.</p>
<p>Musk's pay package of $55.8 billion, set in 2018, was much larger than usual. So, a shareholder brought legal action. His lawyer argued that it was proposed by company directors with ties to Musk. And shareholders were given misleading and incomplete information.</p>
<p>In 2018, Tesla estimated the value of Musk's compensation package at $2.28 billion. But its value has grown as Tesla's stock price increased. Under the plan, Musk would receive <strong>stock options</strong> each time Tesla's market value rose by $50 billion. That means Musk would have the chance to buy nearly 304 million shares for $23.34 each.</p>
<p>Tesla stock is now trading at about $190 a share compared with $21 at the start of 2018. By comparison, in 2022 the median worker at Tesla made $34,084.</p>
<p>Last week, Chancellor Kathaleen St. Jude McCormick of Delaware ruled that the process to set Musk's pay package was "<strong>flawed</strong>" and the price "unfair." She ruled that Tesla's directors lacked independence from Musk and the big pay package was not needed for Tesla to keep Musk or meet its performance goals.</p>
<p>McCormick's ruling moved Musk out of the top spot on the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.forbes.com/real-time-billionaires/#38acc5d43d78"><em>Forbes</em> list of wealthiest people</a>. The publication removed $25 billion from his wealth putting him below French businessman Bernard Arnault.</p>
<p><strong>How do companies decide on CEO pay?</strong></p>
<p>To decide how much to pay their CEO, company directors often look at how much other companies are paying theirs. General Motors, for example, looks at Boeing, Ford, IBM, and other large companies to set its pay.</p>
<p>In 2022, General Motors gave its CEO, Mary Barra, a pay package valued at $29 million. And Jim Farley, the CEO of Ford, another car company, received $22 million that year.</p>
<p>Although Tesla makes automobiles, investors often compare its stock with technology companies. Musk is often compared to Mark Zuckerberg of Meta and Apple's Tim Cook.</p>
<p>In 2023, Cook's pay was valued at $63.2 million. A year earlier, Cook received about $99 million.</p>
<p>Musk's supporters argue that he is not like any other CEO and should not be paid like other CEOs. They said he has built Tesla into the most valuable automaker in the world. Last year, Tesla sold more electric vehicles than any other company. And the company's success has forced the rest of the auto industry to plan for electric vehicles.</p>
<p>Business law experts say any new pay package for Musk will likely be back in court again without independent directors or changes in the decision process for pay.</p>
<p>Before the ruling, however, Musk wrote on X that he wanted Tesla company directors to double his share to give him 25 percent voting control of the company. If not, Musk said he would develop artificial intelligence and robotic software outside of the company.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from The Associated Press, Reuters and other sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>alternative</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>another possible choice that is different from the one currently under consideration</p>
<p><strong>median</strong> <em>–n.</em> the middle value in a group of numbers</p>
<p><strong>stock option </strong><em>–n.</em> a contract that gives the owner the right to buy stock at a set price</p>
<p><strong>flawed </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>containing a mistake or something that should not be there</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Remembering Chita Rivera  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/remembering-chita-rivera.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Groundbreaking American performer Chita Rivera died on January 30 in New York. She was 91 years old.</p>
<p>The famed dancer, singer and actor won many awards and honors in her long career on Broadway and beyond. Her work also broke through ethnic and racial barriers in American entertainment, helping to shape a path for Latin performers.</p>
<p>Her daughter, Lisa Mordente, announced her mother's death. She said Rivera died after a brief sickness.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this Aug. 2, 2015 file photo, Chita Rivera performs during the Chita Rivera: A Lot of Livin' to Do segment of the PBS 2015 Summer TCA Tour held at the Beverly Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, California. (Photo by Richard Shotwell/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3d5d4547-28a2-4dba-bdfb-007572369914_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this Aug. 2, 2015 file photo, Chita Rivera performs during the "Chita Rivera: A Lot of Livin' to Do" segment of the PBS 2015 Summer TCA Tour held at the Beverly Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, California. (Photo by Richard Shotwell/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>Rivera first gained wide notice in 1957 as Anita in the <strong>original</strong> production of the musical play <em>West Side Story</em>. She was still dancing on New York's Broadway stages a half-century later in 2015's <em>The Visit</em>.</p>
<p>"I wouldn't know what to do if I wasn't moving or telling a story to you or singing a song," she told the <em>Associated Press</em> at the time. "That's the spirit of my life, and I'm really so lucky to be able to do what I love, even at this time in my life."</p>
<p>Dolores Conchita Figueroa del Rivero was born January 23, 1933, in Washington, D.C. Her Puerto Rican father, Pedro del Rivero, was a musician who played in the United States Navy Band. He died when Chita was seven. Her mother Katherine was of Scottish and Italian ancestry.</p>
<p>Chita studied dance as a young girl and was accepted to a highly respected school for ballet. She was 17 when she won her first part in a musical.</p>
<p>"She was a true Broadway <strong>legend</strong>," playwright Paul Rudnick said on social media service X. "She always <strong>delivered</strong> and audiences adored her. The moment she stepped onstage, the world became more exciting and <strong>glorious</strong>."</p>
<p>Rivera rose from <strong>chorus line</strong> performer to star. Along the way, she worked with many of Broadway's other greatest playmakers, including Jerome Robbins, Leonard Bernstein, Bob Fosse, and Harold Prince.</p>
<p>She won two Tonys, the highest award for live theater in the United States. Her first came in 1984 with the production <em>The Rink</em>. She won again in 1993 for the play <em>Kiss of the Spider Woman</em>. An <em>Associated Press</em> theater critic wrote at the time that Rivera was "more than a musical theater star. She's a force of nature...."</p>
<p>The second Tony was an especially sweet victory for the star. Just five years earlier, Rivera had been in a serious car accident that crushed her right leg. It could have ended her career. After months of physical <strong>therapy</strong> to regain her dancing skills, she returned to the stage singing and dancing as energetically as ever.</p>
<p>She told the <em>AP</em>: "It never entered my mind that I wouldn't dance again. Never. I can't explain to you why. It's hard work getting back but that's what I'm doing."</p>
<p>When accepting a Special Tony Award for Lifetime Achievement in 2018, Rivera said "I wouldn't trade my life in the theater for anything, because theater is life."</p>
<p>In August 2009, U.S. President Barack Obama honored Rivera with the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian award of the United States. At the presentation of the medal, Rivera put her hand over her heart and shook her head in wonderment.</p>
<p>Rivera was married to dancer Tony Mordente from 1957 until 1966. Their daughter Lisa also became a performer and has appeared on Broadway.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>original </strong><em>– n. </em>not copied or imitated from something else; the first</p>
<p><strong>legend </strong><em>– n. </em>a person or thing that inspires legends; someone widely respected and praised for certain skills or successes</p>
<p><strong>deliver </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce the promised, desired, or expected results</p>
<p><strong>glorious </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely good;<em> </em>wonderful</p>
<p><strong>chorus line </strong><em><strong>– </strong>n. </em>a group of dancers and singers supporting the featured players in a musical comedy or revue</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong><em>– n. </em>medical treatment of impairment, injury, disease, or disorder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Women to Take Center Stage at the Grammys  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/women-to-take-center-stage-at-the-grammys.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American music industry holds its highest honors Sunday night in Los Angeles at the 67th Grammy Awards ceremony.</p>
<p>Artists including Taylor Swift and SZA, as well as songs from the Oscar-nominated movie <em>Barbie</em> lead the competition in nominations. And mostly women are nominated for Album of the Year, the top Grammy. Just one of the eight nominees is male.</p>
<p>SZA has the most nominations of any artist this year: nine in all.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - SZA performs at day one of the Astroworld Music Festival in Houston on Nov. 5, 2021. (Photo by Amy Harris/Invision/AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b053-08dc23522627_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - SZA performs at day one of the Astroworld Music Festival in Houston on Nov. 5, 2021. (Photo by Amy Harris/Invision/AP, File)</span></div>
<p>The wide female representation in nominations follows a year of huge success for women in the mostly male music business.</p>
<p>Swift's Eras Tour broke the record for <strong>ticket</strong> sales, passing that of British singer-songwriter Elton John. Beyoncé also played to full <strong>stadiums</strong>. And, Swift's concert film, also was a huge hit, earning more than $180 million in ticket sales.</p>
<p>"Women had a <strong>phenomenal</strong> year, not just in music, but in <em>Barbie</em> being the biggest-<strong>grossing</strong> movie," said Billboard magazine reporter Paul Grein. "Women dominated pop culture."</p>
<p>In addition to Swift and SZA, the other women nominated for this year's album prize are Miley Cyrus, Lana Del Rey, Olivia Rodrigo, Janelle Monae and boygenius. The group boygenius is musicians Julien Baker, Phoebe Bridgers, and Lucy Dacus. The single male artist nominated for Album of the Year is Jon Batiste.</p>
<p>It is just the 12th time in the Grammys' 66-year history, Grein said, that women received the majority of nominations for album of the year.</p>
<p>In other<strong> </strong>award fields, music from the <em>Barbie</em> movie received 12 Grammy nominations, including one for song of the year: Billie Eilish's, <em>What Was I Made For?</em></p>
<p><strong>Recording Academy recruits women</strong></p>
<p>The Recording Academy has been admitting an increasing number of female music makers as members in recent years. The Academy is the group of musicians, producers, engineers and others who vote on the Grammy nominees and winners. Since 2019, the percentage of female members has gone from 30 percent to 36 percent.</p>
<p>"They are <strong>infusing</strong> the membership with a lot of members who will probably see things differently," Grein said.</p>
<p>Some of the male artists normally in competition were between projects. Harry Styles, Bad Bunny and other past Grammy winners did not release new music during the <strong>eligibility</strong> period. Still, a University of Southern California study shows the percentage of women artists on Billboard Magazine's Hot 100 list at the end of 2023 reached 35 percent, a 12-year high.</p>
<p>Women also made gains behind the scenes, with women of color driving the first increase in female songwriting credits in 12 years. Almost 20 percent of songwriters are women, up from 14 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>Female musicians made a lot of progress in just a few years, Smith said.</p>
<p>"When you look at the data, you see that the collective action across the music industry is moving toward women," she said. "That we haven't seen before."</p>
<p>The number of female producers increased but remain mostly male. In 2023, women received 6.5 percent of producer credits. No women were nominated for the producer of the year Grammy.</p>
<p>But, on Sunday, several women could make history at the ceremony, including Swift and SZA.</p>
<p>Swift could become the first artist to win album of the year four times if her work <em>Midnights </em>wins the big prize. And, if SZA wins for her recording "<em>SOS</em>," she will be the first Black woman to win album of the year as lead artist since Lauryn Hill.</p>
<p>Hill received the honor 25 years ago.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ticket </strong><em>— n. </em>a piece of paper that allows you to see a show, participate in an event, travel on a vehicle, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stadium </strong><em>— n. </em>a very large usually roofless building that has a large open area surrounded by many rows of seats and that is used for sports events, concerts, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>phenomenal </strong><em>— adj. </em>very good or great : unusual in a way that is very impressive</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gross </strong><em>— n. </em>the amount of money earned before taxes, expenses, etc., are taken away</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>infuse </strong><em>— v. </em>to cause to be filled with something</p>
<p><strong>eligible</strong><em>— n. </em>able to be chosen for something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reduction and Assimilation  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/reduction-and-assimilation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about reduced syllables and assimilation.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-830c-08dc233deee0_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I would like you to explain to me in detail, if that is possible...</p>
<p>In spoken English, why do native speakers change or omit these letters, for example:</p>
<ol>
<li>I want to go. (I wanna go)</li>
<li>Handbag (hambag)</li>
<li>A and B (A n B)</li>
</ol>
<p>What's the rule behind this?</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>Adam</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Thanks, Adam, for your question.</p>
<p>You have found that people do not always say words the same way all the time. They sometimes change sounds to make them easier to say.</p>
<p>One example is <strong>syllable</strong> dropping, which we discussed in an earlier <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/syllable-dropping-in-speaking/6997962.html" target="_blank">Ask a Teacher</a>. <strong>Assimilation</strong> and reduction are other ways sounds can change when people are speaking quickly.</p>
<p>Two different sounds can start to sound the same when they are said quickly. This is called "assimilation."</p>
<p>This is what is happening in the word "handbag."</p>
<p>The /n/ sound is a nasal sound, which is made by air moving through our nose. The sound/b/ is produced by pressing the lips together. So, the /n/ sound is affected by the /b/ sound in "bag." The sound becomes /m/, a combination of a nasal sound and the <strong>labial</strong> sound.</p>
<p>The /d/ sound is then dropped.</p>
<p>/Handbag/</p>
<p>/Hambag/</p>
<p>Sometimes it is not just one sound within a word that is reduced, but a whole word, like in the examples of "wanna" or "A n' B."</p>
<p>Function words, like "to" and "and" are often reduced in everyday speech. This helps us to pay more attention to the more important words that carry meaning.</p>
<p>Most unstressed syllables and function words become shorter, softer and less clear. The vowel sound in "to," /oo/, gets reduced to another vowel sound "schwa," /<i></i>601;/.</p>
<p>"Want to" becomes "wanta," /<i></i>601;/. The two /t/ sounds drop off in fast speech. So, "want ta" becomes "wanna."</p>
<p>In "A and B," the "and" gets reduced to /<i></i>601;n/. So, <strong>phrases</strong> like "A and B" or "<strong>cream</strong> and sugar" become "A ‘n B" and "cream ‘n sugar."</p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Adam.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>syllable </strong><em>– n. </em>a unit of spoken language that consists of one or more vowel sounds alone or with one or more consonant sounds preceding or following</p>
<p><strong>assimilation</strong> – <em>n</em>. a sound changes in which some sounds (typically consonants or vowels) change to become more similar to other nearby sounds</p>
<p><strong>labial </strong><em>–adj. </em>involving one or both lips</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong><em><strong> </strong></em><em>– n.</em> a word or group of words forming a syntactic constituent with a single grammatical function</p>
<p><strong>cream</strong> – <em>n</em>. a thick white liquid taken from milk used in cooking, baking and coffee</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Is Canada Limiting Foreign Students?  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/why-is-canada-limiting-foreign-students.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Canada recently announced a two-year limit on the number of foreign students given permission to study in the country. The move is partly to ease a growing housing shortage.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency recently reported on some of the details of the plan:</p>
<p><strong>What are the details?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6941-08dbcb2ac7cd_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Marc Miller is Canada's immigration minister. Miller said the government led by the Liberal Party of Canada will introduce a temporary, two-year limit on student visas. That will result in about 364,000 student visas in 2024. The government said that is a cut of 35 percent from the year before.</p>
<p>The new proposals will also set limits on <strong>postgraduate</strong> work permits issued to foreign students. The new limits will likely cause many postgraduate students to return to their home countries.</p>
<p>The permits were formerly seen as an easy path to securing permanent <strong>residency</strong>. People in master's or post-doctoral programs will be <strong>eligible </strong>for a three-year work permit.</p>
<p>However, people who are married to foreign students in undergraduate and lower-level college programs will no longer be able to receive work permits. The acceptance of new study permit requests in 2025 will be reconsidered at the end of the current year, Miller said.</p>
<p><strong>Why has the government changed its policy?</strong></p>
<p>Canada has become a popular place for international students. It has been easy to receive work permits after finishing study programs in the country. But the increase in international students has led to a shortage of <strong>rental</strong> homes. This has caused the price of rent to go up. In December, the cost of rent nationwide rose 7.7 percent from a year earlier, government data shows.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's popularity has decreased partly because of increasing living costs. Opposition Conservative Party leader Pierre Poilievre has taken a lead over Trudeau in public opinion studies. Elections are expected to be held next year.</p>
<p>The government has also been concerned about the quality of education offered by some schools.</p>
<p><strong>Who will this affect?</strong></p>
<p>Canada's government says international students bring in about $16.4 billion to the nation's economy. The new policy will hurt many colleges and universities.</p>
<p>Ontario, the most populous area, or province, has the biggest share of international students. Some businesses, including restaurants and <strong>retail</strong> industries, have warned that a limit on foreign students will create a shortage of temporary workers.</p>
<p>For example, restaurants across Canada are dealing with a worker shortage. It is estimated there are nearly 100,000 available jobs. International students made up 4.6 percent of the 1.1 million workers in the food service industry in 2023, an unnamed industry group told Reuters.</p>
<p>Canadian banks will gain from the new rules for international students. Each student will be required to have a Guaranteed Investment Certificates (GIC) of more than $15,000. The amount is required for international students to be able to cover living costs. The new GIC is more than double the amount from the earlier policy.</p>
<p>Many of Canada's foreign students, about 40 percent, come from India. China coming in second with about 12 percent, official data from 2022 shows.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Wa Lone reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>postgraduate</strong><strong> </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to studies done after earning a bachelor's degree or other degree</p>
<p><strong>residency </strong>– <em>n</em>. legal permission to live in a place</p>
<p><strong>eligible </strong>– <em>adj</em>. able to do or receive something</p>
<p><strong>rent </strong>– <em>v</em>. money that you pay in return for being able to use property and especially to live in an apartment or house that belongs to someone else</p>
<p><strong>affordable </strong>– <em>v</em>. to be able to pay for (something)</p>
<p><strong>retail </strong>– <em>adj</em>. relating to the business of selling things directly to customers for their own use</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>It Has Never Been More Costly to See the Super Bowl  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/it-has-never-been-more-costly-to-see-the-super-bowl.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p><strong>Tickets</strong> for the American football Super Bowl game are among the hardest to get in all of sports. Because of that, some websites that buy and re-sell tickets have set prices for the upcoming game in Las Vegas, Nevada at almost $10,000.</p>
<p>The National Football League championship game between the Kansas City Chiefs and San Francisco 49ers is on Sunday, February 11.</p>
<p>The Chiefs won last year's Super Bowl. They feature star quarterback Patrick Mahomes and Travis Kelce, the boyfriend of singer Taylor Swift. Many people believe Swift will fly to the game after performing in Japan only one day earlier.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Kansas City Chiefs players and staff celebrate after the NFL Super Bowl 57 football game against the Philadelphia Eagles, February 12, 2023, in Glendale, Arizona. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/15bbfd37-1b4f-47c8-8a70-57ecf60ea954_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Kansas City Chiefs players and staff celebrate after the NFL Super Bowl 57 football game against the Philadelphia Eagles, February 12, 2023, in Glendale, Arizona. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>The 49ers are one of the most popular teams in the western part of the U.S. Las Vegas is a busy, <strong>tourist</strong> city known for its hotels and <strong>casinos</strong>. It is the first-ever Super Bowl in Las Vegas. For many years, the league did not want to have games in Las Vegas because the city permits sports gambling. That changed when the Oakland Raiders moved to Las Vegas to play in a new stadium before the 2020 season.</p>
<p>The combination of two well-known teams plus a city that many people like to visit means tickets on a website called TickPick are in high demand. They are re-selling for almost double last year's cost. The Chiefs defeated the Philadelphia Eagles in the Super Bowl last year near Phoenix, Arizona.</p>
<p>Before this year, the Super Bowl with the highest re-sale ticket price was in 2021 when the Tampa Bay Buccaneers defeated the Chiefs in Tampa, Florida. That year, however, tickets were limited because of restrictions connected to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>TickPick said the highest prices for a non-COVID Super Bowl came in 2020 when the Chiefs and 49ers played in Miami, Florida. The average ticket that year was over $6,000. TickPick, however, noted that prices for this year might go down as the game gets closer.</p>
<p>Brett Goldberg is the co-CEO for TickPick. In a message to the Associated Press, he wrote: "<strong>Location</strong> has always <strong>impacted</strong> demand for a Super Bowl, but Vegas takes things to a whole other level." He said Las Vegas is already "the <strong>entertainment</strong> capital of the world."</p>
<p>Sometimes, Goldberg wrote, two successful teams push down demand, because the average fan is tired of seeing them play again. However, he noted prices are high this year because "fans want to experience their team winning a Super Bowl in Vegas."</p>
<p>StubHub is another ticket-selling website. Prices on that site were over $9,000. StubHub said tickets are selling faster this year than in recent years.</p>
<p>"The demand has far surpassed the last time Kansas City and San Francisco met in Miami," said a spokesperson from StubHub.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ticket </strong>–n. a piece of paper or digital proof that gives the holder the right to see an event or performance</p>
<p><strong>tourist </strong>–n. a person who travels for pleasure and not business</p>
<p><strong>casino </strong>–n. a place where people play games of chance in an effort to win money</p>
<p><strong>location </strong>–n. the place where something is</p>
<p><strong>impacted </strong><em>–adj.</em> affected or influenced</p>
<p><strong>entertainment </strong>–n. the industry aimed at providing performances, activities and services to give people pleasure</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you planning to pay attention to this year's Super Bowl?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australian Filmmaker Shows Japanese Single Mothers, Children Face Poverty  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/australian-filmmaker-shows-japanese-single-mothers-children-face-poverty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In wealthy countries, like Japan, poverty is sometimes considered a <strong>taboo </strong>subject. But an Australian filmmaker, Rionne McAvoy, wants to share the stories of women and children in poverty in Japan in his documentary film <em>The Ones Left Behind</em>.</p>
<p>The film was released last year. It shows single mothers raising their children in poverty. The women work hard. They sleep a few hours at night. And they try to balance working with childcare and housework.</p>
<p>McAvoy said he wanted to deal with a <strong>topic</strong> that no one wanted to discuss. The film shows discussions with poor women and experts on poverty. He said the film also shows a different side of Japanese <strong>society</strong>, where getting married and becoming a stay-at-home mother is normal for many women.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo provided by Japan Media Services shows a scene from The Ones Left Behind: The Plight of Single Mothers in Japan, directed by Rionne McAvoy. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/28524da2-5501-45e1-beed-c0e09774c9ae_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo provided by Japan Media Services shows a scene from The Ones Left Behind: The Plight of Single Mothers in Japan, directed by Rionne McAvoy. </span></div>
<p>"In Japan, it's very taboo. I think it's a very <strong>apt</strong> title because I feel that single mothers and their children have really been left behind in society."</p>
<p>The film shows one woman who works almost twelve hours a day and earns less than $1,350 a month. That amount is low for a county where the cost of living is high. Monthly <strong>rent</strong> for one small room can cost one third of that amount.</p>
<p>Tomiko Nakayama is one of the women in the film. She said, "I have to do everything on my own." Another woman almost cries when she describes how her child stopped asking her to come to "take-your-parent-to-school" days.</p>
<p>Japan has one of the highest rates of childhood poverty although it is one of the wealthiest nations. One in seven children live in poverty in Japan. Almost half of single-parent homes are considered poor.</p>
<p>Japanese society often favors men who work full-time. Women sometimes receive lower pay and fewer benefits than their male counterparts, while working full-time and overtime.</p>
<p>Ayuri McAvoy produced the film and is also McAvoy's wife. She was formerly a single mother. But they say that is not why they made the film.</p>
<p>Rionne McAvoy said that the country's traditional culture makes women accept their difficult lives and makes them <strong>ashamed</strong> to ask for help. He told the Associated Press that the women are "keeping their public face and private face separate."</p>
<p>Akihiko Kato is a professor at Meiji University in Tokyo. He appears in the film. Kato said that Japan does not have a system to legally force fathers to pay for their children if the parents are separated. The Japanese government has promised to give money to people with children, but this is slow to come, he said.</p>
<p>Kato said that this is partly why birth rates in Japan have been so low. There were 1.2 million births in the year 2000 compared to fewer than 800,000 births in 2022.</p>
<p>Some people believe the modern idea of the <strong>nuclear family</strong> means that single parents, mostly mothers, have to do everything on their own. People like grandparents, neighbors and extended family members no longer seem to be able to help with children.</p>
<p>Yanfei Zhou is a social science professor at Japan Women's University in Tokyo who also appears in the film. She said that these changes have serious effects on children. The divide between rich and poor is growing, and children will end up in poverty, she said.</p>
<p>The film won the Best Documentary prize at the Miyakojima Charity International Film Festival last year. It was also officially chosen for the Yokohama International Film Festival.</p>
<p>McAvoy said he has long been interested in telling the story of those who society had forgotten and who do not have a voice. He said that being on the outside of Japanese culture has helped him to share stories with a new viewpoint and without <strong>bias</strong>. He said his next film will be about young people dying by suicide in Japan.</p>
<p>McAvoy said, "It's one thing we can do more of in society: to try recognize people's cries for help."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Yuri Kageyama reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>taboo</strong> – <em>n</em>. something that is not acceptable to talk about or do</p>
<p><strong>topic </strong>–n. the subject of writing or a discussion</p>
<p><strong>society </strong>–n. people who live together in a large area under the same rules, traditions and values</p>
<p><strong>apt</strong> – <em>adj</em>. likely to do something</p>
<p><strong>rent</strong> <em>–</em><em> </em><em>n.</em> a regular payment for the use of property such as the use of a place to live like an apartment or home</p>
<p><strong>ashamed<strong> </strong></strong>– <em>adj. </em>feeling regret and embarrassment for what you have done</p>
<p><strong>nuclear families</strong> – <em>n</em>. a family group consisting of parents and their children living in one home</p>
<p><strong>bias </strong>– <em>n</em>. a tendency to support one side of an argument over another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>European Farmers Keep Up Protests During EU Meeting  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/european-farmers-keep-up-protests-during-eu-meeting.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>European farmers held protests Thursday to demand government help in dealing with rising costs and environmental rules.</p>
<p>One of the protests happened in Brussels, Belgium, where EU leaders gathered for a <strong>summit</strong> meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some farmers drove tractors onto the grounds of the European Parliament building to bring attention to their demands. Protesters also lit off fireworks and threw eggs and bottles at police in the area, The Associated Press reported.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Farmers gather outside the European Parliament for a protest as European leaders meet for an EU summit in Brussels, Thursday, Feb. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9958-08dc2356d92f_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Farmers gather outside the European Parliament for a protest as European leaders meet for an EU summit in Brussels, Thursday, Feb. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla)</span></div>
<p>Smoke could also be seen around parts of Brussels as some farmers set pieces of <strong>hay</strong> on fire, the news agency said. Security forces put out the fires and moved in to protect EU buildings.</p>
<p>In Paris, French farmers continued to block traffic on major roadways around the city. Farmers in several European nations have been holding mostly peaceful protests in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The farmers say it is harder to make a good living because of high operating costs. Costs for fuel and <strong>fertilizer </strong>have risen sharply in Europe since Russia's invasion of Ukraine. They also say they have been hurt by increased competition and weather conditions.</p>
<p>France's government sent in armored vehicles to Paris' large Rungis food market, which was targeted by demonstrators. French police told Reuters news agency they arrested 79 people who entered a storage center at the market.</p>
<p>The market is an important supplier of fruits and vegetables to France and other nations. Rungis has repeatedly become a target for European farmers, many of whom traveled a long way to bring their tractors there.</p>
<p>One farmer who traveled to Brussels to protest was 26-year-old Luca Mouton. He told Reuters, "Time is up. (EU leaders must) think of the farmers. Talk to the farmers rather than about the farmers, discuss what is possible. We are open to <strong>dialogue</strong>."</p>
<p>Jean-Francois Ricker is a farmer from southern Belgium who spent the night in the cold near EU headquarters. He told the AP he hoped a lot of protesters would show up to demonstrate how important the issues are to farmers across Europe. "We are going to show that we do not agree...," said Ricker.</p>
<p>The purpose of Thursday's EU summit was mainly to approve a proposal to provide Ukraine with a new $54 billion aid deal. But Belgian Prime Minister Alexander De Croo urged EU leaders to also hear the farmers' demands. Belgium currently holds the EU presidency.</p>
<p>De Croo said governments "need to make sure that (farmers) can get the right price for the high-quality products that they provide." He also urged an easing of some environmental rules that farmers have said can hurt their profits.</p>
<p>Farmers are an important voting group within the EU as well as in their own countries. This has led some leaders to offer some new proposals.</p>
<p>The European Commission announced plans Wednesday to offer protections to farmers facing increased competition from low-cost imports from Ukraine. The body also proposed easing restrictions on how much of a farmer's own land he can use while still receiving support from the EU.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week, France's government promised to provide farmers emergency aid and some new controls on imported food. On Thursday, French Prime Minister Gabriel Attal offered more measures. They included a move to permit farmers to use more <strong>pesticides</strong> if other nations do the same and an offer to increase financial aid and tax breaks.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>summit </strong><em>–n.</em> a meeting of high-level officials or national leaders</p>
<p><strong>hay </strong><em>–n. </em>dried grass</p>
<p><strong>fertilizer </strong><em>– n. </em>a natural or chemical substance you put on land in order to make plants grow well</p>
<p><strong>dialogue </strong><em>– n. </em>an official discussion between countries or groups of people</p>
<p><strong>pesticide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical that is used to kill insects that damage plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>A Trip Around the World  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/a-trip-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Pack your bags, make sure your travel documents are in order.</p>
<p>Today we are taking a trip around the world — if only in our imagination.</p>
<p>For this Everyday Grammar lesson, we will leave behind our grammar books. We will instead look at messages from friends who are in Pakistan, Spain, Belgium, and Japan.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-e19c-08dc229cb586_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Our goal: to learn more about the populations of different countries. We will learn about English along the way.</p>
<p>Let's begin our journey...</p>
<p><strong>Background </strong></p>
<p>In a recent lesson about the noun "population," we asked our listeners the following questions:</p>
<p><em>What is the population like in your country or city? Is the population increasing or decreasing?</em></p>
<p>Here are some of the answers we received:</p>
<p><strong>Pakistan </strong></p>
<p>Saeed wrote to us from Lahore, Pakistan. Saeed noted:</p>
<p><em>City Lahore – Pakistan </em></p>
<p><em>Increasing </em></p>
<p><em>In 2023 was 13,979,000, a 3.23% increase from 2022. </em></p>
<p>Saeed presented some exact numbers about the city of Lahore.</p>
<p>Our suggestion is to use complete sentences. In other words, Saeed could update the statement to something like this:</p>
<p><em>The population of Lahore, Pakistan, is increasing. </em></p>
<p><em>In 2023, the population was 13,979,000, a 3.23% increase from 2022. </em></p>
<p><strong>Spain </strong></p>
<p>Now that we have learned some information about a big city in Pakistan, we can learn about a major European city. Rafael writes to us from Barcelona, Spain.</p>
<p>Here is part of the message:</p>
<p><em>...The populacion in my city is decreasing due to low birth rate, although the total count is maintained thanks to inmigration....The arrival of people from very different cultures creates some integration problems, but it helps to solve other important ones derived from the general aging.... </em></p>
<p>
Rafael wrote an excellent message. Our main suggestion is to double <strong>check</strong> the <strong>spelling</strong> of a few words: population and immigration.</p>
<p>In terms of grammar, one idea is to include an article such as "the" before "birth rate." Definite and indefinite articles help show the difference between a specific and a general noun.</p>
<p>So, we could update Rafael's statement to something like this: "The population in my city is decreasing due to the low birth rate..."</p>
<p><strong>Belgium </strong></p>
<p>Now let's look at part of a message from Jean Claude, in Belgium.</p>
<p><em>...The population of Belgium was 11.67 million inhabitants on January 2023. The Belgian population increased by 0.98% compared to the previous year... </em></p>
<p>Jean Claude's message was clear and to the point. There is one suggestion we have. It is in the first sentence. We have the <strong>phrase </strong>"on January 2023" but instead we should use the short word "in," like this:</p>
<p><em>The population of Belgium was 11.67 million<strong> inhabitants</strong> in January 2023. </em></p>
<p>We usually use the short word "on" for an exact date, such as "on January 4th" or "on January 27th"</p>
<p>Next, we are in for a long trip to the other side of the world. A friend from Japan would like to tell us about the population of the island country.</p>
<p><strong>Japan </strong></p>
<p>Here is part of a message from an unnamed reader:</p>
<p><em>According to the national statics, Japan's population has been decreasing almost 600,000 people per a year. There are more than 120,000,000 people in Japan now. However, I heard the population will be under 100,000,000 in 30 years. </em></p>
<p>We suggest the following changes to the first sentence. The term "statics" should be changed to "<strong>statistics</strong>." In addition, we often use the short word "by" after decreasing. We can then remove "a" from its position before "year." So, we might update the sentence to something like this:</p>
<p><em>According to national statistics, Japan's population has been decreasing by almost 600,000 people per year. </em></p>
<p><strong>Lessons </strong></p>
<p>That brings us to the end of our imaginative trip around the world.</p>
<p>We received many wonderful pieces of writing – those that were included in today's lesson and many others that were not.</p>
<p>Overall, the general recommendations are to pay careful attention to spelling and to double check short words – prepositions, articles, and so on.</p>
<p>We hope that you have learned a little more about the world, as well as some ideas to use when you write in English.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>check </strong><em>–v. </em>to make sure something is correct by looking at it or reading it again</p>
<p><strong>spelling </strong><em>–n.</em> the way the letters in a word are correctly written, or spelled</p>
<p><strong>phrase </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
<p><strong>inhabitant</strong> <em>– n.</em> a person that lives in a particular place</p>
<p><strong>statistic</strong> <em>– n.</em> (often plural) a number that represents a piece of information</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Elon Musk’s Neuralink Announces First Human Implant  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/elon-musk-s-neuralink-announces-first-human-implant.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Elon Musk says his company Neuralink has placed an experimental brain device in a person in the first human test of the technology.</p>
<p>Neuralink describes the coin-sized device as a "brain-computer <strong>interface</strong>." It is designed to be <strong>implanted</strong> inside the brain through a medical operation.</p>
<p>Musk announced the news on the social media service he owns, X. The billionaire businessman is also the owner of Tesla and SpaceX. His company Neuralink aims to establish direct communication links between the brain and computers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Neuralink logo and Elon Musk are seen in this illustration taken, December 19, 2022. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0edb-08dc22109779_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Neuralink logo and Elon Musk are seen in this illustration taken, December 19, 2022. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>"The first human received an implant from @Neuralink (Sunday) and is recovering well," Musk <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk">wrote</a>. He added that first results of the implanted device showed "promising neuron <strong>spike</strong>" activity.</p>
<p>A spike is a term for a method neurons use to communicate with each other. The <em>Cambridge Learner's Dictionary</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/dictionary/learner-english/neuron">defines</a> a neuron as "a nerve cell that carries messages between your brain and other parts of your body."</p>
<p>The device includes an extremely small computer and extremely thin wires that connect to a part of the brain that controls <strong>intent </strong>of movement.</p>
<p>Neuralink says the implant is designed to treat brain disorders and help serious back injury victims regain body movement. Company officials also say it might be used one day to help <strong>blind</strong> people see again.</p>
<p>The company has said an early goal of the brain-computer interface will be to give people the ability to control basic computer tasks using thoughts alone. Musk says that in the future, the device might also be used to improve human intelligence in an effort to keep up with supercomputers and artificial intelligence (AI) technology.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-approves-testing-of-neuralink-brain-implant-in-humans/7117607.html">approved</a> human testing of the Neuralink device last May.</p>
<p>Neuralink reposted Musk's statement about the implant in a message on X.</p>
<p>In another message on X, Musk wrote that the first Neuralink product is called "Telepathy." He said the goal of the product is to permit users to control smartphones or computers "just by thinking." Musk also noted the first users would be people who have lost the use of their arms or legs.</p>
<p>It remains unclear how well the brain-computer interface system or similar devices will work in humans. FDA-approved trials, like the one permitted for Neuralink, aim to collect data on the safety and effectiveness of proposed products.</p>
<p>Neuralink is not alone in developing systems designed to link the human nervous system to computers. The website clinicaltrials.gov <a class="wsw__a" href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/search?cond=brain%20computer%20interface&amp;aggFilters=status:not%20rec%20enr%20act">reports</a> there are currently more than 40 brain computer interface trials going on in places around the world.</p>
<p>Reuters reported that in the past, Neuralink was fined by the U.S. Department of Transportation for violating rules covering the movement of dangerous substances. The fines against Neuralink totaled $2,480 and the company agreed to fix its problems concerning the violations, the news agency said.</p>
<p>Neuralink carried out earlier trials of the implant using m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s, pigs and sheep. Reuters has also reported on the company's animal experiments in the past.</p>
<p>Some Neuralink employees told Reuters in 2022 the company had made mistakes in its animal testing. They said the mistakes came because the process was hurried. This led to more animal deaths than necessary, the employees said.</p>
<p>In one 2021 case, Reuters reported that Neuralink implanted 25 out of 60 pigs with the wrong-sized devices. All the pigs were later killed. Employees told the news agency such mistakes could have been easily avoided with more preparation.</p>
<p>Last September, Musk wrote in a social media message that "no m<i><i>onkey</i></i> has died as a result of a Neuralink implant." He added that the company chose "<strong>terminal</strong>" m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s to limit risks to healthy animals.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse and Neuralink.</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>interface </strong><em>– n. </em>a connection between two pieces of electronic equipment, or between a person and a computer</p>
<p><strong>implant </strong><em>– n. </em>a device placed inside the body in a medical operation</p>
<p><strong>spike </strong><em>– n. </em>a sudden change or rise in something</p>
<p><strong>intent </strong><em>– n. </em>what a person wants and plans to do</p>
<p><strong>blind </strong><em>– adj. </em>lacking or deficient in sight</p>
<p><strong>terminal </strong><em>– adj. </em>nearing or close to death: being in the final stages of a deadly disease</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Garden Group Names 2024 ‘Year of African Violet’  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/garden-group-names-2024-year-of-african-violet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The African violet, a plant from Tanzania that came to the U.S. in the late 1800s, received a special honor from the National Garden Bureau (NGB).</p>
<p>The organization named 2024 "The Year of the African Violet." Other plants, flowers and vegetables for 2024 include: squash, Angelonia, lily, buddleia and hosta. Past years honored amaryllis, orchids and broccoli.</p>
<p>Jessica Damiano is the garden writer for the Associated Press news service. She recently wrote about the African violet.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by the National Garden Bureau shows a bi-color African violet plant. The NGB has named 2024 as the Year of the African Violet. (National Garden Bureau via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f0a22700-c5b4-400f-a8c1-0dfe3c61952c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by the National Garden Bureau shows a bi-color African violet plant. The NGB has named 2024 as the Year of the African Violet. (National Garden Bureau via AP)</span></div>
<p>Damiano said the violet has been one of the most popular house plants in the U.S. since it arrived. She said the plant, however, is not a violet. It only has the name because of its colorful, purple and white leaves.</p>
<p>In fact, she noted, they are related to the Saintpaulia <strong>genus</strong>. They are named for German Walter von Saint Paul.</p>
<p>The popularity of the plant is one reason why the NGB chose the violet as the "houseplant" of the year, said Diane M. Blazek, the organization's director. She said the plant's name has appeared over 300,000 times on social media.</p>
<p>Beyond popularity, Blazek noted, the violets are easy to grow and people who <strong>breed</strong> flowers are working on creating new <strong>varieties</strong>. Blazek said, "they are coming through the pipeline."</p>
<p>Blazek said people once thought of the violets as "Grandma's plants," or that they were no longer popular. But, she said, the violet "has not gone out of favor at all."</p>
<p>The NGB started in 1920. The group aimed to give <strong>reliable</strong> gardening information to Americans, many of whom had only recently started growing plants at home. The founder was James Burdett. He helped develop the idea of "victory gardens." The gardens started during World War I as way for Americans to grow some of their own food.</p>
<p>Today, the NGB continues the work started by Burdett. It recommends plants, flowers and vegetables each year.</p>
<p>Many people like the African violet because it is easy to grow. It does not need direct sunlight; it does not need too much water and does not need a lot of fertilizer. However, it must receive special care to do extremely well.</p>
<p>Blazek said the plants like <strong>moisture</strong> in the air. So, if you live in a very dry place, they might not do well. If you bring them inside during winter, Damiano suggests, you should run a device that adds moisture to the air – a humidifier – before you take them back outside. They need warmth but do not do well in high heat. Be sure to consider your climate before planting them.</p>
<p>In spring and summer, Damiano said, if the plants are indoors, place them near a window that faces north or east. That way they do not get too much sun. In the winter, the plants may be placed closer to windows because the sun is not too strong at that time for people who live in mid-northern climates.</p>
<p>Feed the plants only every two to three months. Be sure to use a <strong>fertilizer</strong> for African violets. And do not worry about their roots getting <strong>crowded</strong> by other plants – they like <strong>cozy</strong> pots.</p>
<p>With good care, the violets may show their colors all year.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>genus </strong>–<em>n</em>. a group of plants or animals that is bigger than a species but smaller than a family</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong>–<em>v</em>. to raise animals and plants so they reproduce and have offspring with similar or better qualities</p>
<p><strong>variety </strong>–<em>n</em>. a different form of a similar group of things</p>
<p><strong>reliable </strong>–<em>adj</em>. able to be trusted or depended upon</p>
<p><strong>moisture </strong>– <em>n. </em>the amount of liquid in the air or in soil or in a piece of cloth</p>
<p><strong>fertilizer </strong>– <em>n. </em>food and nutrients made to help plants grow</p>
<p><strong>crowded </strong>– <em>adj. </em>a number of things together in a small space</p>
<p><strong>cozy </strong>– <em>adj. </em>comfortable, soft and close together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Renewed Interest in Amelia Earhart’s Final Flight  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/renewed-interest-in-amelia-earhart-s-final-flight.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>An unclear <strong>sonar</strong> image recorded by a private pilot has renewed interest in a past mystery: What happened to Amelia Earhart, the pilot who disappeared in 1937 with her plane?</p>
<p>Many searches have found nothing. But Tony Romeo now believes his new South Carolina-based sea exploration company captured a partial image of Earhart's famous plane.</p>
<p>Researchers and explorers are hopeful. But whether Earhart's plane lies at about 4,800 meters beneath the ocean remains to be seen.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Amelia Earhart's plane is seen at the Smithsonian's National Air and Space Museum in Washington, Tuesday, Nov. 16, 2010, after an overhaul of one of the museum's original galleries, the Pioneers of Flight exhibit. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3da668ae-0272-4f7f-be55-2feedf2cecac_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Amelia Earhart's plane is seen at the Smithsonian's National Air and Space Museum in Washington, Tuesday, Nov. 16, 2010, after an overhaul of one of the museum's original galleries, the "Pioneers of Flight" exhibit. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)</span></div>
<p><strong>How was the object found?</strong></p>
<p>Romeo said he had long held interest in the Earhart mystery. So, he bought a $9 million underwater <strong>drone</strong> from a Norwegian company. The drone is called the Hugin 6000. It includes the newest technology. It can dive down to 6,000 meters.</p>
<p>A 16-person crew began a search in the western Pacific Ocean in September 2023. They searched over 13,400 square kilometers of seafloor. The crew searched around Howland Island between Papua New Guinea and Hawaii.</p>
<p>But it was not until the team looked at the sonar data in December that they saw the unclear yellow outline of what looked like a plane.</p>
<p>"In the end, we came out with an image of a target that we believe very strongly is Amelia's <strong>aircraft</strong>," Romeo told the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>The next step is taking a camera underwater to better examine the unidentified object. If camera images confirm the explorers' hopes, Romeo said the goal would be to raise Earhart's airplane.</p>
<p>Romeo said his team undertook the trip to "solve <strong>aviation's</strong> greatest unsolved mystery." Depending on what they find, they might answer if Earhart and her <strong>navigator</strong>, Fred Noonan, escaped after hitting the ocean, or learn more about what went wrong.</p>
<p><strong>The mystery of Earhart</strong></p>
<p>Earhart and Noonan disappeared while flying from New Guinea to Howland Island. That trip was part of her attempt to become the first female pilot to fly around the world. She had radioed that she was running low on fuel.</p>
<p>The Navy searched but found nothing. The U.S. government's official position has been that Earhart and Noonan went down with their plane.</p>
<p>Since then, there have been many theories. They include that Earhart was taken by <strong>aliens</strong>, lived in New Jersey under another name, she was killed by the Japanese, or died on an island.</p>
<p>"Amelia is America's favorite missing person," Romeo said.</p>
<p><strong>‘We need to see more'</strong></p>
<p>Sea <strong>archaeologist</strong> James Delgado said Romeo's possible find would change the story, but "we need to see more."</p>
<p>"Let's drop some cameras down there and take a look," said Delgado. He is senior vice president of the archaeological company SEARCH.</p>
<p>Delgado said Romeo's search used the newest technologies that were once only available to the government.</p>
<p>But he said Romeo's team must provide detailed documentation to prove it is Earhart's plane.</p>
<p>If the object really is the historic aircraft, the question for the team is if it is safe to raise. How much of the plane is left would be decided by how smoothly Earhart landed," said Dorothy Cochrane of the National Air and Space Museum.</p>
<p>"That's where you have to really look at this image and say, ‘What have we got here?'" said Cochrane.</p>
<p><strong>What if Earhart's plane has been found?</strong></p>
<p>If the discovery turns out to be her plane, international rules for underwater archaeology would suggest that the aircraft remain where it is, said Ole Varmer. He is a retired lawyer with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and an advisor at The Ocean Foundation, an environmental group based in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Less damaging research can still be carried out to find why the plane crashed, Varmer said.</p>
<p>Varmer added, "You <strong>preserve</strong> as much of the story as you can." And he said, "When you <strong>salvage</strong> it, you're destroying part of the site, which can provide information."</p>
<p>Raising the plane and showing it to the public would likely cost hundreds of millions of dollars, Varmer said. And while Romeo could possibly make a salvage claim in a court, the plane's owner has the right to deny it.</p>
<p>Earhart bought the plane with money raised, at least in part, by the Purdue Research Foundation, Purdue University in Indiana said in a blog. She planned to return the aircraft to the school.</p>
<p>Romeo said the team believes the plane belongs in the Smithsonian. He said the issue likely presents a new kind of legal case. He said his exploration company will "deal with those as they come up."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>James Pollard and Ben Finley reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sonar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a device used for finding things that are underwater by using sound waves</p>
<p><strong>drone </strong>– <em>n</em>. a type of small aircraft that flies without a pilot</p>
<p><strong>aircraft </strong><em>– n. </em>a machine (such as an airplane or a helicopter) that flies through the air</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong><em>– n. </em>the business or practice of flying airplanes or helicopters</p>
<p><strong>navigate </strong><em>– v.</em> to find the way to get to a place when you are traveling in a ship, airplane, or car</p>
<p><strong>alien </strong><em>– n. </em>a creature that comes from somewhere other than the planet Earth</p>
<p><strong>archeology </strong>– <em>n</em>. a science that deals with past human life and activities by studying the bones or tools of ancient people</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong>– <em>v</em>. to keep (something) in its original state or in good condition</p>
<p><strong>salvage </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove (something) from a place so that it will not be damaged, destroyed, or lost</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Announce Successful Rhino Embryo Transfer  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/researchers-announce-successful-rhino-embryo-transfer.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists in Berlin announced recently the first successful embryo <strong>transfer</strong> in a white rhinoceros.</p>
<p>The transfer, which occurred in a southern white rhinoceros, offers hope for saving the northern white rhino from completely dying off.</p>
<p><strong>Two kinds of white rhinoceros </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt=" FILE - Keeper Zachariah Mutai attends to Fatu, one of only two northern white rhinos left in the world, in the pen at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Laikipia county in Kenya. (AP Photo/Sunday Alamba, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7c45acc8-d93e-4863-a367-918b44541b3f_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"> FILE - Keeper Zachariah Mutai attends to Fatu, one of only two northern white rhinos left in the world, in the pen at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Laikipia county in Kenya. (AP Photo/Sunday Alamba, File)</span></div>
<p>The white rhinoceros includes two different <strong>subspecies</strong>, the northern and the southern. The last male northern white rhino died in 2018. Only two female members of the subspecies remain. Neither of them can carry a baby.</p>
<p>Southern white rhinos are more numerous.</p>
<p>Researchers hope to use eggs and sperm from northern white rhinos to produce embryos that will be put into southern white rhino surrogate mothers.</p>
<p>A surrogate is something that performs the duties of something else.</p>
<p>To test the plan, scientists said they transferred the embryo of a southern white rhino into a surrogate southern white rhino mother at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Kenya on September 24, 2023.</p>
<p>However, the research team only learned of the pregnancy after the surrogate mother died of a bacterial infection in November 2023. The embryo was discovered during an examination of the body after death.</p>
<p>Even with the death, researchers found reasons to be hopeful.</p>
<p>The international BioRescue team, a group backed by the German government, confirmed recently that the operation had produced a successful pregnancy of 70 days, with a well-developed 6.4-centimeter-long male embryo.</p>
<p>"We <strong>achieved</strong> together something which was not believed to be possible," said Thomas Hildebrandt of the Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research.</p>
<p>"That is really a <strong>milestone</strong> to allow us to produce northern white rhino calves in the next two, two and a half years," Hildebrandt said.</p>
<p><strong>Too late?</strong></p>
<p>The northern white rhinoceros subspecies has only two known examples left in the world. The Ol-Pejeta Conservancy in Kenya says that Najin, a 34-year-old, and her 23-year-old offspring, Fatu, both cannot naturally reproduce.</p>
<p>In 2018, the last male white rhino, Sudan, was 45 when he was <strong>euthanized</strong> because of age-related problems. He was Najin's father. Scientists stored his semen and that of four other dead rhinos.</p>
<p>Some conservation groups have argued that it is probably too late to save the northern white rhino using the method known as <strong>in vitro </strong>fertilization.</p>
<p>The species once lived in Chad, Sudan, Uganda, Congo and Central African Republic, but human conflict has caused the creature to disappear. Critics say the efforts made to save the northern white rhino should instead go to save at-risk species that have a better chance to survive.</p>
<p>About 20,000 southern white rhinos remain in Africa. That subspecies and another species, the black rhino, are increasing in number after illegal hunting nearly caused their disappearance.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell adapted this story from AP and Reuters report.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transfer </strong><em>– v.</em> to move something from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>subspecies </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of related plants or animals that is smaller than a species</p>
<p><strong>achieve</strong> <em>–v.</em> to do something that you were trying to do</p>
<p><strong>milestone</strong> <em>– n. </em>an important point in the progress or development of something</p>
<p><strong>euthanize</strong> <em>– v.</em> to put to death in a humane way</p>
<p><strong>in vitro</strong><em> –adj.</em> (scientific) taking place in a laboratory or outside of normal biological methods</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Are Enlarged Prostate and Prostate Cancer?  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/what-are-enlarged-prostate-and-prostate-cancer.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Britain's King Charles was treated recently for a medical condition called enlarged prostate. American Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin recently spent two weeks in a hospital for treatment following an operation for prostate cancer.</p>
<p>The 70-year-old Austin did not share any news of his medical condition publicly, at first. He also did not inform President Joe Biden of what the defense department described as a "<strong>minimally</strong> invasive" operation on Austin's prostate on December 22.</p>
<p>On January 1, the defense chief developed severe pain and was taken by ambulance to the hospital. He was placed in the intensive care department with an infection linked to the operation. Austin was released two weeks later.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Britain's King Charles III and Queen Camilla leave The London Clinic in central London, on Monday, Jan. 29, 2024. King Charles III was in hospital to receive treatment for an enlarged prostate. (AP Photo/Alberto Pezzali)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c8b9c319-4f9d-42e0-b06b-4a25ce433171_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Britain's King Charles III and Queen Camilla leave The London Clinic in central London, on Monday, Jan. 29, 2024. King Charles III was in hospital to receive treatment for an enlarged prostate. (AP Photo/Alberto Pezzali)</span></div>
<p>The delay in informing the president and the public led to widespread criticism. A spokesman for Austin said at the time, "... discussions about (prostate cancer) screening, treatment and support are often deeply personal and private ones."</p>
<p>King Charles, however, announced on January 17 that he would undergo a "corrective procedure" for an enlarged prostate. His announcement came on the same day the 75-year-old king learned of his medical condition. On January 29, he left London Clinic after spending the weekend there for treatment.</p>
<p>It is unusual for members of the British <strong>royal</strong> family to share details about their health. However, King Charles decided to share his news publicly to <strong>encourage</strong> other men to have their prostates checked as called for by medical experts. The palace said the king sought treatment "in common with thousands of men each year."</p>
<p><strong>What is the prostate?</strong></p>
<p>The prostate is a small organ of the male reproductive system.</p>
<p>It is about the size and shape of a walnut. It sits below the bladder, an organ that stores urine temporarily.</p>
<p>The prostate helps make semen, the fluid that carries sperm cells required for human reproduction. The prostate surrounds part of the urethra, a tube that carries sperm from the testicles or urine out of the bladder through the penis.</p>
<p>As a man gets older, the prostate tends to grow larger. Medical experts say it could grow from the size of a walnut to the size of an apricot by the age of 40, and then to the size of a lemon by age 60. The larger prostate then may press against the urethra and cause problems in passing urine.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/understanding-prostate-changes">U.S. National Institute of Health (NIH) says</a> men in their 30s and 40s may begin to have problems with passing urine. The agency advises men to seek medical help if they experience any of the four conditions. They are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Passing urine more frequently day and night</li>
<li>Having an urgent need to pass urine</li>
<li>Having difficulty passing urine or passing urine very slowly</li>
<li>Feeling pain or burning while passing urine</li>
</ul>
<p>The NIH says the three most common prostate problems are prostatitis (or inflammation of the prostate), enlarged prostate (also known as BPH, or benign prostatic hyperplasia), and prostate cancer.</p>
<p><strong>Prostatitis</strong></p>
<p>Prostatitis is an inflammation of the prostate that may result from a bacterial infection. It affects at least half of all men at some time during their lives.</p>
<p>In the U.S., this condition is most common among younger men. Most cases can be treated with antibiotics medicine. Sometimes, doctors also give drugs to control <strong>inflammation</strong> and pain.</p>
<p><strong>Enlarged prostate (BHP)</strong></p>
<p>King Charles was treated for an enlarged prostate or BPH.</p>
<p>BPH stands for benign prostatic hyperplasia. Benign means "not cancer," and hyperplasia means unusual cell growth. BPH is not linked to cancer and does not increase your risk of getting prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Those with mild cases of enlarged prostate could simply limit drinking in the evening and use the restroom more often to empty their bladders. Some take drugs that help ease muscles that affect urine flow.</p>
<p>People with moderate cases of enlarged prostate could take drugs that help reduce the size of the prostate. The drugs called "5 alpha-reductase inhibitors" help shrink the prostate, reduce blockage and limit the need for invasive medical operations called surgeries.</p>
<p>In more severe cases, surgery is needed when drug treatment does not work.</p>
<p>The most common surgical treatment is to cut away extra prostate tissue using an instrument, radio wave, or laser. In rare cases, when the prostate is very large, doctors might consider a complete removal of the organ.</p>
<p><strong>Prostate cancer</strong></p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cancer.org/cancer/types/prostate-cancer/about/key-statistics.html">American Cancer Society says</a> prostate cancer is the second most common cancer among men. Skin cancer is the most common.</p>
<p>The group estimates that about 1 in 8 American men will be diagnosed with prostate cancer during their lifetime. The number rises to 6 in 10 among those who are 65 or older. The risk is also higher among those with a family history of prostate cancer and among Black Americans than men of other ethnicities.</p>
<p>In 2024, the group estimates there will be 299,010 new cases of prostate cancer with about 35,250 deaths from prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Prostate cancer tends to grow slowly compared with most other cancers. Cell changes may begin many years before a tumor gets big enough to cause noticeable signs.</p>
<p>In addition to difficulties with passing urine, other symptoms of prostate cancer include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blood in the urine or semen</li>
<li>Painful ejaculation</li>
<li>And <strong>constant</strong> pain in the back, hips or pelvis area</li>
</ul>
<p>There are several screening tests to look for signs of possible prostate cancer. They include urine tests, physical examinations and prostate-specific antigen (or PSA) tests.</p>
<p>If symptoms or tests suggest possible prostate cancer, a prostate biopsy is advised. Doctors remove several small tissues from the prostate and examine the material for cancer cells. Any treatment that might follow depends on how far the cancer has developed.</p>
<p>Most men who have biopsies after prostate cancer screening exams do not have cancer.</p>
<p>In the case of Defense Secretary Austin, doctors said on Jan. 26 that "his cancer was treated early and effectively" and no further treatments will be needed.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver .</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English with information from the National Institute of Health and the American Cancer Society. Additional reporting came from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>minimally</strong> - adv. very small or slight in sizr=e or amount</p>
<p><strong>royal</strong> - adj. relating to a king or queen</p>
<p><strong>encourage</strong> - v. to make someone more likely to do something</p>
<p><strong>inflammation</strong> - n. a condition in which a part of your body is swollen and painful</p>
<p><strong>constant</strong> - adj. happening all the time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Study Finds Myanmar Religious Buildings Damaged  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-study-finds-myanmar-religious-buildings-damaged.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>New research provides evidence that attacks by Myanmar's military government have damaged religious centers in the country.</p>
<p>Religious leaders and human rights workers say the reported attacks are part of a wider campaign to attack religious communities across the nation.</p>
<p>A civil war broke out in Myanmar after the military seized power from the elected government of former leader Aung San Suu Kyi in February 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Debris is seen in the St. Peter Baptist Church-Kanan, which was struck by the suspected military's aerial attacks in Kanan village, Khampat town, Sagaing region on Jan. 8, 2024. (David Htan via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1260-08dc21980074_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Debris is seen in the St. Peter Baptist Church-Kanan, which was struck by the suspected military's aerial attacks in Kanan village, Khampat town, Sagaing region on Jan. 8, 2024. (David Htan via AP)</span></div>
<p>Human rights agencies and United Nations investigators say they have found evidence of Myanmar security forces targeting civilians. The evidence includes details about bomb attacks, mass executions and detentions and the burning of private homes.</p>
<p>One group, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://aappb.org/">Assistance Association for Political Prisoners</a>, accuses security forces in Myanmar of killing at least 4,416 people since the 2021 military takeover.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.myanmarwitness.org/">Myanmar Witness</a> project completed the new report on the destruction of religious centers. The project is part of the Britain-based Centre for Information Resilience.</p>
<p>Myanmar Witness examined claims of five airstrikes that caused major damage to religious centers over several months in 2023. The attacks happened in Myanmar's western Chin state.</p>
<p>Religious buildings are given special protection under international law.</p>
<p>Another group, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.chinhumanrights.org/">Chin Human Rights Organization</a>, reported that the military has destroyed at least 107 religious buildings in Chin state since 2021. Those included attacks against 67 <strong>churches</strong> and five Buddhist <strong>monasteries</strong>, the group said.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>A 2023 report by the International <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.icj.org/">Commission of Jurists</a> said 94 Buddhist religious centers and 87 Christian ones had been destroyed or damaged nationwide.</p>
<p>The Myanmar Witness group collects evidence including pictures, video and witness accounts found on social media services. The group compares this evidence with satellite images or other methods to confirm human rights abuses.</p>
<p>Matt Lawrence is director of Myanmar Witness. He said the main goal of the project is to give evidence of "<strong>atrocities</strong>" to international groups for further investigation.</p>
<p>Many human rights activists have accused the military of aiming for religious buildings.</p>
<p>"Bombing churches is much more than just <strong>collateral damage</strong>," wrote Benedict Rogers. He is a former East Asia team leader for the human rights organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.csw.org.uk/home.htm">Christian Solidarity Worldwide</a>. He wrote in an email to The Associated Press, "Targeting them is part of a <strong>deliberate strategy</strong>."</p>
<p>Rogers said the military government discriminates against non-Burmese ethnic minorities and non-Buddhist religious minorities.</p>
<p>In 2017, the military carried out a <strong>counterinsurgency</strong> campaign in Rakhine state. The campaign drove almost 740,000 members of the Muslim Rohingya minority to flee to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The military government offered no immediate comment on the new report.</p>
<p>But in the past, military leaders have repeatedly stated that security forces only attack permissible targets of war.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>church </strong><em>– n. </em>a building where Christians go to worship</p>
<p><strong>monastery </strong><em>– n. </em>a building where people live as part of a specific religious group</p>
<p><strong>atrocity </strong><em>– n. </em>an extremely violent and shocking attack</p>
<p><strong>collateral damage </strong><em>– n. </em>unintentional deaths, injuries and destruction caused during a war to non-military members</p>
<p><strong>deliberate </strong><em>– adj. </em>intentional or planned<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>strategy </strong><em>– n. </em>a careful plan to complete something or achieve a goal over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>counterinsurgency </strong><em>– n. </em>a military action taken by a government to prevent attacks by small groups of soldiers or fighters that are opposed to it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Businesses Plan $8 Billion Investment in Vietnam  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/us-businesses-plan-8-billion-investment-in-vietnam.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Fifteen American businesses, including <strong>semiconductor </strong>companies, have expressed interest in investing $8 billion in Vietnam in clean energy projects, a senior U.S. official said recently.</p>
<p>However, their interest depends on the country's progress on <strong>renewable </strong>energy rules.</p>
<p>Vietnam is seeking to bring in computer <strong>chip</strong> companies. And it wants to build up its renewable energy industries. But it has so far struggled to pass rules that would permit the expansion of renewable energy industries. Those industries include solar and onshore wind and the development of offshore wind farms, of which it has none now.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration//File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0839a524-e3cc-4e0f-91ce-20a946bb627f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration//File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Jose Fernandez is an undersecretary for economic growth at the U.S. State Department. When asked if U.S. companies want to invest in Vietnam, he told reporters in Hanoi last Friday, "They are prepared to invest as much as $8 billion."</p>
<p>Fernandez did not name the companies. But he noted the investment would deal with clean energy <strong>infrastructure.</strong></p>
<p>Fernandez said that those companies made commitments to "use only renewable energy." So the investment would depend on the progress of rules on renewable energy in Vietnam. He added that the companies were also waiting for permits before they could go ahead with their investment plans.</p>
<p>Vietnam is considering rules that would permit factories to negotiate electricity prices directly with producers rather than buy it from the country's state-owned power network operator.</p>
<p>It is also working to pass rules for offshore wind, including creating an area for their operation in the sea. But delays in passing these rules have slowed progress.</p>
<p>An increase in renewables in Vietnam has been driven by the widespread use of <strong>solar panels </strong>and onshore wind farms. But problems connecting the projects to the electrical network, which also needs improvements to deal with the renewable energy, have partly undone this progress.</p>
<p>Fernandez's trip to Vietnam is part of U.S. plans to begin agreements reached last September. That was when the two countries officially raised their relationship to Vietnam's top diplomatic listing, called "comprehensive strategic partnership."</p>
<p>Fernandez had meetings with senior Vietnamese officials during the trip, including with Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh. During those meetings, he mostly discussed chips, critical minerals, and clean energy, he told reporters.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Francesco Guarascio reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– adj.</em> a material or object that allows some electricity or heat to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
<p><strong>renewables </strong><em>– adj. </em>restored or replaced by natural processes: able to be replaced by nature</p>
<p><strong>chip </strong><em>– n. </em>a very small piece of hard material (called silicon) in a computer or other device that contains many electronic circuits</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>– n.</em> the basic equipment and structures (such as roads and bridges) that are needed for a country, region, or organization to function properly</p>
<p><strong>solar panel </strong>– <em>n</em>. a large, flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Spacecraft Regains Power after Moon Landing  (2024/1/30) | 日本月球探测器恢复运行</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-spacecraft-regains-power-after-moon-landing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Japan's space agency says a spacecraft that landed on the moon earlier this month has regained power and is continuing its mission.<br/>
日本的太空机构表示，本月早些时候登陆月球的一艘航天器已经恢复动力，并正在继续执行任务。</p>
<p>Officials from the Japan Exploration Agency (JAXA) said Monday they had successfully reestablished communication with the SLIM moon explorer.<br/>
日本宇宙航空研究开发机构（JAXA）的官员周一表示，他们已经成功地与SLIM月球探测器重新建立了通信。</p>
<p>SLIM touched down on the moon on January 20. But the spacecraft landed the wrong way up. Its solar equipment was unable to see the sun. JAXA said SLIM was likely able to regain power because of a change in the sun's direction.<br/>
SLIM于1月20日登陆月球。但飞船降落的方向不对。它的太阳能设备无法接受到阳光。JAXA表示，由于太阳朝向的改变，SLIM很可能能够重新获得动力。</p>
<p>After the landing, JAXA used the spacecraft's battery power to gather as much data as possible about the touchdown and the surrounding area. The power was then turned off to wait for the sun to rise higher in the lunar sky.<br/>
着陆后，日本宇宙航空研究开发机构利用航天器的电池电量收集了尽可能多的关于着陆点和周围区域的数据。然后关闭电源，等待太阳在月球上空升起得更高。</p>
<p>Mission officials have said the explorer landed within 55 meters of its target near the lunar equator. It also landed in between two craters in an area covered in volcanic rock. JAXA said these results demonstrated progress in what it calls "pinpoint" landing technology.<br/>
任务官员表示，该探测器在月球赤道附近距离目标55米以内着陆。它还降落在覆盖着火山岩的两个火山口之间。日本宇宙航空研究开发机构表示，这些结果证明了其所谓的“精确定位”着陆技术的进步。</p>
<p>Past moon missions generally aimed to hit flat areas at least 10 kilometers wide. But the ability to land on very exact targets is expected to help support future space vehicles traveling to the moon and other places.<br/>
过去的月球任务通常旨在抵达至少10公里宽的平坦区域。但是，降落在非常精确的目标上的能力预计将有助于支持未来前往月球和其他星球的太空飞行器。</p>
<p>The main purpose of the mission was to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets. But SLIM is also capturing images and released two small explorers. The explorers are designed to examine mineral-rich rocks and collect data on the moon's development.<br/>
这次任务的主要目的是测试航天器能够降落在非常特定的目标上的可能性。但SLIM也在拍摄图像，并释放了两台小型探测车。探测车的任务是检查富含矿物质的岩石，并收集有关月球发展的数据。</p>
<p>JAXA has not named a specific date for when SLIM will end its operations on the moon. But the agency has said in the past that the lander was not designed to survive a lunar night. The next lunar night begins on Thursday.<br/>
日本宇宙航空研究开发机构尚未确定SLIM结束其月球使命的具体日期。但该机构过去曾表示，着陆器的设计不适用于月夜生存。下一个月夜从星期四开始。</p>
<p>The mission made Japan the fifth country in the world to successfully land on the surface of the moon, after the United States, the Soviet Union, China and India.<br/>
这次任务使日本成为继美国、苏联、中国和印度之后，世界上第五个成功登上月球表面的国家。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Studies: Gene Treatment Lets Children Deaf at Birth Hear  (2024/1/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/studies-gene-treatment-lets-children-deaf-at-birth-hear.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Gene treatments are being credited with permitting several children born with deafness to hear again.</p>
<p>Gene therapy is a medical treatment that aims to change a few of a patient's genes to cure a genetic disease.</p>
<p>A small study recently published in <em>The Lancet</em> reported improvements in the hearing in five of six children who were treated in China.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by researchers in January 2024, Dr. Yilai Shu examines a young patient at the Eye &amp; ENT Hospital of Fudan University in Shanghai, China, after a gene therapy procedure for hereditary deafness. (Courtesy Dr. Yilai Shu via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/14f4bc8b-c3b2-4500-aa69-c5bc2683e1ae_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by researchers in January 2024, Dr. Yilai Shu examines a young patient at the Eye &amp; ENT Hospital of Fudan University in Shanghai, China, after a gene therapy procedure for hereditary deafness. (Courtesy Dr. Yilai Shu via AP)</span></div>
<p>Around the same time, the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia in the U.S. eastern state of Pennsylvania announced similar improvements in an 11-year-old boy treated there. And earlier, Chinese researchers published a study showing similar improvements in two other children.</p>
<p>The experimental methods, or therapies, target only one rare condition. But scientists say similar treatments could someday help many more children with other kinds of deafness caused by genes.</p>
<p>Around the world, 34 million children have deafness or hearing loss. And information from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention says genes are responsible for up to 60 percent of cases.</p>
<p>Deafness caused by genes is passed down from parents to children. It is called <strong>hereditary</strong> deafness. It is the latest condition scientists are targeting with gene therapy. Gene therapy is already approved to treat illnesses such as sickle cell disease and severe hemophilia.</p>
<p>Children with hereditary deafness often get a device called a cochlear <strong>implant</strong> that helps them hear sound.</p>
<p>"No treatment could <strong>reverse</strong> hearing loss...That's why we were always trying to develop a therapy," said Zheng-Yi Chen of Boston's Mass Eye and Ear, a treatment center for eye and ear problems. He is a writer of the study published in <em>The Lancet</em>. "We couldn't be more happy or <strong>excited</strong> about the results."</p>
<p><strong>Treatment results</strong></p>
<p>The team recorded videos of patients. One shows a baby, who formerly could not hear at all, looking back in response to a doctor's words six weeks after treatment. Another shows a little girl 13 weeks after treatment repeating father, mother, grandmother, sister, and "I love you."</p>
<p>All the children in the experiments have a condition that is believed to cause two to eight percent of hereditary deafness. It is caused by changes in a gene responsible for an inner ear protein called otoferlin, which helps hair cells send sound signals to the brain.</p>
<p>The researchers say that the one-time therapy gives a working copy of that gene to the inner ear during a medical operation. Most of the children were treated in one ear, although one child in the two-person study was treated in both ears.</p>
<p>The study with six children took place at Fudan University in Shanghai. Dr. Yilai Shu helped lead the study and trained in Chen's laboratory. Chen was involved in the research. Chinese science organizations and biotechnology company Shanghai Refreshgene Therapeutics helped provide financial support.</p>
<p>Researchers observed the children for about six months. They do not know why the treatment did not work in one of them. But the five others, who were completely deaf, can now hear a normal discussion, the researchers said.</p>
<p>Chen estimated they now hear at a level 60 percent to 70 percent of normal. The therapy caused no major side effects.</p>
<p>Early results from other research have shown similar results.</p>
<p>Regeneron Pharmaceuticals is a biotech company based in New York state. It announced in October that a child under two years old showed improvements six weeks after gene therapy. The results came from a study Regeneron did with support from Decibel Therapeutics, a company in Boston.</p>
<p>Columbia University's Dr. Lawrence Lustig is involved in the Regeneron study. He said although the children in these studies do not end up with very good hearing, "even a moderate hearing loss recovery in these kids is <strong>pretty astounding</strong>."</p>
<p>He added that many questions remain. They include how long the therapies will last and if hearing will continue to improve in the children.</p>
<p>Some people question if gene therapy for deafness is <strong>ethical</strong>.</p>
<p>Teresa Blankmeyer Burke is a professor who is deaf and who deals with medical ethics. She teaches at Gallaudet University, a university for deaf people in Washington, D.C. She said that there is no agreement about the need for gene therapy targeting deafness.</p>
<p>She also pointed out that deafness does not cause severe or deadly illness. Blankmeyer Burke said that it is important to work with deaf community members about the importance of gene therapy. She added gene therapy is seen by many as a possible threat to "signing Deaf communities."</p>
<p>However, Chen said: "This is real proof showing gene therapy is working." And he added, "It opens up the whole field."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>hereditary </strong><em>–adj.</em> passed down from one generation to the next</p>
<p><strong>implant </strong><em>–n. (medical)</em> something connected to a person's body through a medical operation</p>
<p><strong>reverse </strong><em>– v.</em> to change (something) to an opposite state or condition</p>
<p><strong>excited </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very enthusiastic and eager about something</p>
<p><strong>pretty </strong>– <em>adv</em>. to a great degree or extent: very</p>
<p><strong>astounding </strong><em>– adj.</em> causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong>– <em>adj</em>. following accepted rules of behavior: morally right and good</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>X Blocks Taylor Swift Search after ‘Deepfake’ Image Spread  (2024/1/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/x-blocks-taylor-swift-search-after-deepfake-image-spread.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The social media site X has blocked some searches for Taylor Swift in reaction to an online spread of <strong>pornographic </strong>deepfake images of the singer.</p>
<p>A "deepfake" is an image, sound recording, or video created to make it appear that people in it are saying or doing things that they did not say or do.</p>
<p>Attempts to search for her name without <strong>quotation </strong>marks on the site Monday resulted in a failure<strong> </strong>message. It asked users to retry their search. "Don't <strong>fret</strong> — it's not your fault," also appeared.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Taylor Swift wears a Kansas City Chiefs tight end Travis Kelce jacket as she arrives before an NFL wild-card playoff football game between the Chiefs and the Miami Dolphins, Saturday, Jan. 13, 2024, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Ed Zurga, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/32622053-6b89-4d2d-a493-7adc976ae8f3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Taylor Swift wears a Kansas City Chiefs tight end Travis Kelce jacket as she arrives before an NFL wild-card playoff football game between the Chiefs and the Miami Dolphins, Saturday, Jan. 13, 2024, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Ed Zurga, File)</span></div>
<p>However, putting quotation marks around her name permitted posts to show where her name appeared.</p>
<p>The images of Swift began spreading widely on X last week. She is now the most famous victim of a danger that technology companies and anti-abuse groups have struggled to fix.</p>
<p>"This is a temporary action and done with an <strong>abundance</strong> of <strong>caution</strong> as we <strong>prioritize</strong> safety on this issue," Joe Benarroch, head of business operations at X, said in a statement.</p>
<p>After the images began spreading, the singer's loyal fan base, called "Swifties," quickly came to her defense. They launched a protective movement and flooded the site with more positive images of the singer. They used the hashtag #ProtectTaylorSwift on their posts. Some said they were reporting accounts that were sharing the deepfakes.</p>
<p>The deepfake-search group Reality Defender said it followed many posts of pornographic material of Swift. Many of the posts were found on X, formerly known as Twitter. Some images also made their way to Facebook and other social media sites.</p>
<p>The researchers found at least 20 different images created by artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<p>Researchers have said the number of pornographic deepfakes has grown in the past few years. The increase continues as the technology used to produce such images has become more available and easier to use.</p>
<p>In 2019, a report released by the AI company DeepTrace Labs showed these images were mainly weaponized against women. Most of the victims, it said, were Hollywood actors and South Korean singers.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pornographic </strong><em>– adj.</em> showing or describing naked people or sex in a very open and direct way in order to cause sexual excitement</p>
<p><strong>quotation mark </strong><em>– n. </em>one of a pair of punctuation marks " " or ‘ ' that are used to show the beginning and the end of a quotation, to show that something is a title, to show that a word or phrase is being used in a special way, etc.</p>
<p><strong>fret </strong><em>– v. </em>to worry or be concerned</p>
<p><strong>abundance </strong><em>– n.</em> a large amount of something: an abundant amount of something</p>
<p><strong>caution </strong><em>– n. </em>carefulness in regard to danger</p>
<p><strong>prioritize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to organize (things) so that the most important thing is done or dealt with first</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Evidence Suggests Large Water Ice Supply near Mars’ Equator  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-evidence-suggests-large-water-ice-supply-near-mars-equator.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A Mars explorer has discovered new evidence of a large amount of water ice buried near the planet's <strong>equator</strong>.</p>
<p>The discovery was made with data collected by the Mars Express orbiter. The spacecraft is operated by the European Space Agency (ESA). The American space agency NASA is a partner on the orbiter's <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>ESA launched Mars Express in 2003 and it has been studying the Red Planet ever since. The mission's main goal is to use its seven scientific instruments to search for signs of water underneath the surface of Mars.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This high-resolution image, taken by a camera aboard ESA's Mars Express spacecraft, shows part of the Medusa Fossae formation and surrounding areas near the equator of Mars. (ESA/DLR/FU Berlin (G. Neukum))" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-86f9-08dc1e0c9cb0_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This high-resolution image, taken by a camera aboard ESA's Mars Express spacecraft, shows part of the Medusa Fossae formation and surrounding areas near the equator of Mars. (ESA/DLR/FU Berlin (G. Neukum))</span></div>
<p>Scientists involved in the new research say data suggesting the presence of newly discovered ice <strong>deposits</strong> could mean Mars may have once supported life.</p>
<p>The Mars Express orbiter collected data around an area of the planet known as the Medusae Fossae Formation (or MFF). NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/images/pia03770-medusae-fossae-formation">describes</a> this formation as "a soft, easily <strong>eroded</strong> deposit that extends for nearly 1,000 kilometers along the equator of Mars."</p>
<p>Scientists believe the MFF was most likely formed by wind-blown dust or volcanic ash. The formations could have formed after volcanic activity estimated to have taken place up to 3.8 billion years ago.</p>
<p>Images of the area show raised areas that scientists thought in the past might contain dust blown around the planet by wind over many years. But the new research used newer data collected by the orbiter's MARSIS instrument. It is "a subsurface radar sounder" with a 40-meter-long <strong>antenna</strong>. The tool looks for water on the surface, as well as up to five kilometers below the surface.</p>
<p>The MARSIS instrument is designed to send radio waves to an area scientists choose. It then attempts to listen to and examine "<strong>echoes</strong>" produced by the radio waves. The echoes help researchers recognize where water or ice might be, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://mars.nasa.gov/express/mission/sc_science_marsis01.html">explains</a>.</p>
<p>Scientists say any water identified near the surface results in stronger signals while the presence of ice or other materials would produce weaker signals. The team said MARSIS readings suggest the MFF area of Mars contains a large amount of water ice rather than wind-blown dust.</p>
<p>Thomas Watters of the U.S. Smithsonian Institution led the new research. His team's findings were recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1029/2023GL105490">published in a study</a> in <em>Geophysical Research Letters</em>. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Buried_water_ice_at_Mars_s_equator">said in a statement</a> the radar data showed the deposits in the MFF area were even thicker than earlier measurement estimates had shown.</p>
<p>The researchers said the data showed the examined deposits extended beneath the Mars surface to depths up to 3.7 kilometers. They seemed to contain "<strong>layers</strong> of dust and ice, all topped by a protective layer of dry dust or ash."</p>
<p>Earlier data examinations of the MFF area found similarities in the electrical properties of deposits there to ice-rich deposits found in the planet's north and south poles. The latest MARSIS data strengthens this evidence by suggesting similarities between deposit layering in the MFF and the planet's poles.</p>
<p>"The radar signals <strong>match</strong> what we'd expect to see from layered ice," Watters said. He added that the radar waves were found to be "similar to signals we see from Mars's polar caps, which we know to be very ice rich."</p>
<p>It is not the first time scientists have discovered strong evidence for the presence of water ice on Mars. But the researchers say the latest study suggests the largest amount of water ever identified in the MFF area. They estimated the total amount of water contained there would be enough "to cover the surface of Mars to a depth of about 1.5 to 3 meters."</p>
<p>Colin Wilson is a project scientist with the Mars Express mission. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Buried_water_ice_at_Mars_s_equator">said</a> while the new finding is exciting, it also "raises as many questions as answers." He continued, "How long ago did these ice deposits form, and what was Mars like at that time?" Wilson said if confirmed to be water ice, the large deposits "would change our understanding of Mars climate history."</p>
<p>Watters added that since the discovery was made in an area near the Martian equator, it could be considered a good place for future exploration missions. He explained that with a lower <strong>elevation</strong>, the MFF area would be considered "an ideal landing spot for spacecraft." Such an elevation provides more atmosphere to support an effective, controlled landing, Watters said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from the European Space Agency, NASA, Geophysical Research Letters and the Smithsonian. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>equator </strong>–n. an imaginary line around the middle of a planet that is an equal distance from its north and south poles</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>the flight of a spacecraft to perform a certain task or job</p>
<p><strong>deposit </strong><em>– n. </em>a layer of a substance that has developed from a natural or chemical process</p>
<p><strong>erode </strong><em>– v. </em>to gradually be damaged over time</p>
<p><strong>antenna </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of metal used for receiving television or radio signals</p>
<p><strong>echo </strong><em>– n. </em>the repeating of a sound caused by the reflection of sound waves</p>
<p><strong>layer </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of substance covering a surface</p>
<p><strong>match </strong><em>– v. to fit together or make suitable for fitting together</em></p>
<p><strong>elevation </strong><em>– n. </em>the height of a place above the level of the sea</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple Releases New Stolen Device Protection  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/apple-releases-new-stolen-device-protection.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Imagine that you are in a crowded place. You do not notice, but someone is watching you and learns your iPhone passcode. Then, they steal your phone. Suddenly, your photos, documents, financial information, and the rest of your digital life have been taken from you.</p>
<p>A new security feature may prevent such a situation from happening. Apple, the iPhone maker, recently released an update to its iOS operating system. It has a new feature called Stolen Device Protection. The feature makes it a lot harder for phone <strong>thieves</strong> to open the device and <strong>access</strong> important functions and settings.</p>
<p>The company is urging users to turn this feature on immediately. Here is how to turn on the new security feature and why it is so important to do so.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An Apple iPhone 15 advertisement is seen as it officially goes on sale across China at an Apple Store in Shanghai, China September 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-410f-08dbbb5c0d64_cx6_cy13_cw93_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An Apple iPhone 15 advertisement is seen as it officially goes on sale across China at an Apple Store in Shanghai, China September 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song)</span></div>
<p><strong>Should I turn on Stolen Device Protection?</strong></p>
<p>Stolen Device Protection is a new setting that is included with the latest iOS release, version 17.3. The update for iPhones and iPads includes a new feature designed to prevent thieves from <strong>wiping</strong> phones for resale or getting to your Apple ID or other important accounts.</p>
<p>Apple says the feature adds extra security for users. It addresses a <strong>vulnerability</strong> that thieves have used to lock device owners out of their Apple accounts, <strong>delete</strong> their photos and other files from their iCloud, and take money from their bank accounts.</p>
<p><strong>How does it work?</strong></p>
<p>Stolen Device Protection <strong>keeps track</strong> of a user's "familiar locations," such as their home or workplace. The feature adds extra biometric security if someone tries to use the device to do certain things away from those places.</p>
<p>It also reduces the importance of passcodes. Instead, it favors "biometric" features such as faces or fingerprints, which are a lot harder to copy.</p>
<p>If a thief tries to <strong>erase</strong> or reset an iPhone, the device will require a Face ID or Touch ID scan to confirm that the person is the rightful owner. The new feature does not let someone use the passcode or any other backup method.</p>
<p>Another part of the new feature is designed to slow down thieves trying to change security settings. For example, if someone tries to sign out of an Apple ID account, change the passcode or reset the phone in an unfamiliar <strong>location</strong>, they will have to <strong>authenticate</strong> using Face ID or Touch ID, wait an hour, and then do a second facial or fingerprint scan.</p>
<p>Changing an Apple ID password, updating Apple ID security settings, adding or removing Face or Touch ID, and turning off the Find My device feature or Stolen Device Protection also will <strong>trigger</strong> this feature.</p>
<p>Apple said the delay is meant to prevent a thief from performing these operations so you can mark your device as lost and secure your Apple account.</p>
<p>The company added that, "When your iPhone is in a familiar location, these additional steps will not be required and you can use your device passcode like normal."</p>
<p><strong>How do I turn it on?</strong></p>
<p>First, download and update your iPhone or iPad with the latest iOS update. The update works for iPhone XS and newer models, including second- and third-generation SE models.</p>
<p>Then go to your settings, scroll down to "Face ID &amp; Passcode" or "Touch ID &amp; Passcode" and enter your passcode. Scroll down and you'll see Stolen Device Protection.</p>
<p>Make sure you have turned on two-factor authentication and Find My device for your Apple ID account. Otherwise, it will not show up.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>thief</strong> - n. a person who steals something</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> - v. to be able to enter or get into something</p>
<p><strong>wipe</strong> - v. to completely remove something</p>
<p><strong>vulnerability</strong> - n. the condition of easily open to attack, hurt or damage</p>
<p><strong>delete</strong> - v. to remove</p>
<p><strong>keep track</strong> - v. to be aware of what someone is doing</p>
<p><strong>erase</strong> - v. to remove something from a digital device</p>
<p><strong>location</strong> - n. place or position</p>
<p><strong>authenticate</strong> - v. to prove that something is real</p>
<p><strong>trigger</strong> - v. to cause something else to happen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Find New Penguins Colonies in Antarctica  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/scientists-find-new-penguins-colonies-in-antarctica.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have found four groups of emperor penguins in Antarctica that they did not know about before. These groups, called "<strong>colonies</strong>," were found with new satellite images.</p>
<p>Emperor penguins are the world's largest penguins, sea birds that cannot fly but that swim. They are consider "near threatened." This means the animals might have reduced numbers or live in fewer areas than before.</p>
<p>The penguins raise their babies, called chicks, during the Antarctic winter on areas of frozen sea ice. If the ice breaks up before the chicks grow up, many of the chicks might die.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey in January 2024 shows adult emperor penguins with a chick near Halley Research Station in Antarctica. (British Antarctic Survey via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/22389179-9dd7-4bd6-a0b6-4c8200ec1b62_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey in January 2024 shows adult emperor penguins with a chick near Halley Research Station in Antarctica. (British Antarctic Survey via AP)</span></div>
<p>Recently released research says that some of the penguins are moving away from their old colonies.</p>
<p>Peter Fretwell is a researcher at the British Antarctic Survey, a government organization. He said that conditions at one colony had become more dangerous since 2016. As a result, the colony near Halley Bay seems to have moved about 30 kilometers east.</p>
<p>He said, "Emperor penguins have taken it upon themselves to try to find more <strong>stable</strong> sea ice."</p>
<p>Fretwell said that the four new colonies have likely existed for years, but scientists have just recently seen them. They are small colonies with less than 1000 <strong>pairs</strong> of penguins, Fretwell said.</p>
<p>Scientists have identified 66 emperor penguin colonies and fewer than 300,000 <strong>breeding</strong> pairs. The four newly found colonies do not change population estimates for the birds very much. However, Fretwell said the fact that one of the colonies moved helps scientists to understand where the birds are going.</p>
<p>Daniel Zitterbart is a penguin researcher at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in the U.S. eastern state of Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study of the newly found penguins. But he said that it is unclear if the new groups broke away from the larger colonies.</p>
<p>Zitterbart said that the places where the penguins <strong>reproduce </strong>are changing and that, as the world warms, more "penguins will be on the move."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>colonies</strong> – <em>n</em>. groups of plants or animals living or growing in one place</p>
<p><strong>stable</strong> – <em>adj</em>. remain the same</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>– n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce and raise young</p>
<p><strong>reproduce</strong> – <em>v</em>. to produce offspring by sexual reproduction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia Aims to Develop EV Industry  (2024/1/29) | 沙特意图发展电动汽车行业</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/saudi-arabia-aims-to-develop-ev-industry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Saudi Arabia has spent billions of dollars to become competitive in the electric vehicle (EV) industry.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯花费了数十亿美元，让自己在电动汽车行业具有竞争力。</p>
<p>Such efforts are part of Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's broader plan to create jobs and diversify the country's economy. The kingdom has invested at least $10 billion in Lucid Motors, a United States-based company. It also set up a Saudi EV company, Ceer, and built an EV metals factory.<br/>
这些努力是沙特王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼创造就业机会和实现国家经济多样化的宏大计划的一部分。沙特已向总部位于美国的Lucid Motors公司投资至少100亿美元。它还成立了一家沙特电动汽车公司Ceer，并建造了一家电动汽车金属工厂。</p>
<p>The Public Investment Fund (PIF), Saudi Arabia's $700 billion sovereign wealth fund, has a goal to produce 500,000 EVs yearly by 2030, up from a target of 150,000 in 2026.<br/>
作为管理7000亿美元的主权财富基金，沙特公共投资基金的目标是到2030年每年生产50万辆电动汽车，而2026年的目标是每年生产15万辆。</p>
<p>Yet by December, Ceer, which opened in September 2023, had put together around 800 vehicles. Those vehicles were based on kits supplied from the U.S. state of Arizona.<br/>
然而截至去年12月，于2023年9月开业的Ceer公司已经组装了约800辆汽车。这些车辆是基于美国亚利桑那州提供的套件。</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia has failed in the past to appeal to foreign car makers.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯过去未能吸引外国汽车制造商。</p>
<p>Japan's Toyota rejected a proposed deal with Saudi Arabia in 2019. The company said labor costs were too high, local suppliers were too few, and the market was too small.<br/>
2019年，日本丰田公司拒绝了与沙特阿拉伯的一项拟议交易。该公司表示，沙特劳动力成本太高，当地供应商太少，市场太小。</p>
<p>As the world moves away from cars fueled by oil, experts say Saudi Arabia faces competition in the EV industry.<br/>
专家表示，随着世界逐渐放弃以石油为燃料的汽车，沙特阿拉伯在电动汽车行业面临竞争。</p>
<p>"There is tremendous competition that the country will face from established manufacturing power houses and from established supply chains," said Gaurav Batra of EY, a business advisory company.<br/>
安永商业咨询公司的高罗夫·巴特拉表示：“沙特将面临来自老牌制造业巨头和老牌供应链的巨大竞争。”</p>
<p>Batra added, "A lot of things need to come into place before this industry takes shape and really ignites."<br/>
巴特拉补充道：“在这个行业成型并真正爆发之前，需要做很多事情。”</p>
<p>Saudi officials did not respond to Reuters news agency requests for comment.<br/>
沙特官员没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">EV production<br/>
电动汽车生产</span></p>
<p>China currently leads the new supply chain as well as EV production. Chinese company BYD became the world's biggest maker of EVs last year, pushing Tesla motors into 2nd place.<br/>
中国目前在这条全新供应链和电动汽车生产方面处于领先地位。中国比亚迪公司去年成为全球最大的电动汽车制造商，将特斯拉汽车挤至第二位。</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia faces a lack of auto parts supply - anything from car doors to engines. There is no major local industry to produce these goods.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯面临着汽车零部件供应短缺的问题，从车门到发动机，无所不包。当地没有大型产业可以生产这些产品。</p>
<p>The EV manufacturer Ceer, a joint project between the PIF and Taiwanese company Foxconn, plans to launch a car by 2025. But the company has not yet built its factory.<br/>
电动汽车制造商Ceer是沙特公共投资基金和中国台湾省富士康公司的联合项目，该公司计划在2025年前推出一款汽车。但该公司尚未建厂。</p>
<p>A source connected to Ceer said it was unlikely the company would have a vehicle on the road before 2026. The source spoke on condition that they not be identified.<br/>
一位与Ceer有关的消息人士表示，该公司在2026年之前不太可能有车辆上路。该消息人士要求匿名。</p>
<p>In October, South Korean car manufacturer Hyundai and the PIF announced a project to build a factory for traditional engine vehicles and electric vehicles. The project, along with those of Lucid and Ceer, would create a group of factories in Jeddah's King Abdullah Economic City.<br/>
10月，韩国汽车制造商现代汽车和沙特公共投资基金宣布了一个项目，将为传统发动机汽车和电动汽车建造一个工厂。该项目连同Lucid和Ceer的项目一起，将在吉达市的阿卜杜拉国王经济城创建一批工厂。</p>
<p>Ceer will get parts from Germany's BMW automobile company, including batteries, the highest cost single part of an EV.<br/>
Ceer将从德国宝马汽车公司获得零部件，包括电池，这是电动汽车中成本最高的单个零部件。</p>
<p>Lucid vice president Faisal Sultan told Reuters in December that Saudi Arabia needed the presence of critical suppliers. He said the Saudi factory only rebuilt vehicles and the Arizona site carried out quality control testing.<br/>
Lucid副总裁费萨尔·苏丹12月告诉路透社，沙特阿拉伯需要关键供应商的存在。他说，沙特工厂只是重新组装了车辆，亚利桑那州工厂进行了质量控制测试。</p>
<p>The company's idea - keeping the supply chain and vehicle manufacturing in the United States - could lead other companies to set up rebuild sites as well. As a result, these companies might be able to get Saudi incentives, a Saudi auto industry leader said.<br/>
该公司将供应链和汽车制造留在美国的想法可能会导致其他公司也建立组装基地。一位沙特汽车行业领袖表示，因此，这些公司可能能够获得沙特的激励。</p>
<p>But such moves could slow the growth of local Saudi manufacturing as the country would continue to import foreign-made cars.<br/>
但这些举措可能会减缓沙特当地制造业的增长，因为该国将继续进口外国制造的汽车。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple’s Computer Launch Leads to Study of User Experience  (2024/1/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/apple-s-computer-launch-leads-to-study-of-user-experience.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many people first heard about Apple's Macintosh computer through a television <strong>commercial</strong> during the American football Super Bowl game in 1984.</p>
<p>However, the commercial did not show a computer at all. It showed a woman throwing a hammer at a large screen. On the screen was a man giving a speech. The screen exploded and an announcer said, "Apple Computer will introduce Macintosh. ... And you'll see why 1984 won't be like ‘1984.'"</p>
<p><em>1984</em> is George Orwell's book about an <strong>authoritarian</strong> government. And Apple aimed to tell people that the new computer would be different. It would be easy to use.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Part of an early model central processing unit is seen on display at the Computer History Museum on January 19, 2024 in Mountain View, California, as the museum celebrates Mac's 40th birthday. (Photo by Loren Elliott / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6df27416-531f-4df9-bc58-f6ab6a6cc720_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Part of an early model central processing unit is seen on display at the Computer History Museum on January 19, 2024 in Mountain View, California, as the museum celebrates Mac's 40th birthday. (Photo by Loren Elliott / AFP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Made with humans in mind</strong></p>
<p>Many computers at the time only did one or two things. And they required the user to type complex commands to start the programs.</p>
<p>Jacob O. Wobbrock is a professor of information at the University of Washington. He wrote about Apple's commercial in <em>The Conversation</em>.</p>
<p>Apple "was selling a product for human beings to use," Wobbrock writes. After the commercial, he suggests, Apple became known for design and the world started paying attention to the idea of user experience, or human-computer interaction.</p>
<p>"The Macintosh was one of the first products to really <strong>prioritize</strong> user experience and <strong>focus</strong> on making something useable and understandable, learnable even guessable. So that people didn't have to always read a <strong>manual</strong> to learn how to use it."</p>
<p>Mackenzie Bristow is a former language teacher and researcher who now works in user experience in Atlanta, Georgia. She said Macintosh was one of the first products to think about "the user."</p>
<p>"What is the role of the person? What is the role of the user?" she asked. She explained that in design, the rule is "first, understand the person" before thinking about what the product looks like and what it can do.</p>
<p>Forty years after the launch of the Macintosh computer, we now see computer screens everywhere – at restaurants, at airports and even in cars. All of those devices have been designed by experts in user experience.</p>
<p><strong>STEM plus ‘soft skills'</strong></p>
<p>Many colleges and universities now offer study programs in user experience.</p>
<p>While it is part of STEM – science, technology, engineering and math – Wobbrock said students from different areas of study, including psychology or communication, could be successful.</p>
<p>"The kind of student that <strong>thrives</strong> in user experience is a student who has above all else, a real curiosity about how people <strong>interact</strong> with technology. ... And students whose first language is not English can absolutely do well in user experience."</p>
<p>One of those students is Kartik Sundaram of India. He studied computer science at the University of Michigan and chose user experience for his <strong>graduate</strong> study. He finished last year and is now teaching the subject.</p>
<p>"I never felt like I had a personal desire to pursue [computer science]," he said. He called the work "very <strong>isolating</strong>." For fun, he took a photography class. While in the class, he met someone who was studying in the User Experience Research and Design program.</p>
<p>"He told me about how, you know, it's like this <strong>blend</strong> of design and people and technology, and that kind of lit a fire in my heart to say ok, this seems a lot more interesting, ... ‘let's jump right in, let's learn more about it and let's apply to that school."</p>
<p>Sundaram said user experience is good for people who are "personable and good at making connections." Some of those are called ‘soft skills,' he said. And "the soft skills really matter."</p>
<p>While he grew up speaking English, Sundaram said the world of user experience is more and more open to people who are learning English or who may speak with an accent.</p>
<p>"I don't think it's an expectation that your English is <strong>flawless</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Bristow said the ability to speak more than one language "is kind of a super power in user experience," because those people are comfortable interacting with many different kinds of people. "That's really something to be celebrated," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Future of UX and job outlook</strong></p>
<p>Sundaram is teaching but also looking for work in the field. Wobbrock is a professor and Bristow works on training programs for a large company.</p>
<p>They each spoke about the need for user experience professionals to work in the expanding field of artificial intelligence, or AI.</p>
<p>Sundaram said "We're not going to be restricted to a text box in ChatGPT for much longer. There are going to be other ways to interact with it."</p>
<p>Bristow said the ability to understand language is important. AI programs will need experts who understand how language changes based on where people live, their level of education and their age.</p>
<p>Wobbrock said user experience professionals are starting to work on projects called human-AI interaction. "There will be a great need for user experience professionals to help understand how people and AI can interact and work together in profitable ways," he added.</p>
<p>But Sundaram warned that user experience study programs, also known as UX, are becoming very popular. He said some students see UX as a field to make a lot of money with few <strong>certification</strong> requirements.<strong> </strong>And several companies are letting go of people with experience in the field.</p>
<p>Sundaram said, "It's definitely a difficult market, but it's an incredible field and there are new <strong>interfaces</strong> coming out that need our work."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>commercial </strong>–n. another name for a television advertisement</p>
<p><strong>authoritarian </strong>– <em>adj. </em>describing a restrictive government where power is with one or very few people</p>
<p><strong>prioritize </strong>–v. to put something first in order of importance</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong>– <em>v. </em>to make something the center of attention</p>
<p><strong>manual </strong>–n. a book with instructions or directions on how to operate something</p>
<p><strong>thrive </strong>–v. to do well or produce excellent work</p>
<p><strong>interact </strong>– <em>v. </em>how one thing mixes with another</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong>–adj. a study program for an advanced degree, after a bachelor's degree</p>
<p><strong>isolating </strong>– <em>adj. </em>lonely, away from other people</p>
<p><strong>blend </strong>–n. a mixture of two or more things</p>
<p><strong>flawless </strong>–adj. without mistakes or errors</p>
<p><strong>certification </strong>– <em>n. </em>a test that proves you know how to do or perform a task</p>
<p><strong>interface </strong>–n. a system that permits two different things to connect with each other</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Snow Day? Don't Be 'Left Out in the Cold'  (2024/1/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/don-t-be-left-out-in-the-cold.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, notes on usage, and sometimes we use them in short conversations.</p>
<p>In a recent science report<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/while-us-freezes-much-of-the-world-experiences-record-heat/7445844.html"> we explained</a> about a weather system called the polar vortex. It caused a <u>snowball effect</u> on extreme weather around the world. The event led to record-high temperatures in many parts of the world. But much of North America had to deal with extreme cold. Some areas recorded temperatures as low as minus 20 degrees Celsius.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Mist from the Great Falls has created a frozen wonderland around the waterfalls in Paterson, New Jersey, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-f776-08dc1a7fc685_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Mist from the Great Falls has created a frozen wonderland around the waterfalls in Paterson, New Jersey, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)</span></div>
<p>In an earlier Words and Their Stories program, we explained how to use the expression <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/when-does-a-problem-snowball-/7398657.html">snowball effect</a> to describe a situation where one action or event causes many other similar actions or events.</p>
<p>Are you thinking that there must be many more English expressions related to snow, ice, and cold weather? You are right! The term "snowball effect" is just the <u>tip of the iceberg</u>!</p>
<p>Or, to put it another way, we have many more expressions in American English related to the cold weather. So, today we will explore some winter words and expressions.</p>
<p>In the <u>dead of winter</u>, many people like to skate on frozen lakes. But watch out! You don't want to <u>skate on thin ice</u>. That is dangerous. If it breaks you could fall into the cold, dark water below. You could even drown.</p>
<p>So, the expression <u>skating on thin ice</u> serves as a warning. For example, if a friend is always late to work, you might tell him he is <u>skating on thin ice</u> with his employer.</p>
<p>But, you might not want to say anything to your friend. Maybe it is none of your business when your friend arrives at work. So, you decide to <u>put your warning on ice.</u></p>
<p>To <u>put something on ice</u> means to suspend action on something – a temporary halt. In fact, today a co-worker asked me to <u>put my project on ice</u>, so I would have time to help her with today's lesson.</p>
<p>When we put food on ice we <strong>preserve</strong> its quality for a time. We can wait to eat it later and it will still be good.</p>
<p>What about when we <u>break the ice</u>, though? That sounds dangerous, right? However, it just means reaching out personally to a stranger. Like in this example:</p>
<p><em>A: Hi Matt. Have you met our new teacher, Jennifer?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. Not yet.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Why don't you <u>break the ice</u> and <strong>introduce</strong> yourself this afternoon?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I certainly will.</em></p>
<p>Ice is not all we might face in winter. Sometimes the snow is so deep we cannot even get out of the house. At those times, you might say there is a <u>snowball's chance in hell</u> I'm leaving home today.</p>
<p>Hell is fiery and extremely hot. A snowball has no chance at survival there. So, the expression describes something that is impossible.</p>
<p>Now that we are stuck inside the house, we say we are <u>snowbound</u> or <u>snowed under</u>. And we often use <u>snowed under</u> to describe a situation in which we have too much work to do.</p>
<p>American children usually love a <u>snow day</u>! That phrase is used to mean schools are closed. Students might spend the day outdoors throwing <u>snowballs</u> or building a <u>snowman</u>. Or maybe they stay inside, covered up in a warm blanket next to a hot fire, <u>snug as a bug in a rug</u>.</p>
<p>We use the expression <u>snug as a bug in a rug</u> to describe a soft, warm and safe position or situation.</p>
<p>Sounds like a great place to be, especially during a snow storm. I mean, no one wants to be <u>left out in the cold</u>. That can really hurt, physically and emotionally!</p>
<p>Sometimes we use this phrase, <u>left out in the cold</u>, when someone has rejected or forgotten us.</p>
<p>We will never leave English learners <u>out in the cold</u>, to be sure! Especially not in <u>the dead of winter!</u></p>
<p>And that's <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>preserve</strong> - v. to keep something in its original state or in good condition</p>
<p><strong>introduce</strong> - v. to make someone known to someone else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
