<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>NASA: Oxygen-producing Device on Mars Performed above Expectations  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/nasa-oxygen-producing-device-on-mars-performed-above-expectations.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The American space agency NASA says a device placed on Mars to produce oxygen has performed better than expected in a series of experiments.</p>
<p>The system is called MOXIE. It is designed to change, or convert, carbon dioxide captured from the Mars atmosphere into oxygen. The instrument works through a process called electrolysis. This process uses extreme heat to separate oxygen atoms from molecules of carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Carbon dioxide makes up about 95 percent of the Martian atmosphere, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2019/with-mars-methane-mystery-unsolved-curiosity-serves-scientists-a-new-one-oxygen">reports</a>. The rest is mostly molecular nitrogen and argon. Molecular oxygen makes up just 0.16 percent of the Martian atmosphere.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Technicians at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory lower the MOXIE instrument into the belly of the Perseverance rover in an undated photograph in Pasadena, California. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-4b93-08dbb60f23f3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Technicians at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory lower the MOXIE instrument into the belly of the Perseverance rover in an undated photograph in Pasadena, California. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>But future exploration of Mars and possibly other planets by humans will require a large supply of oxygen. NASA has said the chemical element will be necessary for astronauts to breathe and to produce rocket fuel for launches carried out from the Martian surface.</p>
<p>NASA financed the MOXIE demonstration experiment. A team from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) created the device.</p>
<p>The MOXIE instrument was carried to Mars aboard NASA's Perseverance explorer, or rover. Perseverance arrived on the Red Planet in February 2021. The device is a box-shaped instrument attached to the rover.</p>
<p>NASA reported its first results with the MOXIE system in April 2021. At the time, the space agency reported the device had successfully converted carbon dioxide from the Martian atmosphere into oxygen. In the first experiment, MOXIE produced 5.4 grams of oxygen in one hour. NASA then carried out a series of additional experiments to test the effectiveness of the system.</p>
<p>In a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/nasa-s-oxygen-generating-experiment-moxie-completes-mars-mission">statement</a> issued earlier this month, leaders of the demonstration project said MOXIE had completed its 16th and final experiment. They noted the device's "<strong>impressive</strong> performance" had proven it was possible to capture oxygen from the Martian atmosphere. Such oxygen "could help supply breathable air or rocket <strong>propellant</strong> to future astronauts," the statement said.</p>
<p>NASA said that MOXIE had produced a total of 122 grams of oxygen since Perseverance landed on Mars. This amount is about what a small dog would breathe in 10 hours. While the amount of oxygen is small, it represented the first experimental capture of a natural resource from the environment of another planet.</p>
<p>When working at its highest level of effectiveness, the instrument was able to produce 12 grams of oxygen in one hour. NASA says this is twice as much as its engineers first estimated the system could produce.</p>
<p>The MOXIE team has also been measuring the purity of the oxygen the device produces. Overall, it has reported the instrument produced oxygen that was at least 98 percent pure.</p>
<p>The latest experiments with MOXIE on Mars are designed to help NASA build a much larger version of the system. A full-sized device could be deployed on Mars in the future.</p>
<p>A NASA explanation of the instrument states: "The goal of a Big MOXIE would be to make and store all the oxygen that the astronaut and their rocket would need for their <strong>mission</strong> before they even launch." Such a system would need to make between 2,000 to 3,000 grams of oxygen per hour, the space agency noted.</p>
<p>Trudy Kortes is the director of technology demonstrations at NASA Headquarters in Washington D.C. She said the agency was pleased to be able to support such a technology. "By proving this technology in real-world conditions, we've come one step closer to a future in which astronauts ‘live off the land' on the Red Planet," Kortes said.</p>
<p>MIT's Michael Hecht leads the MOXIE development operation. He said in a statement the team's work will next center on working on the larger version of MOXIE. In addition, scientists will need to create equipment to liquefy and store the produced oxygen.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from NASA and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. </em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impressive </strong><em>– adj. </em>making or attempting to make a marked impression</p>
<p><strong>propellant </strong><em>– n. </em>an explosive substance of fuel that causes something to move forward</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>a flight by an aircraft or spacecraft to perform a specific task</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rights Groups: Mining in the DRC Threatens Human Rights  (2023/9/18) | 人权组织称刚果采矿威胁人权</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rights-groups-mining-in-the-drc-threatens-human-rights.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rights groups say mining cobalt and copper in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, known as the DRC, has led to human rights abuses.<br/>
人权组织表示，在刚果民主共和国开采钴和铜导致了侵犯人权的行为。</p>
<p>London-based Amnesty International and a rights group based in the DRC released a report on the issue on September 11. It said mining companies forcibly removed people from their homes and farmland. Many of those affected said they were not paid enough.<br/>
总部位于伦敦的大赦国际和总部位于刚果民主共和国的一家人权组织于9月11日就此问题发布了一项报告。报告称，矿业公司强行将人们从家中和农田中赶走。许多受此影响的人士表示，他们未得到足够赔偿。</p>
<p>The recent report also said people were attacked, including sexually attacked, and also had their property destroyed or damaged.<br/>
最近的报告还说，人们遭到袭击，包括性侵，他们的财产也遭到破坏。</p>
<p>Cobalt is an element needed for long-lasting batteries in things like electric vehicles and similar technologies. The DRC is believed to have more cobalt than any other country in the world. The country is also Africa's top producer of copper, which is needed in the electrical industry.<br/>
钴是电动汽车和类似技术中的长效电池所需的元素。据信，刚果民主共和国的钴储量超过了世界上任何其他国家。该国也是非洲最大的铜生产国，电力行业需要铜。</p>
<p>Criticism of the trade in cobalt, copper and other minerals in the DRC is not new. Amnesty International accused the cobalt mining industry there of using child labor in 2016.<br/>
对刚果民主共和国钴、铜和其他矿产贸易的批评并不是什么新鲜事。大赦国际在2016年指责那里的钴矿业使用童工。</p>
<p>In July, the U.S. House of Representatives introduced a measure to ban imported products containing cobalt and copper mined through child labor or other abusive conditions in the DRC.<br/>
7月，美国众议院出台了一项措施，禁止进口刚果民主共和国含有通过童工或其他虐待条件下所开采钴和铜的产品。</p>
<p>Amnesty International has also reported many incidents of violence related to mining activity. In 2016, it said soldiers burned down a settlement to begin work on a cobalt and copper mine. The fire left a two-year-old girl with scars that will affect her for the rest of her life.<br/>
大赦国际还报告了许多与采矿活动有关的暴力事件。据报道，2016年，士兵们烧毁了一个定居点，以便开始开采钴铜矿。大火给一名两岁女孩留下了伤痕，这将影响她的余生。</p>
<p>The rights groups said they talked to 133 people during separate visits in February and September 2022. The people were in six places around Kolwezi, a city in the south of the country, and were affected by the abuses related to cobalt and copper mining.<br/>
人权组织表示，他们在2022年2月和9月的单独访问中与133人进行了交谈。这些人生活在该国南部城市科尔韦齐周边的六个地方，受到了与钴和铜矿开采有关的虐待行为的影响。</p>
<p>One neighborhood, home to 39,000 people, has been facing destruction because of the expansion of a copper and cobalt mine since 2015.<br/>
自2015年以来，由于一座铜钴矿的扩建，一处居住着39000人的社区一直面临着破坏。</p>
<p>The rights groups studied documents, photos, videos, satellite images and company communications.<br/>
人权组织研究了文件、照片、视频、卫星图像和企业通信。</p>
<p>Amnesty International said companies are not doing enough to deal with human rights concerns. Chemaf is a cobalt and copper mining company based in Dubai that operates in the DRC.<br/>
大赦国际表示，企业在处理人权问题上做得不够。Chemaf是一家总部位于迪拜的钴和铜矿开采公司，该公司在刚果民主共和国开展业务。</p>
<p>Following protests in 2019, the company paid $1.5 million to former residents through local officials. People received between $50 and $300. But the report said that was not enough. None of the former residents were able to secure good housing.<br/>
在2019年的抗议活动之后，该公司通过当地官员向原先的居民支付了150万美元。人们收到了50到300美元。但报告称这还不够。原先的居民没人能够获得良好的住房。</p>
<p>The rights groups said the world is demanding more "green" technologies that are not linked to climate change. However, the mining of minerals that are needed for these green technologies are causing social and environmental harm.<br/>
人权组织表示，世界正在要求更多与气候变化无关的“绿色”技术。然而，这些绿色技术所需的矿产开采正在造成社会和环境危害。</p>
<p>The group said removing carbon from the world economy "must not lead to further human rights violations."<br/>
该组织表示，从世界经济中消除碳“绝不能导致进一步侵犯人权”。</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.<br/>
我是安德鲁·史密斯。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Letting Mosquitoes Bite You for Science  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/letting-mosquitoes-bite-you-for-science.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>It is lunchtime. And mosquitoes find their way to Ella Branham's arm at a Salt Lake City lab in the American state of Utah.</p>
<p>"They're not very aggressive and they're kind of <strong>picky</strong> eaters," said Branham. She breathed into a glass tank to attract the insects to the carbon dioxide in her breath. "So I'll be feeding them with my arm."</p>
<p>Branham had volunteered to let the South American mosquitoes, called sabethes cyaneus, feed on her blood. She is doing so to help produce eggs and maintain the colony for education and research at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A colony of sabethes cyaneus mosquitoes feed on Ella Branham at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District on Monday, Aug. 28, 2023, in Salt Lake City. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9db9-08dbb5e82ffe_cx6_cy15_cw90_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A colony of sabethes cyaneus mosquitoes feed on Ella Branham at the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District on Monday, Aug. 28, 2023, in Salt Lake City. (AP Photo/Rick Bowmer)</span></div>
<p>The <strong>district</strong> is one of many mosquito control areas around the United States that seek to control one of the world's deadliest animals. Mosquitoes are expected to strengthen as climate change creates a warmer and wetter environment.</p>
<p>Mosquitoes can carry viruses including dengue, yellow fever, chikungunya and Zika. They are especially threatening to public health in Asia and Africa but are closely watched in the United States. Local agencies reported more than 1,100 cases of West Nile virus in 2022, says the U.S. Centers for Disease Control.</p>
<p>Most humans who get West Nile show no <strong>symptoms</strong>. But for some, it can cause <strong>vomiting, </strong>fever<strong> </strong>and in rare cases seizures or meningitis. Over roughly the last 25 years, nearly 3,000 deaths and more than 25,000 hospitalizations connected to West Nile were reported throughout the U.S., mostly in August.</p>
<p>West Nile deaths have been reported this year in states including Texas and Colorado. Mosquitoes are also thought to have caused malaria infections of people in Maryland, Florida and Texas.</p>
<p>Ary Faraji is a disease expert and the director of the Salt Lake City Mosquito Abatement District. He said the mosquito season is starting earlier and lasting longer as the climate has warmed. The district used to shut down each year in mid-September, but that has gotten later and later. Last year, district workers were still setting and checking traps until late November.</p>
<p>And this year, workers estimated that there were five times as many mosquitos in May compared to the average year. There was an unusually snowy winter in Salt Lake City and a very rainy spring that left more water for mosquitoes to <strong>breed</strong> in.</p>
<p>That is where the health threat comes in. While both males and females feed on sugar or nectar throughout their lives, females require blood to provide nutrition to their eggs.</p>
<p>The workers, including scientists and students, use drones, boats and vehicles to trap, sort and test mosquitos for viruses. Their work considers how things like weather systems and population growth will affect the spread of disease.</p>
<p>The more people there are close to a lot of mosquitos, the higher the chance of spread, Faraji said. The wetland areas surrounding Utah's Great Salt Lake are problematic, he added.</p>
<p>Though dangerous, mosquitoes are also important to ecosystems throughout the world. Some serve as <strong>pollinators</strong> or food sources to fish, birds and frogs.</p>
<p>"We try to maintain a balance and suppress them to the point that they're not negatively affecting communities," Faraji said. "Taking them away would definitely <strong>negatively</strong> impact our ecosystem overall."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>abate </strong><em>— v. </em> to become weaker</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>district </strong><em>— n. </em>an area established by a government for official government business</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>symptom </strong><em>— n. </em>a change in the body or mind which indicates that a disease is present</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vomit </strong><em>— n. </em>to have the food, liquid, etc., that is in your stomach come out through your mouth because you are sick</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breed </strong><em>— v. </em>to produce offspring by sexual reproduction</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pollinator </strong><em>— n. </em>to give pollen from another plant of the same kind so that seeds will be produced</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>negative </strong><em>— adj. </em>harmful or bad</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan Says Visitors Disrespecting Mount Fuji  (2023/9/18)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/japan-says-visitors-disrespecting-mount-fuji.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">17 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>On a gray and rainy Saturday, buses arrive continually at a base station of Japan's Mount Fuji. The buses release foreign visitors<strong> </strong>in front of stores and restaurants.</p>
<p>The area looks similar to a <strong>theme</strong><strong> park</strong>. It is not what most Japanese would expect below the 3,776-meter mountain. Mt Fuji is considered an important religious area. And Japanese honor the mountain for its perfectly balanced form.</p>
<p>"Hey, no smoking here!" a store worker told a man wearing shorts and holding a can of beer. He was standing in front of the red "torii" gate which marks the entrance to the Shinto religious center ahead.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Visitors are seen at the fifth stage on the slopes of Mount Fuji, Japan's highest mountain 3,776 metres (12,388 ft), in Fujiyoshida, Japan on September 9, 2023. (REUTERS/Mariko Katsumura)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/b01167f0-ddf7-4992-8535-df76e28ac00c_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Visitors are seen at the fifth stage on the slopes of Mount Fuji, Japan's highest mountain 3,776 metres (12,388 ft), in Fujiyoshida, Japan on September 9, 2023. (REUTERS/Mariko Katsumura)</span></div>
<p>Mt Fuji sits between the Yamanashi and Shizuoka areas in eastern Japan. It has always been popular with local and foreign visitors.</p>
<p>But a recent increase in visitors to Japan has led to high levels of pollution and other difficulties, officials say. They add they may be forced to take extreme measures. They may restrict the number of visitors by limiting the only way to visit the mountain by a yet-to-be-built public transportation system.</p>
<p>"Fuji faces a real crisis," Masatake Izumi, a Yamanashi area official, told reporters recently. It was the last weekend before the paths closed for the year.</p>
<p>"It's uncontrollable and we fear that Mt Fuji will soon become so <strong>unattractive</strong>, nobody would want to climb it," he said.</p>
<p>Mt Fuji was listed as a UNESCO World Heritage area 10 years ago, further increasing its popularity. World Heritage areas are places that the UN protects for having great value to humanity.</p>
<p>But the listing came with conditions that Japan reduce the number of visitors, environmental harm from visitors, and fix man-made areas designed for visitors.</p>
<p>However, the number of visitors has increased. "Subaru," the fifth and largest base station, had about 4 million visitors this summer. That is a 50 percent increase from 2013.</p>
<p>Despite the hard work of cleaners, businesses, and volunteers, social media is filled with posts about dirty bathrooms and waste along the climbing path.</p>
<p>Izumi worries that the International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS), which advises the World Heritage Committee, could come looking for an <strong>update</strong>.</p>
<p>"Bullet climbing" is where climbers try to climb Japan's tallest mountain for sunrise and go down the mountain on the same day. Officials say that it is a growing problem as well.</p>
<p>Rescue requests totaled 61 this year, up 50 percent from last year. Non-Japanese visitors make up about 25 percent, Shizuoka area police found. An official said most were poorly equipped, suffering from cold temperatures or the height of the mountain. Yamanashi police did not have similar data.</p>
<p>One local visitor said restrictions will have to come.</p>
<p>"Any Japanese person would want to climb Mt Fuji at least once in their life," said 62-year-old Jun Shibazaki, who arrived to visit. "But it's so <strong>crowded</strong>. Limited entry might be something we have to live with."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Mariko Katsumura reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>theme park </strong><em>– n.</em> an amusement park where the rides and attractions are based on a particular theme</p>
<p><strong>unattractive </strong><em>– adj.</em> not beautiful, interesting, or pleasing</p>
<p><strong>update</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> a report that includes the most recent information about something</p>
<p><strong>crowded </strong><em>– adj.</em> filled with too many people or things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Professors Blame Pandemic for College Students’ Math Troubles  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/professors-blame-pandemic-for-college-students-math-troubles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>"This is a huge issue," said one college math professor.</p>
<p>"This is <strong>significant</strong> and deep," said another.</p>
<p>They were talking about their students who are still struggling with <strong>basic</strong> math skills three years after the start of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="George Mason undergraduate math major David Wigginton writes an equation on a whiteboard as students Ethan Hill, right, and Diego Fonseca, center, take part in a summer math boot camp on Thursday, Aug. 1, 2023 at George Mason University in Fairfax. Va. (AP Photo/Kevin Wolf)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e418dcfa-2aa1-49b0-b5a4-aa872e9fc3b6_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">George Mason undergraduate math major David Wigginton writes an equation on a whiteboard as students Ethan Hill, right, and Diego Fonseca, center, take part in a summer math boot camp on Thursday, Aug. 1, 2023 at George Mason University in Fairfax. Va. (AP Photo/Kevin Wolf)</span></div>
<p>Most of the students are in their first or second year in college. But when the pandemic started in 2020, they were still in high school, learning algebra or early calculus.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, many U.S. schools closed to in-person classes and started teaching by video call. Education experts said they believed students would catch up.</p>
<p>College professors said they hoped for a "<strong>rebound</strong>" by now. But it has not happened in most places.</p>
<p>As a result, universities in the U.S. are trying to find ways to fix the problem. Some offer summer math camps. Others called on students to learn from each other, a process known as "peer tutoring." Still others offer basic math classes students can take while also attending classes such as calculus.</p>
<p>Brian Rider is the head of the math program at Temple University near Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>"It's not that they're unprepared," he said. "They're almost damaged."</p>
<p>Rider said he hated to say that, but "they're so behind."</p>
<p><strong>One teacher's experience</strong></p>
<p>Erin Vorke is a math instructor at Eastern Florida State College. Many of her students must take a math class to get a two-year associate degree and move on to a four-year college. Some are high school students who are getting college credit. She told VOA about her experience.</p>
<p>She said some of her students did not get a good <strong>foundation</strong> in math even before the pandemic started. Once they missed time in class, their troubles increased.</p>
<p>"It's definitely become a lot worse since the pandemic. And what I've been told is that everyone was just being passed through while they were in high school...I have a lot of students who can't work with <strong>negative</strong> numbers, I have students who don't know what an <strong>even</strong> number is."</p>
<p>Vorke said she cannot stop her class to teach students something they should have learned when they were in middle school.</p>
<p>"I slow down as much as I can, but I have to cover my <strong>curriculum</strong>," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Students struggling</strong></p>
<p>Diego Fonseca is a student in northern Virginia, just outside of Washington, D.C. Nineteen-year-old Fonseca recently finished high school. This summer, he took a math "<strong>boot camp</strong>" at George Mason University so he could "<strong>brush-up</strong>" on math learning. He was one of about 100 students trying to improve their math skills.</p>
<p>He said he did well in physics and computer science while in high school, but he did not get good scores on a math placement test for college. He wanted to take calculus, but in three tries on the test, he did not get a good enough score. He was permitted to take the test four times and wanted to do better on his final attempt.</p>
<p>He was not having trouble with the math he learned recently, but he did not learn algebra well early in high school when schools closed in 2020.</p>
<p>"I didn't have a <strong>hands-on</strong>, in-person class," Fonseca said. He later said he had trouble with more difficult algebra.</p>
<p>The math troubles are a problem for students at universities across the U.S. who want to study engineering and science. Many are being placed into low math classes, which means they are falling behind in their study programs.</p>
<p>Colleges say the pandemic learning problems affected both reading and math, but math skills suffered more, and recovery has been slow.</p>
<p>Maria Emelianenko is one of the math professors at George Mason. She said students are in difficult pre-calculus and calculus classes and they cannot add simple <strong>fractions</strong>.</p>
<p>Jessica Babcock is a math professor at Temple. She said she realized how big of a problem she had while grading a test last year. Nearly all her students missed what she thought was a simple question.</p>
<p>"It was a striking moment," she said.</p>
<p>Babcock teaches a basic math class that includes material students should have learned in their first year of high school. Before the pandemic, it had about 800 students. But by 2021 there were almost 1,400.</p>
<p>Education researchers say math is a "hands-on" subject and it was hard to teach with students learning from home. If students moved on to subjects like geometry or trigonometry without learning algebra, learning gaps could go unnoticed for years. In addition, they say parents have an easier time helping their children with reading than math at home.</p>
<p><strong>'Many students gave up on math'</strong></p>
<p>Katherine Strunk is an education expert who now heads the graduate school of education at the University of Pennsylvania. She led a study that looked at learning problems in Michigan.</p>
<p>She said minority students and low-income students had the most problems during the pandemic.</p>
<p>"They're the ones who are going to suffer the longer-term <strong>consequences</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>Babcock, the Temple professor, said many students gave up on math. They did not come for help and continued getting poor grades on tests.</p>
<p>The problems made Babcock change her class this year. The class has discussions, making students more involved in the learning process.</p>
<p>"We really want students to feel like they're part of their learning," Babcock said.</p>
<p>That kind of class, said Vorke, may be more helpful for students who wonder when they will use algebra or other math in the future. She is part of a group of educators at her college who teach what she called "real-world problems (students) can actually relate to," each summer.</p>
<p>"If you go shopping, and there's a sale, and you want to figure out how much you'll be paying for an item that's 10 percent off. That's algebra," Vorke said.</p>
<p>After the summer boot camp, Fonseca said he chose to start his college studies at Northern Virginia Community College. In two years, he can move on to George Mason. He recently took the placement test again. On his final attempt, he qualified for calculus.</p>
<p>"I didn't have any expectation I'd do that," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press and his own reporting.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>significant </strong><em>–adj.</em> important in some way</p>
<p><strong>basic </strong><em>–adj.</em> simple and low-level</p>
<p><strong>rebound </strong><em>–n.</em> a return to an earlier, better condition</p>
<p><strong>foundation </strong><em>–n.</em> the base on which later learning is built</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong><em>–adj.</em> less than zero</p>
<p><strong>even </strong><em>–adj</em>. a multiple of two</p>
<p><strong>curriculum </strong><em>–n.</em> the classes that are part of a school study program</p>
<p><strong>boot camp </strong><em>–n.</em> an intensive training program aimed at getting students to become much better in a short period of time</p>
<p><strong>brush up </strong><em>–v.</em> to improve skills or knowledge usually some time after learning them</p>
<p><strong>fraction </strong><em>–n.</em> non-whole numbers that are expressed as division of one whole number into another</p>
<p><strong>hands-on </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving actually doing something rather than reading or thinking about it</p>
<p><strong>consequences </strong><em>–n. (usually pl.) </em>the results of words or actions</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Icing on the Cake' Is As Good As It Sounds  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/icing-on-the-cake-is-as-good-as-it-sounds.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program we explore English words and expressions. We give you examples and notes on usage.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a <strong>delicious</strong> <strong>dessert</strong> made from flour, butter, sugar, and <strong>flavorings</strong> such as vanilla, chocolate, or my favorite, coconut. We are talking about cake!</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Cakes with different icing and flavors are for sale ahead of Valentine's Day in London, Britain, February 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Peter Nicholls)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-164b-08db0e50cba7_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Cakes with different icing and flavors are for sale ahead of Valentine's Day in London, Britain, February 13, 2023. (REUTERS/Peter Nicholls)</span></div>
<p>Cake is a commonly served sweet treat at celebrations. And the word also appears in several English idioms.</p>
<p>Back in 2022, we taught the idiom <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/have-your-cake-and-eat-it-too/6808031.html">to have your cake and eat it too</a>. This means to have the best of both worlds. You do not have to choose between two good things. Another expression is <u>a piece of cake.</u> This describes something that is very easy to do or finish.</p>
<p>Because of all the sugar and butter, we probably should not eat too much cake. But it is so good! And sometimes having a lot of something good is better. That is the message of today's show.</p>
<p>Most cakes are made up of two parts: the part made from flour and the sweet topping, or icing.</p>
<p>Now, a cake without the sweet icing on top is already great. After all, it's made with lots of butter and sugar. It's sweet and satisfying. So, the icing is not really necessary. But it makes the cake extra special.</p>
<p><strong>Icing on the cake</strong></p>
<p>And that is the meaning of the idiom <u>icing on the cake</u>. Something already good is made better by the addition of something else. If you describe something as <u>icing on the cake</u> or <u>the icing on the cake</u>, you mean that it makes a good thing even better, or sweeter!</p>
<p>Let's hear an example.</p>
<p><em>She loves her new job and her new co-workers. So, getting her own parking spot was <u>the icing on the cake</u>! She hates looking for parking. </em></p>
<p>The idiom <u>icing on the cake</u> has another meaning. It can be someone's greatest <strong>accomplishment </strong>or victory.</p>
<p>Here is an example of that usage.</p>
<p><em>He had achieved the highest level of success in the company. So, his <strong>fancy</strong> new title was simply <u>icing on the cake</u>. </em></p>
<p><strong>Cherry on top</strong></p>
<p>We have another dessert saying that means about the same thing. Some cakes or ice cream dishes have a special topping: a sweetened cherry.</p>
<p>So, if something is the <u>cherry on top</u>, it is an addition that turns something good into something great!</p>
<p><em>The Taylors bought the house without even knowing it had a large garden in the back. That was the <u>cherry on top</u> since they both love to garden.</em></p>
<p>Sometimes we use the ‘cherry on top' when making an appeal for assistance.</p>
<p>Let's say, I really need a friend's help. I might say, "Please help me! Pretty please with a cherry on top." This specially worded appeal often does the trick and the help comes! But, just know that it can also make you sound a little <strong>desperate</strong>!</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this Words and Their Stories. Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo!</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>delicious</strong> <em>– adj.</em> appealing to one of the bodily senses especially of taste or smell</p>
<p><strong>dessert</strong> <em>– n. </em>a usually sweet course or dish (as of pastry or ice cream) usually served at the end of a meal</p>
<p><strong>flavoring </strong><em>– n. </em>a substance added to food or drink to give it a desired taste</p>
<p><strong>accomplishment </strong><em>– n.</em> an ability, social quality, or skill gained through training or practice</p>
<p><strong>fancy </strong><em>– adj. </em>impressive</p>
<p><strong>desperate </strong><em>– adj. </em>being beyond or almost beyond hope</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Calvin Coolidge: Silent  (2023/9/17)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-calvin-coolidge.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">16 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Calvin Coolidge. He was the vice president under <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-presidents-warren-harding/4018013.html">Warren Harding</a>. When Harding died suddenly a little more than two years into his term, Coolidge became president.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Calvin Coolidge" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5765aa12-6437-4c9a-9107-fdf3e26d3c0a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Calvin Coolidge</span></div>
<p>Coolidge is linked to two opposing ideas. The first idea is quiet restraint.</p>
<p>The president's nickname was "Silent Cal." He rarely took part in <strong>casual conversation</strong>. And as a leader, he often thought the best action was not to take any action.</p>
<p>Many voters liked his "cool" style. Coolidge quickly earned a public image as a serious man who did not spend money or words easily.</p>
<p>But Coolidge is also linked to a period in U.S. history known as the Roaring Twenties.</p>
<p>In those years, the 1920s, the American economy was generally good. Many people spent money on exciting things – such as the still-new automobile – and on entertainment, including alcoholic drinks, cigarettes, and dancing. Creative expression such as jazz and Art Deco architecture became popular.</p>
<p>Calvin Coolidge is often given credit for helping fuel the Roaring Twenties with his pro-business economic policies.</p>
<p>But some historians <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/coolidge/impact-and-legacy"><strong>caution</strong></a> against remembering Coolidge's business freedom policies too <strong>fondly</strong>. They say he helped create the conditions for the severe economic depression that followed his presidency.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Calvin Coolidge and his sister were born and raised on a farm in the northeast state of Vermont.</p>
<p>Coolidge spoke highly of both his parents.</p>
<p>His father owned a store, and also held local political offices. He had a public image for honesty, public service, and <strong>thrift</strong>.</p>
<p>Young Calvin Coolidge helped his father in the store, and hoped to be just like him.</p>
<p>Coolidge also admired his mother's strong character. He was 12 years old when she died, and he wrote that losing her was "the greatest <strong>grief</strong> that can come to a boy."</p>
<p>Six years later, his sister also died.</p>
<p>Their deaths made young Calvin Coolidge even more serious than he already was.</p>
<p>But Coolidge was also known for his <strong>wit</strong> – a kind of humor that often depends on word play or intelligence. As a student at Amherst College in Massachusetts, Coolidge became known as an able and funny public speaker.</p>
<p>That skill helped him rise in politics. He began with lower-level offices in Massachusetts, and later served as that state's governor.</p>
<p>Along the way, he married <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/topics/first-ladies/grace-coolidge">Grace Anna Goodhue</a>, a teacher for the deaf. She was known to be warm and social, and the couple were reported to have a loving marriage. They went on to have two sons.</p>
<p>In 1920, the Republican Party nominated Coolidge to be its vice presidential candidate. In general, voters liked the Republican <strong>ticket</strong>. They were ready for a change after the reform policies and international <strong>engagement</strong> of Democrat <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/americas-president-woodrow-wilson/4001252.html">Woodrow Wilson</a>.</p>
<p>Sure enough, the Republicans won the election in a landslide.</p>
<p>But Coolidge did not enjoy the office of vice president very much. He had little power in the government. During meetings, he often remained silent.</p>
<p>One summer night he and his wife were on vacation in Vermont. His father, Colonel Coolidge, woke them up in the middle of the night with some dramatic news: President Harding had died.</p>
<p>Reporters quickly gathered at the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nps.gov/nr/travel/presidents/calvin_coolidge_homestead.html">small farmhouse</a>. Colonel Coolidge had not put electricity in the house. So everyone watched by the light of an oil lamp.</p>
<p>Colonel Coolidge was a public official. He used the family Bible and a copy of the Constitution to <a class="wsw__a" href="http://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/calvin-coolidge-takes-oath-of-office-after-hardings-death">swear in his son</a> as the 30<sup>th</sup> U.S. president.</p>
<p>Then the country's new leader did a very <strong>sensible</strong> thing: he went back to bed.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>President Coolidge believed in limited government, especially limited federal government. He permitted state and Cabinet officials to decide as many issues as they could.</p>
<p>Coolidge used his authority to <strong>focus</strong> mostly on the country's economy.</p>
<p>At the time he took office, the U.S. was at the start of an economic <strong>boom</strong>. Coolidge tried to <strong>maintain</strong> that <strong>prosperity</strong>. He did not <strong>regulate</strong> businesses too much, and he sharply reduced taxes, especially on the wealthy.</p>
<p>By nearly every measure, the economy grew.</p>
<p>But the policies also widened the divide between rich and poor Americans, and put the country's economy in a risky situation.</p>
<p>More and more people began to invest their money in the stock market. Some put their dollars in dangerous investments.</p>
<p>And business owners produced more goods than most members of the public could really <strong>afford</strong>. Increasingly, people borrowed money on credit to pay for <strong>luxury</strong> goods.</p>
<p>At the same time, the economic situation of many American farmers was getting worse. The weather had been unusually dry in some places. And the price of food was falling.</p>
<p>Farmers asked the federal government for assistance. But Coolidge rejected several bills that might have helped them. The bills had other problems, Coolidge reasoned, and he did not think that the federal government should intervene in the situation.</p>
<p>So the farmers continued to suffer.</p>
<p>But most voters remained supportive of Coolidge. Even though the president was considered a quiet person, he spoke often on the radio, appeared in a talking film, met with reporters regularly, and posed in funny costumes for photographers.</p>
<p>He easily won elected in 1924. Historians believe he could have won another term, too, in 1928. But Coolidge chose not to seek office.</p>
<p>Some believed he was too saddened by the death of his teenaged son. Shortly after Coolidge became president, the boy had been playing tennis and slightly wounded his toe. The wound became infected. The infection spread to the boy's blood. A few days later, he died.</p>
<p>Although Coolidge continued his presidency, he later said the joy had gone from the job.</p>
<p>But when he decided not to seek re-election, he did not talk about his feelings. Instead, he simply wrote a note to reporters saying: "I do not choose to run for President in 1928."</p>
<p>His secretary of commerce, Herbert Hoover, was elected instead. Coolidge retired to his home in Massachusetts and led a quiet private life.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy</strong></p>
<p>President Coolidge was well-liked by most Americans. Later presidents – including Ronald Reagan – sought to follow some of his economic policies.</p>
<p>But many historians have questioned those policies. They say that Coolidge did not pay enough attention to the situation of farmers. And they say the stock market was rising too fast.</p>
<p>Seven months after Coolidge left office, the U.S. economy collapsed.</p>
<p>The country was still deep in the Great Depression when Coolidge passed away. He died – quietly, of course – during an afternoon nap at the age of 60.</p>
<p>His will was but a single sentence.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. Caty Weaver was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>_______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>casual</strong> - <em>adj. </em>happening by chance : not planned or expected</p>
<p><strong>conversation</strong> - <em>n.</em> talking in an informal way</p>
<p><strong>fondly</strong> - <em>adv. </em>in a loving way</p>
<p><strong>thrift </strong>- <em>n. </em>careful use of money so that it is not wasted</p>
<p><strong>grief</strong> - <em>n. </em>deep sadness caused especially by someone's death</p>
<p><strong>wit</strong> - <em>n. </em>an ability to say or write things that are clever and usually funny</p>
<p><strong>ticket</strong> - <em>n.</em> a list of the candidates supported by a political party in an election</p>
<p><strong>engagement</strong> -<em> n.</em> the act or state of being involved with something</p>
<p><strong>sensible</strong> - <em>adj.</em> having or showing good sense or judgment</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Art, Culture of an Old New York Train Station  (2023/9/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/art-culture-of-an-old-new-york-train-station.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The first subway station in New York City was designed to be a <strong>masterpiece</strong> and was considered a "<strong>jewel in the crown</strong>" when it opened.</p>
<p>The trains in New York City's public transportation system, its subway, mostly run underground. Today, the main concern of subway designers is that their systems work correctly.</p>
<p>New York's subway opened in 1904. City Hall Station was one of New York City's first underground subway stations. Now called Old City Hall Station, it was built during a time when many public buildings and spaces were designed to appear <strong>majestic</strong>. The goal was to demonstrate that New York could compete culturally with great European cities, sometimes called metropolises.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Visitors take pictures during a tour of the City Hall Station, New York City, June 3, 2018. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-973d-08dba975b0b8_cx0_cy14_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Visitors take pictures during a tour of the City Hall Station, New York City, June 3, 2018. </span></div>
<p>"It was a statement that New York City had arrived at the level of the great European metropolises like London and Paris, Rome, Madrid...that New York City was taking its place as a world city," said Clifton Hood. Hood is a history professor at Hobart and William Smith Colleges in Geneva, New York.</p>
<p>Inside Old City Hall Station, the top is not flat in shape but <strong>curved</strong> instead. The walls rise up to create a high, round shape known as a vault. Square pieces of glass, called tiles, shine. Some of the lights in the station are called chandeliers. These are beautiful hanging lights that hold many individual light <strong>bulbs</strong> and look like huge pieces of jewelry.</p>
<p>Polly Desjarlais is with the New York Transit Museum. She said she was "blown away" when she first saw the old station. She used words like "lovely, elegant and really unique space" to describe the station.</p>
<p>"I've heard [the station] be described as a celebration of curves, because there are a lot of curves. Everything is sort-of rounded," Desjarlais said.</p>
<p>But those beautiful curves are why the station is no longer part of the normal subway system. Its rounded <strong>platform</strong> cannot fit long trains.</p>
<p>"The platform at City Hall is really curved. It's a very, very tight curve, and the platform itself is just over 200 feet long. So, it's short," Desjarlais said. "As the subway got busier...trains got longer, and we added cars...We were growing those platforms and making them longer..."</p>
<p>Although it is no longer part of the subway system, Old City Hall Station is still being used. One train line, the No. 6, uses the Old City Hall Station to turn around. And while the public cannot enter the station from the street, the members of the New York Transit Museum can see the station a few times a year at a cost of about $50.</p>
<p>Over the years, there have been ideas to make the old station a restaurant or a place for travelers to the city to visit. However, security concerns put those ideas to rest. Today, the unofficial way for the public to see the old station is by taking the No. 6 train and staying on after the last stop. Then, the train turns around at the Old City Hall Station, and riders will be able to see the majestic space.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dora Mekouar reported this story for VOA. Gena Bennett adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>masterpiece</strong>–<em>n</em>. a work of outstanding art</p>
<p><strong>jewel in the crown</strong> –<em>expression</em> something that is the best among similar, often costly or beautiful things</p>
<p><strong>majestic</strong>–<em>adj</em>. having or showing extreme beauty</p>
<p><strong>curved</strong> –<em>adj</em>. a smooth, rounded line or shape</p>
<p><strong>bulb</strong> –<em>n</em>. an electric device that produces light</p>
<p><strong>platform</strong>–<em>n</em>. an area where people stand to wait for or enter and exit a train</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Awareness vs. Consciousness  (2023/9/16)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/awareness-vs-consciousness.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">15 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "awareness" and "consciousness."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Dear teacher,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Awareness vs. Consciousness " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1d4a-08dbb52e44ff_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Awareness vs. Consciousness </span></div>
<p>I am Mayer from Colombia. I hope you are well.</p>
<p>I would like to know the difference between the words, "awareness" and "consciousness."</p>
<p>Thanks a lot,</p>
<p>Mayer</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for this wonderful question, Mayer.</p>
<p>"Awareness" and "consciousness" share somewhat similar definitions.</p>
<p>The <em>Merriam-Webster</em> dictionary defines "awareness" as having knowledge and understanding that something is happening or exists. And it defines "consciousness" as being aware of things around you or something within oneself.</p>
<p>But these two words can have many different meanings.</p>
<p>Let's look at each one more closely.</p>
<p><strong>Awareness</strong></p>
<p>"Awareness" is a noun that comes from the adjective "aware." When you are aware of something, you know or you have a sense that something exists. For example:</p>
<p><em>Many drivers have no awareness of other cars in their blind spots, areas around the car that they cannot easily see. </em></p>
<p><em>In <strong>yoga</strong>, your mind and your body connect to bring awareness to places of pain so that you can ease it. </em></p>
<p>We often talk about "awareness" of social or political causes or beliefs. This is one of the meanings that is shared with "consciousness."</p>
<p><em>World Pangolin Day is celebrated on February 18th to raise more awareness for these animals.</em></p>
<p>Let's move on to "consciousness."</p>
<p><strong>Consciousness</strong></p>
<p>"Consciousness" is a noun that has several meanings. It comes from the adjective "conscious." When you are "conscious," you are awake and can think and make decisions for yourself.</p>
<p><em>When you are asleep, you are not conscious. </em></p>
<p>Your "consciousness" is your physical and mental state of being conscious or awake.</p>
<p><em>She lost consciousness after she fell and hit her head. </em></p>
<p>Your "consciousness" also includes your mind and thoughts.</p>
<p><em>Don't let his bad feelings cloud your consciousness. </em></p>
<p>And lastly, "consciousness" is the belief that people can have, or it can be an interest or knowledge of certain ideas.</p>
<p><em>Greta Thunberg helped younger people to have more interest in climate consciousness and activism. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Mayer.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>yoga </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of exercises for gaining bodily or mental control and well-being</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>France Bans iPhone 12 Over Radiation, Belgium Considering Move  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/france-bans-iphone-12-over-radiation-belgium-considering-move.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Belgium says it plans to study possible health risks from electromagnetic radiation release by Apple's iPhone 12 smartphone.</p>
<p>Belgium's move comes after French <strong>regulators </strong>ordered Apple to stop selling the iPhone 12. French officials said the phone creates more electromagnetic radiation than the European Union permits. Apple disputes this. The company said the device meets all requirements.</p>
<p>The French government agency that oversees wireless communications <strong>frequencies</strong> said it issued the order after the phone failed one of two tests. The tests are related to the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_elOPCnYI">amount</a> of electromagnetic waves the body can <strong>absorb</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A man looks at Apple iPhones at a shop in Bilbao, Spain on September 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Vincent West)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/82a23220-a6d9-4ccf-985e-39d6863d2f64_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A man looks at Apple iPhones at a shop in Bilbao, Spain on September 14, 2023. (REUTERS/Vincent West)</span></div>
<p>Apple released the iPhone 12 in late 2020. It is unclear why the phone did not pass the agency's latest tests or why only the iPhone 12 is affected.</p>
<p>France's <strong>digital </strong>minister said the iPhone 12's radiation levels are still much lower than levels that scientific studies found could harm users. The French agency said its tests do not test normal phone use.</p>
<p>The National Frequency Agency on Tuesday called on Apple to use all means to fix the problem for phones already in use. It said it would study <strong>updates</strong> to the phones. If they do not work, "Apple will have to <strong>recall</strong>" phones that have already been sold, it said.</p>
<p>The agency recently tested 141 cellphones. It found that when the iPhone 12 is held in a hand or near the body, its level of electromagnetic energy absorption is 5.74 watts per kilogram. That is higher than the EU requirement of 4 watts per kilogram or less.</p>
<p>Watts per kilogram is a measure of the rate at which energy is absorbed by the body.</p>
<p>The phone passed a separate test of radiation levels for devices kept in heavy clothes or in a container, the agency said.</p>
<p>Malcolm Sperrin is director of medical physics at Britain's Royal Berkshire hospital group. He said the radiation limits are set well below the level at which harm will happen. He said a small increase above those limits is unlikely to affect a person's health.</p>
<p>Users of the iPhone 12 should be able to download an update that prevents the radiation from going above the limit, Sperrin said.</p>
<p>It is not clear why this model appears to release higher radiation. But it might be related to when the phone is seeking a connection to send or receive signal, he said.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization says it has not found any harm to health caused by the use of mobile phones. Apple said the iPhone 12 has been approved by many international bodies and meets requirements for radiation around the world.</p>
<p><strong>Other country's responses </strong></p>
<p>Belgium's latest action on the phone raises the possibility that other European countries might ban the model after France.</p>
<p>Italy said it would take no steps for now. But Germany's network regulator BNetzA said that the work in France could act as a guide for Europe. The agency said that it might reconsider the smartphone for the German market if the situation progresses in France.</p>
<p>A Dutch digital organization said it was looking into Apple's phone and would ask the U.S. company for an explanation. But it said that there was no immediate risk.</p>
<p>Britain has not announced any plans after France's decision.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English using material from The Associated Press and Reuters. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>frequency </strong>–n. the measure of radio waves used for communications</p>
<p><strong>regulate </strong><em>– v.</em> to make rules or laws that control (something)</p>
<p><strong>absorb </strong><em>– v.</em> to take in (something, such as a liquid) in a natural or gradual way</p>
<p><strong>digital </strong><em>– adj.</em> using or characterized by computer technology</p>
<p><strong>update </strong><em>– n.</em> a change or addition to computer software that includes the most recent information</p>
<p><strong>recall </strong><em>– v.</em> to ask people to return (a product with a defect or problem)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is Green Hydrogen a Truly Clean Burning Fuel?  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/is-green-hydrogen-a-truly-clean-burning-fuel.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Green hydrogen has been presented around the world as a clean energy solution. But is this fuel truly clean burning? And what does it take to produce it?</p>
<p><strong>What is hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>Hydrogen is the lightest chemical element. It has no color, taste, or smell, and can combine with oxygen to form water.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="P V R Murthy, center, general manager at Oil India Limited, pump station 3, shows a part of a hydrogen plant in Jorhat, India, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-944b-08dbafe782f4_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">P V R Murthy, center, general manager at Oil India Limited, pump station 3, shows a part of a hydrogen plant in Jorhat, India, Thursday, Aug. 17, 2023. (AP Photo/Anupam Nath)</span></div>
<p><strong>What is green hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>To be considered green hydrogen, the production process of separating hydrogen from other elements must be powered by <strong>renewable</strong> energy.</p>
<p>Hydrogen has been produced and widely used for more than 100 years, mainly to make fertilizers and plastics and to process oil. The gas has mostly been produced from <strong>fossil fuels</strong>, especially natural gas.</p>
<p>Industry estimates predict the worldwide market for green hydrogen could reach $410 billion by 2030. This would double its current market size.</p>
<p><strong>What can green hydrogen be used for?</strong></p>
<p>Green hydrogen can be used in several industries, including steelmaking, <strong>concrete</strong> production and in manufacturing chemicals and fertilizers. It can also be used to produce electricity, as a fuel for transportation and to heat homes. Supporters say green hydrogen could be used to make these processes better for the environment.</p>
<p>Francisco Boshell is an energy expert at the International Renewable Energy Agency in Abu Dhabi, the United Arab Emirates. He told the Associated Press (AP) that he is hopeful about green hydrogen being able to produce more clean energy. This could especially be true with energy from renewables like sun and wind power, which cannot easily be stored for later use.</p>
<p><strong>Are there concerns about green hydrogen?</strong></p>
<p>Boshell said one problem with hydrogen is its unpredictability. The gas is highly flammable, meaning it can easily catch fire, and requires special pipelines for safe transport. This means most green hydrogen will likely be used close to where it is produced.</p>
<p>The Energy Transitions Commission is a research group based in London. Its experts said in a 2021 report that, because hydrogen is highly flammable and difficult to transport, its use for heating buildings and other uses is limited. The commission is calling for <strong>net-zero</strong> <strong>emissions</strong> by 2050.</p>
<p>The report said hydrogen is also less effective than direct electrification methods. This is because some energy is lost when renewable resources are changed into hydrogen and then that hydrogen is changed again to power. The report suggested that the gas could be used as a way to avoid storing electricity in <strong>batteries</strong>.</p>
<p>Some studies have questioned the high cost of hydrogen production as well as its investment risks. There are concerns linked to a greater need for water than other clean power systems. Critics have also pointed out the lack of international guidelines that make it difficult for a worldwide market to develop.</p>
<p>Robert Howarth is an environmental expert and professor of environmental biology at Cornell University in New York state. He told the AP he thinks green hydrogen is being praised too much, in part because of <strong>lobbying</strong> efforts by the oil and gas industry.</p>
<p>But Boshell, of the International Renewable Energy Agency, disagreed. His organization has projected hydrogen demand will grow to 550 million tons by 2050. That would be up from the current 100 million tons.</p>
<p>The International Energy Agency says production of hydrogen is responsible for creating around 830 million tons of carbon dioxide per year. Boshell said just replacing this so-called gray hydrogen – hydrogen produced from fossil fuels – would establish a long-term market for green hydrogen.</p>
<p>"The first thing we have to do is start replacing the existing demand for gray hydrogen," he said. "And then we can add additional demand and <strong>applications</strong> of green hydrogen as a fuel for industries, shipping and aviation."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>renewable </strong><em>– adj. </em>any naturally occurring kind of energy, such as sunlight or wind</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>– n. </em>fuels such as coal, oil, or natural gas that are formed in the Earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>concrete </strong><em>– n</em>. a hard substance using in building operations</p>
<p><strong>net-zero </strong><em>– v. </em>when a country, city, or territory removes as many emissions as they produce</p>
<p><strong>emission </strong><em>– n. </em>the act of sending something out such as a gas, heat, or light</p>
<p><strong>battery </strong>–n. a device that stores electricity chemically</p>
<p><strong>lobby </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to persuade a politician, the government or an official group that a particular thing should or should not happen</p>
<p><strong>application </strong>–n. uses for a product, resource, idea or method</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Say a Common Cold Medicine is Ineffective  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/experts-say-a-common-cold-medicine-is-ineffective.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Mario Ritter, Jr</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>American government experts who studied a popular medicine used for colds say the drug is likely not effective and should not be taken by mouth.</p>
<p>Sixteen experts for the U.S. Food and Drug Administration examined the drug phenylephrine. The drug is in many medicines that treat nasal <strong>congestion</strong>, a condition also known as a stuffy nose. The medicines include Sudafed, Allegra and Dayquil among others.</p>
<p>The experts read a scientific <strong>review</strong> released by the FDA before they met. The scientific study said there were many mistakes in earlier tests of phenylephrine's effectiveness. It said the FDA no longer accepted the earlier testing results.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - On Sept. 12, 2023 advisers to the Food and Drug Administration said that an ingredient, phenylephrine, is ineffective at relieving nasal congestion. Shown here is Sudafed containing another ingredient at Hospital Discount Pharmacy in 2005. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6154-08dbb5505c5e_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - On Sept. 12, 2023 advisers to the Food and Drug Administration said that an ingredient, phenylephrine, is ineffective at relieving nasal congestion. Shown here is Sudafed containing another ingredient at Hospital Discount Pharmacy in 2005. </span></div>
<p>One of the experts was Dr. Mark Dykewicz. He is an allergy specialist at Saint Louis University School of Medicine. Dykewicz said, "Modern studies, when well <strong>conducted</strong>, are not showing any improvement in congestion with phenylephrine."</p>
<p>Phenylephrine is an over-the-counter drug. Anyone can buy it at a store. A doctor's order is not required to purchase it. Phenylephrine is the most popular decongestant in a market valued at $2.2 billion dollars.</p>
<p>If the FDA follows the advice of the experts, companies that make the medicine will have to remove it from stores. These companies include Johnson &amp; Johnson, Bayer and other leading drug makers.</p>
<p>The drug would remain in medicines taken through the nose, however. The nasal <strong>spray</strong> form of phenylephrine is considered effective and there are no plans to review it.</p>
<p>But offering higher amounts of the drug by mouth is not possible because it can increase blood pressure to dangerous levels.</p>
<p>Researchers at the University of Florida first requested that the FDA remove phenylephrine from a list of approved drugs. The same researchers questioned the drug's effectiveness in 2007. They said they found no difference between using the drug and using an inactive substance called a placebo.</p>
<p>Phenylephrine has been sold in different forms for 75 years. Dr. Theresa Michele leads the FDA's office of nonprescription drugs. She said, "Any time a product has been on the market that long, it's human nature to make <strong>assumptions</strong> about what we know about the product."</p>
<p>The FDA reviewers said the studies they examined showed how quickly the body processes phenylephrine. The research shows that too little of the drug reaches the area of the nose when the medicine is taken by mouth. Forms of the drug sprayed into the nose appear more effective.</p>
<p>The reviewers said barring the drug from medicine taken by mouth would avoid the "unnecessary costs and delay in <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_MAAS5KIO">care of taking</a> a drug that has <strong>no</strong> <strong>benefit</strong>.</p>
<p>The FDA has not updated its list of approved drugs to treat nasal congestion since 1995. The process for changing the list takes years. But Congress passed a law in 2020 that would speed the process for drugs that do not require a doctor's permission to use.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Matthew Perrone reported this story for the Associated Press. Mario Ritter, Jr. adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>congestion</strong> <em>–n. (medical)</em> blocked with fluid</p>
<p><strong>pharmacist </strong><em>–n.</em> a person whose job it is to prepare and sell drugs that doctors order for their patients</p>
<p><strong>spray </strong><em>–n.</em> liquid that is forced out of a container in very small drops</p>
<p><strong>assumption </strong><em>–n</em>. something that a person thinks is true but of which they have no proof</p>
<p><strong>no</strong> <strong>benefit</strong> <em>–phrase</em> something that does not have a useful or good result</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Phrasal Verbs with 'Along'  (2023/9/15)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/three-phrasal-verbs-with-along.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">14 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Sometimes, the Learning English program <em>Ask A Teacher</em> receives questions from learners that we are not able to answer on that program. The question might be more <strong>advanced</strong>, and the answer longer, than we have time for on <em>Ask A Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>But the questions are worthy! So, in this week's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore Noura's question about phrasal verbs with "along."</p>
<p>Noura writes that she does not understand why we add "along" to such words as "come," "send" and "<strong>tag</strong>." She says that she does not see any changes to their meanings when "along" is added.</p><div class="contentImage"><img along="" alt="Three Phrasal Verbs with " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1b5a-08dbb47bd25b_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Three Phrasal Verbs with "Along" </span></div>
<p>Let's answer Noura's question about these three phrasal verbs.</p>
<p><strong>Along </strong></p>
<p>"Along" as a preposition means in a line <strong>matching</strong> the length or direction of something. It can also mean points on or near something.</p>
<p><em>We drove along the coast of Maine.</em></p>
<p>We use "along" in this sentence to say that we drove on a road that runs next to, or near, the coast.</p>
<p><em>We saw beautiful <strong>beach </strong>houses along the drive.</em></p>
<p>Here we use "along" to mean points. The beach houses are the points.</p>
<p>Along as an adverb has many meanings. We can use "along" to describe the forward movement of something. It can also mean to be "in the company of" or "in addition to."</p>
<p>When we add "along" to a verb, we get these more exact meanings.</p>
<p><strong>What are phrasal verbs?</strong></p>
<p>Phrasal verbs are groups of words made up of a verb and another short word or words. Together, these groups of words mean something different from what the individual words suggest. As a result, you can think of phrasal verbs as kinds of special expressions.</p>
<p>There are many phrasal verbs in English, and often each phrasal verb can have different meanings.</p>
<p>Let's try to simplify Noura's three phrasal verbs, "come along," "send along" and "tag along."</p>
<p><strong>Come along</strong></p>
<p>"Come along" is our first phrasal verb. It means to go with or <strong>accompany </strong>someone. Usually that person is the one who leads the way. So, the person that is "coming along" is the secondary person, who is okay with someone leading them.</p>
<p><em>Do you mind if I come along to the store with you? I just need a few<strong> </strong>things for dinner.</em></p>
<p>Come along is a phrasal verb with other meanings, too.</p>
<p>It can mean to make progress.</p>
<p><em>Your painting is coming along nicely. It is almost done.</em></p>
<p>And lastly, "come along" means to make an appearance.</p>
<p><em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/super-blue-and-blood-a-guide-to-different-full-moons/7250151.html">Blue moons</a> come along every two or three years, usually.</em></p>
<p><strong>Send along</strong></p>
<p>The next phrasal verb with "along" is "send along." It has two meanings. The first meaning is to send something additional with something else.</p>
<p><em>My sister mailed me a gift last week and sent along a letter from my parents.</em></p>
<p>In addition to the gift, the letter was also sent.</p>
<p>"Send along" also means to dismiss. Usually, we can separate this phrasal verb for this meaning.</p>
<p><em>The teacher sent the children along to lunch.</em></p>
<p><strong>Tag along</strong></p>
<p>"Tag along"<strong> </strong>is like "come along." It means to follow someone else, but with an added meaning that the person "tagging along" might not be so welcomed or is just following the other person. It has a more <strong>negative</strong> association than "come along."</p>
<p><em>Sam's little sister always tags along when he plays outside with his friends.</em></p>
<p>The verb "tag" by itself can mean to attach as an additional element or to follow closely. While both meanings share similarities to "tag along," the phrasal verb has additional meaning "tagged" on.</p>
<p><strong>Final thoughts</strong></p>
<p>Today, we looked at three phrasal verbs with the preposition "along." Phrasal verbs have their own separate meaning apart from the original verbs and preposition/adverb combination. "Come along" and "tag along" are similar, but "tag along" has a more negative association. You might want someone to come along with you, but tagging along, probably not. "Send along" has two meanings, to dismiss and to send something together with something else.</p>
<p>Thanks for the question, Noura. We hope our exploration of come, send and tag along has cleared up some of the mystery around phrasal verbs.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p>And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>advanced</strong> – <em>adj</em>. having a high level of skill or difficulty</p>
<p><strong>tag</strong> – <em>v</em>. to choose for a special purpose</p>
<p><strong>matching </strong>– <em>adj</em>. having the qualities and looking appealing together</p>
<p><strong>beach </strong>– <em>n</em>. an area covered with sand that is by a body of water</p>
<p><strong>accompany </strong><em>– v. </em>to go somewhere with someone</p>
<p><strong>ingredient</strong> <em>– n. </em>one of the things used to make a food product</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong><em> </em>–<em> adj. </em>having harmful or undesirable effects</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>AI Development Requires Large Amounts of Water  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/ai-development-requires-large-amounts-of-water.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Researchers say the methods used to create artificial intelligence (AI) systems require large amounts of water. As a result, people are calling on AI developers to reduce their water usage and take more responsibility for the environmental resources they use.</p>
<p>The <em>Associated Press</em> recently reported on water usage by American-based OpenAI, the company that launched the ChatGPT AI tool. ChatGPT is a so-called "chatbot" designed to interact smoothly with humans and perform high-level writing. Such tools are also known as "generative AI" or "large language models."</p>
<p>The development and training methods used to create large language models require powerful computing systems. This process uses a lot of electricity and produces a lot of heat. Data center operators pump in water to keep equipment cool.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Traffic is shown on Interstate 35 near a Microsoft data center, Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023, in West Des Moines, Iowa. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0622-08dbb3d9f565_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Traffic is shown on Interstate 35 near a Microsoft data center, Tuesday, Sept. 5, 2023, in West Des Moines, Iowa. (AP Photo/Charlie Neibergall)</span></div>
<p>Open AI – which is backed by software maker Microsoft – operates a series of data centers in West Des Moines, Iowa. The city in the central part of the state is home to about 68,000 people.</p>
<p>"They're building them as fast as they can," said Steve Gaer, who served as the city's mayor when Microsoft first arrived. He said the software maker was attracted to the city because of its efforts to improve public projects. The former official also said Microsoft provided a huge amount of money in taxes in support of the efforts.</p>
<p>"But," Gaer said of the company, "they were pretty secretive on what they're doing out there."</p>
<p>In 2020, Microsoft said it was developing one of the world's most powerful supercomputers for OpenAI. At the time, it did not name the Iowa city as home to the project. Microsoft described the effort as a "single system" with a huge number of <strong>semiconductors</strong> and processors to support AI workloads.</p>
<p>In late May, Microsoft President Brad Smith made his first public comment about the company's new "AI supercomputing data center" in West Des Moines. He noted the center was built to support development efforts for the ChatGPT system.</p>
<p>Water is taken from the nearby Raccoon and Des Moines rivers to cool down the Microsoft-OpenAI computing equipment, the <em>AP</em> reports. In its latest environmental report, Microsoft said its worldwide water usage rose 34 percent from 2021 to 2022 to almost 1.7 billion gallons. Industry experts have suggested the large increase was directly linked to the company's AI research.</p>
<p>"It's fair to say the majority of the growth is due to AI," said Shaolei Ren. He is a researcher at the University of California, Riverside who has been studying the environmental effects of AI products such as ChatGPT.</p>
<p>In a paper set to be published later this year, Ren's team estimates ChatGPT takes up 500 milliliters of water each time someone asks the tool a series of between five and 50 questions. The estimate also includes indirect usage companies generally do not measure. This includes water used to cool power plants that supply the data centers with electricity.</p>
<p>"Most people are not <strong>aware</strong> of the resource usage <strong>underlying </strong>ChatGPT," Ren said. "If you're not aware of the resource usage, then there's no way that we can help <strong>conserve</strong> the resources."</p>
<p>Ren noted that Google reported a 20 percent growth in water usage during the same period. He believes that growth is largely linked to the American-based search engine company's AI development work.</p>
<p>Microsoft said in a recent statement to the <em>AP</em> that it is investing in research to measure the environmental effects of AI activities. The company promised to work on ways "to make large systems more <strong>efficient</strong>, in both training and <strong>application</strong>."</p>
<p>In its own statement, OpenAI said it had given "considerable thought" to the best use of computing power. "We recognize training large models can be energy and water-intensive," it said.</p>
<p>A West Des Moines government document from 2022 says the city "will only consider future data center projects" from Microsoft if those projects can "demonstrate and <strong>implement</strong>" technology to <strong>significantly</strong> reduce water usage from current levels.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– n. </em>a material, such as silicon, that permits electricity to move through it more easily when its temperature increases</p>
<p><strong>underlying </strong><em>– adj. </em>used to describe something on which something else is based</p>
<p><strong>conserve </strong><em>– v. </em>to keep and protect something from damage, change or waste</p>
<p><strong>efficient </strong>– <em>adj. </em>working or operating quickly and in a safe, organized way</p>
<p><strong>application </strong><em>– n. </em>the way in which something can be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>aware </strong>– <em>adj.</em><strong> </strong>having or showing realization, perception, or knowledge</p>
<p><strong>implement </strong><em>– v.</em> to take steps to put into practice; to carry out</p>
<p><strong>significant </strong>– <em>adj.</em><strong> </strong>of a noticeably or measurably large amount</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>App Identifies Birds by Sound  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/app-identifies-birds-by-sound.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Tracee Herbaugh lives in the Boston area of Massachusetts.</p>
<p>Herbaugh thought she was alone in her <strong>backyard</strong> recently when she used the Merlin Bird ID app. She learned from listening that she was surrounded by more than 12 kinds of birds.</p>
<p>There were the familiar blue jays, cardinals and goldfinch. But the app also identified birds like chimney swift, northern flicker, fish crow, killdeer and gray catbird.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology shows a winter wren. (James Davis/Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6a52-08db105cbf18_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology shows a winter wren. (James Davis/Macaulay Library/Cornell Lab of Ornithology via AP)</span></div>
<p>Two birds identified by the app, veery and great horned owl, even had a red <strong>dot</strong> next to their names. The red dot meant it was a rare sighting.</p>
<p>Herbaugh wrote: "Who knew all these birds could be in one yard?"</p>
<p>Cornell Lab of Ornithology is the maker of Merlin Bird ID. The app was released in 2014. At first, the app only identified birds by sight called Photo ID. The user answered a series of questions to help identify the bird, such as date, area, color, and size. The app became popular during the pandemic when people increasingly wanted to be outdoors.</p>
<p>In 2021, Cornell Lab added Sound ID to identify birds by their sound. In the United States alone, Merlin's Sound ID can identify over 700 kinds of birds. More than 7 million people now use the Merlin Bird ID worldwide.</p>
<p>Alli Smith works on the Merlin project at Cornel Lab. Smith said birdwatching by sound "opens up a whole new world." Even if you cannot see the birds, Smith added, "you can hear their beautiful songs and know they're sharing your neighborhood."</p>
<p>Other bird-identifying apps include the Audubon Bird Guide, ChirpOMatic, Picture Bird and Smart Bird.</p>
<p><strong>Connecting with people</strong></p>
<p>More than birds, Herbaugh said the app also helped her reconnect with people across the country.</p>
<p>When Herbaugh shared her bird list on social media, two childhood friends who also used the app messaged her about it.</p>
<p>Her relative in Montana shared a list that included hawks, raptors and hummingbirds. And even her young children now quickly go for the app any time they hear an unfamiliar bird call.</p>
<p>Herbaugh has identified 45 birds on her list so far. She said her children are now the ones driving her to get more on the bird list.</p>
<p>Smith said when people write to Merlin, they often talk about connection. She said, "There are so many little wonders around and it's fun to share that with people."</p>
<p>I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Tracee Herbaugh reported this story for The Associated Press. Gena Bennett adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>backyard</strong>–<em>n</em>. the area outside around a house</p>
<p><strong>dot</strong>–<em>n</em>. a small round mark</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Taylor Swift Takes MTV's Top Award  (2023/9/14)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/taylor-swift-takes-mtv-s-top-award.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">13 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Taylor Swift took home the top prize at the 2023 MTV Video Music Awards (VMAs) for her <em>Anti-Hero</em> music video.</p>
<p>The music network's yearly awards show took place at the Prudential Center in Newark, New Jersey.</p>
<p>"This is unbelievable. The fact that this is a fan-voted award means so much to me," Swift said in her acceptance speech. "I can't believe it was a year ago that I announced the <em>Midnights </em>album."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Joey Fatone, from center, Lance Bass, and Justin Timberlake of NSYNC present the award for best pop to Taylor Swift, far left, for Anti-Hero during the MTV Video Music Awards on September 12, 2023, at the Prudential Center in Newark, N.J. (Photo by Charles Sykes/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/013566e3-6899-44b8-b19d-44539a245179_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Joey Fatone, from center, Lance Bass, and Justin Timberlake of NSYNC present the award for best pop to Taylor Swift, far left, for "Anti-Hero" during the MTV Video Music Awards on September 12, 2023, at the Prudential Center in Newark, N.J. (Photo by Charles Sykes/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>The night's first presenters were from the male musical act NSYNC. They reunited to hand the best <strong>pop</strong> video award to Swift.</p>
<p>Swift received the most nominations of any performer. Swift later returned to the stage to receive the song of the year award for <em>Anti-hero</em> and also the best direction award.</p>
<p>The performer received nine awards in total. Those included artist of the year in a group of nominees made up of women for the first time on the VMA show.</p>
<p>Ice Spice, who worked with Swift on <em>Karma (Remix)</em>, won best new artist.</p>
<p>New music filled the show with songs from Nicki Minaj who also was the <strong>host</strong>. Minaj performed the new song <em>Last Time I saw You</em>. She then performed a piece from her upcoming <em>Pink Friday 2 </em>album.</p>
<p>The award show centered on showing music's international power. K-pop, or Korean pop, boy group Tomorrow X Together and Brazilian artist Anitta introduced a new song together, <em>Back for More</em>.</p>
<p>Another K-pop group, Stray Kids, performed the song <em>S-Class</em>. Mexican singer Peso Pluma performed a song called <em>Lady Gaga </em>and Colombian singer Karol G sang <em>Oki Doki </em>and another song <em>Tá OK (remix)</em>.</p>
<p>Tiffany Haddish presented the award for "Best Afrobeats," a new award group. Afrobeats is music with influences from Africa and Black American culture. Rema and Selena Gomez won the award for the popular song <em>Calm Down. </em></p>
<p>"Africa in the house!" Rema said in his acceptance speech. Gomez said, "I want to send all of my love to Nigeria, thank you."</p>
<p>Colombian star Shakira received the Video Vanguard Award and performed a mix of her popular songs.</p>
<p>"MTV, thank you for being such a big part of my career since I was only 18 years old," Shakira said. She also thanked her parents and her children, who she brought to the show.</p>
<p>"This is for you my people, my Latin American people, inside and outside this country," she said in the Spanish language.</p>
<p>Diddy received the Global Icon Award from Mary J. Blige and his daughter Chance Combs. He is the third act to receive the award, after the <a class="wsw__a" name="_Int_bl5dFMm0">Red Hot</a> Chili Peppers in 2022 and the Foo Fighters in 2021.</p>
<p>The artist also performed at the VMAs for the first time since 2005. The performance was a collection of some of his most popular songs like <em>Bad Boy for Life </em>and <em>Mo Money Mo Problems</em>.</p>
<p>Lil Wayne opened the show with a performance of his new single <em>Kat Food. </em>Olivia Rodrigo then brought her <em>Vampire</em> music video to the stage before performing <em>Get Him Back!</em></p>
<p>Later, Anitta would win the "best Latin" award for the second year. In her acceptance speech, she laughed, saying, "I wanna thank myself." And she added, "Because I work so hard!"</p>
<p>French Montana, a performer who presented an award, brought attention to an effort to provide aid to victims of the Morocco earthquake. The performer grew up in Morocco.</p>
<p>The VMA show ended with a celebration of 50 years of the musical form <strong>hip-hop</strong>. It included Nicki Minaj, Lil Wayne, LL Cool J, and DMC of Run-DMC.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Maria Sherman reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pop </strong><em>– n.</em> music that is popular</p>
<p><strong>host </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who talks to guests on a television or radio show</p>
<p><strong>hip-hop </strong><em>– n.</em> rap music</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>North Korean, Russian Leaders Meet to Discuss Military Aid  (2023/9/14) | 朝俄领导人会晤讨论军事援助</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/north-korean-russian-leaders-meet-to-discuss-military-aid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin met Wednesday at Russia's new spaceport in the Far East.<br/>
朝鲜领导人金正恩和俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京星期三在俄罗斯位于远东的新航天港会晤。</p>
<p>Putin showed Kim the Vostochny Cosmodrome spaceport and discussed the possibility of sending a North Korean cosmonaut into space. After the tour, Putin and Kim talked for several hours about world issues and possible areas of cooperation.<br/>
普京陪同金正恩参观了东方航天发射场(又称沃斯托奇尼航天港)，并讨论了将一名朝鲜宇航员送入太空的可能性。参观结束后，普京和金正恩就世界问题和潜在合作领域进行了几个小时的交谈。</p>
<p>At lunch, Kim gave a toast to Putin's health, to the victory of "great Russia" and Korean-Russian friendship. He predicted victory for Russia in, what he called, its "sacred fight" with the West in the Ukraine war.<br/>
午餐时，金正恩为普京的健康、“伟大俄罗斯”的胜利和韩俄友谊干杯。他预测俄罗斯将在乌克兰战争中与西方的“神圣之战”中获胜。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Russia seeking help with ammunition<br/>
俄罗斯寻求弹药援助</span></p>
<p>Putin suggested that military cooperation was discussed but released few details. Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu also attended the talks. However, Russian officials said sensitive discussions between the neighbors were a private matter.<br/>
普京表示，双方讨论了军事合作，但没有透露任何细节。国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古也出席了会谈。然而，俄罗斯官员表示，这两个邻国之间的理性讨论是私事。</p>
<p>U.S. and South Korean officials have expressed concern that the rare meeting could lead to a deal to supply Russia with ammunition for the war in Ukraine.<br/>
美国和韩国官员表示担心，这次罕见的会议可能会达成一项为俄罗斯提供弹药供给乌克兰战争的协议。</p>
<p>Concern about the two countries' military cooperation grew after Shoigu visited North Korea in July. Kim then visited his weapons factories, which experts said aimed to support North Korea's weapons modernization and show military supplies for export to Russia.<br/>
绍伊古7月访问朝鲜后，西方对两国军事合作的担忧加剧。金正恩随后参观了他的武器工厂，专家们称这些工厂旨在支持朝鲜的武器现代化，并展示出口到俄罗斯的军事物资。</p>
<p>Putin is believed to be seeking North Korean supplies of aging ammunition and rockets from the time when the Soviet Union existed. Such a request would mark a change from the period of the Korean War which lasted from 1950 to 1953. At that time, Russia gave weapons to support North Korea's invasion of South Korea.<br/>
据信，普京正寻求朝鲜提供苏联存在时的老化弹药和火箭。这样的要求将标志着1950年至1953年朝鲜战争时期的变化。当时，俄罗斯提供武器支持朝鲜入侵韩国。</p>
<p>James Nixey is the director of the Russia and Eurasia program at London-based research group Chatham House. He said Russia cannot produce enough weapons for the war in Ukraine and any deal with North Korea would be to ensure that immediate needs are met.<br/>
詹姆斯·尼克希是伦敦查塔姆研究所俄罗斯和欧亚大陆项目的负责人。他说，俄罗斯无法为乌克兰战争生产足够的武器，与朝鲜的任何协议都将确保满足眼前的需求。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">North Korea wants space technology<br/>
朝鲜想要太空技术</span></p>
<p>The decision to meet at the Vostochny Cosmodrome suggests Kim is seeking Russian help in developing spy satellites. In recent months, North Korea has repeatedly failed to put its first military spy satellite into orbit.<br/>
在东方航天发射场会面的决定表明，金正恩正在寻求俄罗斯帮助开发间谍卫星。近几个月来，朝鲜一再失败，未能将其首颗军事间谍卫星送入轨道。</p>
<p>Official photos showed Kim brought Pak Thae Song, head of North Korea's space science and technology committee, and Kim Myong Sik who is linked with spy satellites and submarine-based nuclear ballistic missile efforts.<br/>
官方照片显示，金正恩带来了朝鲜太空科学技术委员会主席朴泰成，以及与间谍卫星和潜艇核弹道导弹有关的金明植。</p>
<p>When asked by Russian media that attended the meeting, if Russia would help Kim build satellites, Putin said: "That's why we came here."<br/>
当被参加会议的俄罗斯媒体问及俄罗斯是否会帮助金正恩建造卫星时，普京说：“这就是我们来这里的原因。”</p>
<p>Putin told Russian state TV that Kim will visit two more cities in the Russian Far East on his own after the meeting. Kim is expected to visit an aircraft factory in Komsomolsk-on-Amur and then go to Vladivostok to observe Russia's Pacific Fleet, a university and other places.<br/>
普京对俄罗斯国家电视台说，会谈结束后，金正恩将独自访问俄罗斯远东地区的另外两个城市。预计金正恩将参观阿穆尔河畔科索莫尔斯克的一家飞机工厂，然后前往符拉迪沃斯托克观看俄罗斯太平洋舰队、一所大学和其他地方。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Google's Search Engine at Center of Antitrust Trial  (2023/9/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/google-s-search-engine-at-center-of-antitrust-trial.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Department of Justice accuses Google Tuesday of using its internet search engine to push out competitors and limit new ideas.</p>
<p>Kenneth Dintzer is the Justice Department's lead lawyer. He said, "This case is about the future of the internet and whether Google's search engine will ever face meaningful competition."</p>
<p>Over the next 10 weeks, federal lawyers and state attorneys general will try to prove that Google unfairly controls the market in its favor by making its search engine the first choice in software and on devices that people use every day.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Various Google logos are seen in search results on two devices in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0d03-08dbb3b34ea7_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Various Google logos are seen in search results on two devices in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. (AP Photo/Richard Drew)</span></div>
<p>The case is similar to the <strong>antitrust</strong> trial brought against computer software maker Microsoft in 1998. At that time, the government accused Microsoft of using its strength in software to force computer makers to use its other products, including the Internet Explorer web browser. The case ended with restrictions to prevent Microsoft from having total control of the marketplace.</p>
<p>Many Google products including the Chrome web browser, Gmail, YouTube, and online maps are extremely popular. But none have controlled the market and become as valuable as its internet search engine.</p>
<p>The government accuses Google of paying billions of dollars yearly to make its search engine the first choice on the iPhone and web browsers such as Apple's Safari and Mozilla's Firefox. The legal action notes that Google also requires its search engine to be a part of the Android operating system used by smartphones of many manufacturers.</p>
<p>Dintzer said, "This is Google saying: Take it or leave it." He said that Google's moves prevented Apple from developing a search engine of its own.</p>
<p>Google argues that it faces many competitors although it controls about 90 percent of the internet search market. The company says it faces competition from search engines such as Microsoft's Bing and DuckDuckGo and websites like Amazon and Yelp. These websites let users ask questions about what to buy or where to go.</p>
<p>The company also argues that it faces competition from new technology like artificial intelligence (AI). Microsoft, for example, is adding AI abilities from its partner Open AI to its Bing search engine. That move in early February forced Goggle to equip its search engine with results that come from AI-aided processes.</p>
<p>Google says users can always use any other search engine. But continuous improvements to its search engine are the reason why users keep coming back. It is a process that made the name Google <strong>synonymous</strong> with looking things up on the internet.</p>
<p>However, critics say the quality of search results has decreased. They note that Google uses its engine to sell advertisements. The company brings attention to its products over those of competitors.</p>
<p>Today, the stock market value of Google's parent company, Alphabet, is $1.7 trillion. The company employs 182,000 people. Most of the money Google makes comes from $224 billion in yearly ad sales. The sales come through a network of digital services that are linked by the search engine, which answers billions of requests a day.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press sources. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>antitrust </strong><em>–adj. </em>related to cases brought by a government against a company that appears to control so much of a market that it prevents normal market competition</p>
<p><strong>synonymous</strong> <em>–adj.</em> having the same meaning as</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Unusual Bird-like Dinosaur Discovered in China  (2023/9/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/unusual-bird-like-dinosaur-discovered-in-china.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>About 148 to 150 million years ago, a strange chicken-sized and bird-like dinosaur with long legs and arms much like wings lived in southeastern China. Its unusual body suggests it was either a fast runner or lived near water.</p>
<p>Scientists said last week they had unearthed in the Fujian area the <strong>fossil</strong> of a dinosaur they named Fujianvenator prodigiosus. They say it lived during the time in Earth's history called the Jurassic Period.</p>
<p>The new dinosaur find provides more information about an important stage in how birds developed, or evolved, the researchers say.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A life reconstruction of the bird-like dinosaur Fujianvenator prodigiosus. (Chuang Zhao/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-0b29-08dbb3adf29b_cx0_cy29_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A life reconstruction of the bird-like dinosaur Fujianvenator prodigiosus. (Chuang Zhao/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>The question of whether the dinosaur should be called a bird depends on how one defines a bird, said study leader Min Wang. He is a <strong>paleontologist</strong> at the Institute of Vertebrate Paleontology and Paleoanthropology of the Chinese Academy of Sciences.</p>
<p>Asked for a word to describe Fujianvenator, Wang answered, "I would say ‘<strong>bizarre</strong>.' Fujianvenator is far from similar to any modern birds."</p>
<p>Birds evolved from a grouping of dinosaurs known as theropods in the late Jurassic. The oldest known bird, Archaeopteryx, dates to around 150 million years ago in Germany.</p>
<p>Fujianvenator is a member of a grouping called avialans that includes all birds and their closest non-bird dinosaur relatives, Wang said.</p>
<p>The fossil was discovered last October. It is mostly complete but lacks the animal's head and part of its feet. That makes it hard for scientists to suggest what it ate and how it lived.</p>
<p>Fujianvenator's lower leg bone – the tibia – was twice as long as its upper leg bone – the femur. These sizes are exceptional among theropods. The theropod group includes all the meat-eating dinosaurs like Tyrannosaurus.</p>
<p>Wang said that Fujianvenator did have wings, but it is not clear if it could fly. Wang said, if it did fly it probably did not fly well, based on its bone structure.</p>
<p>Wang said the fossil did not include <strong>feathers</strong>. But, the animal's closest relatives and almost all bird-like theropods have feathers. Many dinosaurs had feathers, also.</p>
<p>Wang said, "It would not be a surprise if Fujianvenator had feathers ."</p>
<p>Based on its long legs, the researchers suggested it lived in two possible ways – either as a fast runner or near water, similar to birds like cranes or herons.</p>
<p>Wang has an opinion on the mystery: "I would put my money on runner," the scientist said.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p><strong>paleontology </strong><em>– n.</em> the science that deals with the fossils of animals and plants that lived very long ago especially in the time of dinosaurs</p>
<p><strong>bizarre </strong><em>– adj.</em> very unusual or strange</p>
<p><strong>feather </strong><em>– n.</em> any one of the light growths that make up the outer covering of the body of a bird</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Schools Help Students Behind in Math  (2023/9/13)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-schools-help-students-behind-in-math.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">12 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Across the United States, schools are working hard to help students catch up in math.</p>
<p>Test scores after the pandemic show just how behind students are. On average, education experts say American students' math knowledge is about half a school year behind where it should be.</p>
<p>Children lost ground on reading tests, too, but the math declines were more severe. Experts say online learning made it more difficult for math instruction. It was harder for teachers to guide students over a screen or see weaknesses in their skills. At home, parents were more likely to read with their children than to practice math.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Giada Gambino, 10, left, uses her smartphone to consult a voice assistant about a math problem. (AP Photo/Michael Wyke)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6727-08dbae1dc031_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Giada Gambino, 10, left, uses her smartphone to consult a voice assistant about a math problem. (AP Photo/Michael Wyke)</span></div>
<p>The result: students' math skills declined around the nation. And students are not recovering as quickly as educators hoped. Educators worry about how they will perform in high school and whether science, technology and medical fields will be available to them.</p>
<p>Students had been making progress on national math tests since 1990. But over the past year, fourth- and eighth-<strong>grade</strong> math scores fell to the lowest levels in about 20 years. The information comes from the National Assessment of Educational Progress, known as the "Nation's Report Card."</p>
<p>"It's a generation's worth of progress lost," said Andrew Ho. He is a professor at Harvard University's Graduate School of Education.</p>
<p>Jennifer Matthews teaches eighth grade at Moultrie Middle School in Mount Pleasant, South Carolina. She said her students have shown little interest in understanding her pre-algebra and Algebra I lessons.</p>
<p>"They don't <strong>allow</strong> themselves to process the material. They don't allow themselves to think, ‘This might take a day to understand or learn,'" she said.</p>
<p>Many students lack an understanding of math <strong>concepts</strong>. Basic <strong>fractions</strong>, for example, continue to confuse many of them, she said.</p>
<p>Using federal pandemic money, some schools have added <strong>tutors</strong>. Some have started new approaches to teaching to help in the recovery. But that money will run out by next September before many children have caught up.</p>
<p>Like other school systems across the country, Jefferson County Schools in Birmingham, Alabama, saw students' math skills fall from 2019 to 2021. Using pandemic aid, the system placed math <strong>coaches</strong> in all middle schools.</p>
<p>The coaches help teachers learn new and better ways to teach students. About 1 in 5 public schools in the United States have a math coach, federal data says. The efforts appear to be working: State testing shows math scores have started to increase for most of the Jefferson County middle schools.</p>
<p>Adding to the difficulty of catching kids up is the debate over how math should be taught. Some say schools should center procedural learning, like teaching kids to memorize how to solve problems step-by-step. Others prefer conceptual understanding, in which students learn <strong>underlying</strong> math relationships.</p>
<p>Kevin Dykema is president of the National Council of Teachers of Mathematics. He said many people do not think of math as a fun subject. But "When people start to understand what's going on, in whatever you're learning but especially in math, you develop a new <strong>appreciation</strong> for it."</p>
<p>Sarah Powell is a professor at the University of Texas at Austin who researches math instruction. She said teaching math should not be either one way or another way. A change too far in the conceptual direction, she said, risks losing students who have not fully learned basic math skills.</p>
<p>Even at a nationally recognized <strong>magnet school</strong>, the effect of the pandemic on students' math skills is clear. At the Townview School of Science and Engineering in Dallas, the incoming ninth graders in Lance Barasch's summer program needed to relearn the meaning of words like "<strong>term</strong>" and "<strong>coefficient</strong>."</p>
<p>Barasch was not surprised that the students were missing some skills after their middle school years during the pandemic.</p>
<p>The hope is that by taking a step back, students can begin to move forward.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grade</strong><em>— n. </em>a level of study that is completed by a student during one year</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>allow </strong><em>— v. </em>to permit</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>concept </strong><em>— n. </em>an idea of what something is or how it works</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fraction</strong><em>— n. </em>a number (such as <i></i>185;/<i></i>8322; or <i></i>179;/<i></i>8324;) which indicates that one number is being divided by another</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tutor </strong><em>— n. </em>a teacher who works with one student</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coach </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who teaches and trains an athlete or performer</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>underlying </strong><em>— adj. </em>used to identify the idea, cause, problem, etc., that forms the basis of something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>magnet school </strong><em>— n. </em>a school that has courses in special subjects and is designed to attract students from all parts of a community</p>
<p><strong>term</strong><em>— n. </em>the values on which mathematical operations occur in an algebraic expression</p>
<p><strong>coefficient</strong><em>— n. </em>a number by which another number or symbol is multiplied</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Libya Flooding Leaves 10,000 People Missing  (2023/9/13) | 利比亚洪灾导致1万人失踪</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/libya-flooding-leaves-10-000-people-missing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Officials in Libya say as many as 10,000 people are missing after severe flooding in the northeastern part of the country.<br/>
利比亚官员表示，该国东北部发生严重洪灾，造成多达1万人失踪。</p>
<p>The flooding began when Mediterranean Storm Daniel dropped heavy rain on the area beginning Sunday night.<br/>
从周日晚上开始，地中海风暴丹尼尔在该地区降下暴雨，由此爆发了洪水。</p>
<p>As of Tuesday, more than 1,000 bodies had been recovered in the city of Derna alone. Emergency workers say they expect the number of dead to climb sharply.<br/>
截至周二，仅在德尔纳市就发现了1000多具尸体。急救人员表示，他们预计死亡人数将急剧攀升。</p>
<p>Flooding led to the collapse of at least two dams outside Derna, a coastal city of about 89,000 people, local officials said. A wall of water that passed through the city "erased everything in its way," witness Ahmed Abdalla told the Associated Press.<br/>
当地官员表示，德尔纳市是一座约有89000人的沿海城市，洪水导致德尔纳郊外至少两座大坝倒塌。目击者艾哈迈德·阿布达拉告诉美联社，一堵穿过城市的水墙“抹去了一切”。</p>
<p>A local minister of civil air travel in the country's east told Reuters news agency after visiting Derna that bodies were "lying everywhere," including the sea, in valleys and under buildings.<br/>
该国东部的一位民航部长在访问德尔纳市后告诉路透社，尸体“到处都是”，包括大海、山谷和建筑物下。</p>
<p>The minister local officials estimated about 25 percent of Derna had disappeared, with "many, many buildings" destroyed.<br/>
这位部长级地方官员估计，德尔纳市大约25%的面积已经不复存在，“很多很多建筑”被毁。 </p>
<p>Storm Daniel hit other eastern Libyan towns, including Benghazi, the second largest city in the country. Tamer Ramadan is head of a delegation from the International Federation of the Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies. He told Reuters the number of missing had hit 10,000 and the total number of deaths would be "huge."<br/>
丹尼尔风暴袭击了利比亚东部的其他城镇，包括该国第二大城市班加西。泰默·拉马丹是红十字会与红新月会国际联合会代表团团长。他告诉路透社，失踪人数已达10000人，死亡总人数将很“巨大”。</p>
<p>United Nations aid chief Martin Griffiths said in a message on X, formerly known as Twitter, that emergency teams had been deployed to help on the ground. Turkey and other countries immediately sent aid to Libya, including search and rescue vehicles, rescue boats, power generators and food.<br/>
联合国援助负责人马丁·格里菲思在X（前身为推特）网站上发表消息称，已经部署了应急小组在当地提供帮助。土耳其和其他国家立即向利比亚提供了援助，包括搜救车、救援船、发电机和食品。</p>
<p>People living in Derna reported hearing loud explosions Sunday night as the storm arrived and they realized dams outside the city had collapsed.<br/>
据报道，周日晚上风暴来临时，德尔纳市的居民听到了巨大的爆炸声，他们意识到城外的水坝已经垮塌。</p>
<p>Videos posted online showed large areas of mud and wreckage where floodwaters carried away neighborhoods along banks of the Wadi Derna river. The river runs from the mountains through the city and into the sea.<br/>
网上发布的视频显示了大片淤泥和废墟，洪水冲走了德尔纳河岸的街区。这条河从山上流过城市，然后汇入大海。</p>
<p>Local emergency workers – including troops, government workers and volunteers – dug through the wreckage and used boats to search for bodies.<br/>
包括军队、政府工作人员和志愿者在内的当地急救人员在废墟中挖掘，并用船只搜寻遇难者遗体。</p>
<p>Eastern Libya's health minister, Othman Abduljaleel, told the AP that many bodies are believed to be trapped under wreckage or had been carried out to the sea.<br/>
利比亚东部卫生部长奥斯曼·阿卜杜勒贾利勒告诉美联社，据信有许多尸体被埋在残骸下或被冲入大海。</p>
<p>Military commander Khalifa Hifter currently leads the east Libya government. He captured Derna in 2019 after months of fierce fighting. Hifter's government, based in Benghazi, is fighting the western government based in the capital, Tripoli.<br/>
军事指挥官哈利法·希夫特目前领导利比亚东部政府。经过数月的激战，他于2019年攻占了德尔纳。总部位于班加西的希夫特政府正在与总部位于首都的黎波里的西部政府作战。</p>
<p>Each side is backed by powerful militias and foreign powers. Egypt, Russia, Jordan and the United Arab Emirates support Hifter. Turkey, Qatar and Italy support the west Libya administration.<br/>
双方都有强大的民兵和外国势力撑腰。埃及、俄罗斯、约旦和阿拉伯联合酋长国支持希夫特政府。土耳其、卡塔尔和意大利支持利比亚西部政府。</p>
<p>There were early signs the two sides were willing to work together on aid efforts. The government of western Libya sent a plane carrying 14 tons of medical supplies and health workers to Benghazi. Another plane, carrying humanitarian aid and rescue teams from Egypt, Turkey and the United Arab Emirates, also landed in Benghazi.<br/>
早期迹象表明，双方愿意在援助方面共同努力。利比亚西部政府派出一架载有14吨医疗用品和卫生工作者的飞机前往班加西。另一架载有来自埃及、土耳其和阿拉伯联合酋长国的人道主义援助和救援队的飞机也降落在班加西。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Israeli Scientists Announce Creation of Embryo Model in Lab  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/israeli-scientists-announce-creation-of-embryo-model-in-lab.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Israeli scientists say they have created a model of a human embryo from stem cells in a laboratory.</p>
<p>The embryo model – created without using sperm, eggs or a <strong>uterus</strong> – is designed to support research on early human development.</p>
<p>Only stem cells were used in the process. Stem cells are simple cells in the body that can develop into one of many specialized cells. Researchers say the embryo models cannot grow into babies. But they are complete enough to provide information about what happens in the embryo during a pregnancy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="PhD student, Nir Livnat, works at the laboratory on models of an early-stage human embryo, in a laboratory at the Weizmann Institute of Science in Rehovot, Israel September 7, 2023. (REUTERS/Amir Cohen)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d287-08dbb2d47717_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">PhD student, Nir Livnat, works at the laboratory on models of an early-stage human embryo, in a laboratory at the Weizmann Institute of Science in Rehovot, Israel September 7, 2023. (REUTERS/Amir Cohen)</span></div>
<p>The use of embryo models permits scientists to carry out research without the <strong>ethical</strong> concerns linked to experiments using real embryos.</p>
<p>Several international research teams have been working separately on studies involving human embryo models. Scientists from the United States, Britain and China <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/stem-cells-used-to-create-embryo-models-to-study-early-human-development/7161770.html">published their research results</a> on the subject in recent months.</p>
<p>The Israeli researchers say their embryo model looks similar to a real human embryo at day 14. At this point, the embryo model has begun building inner structures. But it has not yet developed enough to start forming body organs, the team said.</p>
<p>The scientists recently reported their results <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06604-5">in a study</a> in the publication <em>Nature</em>. They also shared their research with scientists during a June meeting of the International Society for Stem Cell Research in Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>The Israeli team noted that their current research is still a long way from being able to create a full embryo in the lab.</p>
<p>Jacob Hanna was the team leader on the research. He told the Reuters news agency, "The question is, when does an embryo model become considered an embryo? When that happens, we know the <strong>regulations</strong>. At the moment we are really, really far off from that point."</p>
<p>But the researchers said the work could open the door to new ways to study early human development. For example, the embryo models could test the effect of drugs on pregnancies. They could also help scientists better understand <strong>miscarriages</strong> and genetic diseases. And they might one day be used to grow <strong>transplant</strong> tissues and organs.</p>
<p>Hanna noted that the models are not exactly like human embryos. "There are differences from human embryos, but still, this is the first time, if you open an <strong>atlas</strong> or a textbook, you can say - yeah I can really see the similarity between them," he said.</p>
<p>Hanna said his team took stem cells produced from adult human skin cells, as well as others, and let them develop in the lab. The researchers then <strong>reverted</strong> the cells to an early state, with the possibility that they could develop into different kinds of cells.</p>
<p>The team then genetically changed the cells in an effort to get them to start developing into something that looks and behaves like a real human embryo. However, the researchers said their creation is not an actual or <strong>synthetic</strong> embryo. Instead, it is considered a model that shows how a real embryo works.</p>
<p>Hanna said the process was able to start effective structure development. But he added that "the farthest we could get is day 14 in human embryo development."</p>
<p>Hanna said the team's next goal will be to extend model development to 21 days and also reach a success rate of at least 50 percent.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Reuters reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>uterus </strong><em>– n. </em>(medical) a term for the organ in a woman that holds the baby during pregnancy; womb</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong><em>– adj. </em>relating to what is right or wrong</p>
<p><strong>regulation </strong><em>– n. </em>an official rule that controls how something is done</p>
<p><strong>miscarriage </strong>– <em>n. </em>a situation in which a baby is born too early and dies because it has not developed enough to survive</p>
<p><strong>transplant </strong><em>– v. </em>to perform a medical operation in which an organ or other part that has been removed from the body of one person is put into the body of another person</p>
<p><strong>atlas </strong><em>– n. </em>a book of maps</p>
<p><strong>revert </strong><em>– v. </em>to go back to the way something was before</p>
<p><strong>synthetic </strong>–<em> adj. </em>a group of products made from artificial substances, often copying a natural product</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Gardeners Can Reduce Risk of Fire  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/how-gardeners-can-reduce-risk-of-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Invasive grasses might have played a part in the deadly wildfires that burned Lahaina, Hawaii recently. The grasses have taken over land that was once occupied by crops like sugar and pineapple.</p>
<p>Michele Steinberg is wildfire division director at the National Fire Protection Association. She said some plants are more <strong>flammable</strong> than others. But, she noted, "there is no such thing as a fireproof plant." All plants can catch fire under the right conditions.</p>
<p>Those conditions include poor <strong>pruning</strong>, lack of watering, and letting dry, dead plant parts remain on the soil surface in high-risk areas.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by John Ruter shows pampas grass (Cortaderia selloana), an invasive, nonnative plant that is highly-flammable. (John Ruter, University of Georgia, Bugwood.org)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/4409f9fa-a686-4c06-a876-be3a3ecd713c_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by John Ruter shows pampas grass (Cortaderia selloana), an invasive, nonnative plant that is highly-flammable. (John Ruter, University of Georgia, Bugwood.org)</span></div>
<p>If you are selecting plants for your <strong>garden</strong>, knowing which plants offer some fire resistance and which are more flammable can serve you well.</p>
<p><strong>Quicker to catch fire</strong></p>
<p>Plants that produce flammable substances, like aromatic oils, resins, waxes, or sap, are among the quickest to catch fire. They will often catch fire even if they have been well-watered and cared for. They include bamboo, rosemary, and eucalyptus.</p>
<p>Trees with papery <strong>bark </strong>that falls off, like river birch, are usually more flammable than those without. And fine-<strong>needled</strong> plants like pine, juniper, and spruce contain saps and resins. Their needle-like leaves increase the risk of fire when left on the ground or on the top of a house.</p>
<p>Many grasses are highly flammable. Their ability to <strong>ignite</strong> increases when they are left to stand dry over winter or during periods without rain. Additionally, too much heat dries out the soil and under such conditions, many kinds of plants turn into a fire starter.</p>
<p><strong>Native vs. non-native</strong></p>
<p>As a group, "native plants aren't necessarily less flammable" than introduced kinds of plants, Steinberg said.</p>
<p>But nonnative, invasive plants often are a greater fire risk because they spread quickly and are usually left alone by wildlife. The nonnative plants spread faster than native plants, and often <strong>tolerate</strong> heat, lack of rain and heavy rain better.</p>
<p>For the best fire resistance, choose <strong>deciduous </strong>trees, like ash, crabapple, and maple, over fine-needled trees. Plants like succulents with water-filled leaves are slow to burn. They include ice plants and sedums. Some groundcover plants, like ajuga and creeping phlox, are also slow burners.</p>
<p><strong>What to look for in plants</strong></p>
<p>The Washington State University Extension Service has published advice for choosing plants that are fire-resistant. Qualities that make a plant less likely to burn include:</p>
<p>· High water content in leaves (these ignite and burn more slowly).</p>
<p>· Little or no seasonal gain of dead plant material.</p>
<p>· Open branching (they provide less fuel for fires).</p>
<p>· Fewer total branches and leaves (again, less fuel for fires).</p>
<p>· Slow-growing, so less pruning is required (to keep open structure as noted above).</p>
<p>· Non-flammable material on the plant, like resins, oil, or wax.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Jessica Damiano reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>flammable </strong><em>– adj.</em> capable of being set on fire and of burning quickly</p>
<p><strong>prune </strong><em>– v.</em> to cut off some of the branches of (a tree or bush) so that it will grow better or look better</p>
<p><strong>garden </strong><em>– n.</em> an area of ground where plants (such as flowers or vegetables) are grown</p>
<p><strong>bark <em>–</em></strong><em>n.</em> the outer surface of a tree</p>
<p><strong>needle </strong>– <em>n.</em> a leaf that is shaped like a very thin stick</p>
<p><strong>ignite </strong>– <em>v</em>. to set (something) on fire: to cause (something) to burn</p>
<p><strong>tolerate </strong><em>– v.</em> to experience (something harmful or unpleasant) without being harmed</p>
<p><strong>deciduous </strong>– <em>adj.</em> having leaves that fall off every year</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rescuers Work to Help Morocco Earthquake Victims  (2023/9/12) | 救援人员抓紧救助摩洛哥地震受害者</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rescuers-work-to-help-morocco-earthquake-victims.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Rescue workers continue to search the wreckage of a large earthquake that struck Morocco Friday.<br/>
摩洛哥周五发生大地震，救援人员仍在废墟中搜救。</p>
<p>Officials say almost 2,500 were killed in the quake, but that they expect that number will rise. On Monday, Morocco's state news agency reported almost 2,500 others are injured. And, it reported more injured people continue to arrive at hospitals.<br/>
官方表示，地震造成近2500人死亡，但他们预计这一数字还会上升。周一，摩洛哥国家通讯社报道，另有近2500人受伤。据报道，越来越多的伤者还在被送往医院。</p>
<p>Moroccan soldiers, doctors and other aid teams are still making their way to the Al Haouz area high in the Atlas mountains, the epicenter of the earthquake. The area is about 70 kilometers from the city of Marrakech.<br/>
摩洛哥士兵、医生和其他救援队仍在前往震中阿特拉斯山脉高处的豪兹地区。该地区距离马拉喀什市约70公里。</p>
<p>The United Nations said the magnitude 6.8 earthquake affected 300,000 people. The damage was great because the starting point of the shaking was not far below the ground.<br/>
联合国表示，这场6.8级地震影响了30万人。因为震中距离地面不远，造成的损失很大。</p>
<p>The U.S. Geological Survey said it was the strongest quake to strike the North African nation since 1900. And, it is reported to be country's deadliest since 1960, when at least 12,000 people were killed in and near the city of Agadir.<br/>
美国地质调查局表示，这是摩洛哥自1900年以来遭受的最强地震。据报道，这也是自1960年以来该国死亡人数最多的一次，当时阿加迪尔市及其附近至少有1.2万人死亡。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Offers of help<br/>
提供援助</span></p>
<p>So far, Morocco has accepted assistance from four countries – Spain, Qatar, Great Britain and the United Arab Emirates. Other nations have offered help, as well.<br/>
到目前为止，摩洛哥已经接受了西班牙、卡塔尔、英国和阿联酋这四个国家的援助。其他国家也提供了援助。</p>
<p>But, the Moroccan government says it wants to avoid a "counterproductive" lack of coordination by accepting help from too many countries.<br/>
但是，摩洛哥政府表示，它希望避免接受太多国家的援助，以免因为缺乏协调而造成适得其反。</p>
<p>One survivor, Salah Ancheu, called the earthquake "a catastrophe" even as a truckload of soldiers arrived in Amizmiz to help. "We don't know what the future is. The aid remains insufficient," the 28-year-old said.<br/>
幸存者萨拉称此次地震为“一场灾难”，即便一卡车士兵抵达艾米兹米兹提供帮助。“我们不知道未来会怎样。援助仍然不足，”这位28岁的年轻人说。</p>
<p>Mountainside homes and the tower of the local mosque fell down.<br/>
山上的房屋和当地清真寺的塔楼倒塌了。</p>
<p>Groups from the Moroccan army left Monday from Amizmiz to move into the small mountain villages. Heavy equipment was sent to clear the roads and both visitors and residents lined up to give blood.<br/>
摩洛哥军队的队伍星期一从艾米兹米兹出发，进入小山村。重型设备被派去清理道路，游客和居民都在排队献血。</p>
<p>Some news reports said villagers wept as they saw dead bodies being carried through the streets.<br/>
一些新闻报道说，当村民们看到尸体被抬过街道时，他们哭了。</p>
<p>A number of nations said they were ready, but not yet permitted to send help. The group Rescuers Without Borders said about 100 teams, totaling 3,500 rescuers, are prepared to help.<br/>
一些国家表示，他们已做好准备，但尚未获准提供援助。无国界救援组织表示，大约有100支队伍，共计3500名救援人员准备提供援助。</p>
<p>France said four of its citizens died. It has offered assistance but has not been given permission to send rescuers.<br/>
法国称有四名该国公民死亡。它已经提供了援助，但没有得到派遣救援人员的许可。</p>
<p>In the Czech Republic, 70 rescuers are waiting at an airport for permission to enter Morocco. In Germany, a rescue team of 50 was sent home after waiting at an airport.<br/>
在捷克共和国，70名救援人员正在机场等待进入摩洛哥的许可。在德国，一支由50人组成的救援队在机场等候后被遣送回国。</p>
<p>A spokesperson from the German foreign ministry said Morocco's refusal of aid from some nations should not be seen as political. "I'm sure they have thought very carefully about which forces can be deployed and how they can get there," the spokesperson said.<br/>
德国外交部发言人表示，摩洛哥拒绝一些国家的援助不应被视为政治行为。这位发言人说：“我相信他们已经非常仔细地考虑了可以部署哪些队伍，以及他们如何到达那里。”</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Catherine Colonna said France has offered more than $5 million in support. She said Morocco's decision on that offer is its own to make and "must be respected."<br/>
法国外交部长凯瑟琳·科隆纳表示，法国已提供超过500万美元的援助。她说，摩洛哥对此援助的决定是他自己的事，“必须得到尊重”。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">People sleeping outside<br/>
人们露宿街头</span></p>
<p>Many people continue to sleep outside, fearing smaller earthquakes that often follow a major one.<br/>
许多人担心大地震后会发生较小的余震，从而继续露宿街头。</p>
<p>In the village of Imgdal, women and children gathered outside and some kept warm around an open fire on Monday morning.<br/>
周一早上在Imgdal村，妇女和儿童聚集在外面，一些人在明火旁取暖。</p>
<p>In another village, Tafeghaghte, Hamid ben Henna said his 8-year-old son died in the quake. He had gone to another room while the family was sharing a meal Friday. The rest of the family survived.<br/>
在另一个村庄Tafeghahte，哈米德· 本·汉拿说他8岁的儿子在地震中死亡。周五时一家人正在一起吃饭，孩子去了另一个房间。家里其他人都活了下来。</p>
<p>On a road near the town of Adassil, close to the center of the quake, one rescue worker was trying to clear the rocks that were preventing vehicles from getting by.<br/>
在靠近震中的阿达西尔镇附近的一条道路上，一名救援人员正试图清理阻碍车辆通行的岩石。</p>
<p>He said other roads were in bad shape. "We're trying to open them, too," said Ayman Koait.<br/>
他说，其他道路状况不佳。艾麦尼表示：“我们也在努力打通它们。”</p>
<p>People said they dug through the rubble of their homes looking for relatives. They also moved rocks and walls looking for important items.<br/>
人们说，他们在房屋的废墟中挖掘以寻找亲人。他们还搬动石头和墙块来寻找重要物品。</p>
<p>Many of the homes are made from wood, rock, and mud, which made them fall easily when the ground started shaking.<br/>
许多房屋是由木材、石头和泥土建造的，当地面开始震动时，它们很容易倒塌。</p>
<p>One military worker said "it is difficult to pull people out alive" because the walls turned to rubble and did not leave any space for air.<br/>
一名军事工作者表示，“很难把人活着救出来”，因为墙壁变成了瓦砾，没有留下任何呼吸的空间。</p>
<p>UNESCO, the United Nations cultural organization, said many historic buildings in both Marrakech and the areas closer to the center of the earthquake were damaged.<br/>
联合国文化组织联合国教科文组织表示，马拉喀什和震中附近地区的许多历史建筑都遭到了破坏。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Drug Traffickers Use Banana Industry in Ecuador for Shipping  (2023/9/12)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/drug-traffickers-use-banana-industry-in-ecuador-for-shipping.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">11 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Ecuador is increasingly at the meeting point of two worldwide trades: bananas and cocaine.</p>
<p>The South American country is the world's largest exporter of bananas with about 6.5 million metric tons a year. Its neighbors, Peru and Colombia, are the world's largest cocaine producers.</p>
<p>Drug traffickers find containers filled with bananas the perfect vehicle to <strong>smuggle</strong> their product.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Recently harvested bananas are washed at a farm in Los Rios, Ecuador, Tuesday, Aug. 15, 2023. Bananas headed to a commercial port must meet long-established beauty standards of the export market. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-015d-08dbafe3a3ea_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Recently harvested bananas are washed at a farm in Los Rios, Ecuador, Tuesday, Aug. 15, 2023. Bananas headed to a commercial port must meet long-established beauty standards of the export market. (AP Photo/Martin Mejia)</span></div>
<p>Drug trafficking has since brought extreme violence across this once-peaceful nation. Shootings, murders, kidnappings and <strong>extortions</strong> have become part of daily life. That is especially true in the Pacific port city and banana-shipping center of Guayaquil.</p>
<p>The country was shocked when Fernando Villavicencio, a presidential candidate known for his tough position on organized crime, was shot to death on August 9. He had accused the Ecuadorian Los Choneros criminal group and its imprisoned leader of threatening him and his campaign team days before the killing.</p>
<p>In addition to being close to cocaine production, drug smugglers from Mexico, Colombia and the Balkans in Europe have also set up operations in Ecuador. That is because the country uses the U.S. dollar; its laws and <strong>institutions</strong> are weak; and criminal groups like Los Choneros are ready to work.</p>
<p>A record 2,304 metric tons of cocaine was produced in 2021 around the world, mostly in Colombia, Peru and Bolivia. That year, nearly a third of the cocaine seized by officials in Western and Central Europe came from Ecuador, two times the amount reported in 2018, found a United Nations report.</p>
<p>Large drug seizures have become more common within the past month. European officials have made record-setting seizures after inspecting containers carrying bananas from Ecuador.</p>
<p>Officials on August 25 announced Spain's biggest cocaine seizure yet: 9.5 metric tons hidden among boxes of bananas from Ecuador in a <strong>refrigerated</strong> container. Dutch officials also made their country's largest-ever cocaine seizure last month — nearly 8 metric tons — in a container of Ecuadorian bananas. Officials in Greece and Italy also announced seizures of cocaine hidden in Ecuadorian bananas this year.</p>
<p>Knowingly or not, banana growers, exporters, shipping companies, port operators, private security companies, <strong>customs</strong> agents, agriculture officials, police, and buyers can be used by drug traffickers.</p>
<p>Some traffickers have created false companies to look like real banana exporters. Others have taken control of legal businesses, including plantations. They have found companies willing to cooperate in trafficking. They have also paid off, threatened or kidnapped truck drivers and other workers to help get cocaine into shipments.</p>
<p>Violent deaths in Ecuador have doubled from 2021 to 2022, when 4,600 died, the most ever recorded in a year. The country is likely to break the yearly record again, with 3,568 violent deaths recorded in the first half of 2023. In Guayaquil, people live in fear.</p>
<p>No more than 30 percent of containers are currently inspected at Ecuadorian ports. President Guillermo Lasso's government says it wants to use <strong>scanners</strong> on entire containers. Twelve of those machines were supposed to be operating already but that has not happened yet, said National Police General Pablo Ramírez. He is Ecuador's national director of anti-drug investigations.</p>
<p>Jose Hidalgo is director of the Association of Banana Exporters of Ecuador. He said the industry is more <strong>vulnerable</strong> to trafficking than other export products because of the number of containers that it uses.</p>
<p>He explained that exporters spend about $100 million yearly on security measures. That includes <strong>surveillance</strong> cameras at plantations, GPS <strong>monitoring</strong> of trucks, and the identification of land routes that require police patrols to keep criminals away.</p>
<p>Still, some exporters have been accused of being involved in trafficking cocaine. The organization behind the cocaine seizure in Spain operated through a banana exporting company in Machala, a city south of Guayaquil.</p>
<p>After this story was published in The Associated Press, agriculture and customs officials in Ecuador announced in a statement that they had removed a government-run banana export database. It removed information on export companies considered to be false or incomplete. It also canceled permits of plantations covering 16,000 hectares found to be nonexistent.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>smuggle </strong><em>— v. </em>to move from one country into another illegally and secretly</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extort </strong><em>— v. </em>to get from a person by the use of force or threats</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>institution </strong><em>— n. </em>an established organization</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>refrigerate </strong><em>— adj. </em>to put or keep in a refrigerator in order to make it cold or keep it fresh</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>customs </strong><em>— n. </em>an action or way of behaving that is usual and traditional among the people in a particular group or place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scanner </strong><em>— n. </em>a device that reads or copies information or images into a computer</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vulnerable </strong><em>— adj. </em> easily hurt or harmed physically, mentally, or emotionally</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>surveillance </strong><em>— n. </em>the act of carefully watching someone or something especially in order to prevent or detect a crime</p>
<p><strong>monitor </strong><em>— v. </em>a device that is used for showing, watching, or listening to something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is the Goal of Japan’s New Moon Mission?  (2023/9/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/what-is-the-goal-of-japan-s-new-moon-mission.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Last week, Japan's space agency launched a rocket carrying a spacecraft designed to explore the moon.</p>
<p>The lunar lander is known as the Smart Lander for Investigating the Moon (SLIM). It aims to touch down on the moon's surface early next year. If successful, it would make Japan the fifth nation to land a spacecraft on the moon.</p>
<p>So far, only the United States, Russia, China and India have successfully landed spacecraft on the moon. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/india-successfully-lands-spacecraft-on-moon/7238173.html">India's landing</a> happened last month. India's landing came days after Russia failed in its attempt to return to the moon for the first time in nearly 50 years.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="An HII-A rocket blasts off from the launch pad at Tanegashima Space Center in Kagoshima, southern Japan Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023. (Kyodo News via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-7083-08dbb008fc8f_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">An HII-A rocket blasts off from the launch pad at Tanegashima Space Center in Kagoshima, southern Japan Thursday, Sept. 7, 2023. (Kyodo News via AP)</span></div>
<p>In April, a private Japanese space exploration company announced its space vehicle <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/japanese-space-company-says-moon-lander-likely-crashed/7067305.html">crashed</a> while trying to land on the moon. If that landing had been successful, it would have marked the first time a private business landed on the moon.</p>
<p>In the latest launch, an H-IIA rocket lifted off on September 7 from Tanegashima Space Center in southwestern Japan, the country's JAXA space agency said. Hours after the launch, JAXA said it was receiving signals from the SLIM spacecraft, suggesting it was operating normally. It is expected to start the lunar landing process by February, the Reuters news agency reported.</p>
<p>Japanese space officials have said SLIM aims to land within 100 meters of its target area on the moon's surface. The purpose, or mission, of the lander is to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets.</p>
<p>JAXA President Hiroshi Yamakawa told a news conference the mission aims to prove that in the future, spacecraft will be able to land "where we want," rather than only landing "where we can."</p>
<p>SLIM is set to touch down in an area called Mare Nectaris, on the southeastern half of the moon. The area contains <strong>plains</strong> of solidified lava and appears as a dark area from Earth.</p>
<p>After landing, SLIM will seek to examine the mineral-rich rocks to search for clues about the moon's development. The spacecraft is not carrying a lunar explorer.</p>
<p>SLIM is a small lander. It weighs a little more than 700 kilograms. JAXA plans to use additional light spacecraft in the future to reduce launch costs and permit more missions.</p>
<p>The spacecraft uses a chemical <strong>propulsion</strong> system and is equipped with very small electronic devices to control the lander. SLIM's overall development cost about $102 million.</p>
<p>The rocket that launched SLIM also carried the X-Ray Imaging and Spectroscopy Mission (XRISM) satellite. This part of the mission is a joint project of JAXA, the American space agency NASA and the European Space Agency.</p>
<p>The lander successfully separated from the rocket about 45 minutes after the launch. Ground stations in Hawaii and Japan received signals from XRISM soon after the launch. This confirmed the satellite's solar equipment had successfully deployed, JAXA said.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse, JAXA and NASA.</em></p>
<p>The XRISM satellite is designed to take images in many wavelengths of X-rays and to study the chemicals that exist in matter at high temperatures. It can gather information on the speed and makeup of what lies between galaxies. This can help scientists better understand how stars and galaxies developed. The satellite is equipped to look at X-rays of different wavelengths, or <strong>spectra,</strong> even ones at very high energy levels.</p>
<p>JAXA is also planning a joint lunar mission with the Indian Space Research Organization sometime after 2025. This will involve Japan's H3 rocket carrying India's next lunar lander into space.</p>
<p>And Japan also aims to send an astronaut to the moon's surface in the latter half of the 2020s as part of NASA's Artemis program.</p>
<p>I’m Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>plain </strong><em>– n. </em>a large area of flat land</p>
<p><strong>propulsion </strong><em>– n. </em>a force that pushes something forward</p>
<p><strong>galaxy </strong><em>– n. </em>a very large group of stars held together in the</p>
<p>universe</p>
<p><strong>spectrum (spectra pl.) </strong>–n. the wavelengths of electromagnetic radiation that scientist use to find the chemical properties of very hot gases</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Who Are the Wealthy Investors Buying Rural California Land?  (2023/9/11)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/who-are-the-wealthy-investors-buying-rural-california-land.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">10 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A group of technology investors recently released its plans to create a new "green" city between San Francisco and Sacramento in California.</p>
<p>The group's name is California Forever. It posted the plans on its website of the same name. The leader is Jan Sramek, a former trader for the financial services company Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>California Forever has purchased about $800 million of land in Solano County. The county includes small cities, many farms, and an American military base.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A wind farm is seen at dusk in rural Solano County, Calif., Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V&lt;I&gt;&amp;#&lt;/I&gt;225;squez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/85093003-cc89-49a0-8c55-c9e0c3c8ee96_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A wind farm is seen at dusk in rural Solano County, Calif., Wednesday, Aug. 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Godofredo A. V<i>&amp;#</i>225;squez)</span></div>
<p>The area is about 100 kilometers from San Francisco and 50 kilometers from the state capital of Sacramento. About 450,000 people live in the county. The cost of a mid-level home is around $600,000 while homes closer to San Francisco can be two or three times more. Housing supply is one of the greatest concerns in California, and those who work as schoolteachers, nurses or police officers cannot live close to where they work.</p>
<p>California Forever's announcement opened with this message, "Starting a conversation about eastern Solano County. A chance for a new community, good paying local jobs, solar farms and open space."</p>
<p>The post includes a lot of information about the land purchases and the group's ideas. The website includes drawings of new homes, farms, fields with solar panels, people sitting in boats and fishing and eating meals in a central city area.</p>
<p>The investment group has purchased 202 square kilometers of land since 2018. Among the investors are business leaders Laurene Powell Jobs, tech investor Marc Andreessen and LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman. California Forever's post reported that 97 percent of its investors are American. There had been some concerns that the investment group was from outside of the U.S.</p>
<p>The project sounds good to the investors, but local leaders and <strong>residents</strong> are not sure they agree.</p>
<p>To start with, many people are upset with the group's secrecy. The investors made the purchases under the name "Flannery Associates LLC."</p>
<p>Mike Thompson represents the area in the lower house of the U.S. Congress. He said the U.S. Department of Treasury and the Federal Bureau of Investigation has been working to learn who was behind the land purchases.</p>
<p>"Their secrecy has caused a lot of problems, a lot of time and a lot of <strong>expense</strong>," Thompson said.</p>
<p>The investors say they needed to keep their identities secret until they had enough land. Now that they are discussing the project, they say they want to have conversations with the residents of Solano. The group started by sending a <strong>survey</strong> to homeowners.</p>
<p>The survey asked residents about what they want for the future of Solano County. Residents' answers included lower cost of living, more good jobs, as well as improved schools and safety from crime.</p>
<p>Solano County resident Princess Washington is suspicious of California Forever's plans. Washington is the acting mayor of Suisun City, in central Solano. She says many people who live in the area do not want development. They want to keep the area close to Travis Air Force Base open.</p>
<p>She said she is concerned that the Flannery group wants to create a "city for the <strong>elite</strong>" by falsely saying they plan to build low cost homes.</p>
<p>She wondered why the group does not want to <strong>transform</strong> cities that already exist.</p>
<p>"The better thing would be to <strong>approach</strong> our city leaders and work with us within our city boundaries. Not to create a new city."</p>
<p>Flannery also faced anger earlier this year when it opened a court case against a group of landowners. Flannery said the land owners were working together to make sure they sold only at high prices.</p>
<p>Other residents say they became worried just recently, when the group sent out a survey. It asked the community about its level of support for "a major new project ... with tens of thousands of new homes."</p>
<p>Representative Thompson says he is not sure Sramek and the other investors understood Solano County or its values.</p>
<p>He said Sramek thinks his financial expertise will help the developers push the project forward faster than other California homebuilders.</p>
<p>"He doesn't have a plan, he's not there yet," Thompson said.</p>
<p>Many homebuilders say California is a difficult place to do business because there are many rules for the industry to follow.</p>
<p>Hoffman and Andreessen did not respond to emailed requests for comment, nor did Jobs through her business Emerson Collective.</p>
<p>Project developers said they will protect the military base and farmers who want to keep farming on their parcels.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>resident</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who lives in a region, city; a home or land owner</p>
<p><strong>expense</strong> <em>–n. </em>money spent to do business or work or to purchase something</p>
<p><strong>survey</strong> <em>–n. </em>a group of questions asked of many people in order to get the public's opinion about a topic</p>
<p><strong>elite</strong> <em>–adj. </em>at the highest level</p>
<p><strong>transform</strong> <em>–v. </em>to change something into something else</p>
<p><strong>approach</strong> <em>–v. </em>to come to a person and ask for something or to make an introduction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Help for Gamblers as Sports Betting Rise in US  (2023/9/11) | 美国要求体育博彩资助戒赌服务</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/help-for-gamblers-as-sports-betting-rise-in-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>People in the American state of Kentucky will be able to legally bet on sporting events for the first time in September. When they do, they also help to pay for the first-ever state program to help people with gambling problems.<br/>
今年9月，美国肯塔基州的人们将首次能够合法地在体育赛事上下注。当他们下注时，他们还承担了有史以来首个州级戒赌项目的费用。</p>
<p>Five years ago, the U.S. Supreme Court cleared the way for legalized sports betting. Almost three-fourths of U.S. states have since permitted sports betting but support for problem gambling services has been limited. Now, more states like Kentucky are requiring at least some sports gambling money to go toward helping addicted gamblers.<br/>
五年前，美国最高法院为体育博彩合法化扫清了道路。此后，美国近四分之三的州允许体育博彩，但对戒赌服务的支持有限。现在，更多像肯塔基州这样的州要求至少将部分体育博彩资金用于帮助上瘾的赌徒。</p>
<p>Research shows that younger, higher-educated men are among the most likely to bet on sports. Technology has made gambling much easier. In many states, people can now bet on smartphone apps, 24 hours a day. People can bet not only on the winners of games but on all sorts of events that happen during the game.<br/>
研究表明，受过高等教育的年轻男性最有可能在体育运动上下注。科技让赌博变得更加容易。在许多州，人们现在24小时可以在智能手机应用程序上下注。人们不仅可以把赌注押在比赛的获胜者身上，还可以押在比赛中发生的各种事件上。</p>
<p>For the last five years, legal sports betting brought in $3 billion in taxes for local and state governments. However, the states spent little on problem gambling services.<br/>
在过去的五年里，合法的体育博彩为地方和州政府带来了30亿美元的税收。然而，各州在戒赌服务上的支出很少。</p>
<p>In 2022, the state of Massachusetts budgeted $10 million for problem gambling services. And nine other states did not spend any. Most of the money from gambling went toward services like telephone helplines, counseling, and public awareness campaigns.<br/>
2022年，马萨诸塞州预算1000万美元用于戒赌服务。其他九个州没有任何支出。赌博带来的大部分资金用于电话求助热线、咨询和公众宣传活动等服务。</p>
<p>The federal government, which spends billions of dollars on substance abuse prevention and treatment, provides nothing for gambling problems.<br/>
联邦政府在药物滥用预防和治疗上花费了数十亿美元，却没有为戒赌提供任何帮助。</p>
<p>Kentucky is projected to spend about $575,000 in its first year on gambling problems.<br/>
肯塔基州预计第一年将在戒赌上花费约575000美元。</p>
<p>Michael R. Stone is the director of the nonprofit Kentucky Council on Problem Gambling. He said the amount of money is a good start, but "we've only got five certified gambling counselors in the state right now, and we're going to need probably five times that many..."<br/>
迈克尔·R·斯通是非营利组织肯塔基州戒赌委员会的主任。他说，这笔钱是一个良好的开端，但“我们目前在该州只有五名经过认证的戒赌顾问，我们可能需要五倍数量的……”</p>
<p>As of a year ago, 15 states and the District of Columbia had laws requiring some of the money from sports betting to go toward problem gambling services. But another 15 states did not.<br/>
截至一年前，15个州和哥伦比亚特区制定了法律，要求体育博彩的部分资金用于戒赌服务。但另有15个州没有这样做。</p>
<p>Since then, seven more states have either launched sports betting or passed laws to do so. All of those have required part of their sports betting money to go to problem gambling services, said Rachel Volberg. She is a researcher at the University of Massachusetts-Amhurst.<br/>
自那以后，又有七个州启动了体育博彩或通过了相关法律。雷切尔·沃伯格表示，所有这些州都要求将部分体育博彩资金用于戒赌服务。她是马萨诸塞大学阿姆赫斯特分校的研究员。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Newly Discovered Comet Won't Return for 400 Years  (2023/9/10) | 新发现彗星可肉眼观测</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/newly-discovered-comet-won-t-return-for-400-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A newly discovered comet is passing through our solar system for the first time in more than 400 years.<br/>
一颗新发现的彗星400多年来首次穿过我们的太阳系。</p>
<p>Scientists say star watchers across the Northern Hemisphere should look to the sky as soon as possible, either this week or early next. They say it will be another 400 years before the comet returns to our neighborhood.<br/>
科学家表示，北半球的观星者应该尽快观测天空，无论是本周还是下周初。他们说，这颗彗星还需要400年才能回到我们附近。</p>
<p>The comet's official name is C/2023 P1 Nishimura. It is about one kilometer wide. Comet Nishimura will travel to within 125 million kilometers of the Earth on September 12.<br/>
这颗彗星的官方名称是C/2023P1西村彗星。它宽约一公里。西村彗星将于9月12日到达距离地球1.25亿公里以内的地方。</p>
<p>The comet was discovered in August by a Japanese star watcher, Hideo Nishimura. He discovered the comet using 30-second-long exposures with a digital camera.<br/>
这颗彗星是由日本观星者西村秀夫于8月发现的。他用数码相机进行了30秒长的曝光，发现了这颗彗星。</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA says the comet has increased in brightness as it crosses our solar system. As the comet heads closer to the Sun, it will continue to get brighter.<br/>
美国宇航局表示，这颗彗星在穿越太阳系时亮度有所增加。随着彗星向太阳靠近，它将继续变得更亮。</p>
<p>Early risers should look toward the northeastern horizon about 90 minutes before sunrise. The comet will be less than 10 degrees above the horizon making it difficult to see.<br/>
早起者应该在日出前90分钟左右眺望东北地平线。彗星离地平线不到10度，因此很难看到。</p>
<p>Paul Chodas is head of NASA's Center for Near-Earth Object Studies. He said, "You really need a good pair of binoculars to pick it out and you also need to know where to look."<br/>
保罗·乔达斯是美国宇航局近地天体研究中心的负责人。他说：“你真的需要一副好的双筒望远镜才能把它找出来，你还需要知道去哪里看。”</p>
<p>The comet will come closest to the sun on about September 17. Then it will leave the solar system. Chodas said that the comet is "likely to survive its passage," meaning he does not believe it will burn up near the sun.<br/>
这颗彗星将于9月17日左右离太阳最近。然后它将离开太阳系。乔达斯说，这颗彗星在掠过太阳系时“很可能会幸存下来”，这意味着乔达斯认为它不会在太阳附近燃烧殆尽。</p>
<p>Italian astronomer Gianluca Masi is the founder of the Virtual Telescope Project. He said in an email to the Associated Press that the next week represents "the last, feasible chances" to see the comet from the Northern Hemisphere before it is lost in the sun's glare.<br/>
意大利天文学家詹卢卡·马西是虚拟望远镜项目的创始人。他在给美联社的一封电子邮件中说，下周是从北半球观测西村彗星的最后也是最可行的时机，之后它将“消失在太阳光芒中”。</p>
<p>"The comet looks amazing right now, with a long, highly structured tail, a joy to image with a telescope," he said.<br/>
他说：“这颗彗星现在看起来很神奇，它拖一条长长的、高度结构化的尾巴，用望远镜成像是一种享受。”</p>
<p>If it survives its passage by the sun, the comet should be visible in the Southern Hemisphere by the end of September, Masi said.<br/>
马西说，如果它在掠过太阳时没有解体，那么到9月底，这颗彗星应该可以在南半球看到。</p>
<p>Professional astronomers use powerful telescopes around the world to watch the sky. It is unusual for a non-professional sky watcher to discover a comet these days. Chodas of NASA said of Nishimura's discovery, "This is his third find, so good for him."<br/>
专业天文学家使用世界各地强大的望远镜观测天空。对于非专业的天空观测者来说，如今发现彗星是不寻常的。美国宇航局的乔达斯在谈到西村的发现时说：“这是他的第三次发现，对他来说太棒了。”</p>
<p>The comet last visited about 430 years ago, Chodas said.<br/>
乔达斯说，这颗彗星上次造访太阳系大约是在430年前。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thirteen US Universities Form a Free Speech Group  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/thirteen-us-universities-form-a-free-speech-group.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Thirteen American colleges and universities recently announced the creation of a plan to support freedom of speech.</p>
<p>The plan is part of an effort designed to fight what the schools call threats to U.S. democracy.</p>
<p>Among the schools taking part are Cornell University in New York state; Rutgers University in New Jersey; Notre Dame, the Catholic university in the Midwestern state of Indiana; and Benedict College, a historically Black school in South Carolina.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this May 15, 2016 file photo, students embrace as they arrive for the Rutgers graduation ceremonies in Piscataway, New Jersey. (AP Photo/Mel Evans)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6223A73D-0D7D-4727-849B-9205E51345A5_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this May 15, 2016 file photo, students embrace as they arrive for the Rutgers graduation ceremonies in Piscataway, New Jersey. (AP Photo/Mel Evans)</span></div>
<p>The effort is called The Campus Call for Free Expression. The organizer of the group is The Institute for Citizens and Scholars based in Princeton, New Jersey. It is paid for by the Knight Foundation, a private group based in Miami, Florida. The aim is to build respect for freedom of expression in colleges. Another goal is to help students bring opposing groups together.</p>
<p>The effort for free speech comes after students at several schools blocked people invited to speak in recent years. The students said they disagreed with the writings, comments, ideas or actions of the invited speaker.</p>
<p>Jonathan Alger is the president of James Madison University in Virginia, one of the schools in the group. He said the group is concerned about "deep <strong>polarization</strong>" in the U.S. where people cannot discuss their different ideas in "<strong>constructive</strong> and civil ways." He said colleges and universities need to be an example for the nation.</p>
<p>The group started preparing for The Campus Call for Free Expression in March 2022. That was when college presidents gathered to discuss ways to get their students involved in democracy.</p>
<p>The group came up with five <strong>principles</strong> of free expression and pushed for each school to design its own programs. The principles are to be used for new student <strong>orientations</strong>, educator training and special campus gatherings called convocations.</p>
<p>The principles include developing knowledge that <strong>challenges</strong> common beliefs and <strong>assumptions</strong>; reaching decisions based on evidence; understanding one's own values and gaining respect for others who have different opinions; feeling a sense of responsibility to others and the need to work toward change; and learning that free expression has <strong>consequences</strong> and does not always lead to approval.</p>
<p>Jonathan Holloway is the president at Rutgers. He said he saw a growing lack of respect for American <strong>institutions,</strong> and he wanted to push back against those feelings. In a discussion with the Associated Press, he said he was concerned by seeing the Confederate flag marched through the U.S. Capitol building during the riot on January 6, 2021. "That's when things <strong>shifted</strong> for me," he said.</p>
<p>Holloway will lead a first-year class at Rutgers this year that looks at the meaning of democracy. The aim is for the class to create a program that will improve civic education.</p>
<p>The nonprofit groups who are supporting the presidents say they are concerned that students may not be learning about how to be good citizens while in college.</p>
<p>Rajiv Vinnakota is president of the Institute for Citizens and Scholars. He said students become part of a community with more different kinds of people than they have ever experienced while in college. He wants students to learn how to interact with people who have different opinions and experiences. And he hopes the 13 schools will be able to lead the way for others who will soon join the group.</p>
<p>Vinnakota questioned if educators can "get above" issues of free expression to get people to see that higher education "can and should" play a leading part in what he called "civic preparedness."</p>
<p>Some other colleges and universities in the group include Wellesley College in Massachusetts, Wesleyan University in Connecticut, Claremont McKenna College in California, Duke University in North Carolina and the University of Pittsburgh in Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>The Knight Foundation gave Vinnakota's institute $250,000 to organize discussions among university leaders over the next year-and-a-half.</p>
<p>Alberto Ibargüen is the head of the Knight Foundation. He said the group is interested in supporting the project because, "we believe in the free exchange of ideas...we believe in an informed citizenry..."</p>
<p>PEN America is a nonprofit group that works with colleges and universities on free expression programs. It is not involved in the Campus Call for Free Expression. Kristen Shahverdian is the group's Free Expression and Education program senior manager. She said her group tells students about writers and artists around the world who have faced attacks or suffered for their ideas.</p>
<p>"They understand the <strong>ramifications</strong> of <strong>squashing</strong> another's speech," she said.</p>
<p>Lucas Morel is a professor of politics at Washington and Lee University in Virginia who is not involved in the project. He is the head of a group called the Academic Freedom Alliance. He said more universities should work on programs that permit students to learn by discussing different evidence-based ideas. He said colleges are not just for helping students get a job, but they should help young people become citizens who care about the world around them.</p>
<p>"If we don't do a good job of helping them be careful readers and careful listeners, it stands to reason that as citizens they won't be careful listeners and careful expressers of their own thought," he said. "And it will be difficult for us to <strong>function</strong> as a self-governing society."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>polarization </strong>–n. to cause people to separate into opposing groups</p>
<p><strong>constructive </strong>–adj. useful in some way; not useless</p>
<p><strong>principles </strong>–n. (pl.) a set of ideas rules and beliefs that guide how people see right and wrong</p>
<p><strong>orientation </strong>–n. a process of giving people who are new to a job or school information and training</p>
<p><strong>challenge </strong>–v. to question something or dispute it</p>
<p><strong>assumption </strong>–n. something that a person believes to be true, but that is not known to be true</p>
<p><strong>consequences </strong>–n. (pl.) the results of some action or decision</p>
<p><strong>institution </strong>–n. an established organization that has a part in society or an established belief or behavior</p>
<p><strong>shift </strong>–v. to change position</p>
<p><strong>ramifications </strong>–n. (pl.) a result of an action or decision that are not easily realized or understood</p>
<p><strong>squash </strong>–v. to crush or smash</p>
<p><strong>function </strong>–n. to operate; to do a specific job correctly</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Tennis Looks for Solutions to Tennis Ball Waste  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/tennis-looks-for-solutions-to-tennis-ball-waste.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The sport of tennis has a problem with waste that many players do not even recognize each time they open a new container of game balls.</p>
<p>The balls are not <strong>recyclable</strong>. Almost all of the 330 million balls manufactured each year end up in waste, or garbage, landfills. Once there, it can take as long as 400 years for the balls to <strong>decompose.</strong> Major professional tennis competitions go through nearly 100,000 balls during two weeks of play.</p>
<p>The problem of tennis ball waste has sent ball makers, tennis officials, and recycling companies looking for solutions.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A box of game-used tennis balls are packed in a recycling box during the U.S. Open tennis championships, Monday, Sept. 4, 2023, in New York. AP Photo/Eduardo Munoz Alvarez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-e274-08dbaf191877_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A box of game-used tennis balls are packed in a recycling box during the U.S. Open tennis championships, Monday, Sept. 4, 2023, in New York. AP Photo/Eduardo Munoz Alvarez)</span></div>
<p>Nickolas J. Themelis is director of Columbia University's Earth Engineering Center.</p>
<p>"Tennis balls, like a lot of objects, are made to be indestructible, which means they're very resistant to mechanical processing," he said.</p>
<p>"But do you take a useful object that lasts forever and say people shouldn't use it because it lasts forever? That's nonsense," he added.</p>
<p>Themelis and other experts note that tennis balls make up a tiny percentage of the hundreds of millions of metric tons of garbage produced every year. He says part of the solution is finding ways to do other things with the balls.</p>
<p>"Anyone who would say you shouldn't play tennis because of the tennis balls is misinformed," said Jason Quinn, director of Colorado State University's Sustainability Research Laboratory. He added, "There are things you can do to reuse and repurpose tennis balls to lessen the impact."</p>
<p>Individual used balls sometimes become playthings for dogs or are re-used in other small ways. But, huge numbers of used balls can also be crushed<strong> </strong>to pieces for use as building material, like flooring.</p>
<p><strong>Tennis ball materials</strong></p>
<p>However, experts and environmental groups say that still does not solve the problem of tennis ball recycling. The balls' outer soft <strong>layer</strong>, called the felt, is strongly attached to a soft center. The felt is a combination of wool and nylon which cannot be recycled.</p>
<p>In addition, the center of top-level balls are made with rubber from rubber trees. Environmental groups say this leads to deforestation in the Amazon.</p>
<p>Jason Collins is chief of international <strong>racquet</strong> sports for Wilson Sporting Goods company. He said that its top-level balls use rubber directly from the trees. However, he said Wilson also makes other tennis balls that include recycled rubber material.</p>
<p><strong>Working on the problem</strong></p>
<p>The International Tennis Federation (ITF) is a governing body of professional tennis. Last year the ITF brought together manufacturers, tennis officials and recyclers to begin working on the tennis ball issue. The group is working to find answers to questions such as: Is there a way to design a fully recyclable ball? Can the ITF change rules so balls are used longer in play? How well do various kinds of balls perform at different levels of play?</p>
<p>Currently, professional players change to a new set of balls after the first seven games and then after every nine games.</p>
<p>Jamie Capel-Davies is the head of science and tech at ITF. He said there are four levels in the effort to reduce the waste.</p>
<p>"First of all, to try and reduce the number of balls that are being used. Then reuse balls as best we can. Recycling is third," he said.</p>
<p>The fourth level is disposal, meaning placing the balls in landfills. Most balls are disposed into landfills.</p>
<p>Manufacturers and recyclers have begun taking steps to reduce and reuse balls.</p>
<p>Wilson Sporting Goods introduced its Triniti ball that keeps air inside the core longer and has a stronger felt.</p>
<p>Vermont-based RecycleBalls says it expects to collect 3 million tennis balls this year from across the U.S and Canada.</p>
<p>"We believe in multiple lives for tennis balls," said RecycleBalls leader Erin Cunningham. But, the group does not want the used balls to stay forever in their storage center.</p>
<p>"We need to make sure that there's <strong>actually</strong> demand for recycled product on the back end," Cunningham said.</p>
<p>Columbia University's Themelis believes the final resting place of tennis balls should not be landfills but waste-to-energy plants that burn garbage to generate electricity.</p>
<p>However, opponents of the idea say burning the balls to create electricity also adds to air pollution. They say there are better and cleaner new uses.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>James Martinez wrote this story for The Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>recycle </strong><em>-v. </em>to process material, such as paper, glass, or plastic, in order to use it again</p>
<p><strong>decompose </strong><em>-v. </em>to chemically break down</p>
<p><strong>layer </strong><em>-n. </em>a piece of material that covers a surface or is between two other things</p>
<p><strong>racquet </strong><em>-n. </em>an oval shaped bat with strings across it, used to hit balls in sports such as tennis, squash and badminton</p>
<p><strong>actually </strong><em>-adv. </em>true in fact; in reality</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Warren Harding: Damaged  (2023/9/10)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/americas-presidents-warren-harding.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Kelly Jean Kelly</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">09 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>VOA Learning English presents America's Presidents.</p>
<p>Today we are talking about Warren Harding. He was the 29<sup>th</sup> president of the United States.</p>
<p>Harding was very different from the 28th president, Woodrow Wilson.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="America's Presidents - Warren G. Harding" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6069a603-303c-4e5e-b4e2-f9337789781a_tv_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">America's Presidents - Warren G. Harding</span></div>
<p>Wilson supported change; Harding promised "a return to normalcy."</p>
<p>Wilson took steps to protect American workers; Harding often worked to protect business owners.</p>
<p>Wilson was slow in supporting voting rights for women, and in accepting African-American people as equal to whites. Harding supported women's suffrage and civil rights for African-Americans.</p>
<p>Yet both men were popular during their years in office.</p>
<p>Today, however, historians usually think of Wilson as one of America's best presidents. But Harding is remembered as one of the worst.</p>
<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>
<p>Warren Harding was the eighth president from the state of Ohio. His parents were both doctors.</p>
<p>Harding spoke about having a happy childhood, growing up on a farm with his brothers and sisters. Some of his favorite early activities were performing in a <strong>band.</strong></p>
<p>Later, Harding – along with two friends – bought a newspaper. The paper became successful for <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/harding/life-before-the-presidency">several reasons</a>.</p>
<p>Harding was kind to his employees and shared the company's profits with them. He also tried not to publish stories that criticized politics or politicians from any party. Finally, he married a woman who had an excellent head for business.</p>
<p><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/1600/first-ladies/florenceharding">Florence Kling Harding</a> led the newspaper's <strong>circulation</strong> <strong>department</strong>. She also helped to direct her husband's political career.</p>
<p>In time, Warren Harding became a state senator, a lieutenant governor of Ohio, and then a member of the U.S. Senate. He especially liked being a senator – and many of the other lawmakers liked him.</p>
<p>One <a class="wsw__a" href="https://millercenter.org/president/harding/life-before-the-presidency">reason</a> is because Harding rarely took a controversial position on any issue.</p>
<p>Instead, he accepted most of the ideas of the Republican Party. He was also good-looking and had an excellent speaking voice.</p>
<p>These qualities helped earn him the Republican presidential nomination in 1920. A few months later, he easily won the national election.</p>
<p><strong>Presidency</strong></p>
<p>President Harding took office shortly after World War I ended. He promised to make Americans feel calm again, and also improve the nation's <strong>prosperity</strong>. Two of Harding's goals were to support business and to limit immigration.</p>
<p>He succeeded on both issues. His administration reduced taxes for big businesses and wealthy people. It also increased tariffs -- taxes on foreign imports.</p>
<p>And the Harding administration put in place <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/united-states-history-of-immigration-restrictions/3700234.html" target="_blank">new rules on immigration</a>. The rules made it easier for immigrants from northern Europe to enter the country, but harder for immigrants from Russia, eastern and central Europe.</p>
<p>Harding also took steps to improve the effectiveness of the federal government.</p>
<p>But his administration is remembered mostly for its problems.</p>
<p>At the beginning of his term, Harding reportedly told friends that the job of being president was too much for him. He appeared to want to do well, and he worked hard. But he turned over most of the responsibility to his friends in the cabinet.</p>
<p>A few were very able. But some were dishonest. They abused their positions to gain wealth for themselves and their families.</p>
<p>One of the most famous examples of corruption during Harding's administration is known as the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.wyohistory.org/encyclopedia/teapot-dome-scandal">Teapot Dome Scandal</a>.</p>
<p>The name "Teapot Dome" comes from a rock in the state of Wyoming. The rock looked like a teapot. Scientists correctly believed that oil could be found in the ground underneath it.</p>
<p>At the time, the U.S. navy depended on oil to fuel its ships. So, the federal government claimed the land in case the navy needed to use the oil in an emergency.</p>
<p>But a cabinet official who was a friend of Harding took control of the land. He gave a private company permission to search for oil on it in exchange for a large amount of money.</p>
<p>Some lawmakers became suspicious. So they opened an investigation.</p>
<p>In time, lawyers proved the act of corruption. Harding's friend was the first person to be found guilty of a crime while serving as a cabinet official.</p>
<p>But President Harding did not live to see his friend go to jail.</p>
<p>The investigation was just beginning when Harding took a trip to the West Coast to campaign for his policies.</p>
<p>Some say that Harding was also trying to escape the problems in his administration. He reportedly told one reporter that worrying about what his friends were doing kept him awake at nights.</p>
<p>During the trip, Harding showed signs of not being in good health. Doctors thought he could have food poisoning or pneumonia. He was taken to a hotel in San Francisco, California. For a day, he appeared to be feeling better.</p>
<p>He was sitting up in bed. And then suddenly, his body shook and collapsed. He died <strong>instantly</strong>.</p>
<p>Reports at the time differed on the cause of Harding's death. Some even said that his wife poisoned the president to protect him from being punished for the wrongdoing in his administration.</p>
<p>But most historians think that he had long suffered from heart failure, and was struck by a heart attack. He was 57.</p>
<p><strong>Legacy </strong></p>
<p>Millions of Americans mourned over Warren Harding's death. They stood beside railroad tracks as his body traveled from California back to Washington, DC.</p>
<p>The following year, Florence Harding also died. She and her husband are buried together under a <strong>grand</strong> memorial in their hometown in Ohio.</p>
<p>But in the years after his death, Harding's public image worsened. More corruption scandals in his administration came to light. And some historians have criticized him for not having a clear idea about how he wanted to lead the country.</p>
<p>In 1927, a woman published a book saying she had a long, but secret relationship with Harding, both before and during his presidency. She also said he was the father of her daughter. Genetic testing has confirmed her claim.</p>
<p>More than 30 years after her book was published, a lawyer discovered love letters from Harding to a different woman. They confirmed that he had a long romantic affair with the wife of one of his friends. Harding had also been married at the time.</p>
<p>These reports, as well as the corruption during his administration, damaged Harding's public image. But he also seemed to know that he would not be remembered as one of the best occupants of the White House.</p>
<p>Instead, he tried to be likable and modest. He called himself "a man of limited <strong>talents</strong>" who was "not fit for the office" of president.</p>
<p>I'm Kelly Jean Kelly.</p>
<p><em>Kelly Jean Kelly wrote this story for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.</em></p><div id="bottom"><!-- 51-content-bottom -->
<ins class="adsbygoogle" data-ad-client="ca-pub-3585518775245612" data-ad-format="auto" data-ad-slot="9284795419" data-full-width-responsive="true" style="display:block; text-align:center;"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script></div>
<p><em>____________________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>band </strong>-<em> n. </em>a usually small group of musicians who play popular music together</p>
<p><strong>circulation </strong>- <em>n. </em>the average number of copies of a newspaper that are sold over a particular period</p>
<p><strong>prosperity</strong> - <em>n.</em> the state of being successful usually by making a lot of money</p>
<p><strong>instantly</strong> - <em>adv. </em>without delay; immediately</p>
<p><strong>grand</strong> - <em>adj.</em> impressive because of size or importance</p>
<p><strong>talents</strong> - <em>n.</em> special abilities that allow someone to do something well</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Are Biofuels a Clean Source of Energy?  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/are-biofuels-a-clean-source-of-energy.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>India has proposed an alliance to speed up the development of biofuels to support energy <strong>transition</strong> worldwide.</p>
<p>Biofuel is a kind of fuel produced from agricultural products or organic waste.</p>
<p>India plans to announce the alliance at the G-20 gathering in New Delhi. It is expected that more than 15 countries will sign up to be part of the alliance. The United States, Canada, and Brazil are among a few of the countries expected to join India in such an alliance.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Sprawling fields of sugar cane are visible near Meerut, India, on August, 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/92aa66f4-81e5-4b63-9f3a-242c0970cc22_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Sprawling fields of sugar cane are visible near Meerut, India, on August, 30, 2023. (AP Photo/Altaf Qadri)</span></div>
<p><strong>What are biofuels?</strong></p>
<p>Humans have used biofuels since ancient times. For example, humans burn wood and animal waste for cooking, heating, and light. They have gained popularity in recent years for their possibility to deliver cleaner energy than some other sources.</p>
<p>Biofuels are grouped based on their source. Each group is known as a "generation." First-generation biofuels come from food crops like corn and sugar cane. Second generation come from non-food crops and agricultural waste. And third-generation come from small plants called algae.</p>
<p>Ethanol, biodiesel, and biogas are popular kinds of biofuels. They can be produced from any of these sources and are grouped based on the source from which they are produced. For example, ethanol produced from farm-grown corn is grouped as first-generation ethanol.</p>
<p><strong>Are biofuels always a source of clean energy?</strong></p>
<p>Biofuels are not always a clean source of energy. But it depends on how it is produced. A biofuel made from waste, for example, with <strong>renewable</strong> energy to power the production, would have little or no <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> production, making it a clean fuel. But when crops are grown to just produce biofuels, the fertilizer and nonrenewable fuels needed to produce the fuel make it much less clean.</p>
<p>"If you look at the full life <strong>cycle</strong> of producing biofuels, it's many times not clean," said Lydia Powell. She is an energy policy researcher at the New Delhi-based Observer Research Foundation. She has followed developments related to biofuels for over 20 years.</p>
<p>Biofuels can also mean land that could have produced food is being used for energy. They can add to deforestation when land is cleared for their production.</p>
<p>Powell noted Europe's imports of plant-based palm oil from Indonesia and other East Asian countries to make biodiesel for cars and trucks. Those imports greatly fell after the European Union banned the sale of palm oil and other palm-based products when they could be linked to deforestation.</p>
<p>"They were destroying natural forests to plant palm trees so you produce oil to export to Europe. When you destroy forests, you destroy large <strong>chunks</strong> of carbon sinks," Powell said.</p>
<p>Those problems have led to debates about exactly how sustainable biofuels are.</p>
<p><strong>What are biofuels used for?</strong></p>
<p>Biofuels are often used for transportation of people and products.</p>
<p>Experts say once they are made, biofuels produce little to no greenhouse gases when used. The same cannot be said with the <strong>fossil fuels</strong> they are mixed with.</p>
<p>But there is a hope that biofuels might completely replace fossil fuels to power airplanes and ships.</p>
<p>"They are one<strong> option </strong>among a larger set of solutions," said Jane O'Malley of International Council on Clean Transportation, a Washington-based independent nonprofit.</p>
<p>O'Malley said it is important to use the right kind of biofuel for the right purpose. She said it is important for countries using biofuels to move as quickly as possible to produce them with little to no greenhouse gas production.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Ange Adihe Kasongo and Benoit Nyemba reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transition </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to make a change from one state, place, or condition to another</p>
<p><strong>renewable</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>adj.</em> restored or replaced by natural processes</p>
<p><strong>greenhouse effect </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> the warming of the Earth's atmosphere that is caused by air pollution</p>
<p><strong>cycle </strong><em>– n.</em> a set of events or actions that happen again and again in the same order</p>
<p><strong>chunk </strong><em>– n.</em> a large amount or part of something</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuels </strong>–<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> a fuel (such as coal, oil, or natural gas) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>option </strong><em>– n.</em> the opportunity or ability to choose something or to choose between two or more things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Rolling Stones Announce First New Album in 18 Years  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/rolling-stones-announce-first-new-album-in-18-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>
The Rolling Stones said this week that their first new collection of songs in almost 20 years comes out on October 20.</p>
<p>The album will be called <em>Hackney Diamonds</em>. The name comes from broken glass often seen on the streets of east London's Hackney area.</p>
<p>Three of the band's <strong>original</strong> members - Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood – came to the Hackney Empire, a historic theater, for the announcement.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rolling Stones band members Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood attend a launch event for their new album Hackney Diamonds, at Hackney Empire in London, Britain, September 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/205a3811-7361-4e74-85db-bdc11fe5c9e9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rolling Stones band members Mick Jagger, Keith Richards and Ronnie Wood attend a launch event for their new album "Hackney Diamonds", at Hackney Empire in London, Britain, September 6, 2023. (REUTERS/Toby Melville)</span></div>
<p>The Rolling Stones are still traveling the world and performing concerts, but they have not made an album since 2016. That recording did not include new material.</p>
<p>Richards, 79, said the band only made a new album because Jagger wanted to sing. So they went to record new songs after almost 20 years.</p>
<p>"When you have a singer that wants to sing," Richards said, "you <strong>grab</strong> him and throw him in the studio." Richards said the songs came together with "energy and urgency."</p>
<p>Jagger, who is 80, said, "we are quite pleased," with the new album. He said the group would not have put a recording together if "we hadn't really liked it. We said we had to make a record we really love ourselves ... we hope you all like it."</p>
<p>They released the first song, called <em>Angry</em>, this week. But Jagger said the rest of the songs are not angry. He said the album contains "love songs, <strong>ballads</strong>, country..." sounds.</p>
<p>The new recording includes songs with Paul McCartney, Lady Gaga, Stevie Wonder and Charlie Watts, the Rolling Stones <strong>drummer</strong> who died in 2021. Watts recorded sounds for two songs in 2019. Steve Jordan is the drummer for the other 10.</p>
<p>"Of course, he's missed incredibly," Richards said about Watts. But he added that Jordan was Watts' suggestion for a <strong>replacement</strong>.</p>
<p>Jagger said the addition of Lady Gaga to the album was unplanned. The Stones were recording at a <strong>studio</strong> in Los Angeles and Lady Gaga just happened to be in the studio next door. So, she recorded the song <em>Sweet Sound of Heaven</em> with the band.</p>
<p>"She walked in next to me and we started singing together," Jagger said.</p>
<p>Wood said McCartney of the Beatles played the bass guitar on one <strong>track</strong>. "You know, he was loving it." McCartney's band was perhaps the Rolling Stones' biggest <strong>rival</strong> in the 1960s.</p>
<p>Taric Fioravanti was one of the fans who lined up outside hoping to see the band arrive. He is from Brazil. "I love these guys," he said. "They're 80 years old. Most bands have stopped making music by that age," he added.</p>
<p>The Rolling Stones started in 1962. They celebrated their 60th year with a tour of Europe in 2022 and they said they have plans to visit North America in 2024.</p>
<p>Wood, 76, plays guitar. He said the idea of retirement is "Impossible. You've got to keep playing," he added.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on reports by The Associated Press and Reuters.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>resident</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who lives in a region, city; a home or land owner</p>
<p><strong>original</strong> <em>–adj. </em>the first or existing at the beginning</p>
<p><strong>grab</strong> <em>–v. </em>to quickly take hold of something with your hands</p>
<p><strong>ballad</strong> <em>–n. </em>a kind of slow, romantic song</p>
<p><strong>drummer</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who provides the beat in music, usually using drumsticks and drums to make a sound</p>
<p><strong>replacement</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person who steps in if someone is not available to do a task</p>
<p><strong>studio</strong> <em>–n. </em>quiet room used to record music or voice</p>
<p><strong>track</strong> <em>–n. </em>one song of a group that are included in an album</p>
<p><strong>rival</strong> <em>–n. </em>a person or thing trying to be more successful than another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Mandatory, Compulsory and Obligatory  (2023/9/9)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/mandatory-compulsory-and-obligatory.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">08 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we will answer a question about the difference between "mandatory," "compulsory," and "obligatory."</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello. My name is Nelson, and I'm from Nicaragua.<br/>
Can you help me to understand the difference between "compulsory," "mandatory" and "obligatory?"<br/>
Thank you in advance,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Mandatory, Compulsory, and Obligatory " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a5ad-08dbae4c5d99_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Mandatory, Compulsory, and Obligatory </span></div>
<p>Nelson.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>This is a great question, Nelson. These three adjectives have the same meaning, so they are synonyms. They share a basic definition of "required." But there are some slight differences in how often we use each. Let's start with the most common, "mandatory."</p>
<p><strong>Mandatory</strong></p>
<p>Mandatory comes from the word "mandate," which means to give <strong>authority</strong> to act or as a noun means an official order. Something that is "mandatory" is the result of that action or order. It usually comes from a law or rule.</p>
<p>This is the most common of the three words in question because it is often used in everyday conversations. We use it to describe something that is required by a mandate, law, or rule.</p>
<p><em>In most public high schools, there is mandatory testing every year.</em></p>
<p><em>Seatbelts are mandatory in the U.S. If you do not wear a seatbelt, you are breaking the law. </em></p>
<p><strong>Compulsory</strong></p>
<p>"Compulsory" is the second most common adjective out of the three, so it is used less often than "mandatory. It also means required by law. We often use it to describe education and military service.</p>
<p><em>Many countries in the world have compulsory military service like Ukraine, South Korea, and Egypt. </em></p>
<p><em>Massachusetts became the first place in the United States to have compulsory schooling for children in the year 1642.</em></p>
<p><strong>Obligatory </strong></p>
<p>The least common adjective is "obligatory," but it is the most formal of the three. It means the same as "mandatory" and "compulsory," but also has other meanings.</p>
<p>We use "obligatory" not just for laws or rules, but we use it to describe <strong>obligations </strong>that are based on moral or social instances.</p>
<p><em>Social media is now the obligatory way to message friends because young people do not like to talk on the phone. </em></p>
<p>Another way we use obligatory is when we are talking about something that people have stereotypically used but is not really needed.</p>
<p><em>Many movies for young people feature obligatory dance<strong> </strong>scenes at the end of the film. </em></p>
<p><em>The obligatory two-week notice before you quit your job is common in the U.S. but not required by law. </em></p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Nelson.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>authority </strong>– <em>n</em>. a leadership figure or government</p>
<p><strong>obligation </strong><em>– n. </em>something that you must do because it is morally right</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Congolese Arts Center Helps Street Children Find Their Voice  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/congolese-arts-center-helps-street-children-find-their-voice.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>A small recording room outside the Congolese capital Kinshasa has become a safe space for homeless <strong>teenagers</strong>. They sing about their life on the streets and dream of a better future.</p>
<p>The homeless sing about sexual abuse, stealing, theft, and dealings with the police at the Mokili Na Poche cultural center. It is a safe space that permits young people and children to wash, eat, and learn.</p>
<p>"It really makes me happy when I sing," said 19-year-old Osé Mavakala. He has slept on the streets for years. There are more than 20,000 homeless children in Kinshasa, UNICEF, the U.N. agency, has found.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Cedrick Tshimbalanga, 32, the founder of Mokili Na Poche cultural centre, uses his phone while talking to homeless teenagers during a lunch at the cultural center in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo September 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Justin Makangara)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/86272891-6fe4-4a5d-9eed-33e23ba8cc4b_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Cedrick Tshimbalanga, 32, the founder of Mokili Na Poche cultural centre, uses his phone while talking to homeless teenagers during a lunch at the cultural center in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo September 5, 2023. (REUTERS/Justin Makangara)</span></div>
<p>Other teenagers looked on with<strong> </strong>happiness as Mavakala <strong>rapped</strong> into the recording equipment at the center in late August.</p>
<p>Mavakala dreams of bigger goals after having the chance to record in a real recording space. He said, "It <strong>encourages</strong> me and I tell myself - ah, life belongs to the <strong>courageous</strong>." He added that U.S. rapper Lil Wayne and Congolese star Fally Ipupa influenced his music.</p>
<p>He has been coming to the center for the past three years, taking part in the music, art, and reading classes it offers throughout the day. Founder Cedrick Tshimbalanga hopes these skills and daily experiences will help the children build a base for their life and their voices.</p>
<p>"With music...young people are able to talk about their daily experience - everything they live through daily: rape, theft, <strong>trauma</strong>, attacks," said Tshimbalanga, who plans to release their music soon.</p>
<p>The classes are also a chance for young people to make up for lost possibilities in life. While the Democratic Republic of Congo has made progress in education, over 7 million children aged between five and 17 still do not have schooling, UNICEF found.</p>
<p>"Break free from the criminal life, my friend, it's time to see what the future holds for you," Mavakala rapped during an emotion-filled performance at the center in August.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Ange Adihe Kasongo and Benoit Nyemba reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>teenager </strong><em>– n.</em> someone who is between 13 and 19 years old</p>
<p><strong>rap </strong><em>– n.</em> a type of music that has words that are spoken with the rhythm instead of being sung</p>
<p><strong>encourage</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>v.</em> to make (someone) more determined, hopeful, or confident</p>
<p><strong>courageous </strong><em>– adj.</em> very brave</p>
<p><strong>trauma </strong><em>– n.</em> a very difficult or unpleasant experience that causes someone to have mental or emotional problems usually for a long time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Afghans in US Face Difficulties  (2023/9/8) | 阿富汗人在美国陷入困境</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/afghans-in-us-face-difficulties.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The U.S. Department of State says that nearly 90,000 Afghans have come to the United States through a special federal program since 2021. The program is called Operation Allies Welcome.<br/>
美国国务院表示，自2021年以来，已有近9万名阿富汗人通过一项特殊的联邦计划来到美国。该项目名为“欢迎盟友行动”。</p>
<p>The U.S. government created Operation Allies Welcome to help resettle Afghans who had worked with the U.S. in Afghanistan until it withdrew.<br/>
美国政府创建了“欢迎盟友行动”项目，以帮助重新安置在美国撤军前曾在阿富汗与美国合作的阿富汗人。</p>
<p>Farzana Jamalzada fled Afghanistan after the Taliban took control of the country in August 2021. Jamalzada feared that her work with the U.S. government put her in danger.<br/>
2021年8月塔利班控制阿富汗后，法扎娜·贾马尔扎达逃离了该国。贾马尔扎达担心她与美国政府的合作会将她置于危险之中。</p>
<p>Jamalzada settled in New York City. The government program gave her permission to live and work in the U.S. for two years. She got a job with an organization that helps people in need, a charity. The job provided her with money to pay for a place to live and other necessities. But the two years ended at the end of August.<br/>
贾马尔扎达在纽约市定居。该政府项目允许她在美国生活和工作两年。她在一家帮助有需要的人的慈善机构找到了一份工作。这份工作为她提供了钱来支付房租和其他必需品。但到8月底这两年时间就结束了。</p>
<p>She and her family are waiting for an immigration interview for their application to live and work in the U.S. permanently. The document that permits this is known as a green card.<br/>
她和她的家人正在等待移民面试，以申请在美国永久生活和工作。这种许可文件被称为绿卡。</p>
<p>Reuters news agency reported that President Joe Biden's administration extended the permission for two more years in June. But the permission to stay in the country is still temporary.<br/>
路透社报道称，拜登政府于6月将该许可延长了两年。但是，留在该国的许可仍然是暂时的。</p>
<p>Difficulty with immigration documents is common for many Afghans who were resettled through Operation Allies Welcome. Their path to legally living in the U.S. permanently is not simple.<br/>
对于许多通过“欢迎盟友行动”重新安置的阿富汗人来说，通常很难获取这份移民文件。他们在美国合法永居的道路并不平坦。</p>
<p>A group of U.S. lawmakers from both political parties, men and women who served in the U.S. military and others are working to support a new law to help Afghan immigrants.<br/>
一群来自两党的美国议员，包括美国服役人员以及其他人员，正在努力支持一项帮助阿富汗移民的新法律。</p>
<p>The Afghan Adjustment Act aims to create a direct path for Afghans to live and work in the U.S. permanently. The goal would be for many Afghans to become citizens in the future.<br/>
《阿富汗调整法案》旨在为阿富汗人在美国永久生活和工作创造一条直接途径。目标是让众多阿富汗人在未来成为公民。</p>
<p>But the legislation has not made progress in the House of Representatives or in the Senate.<br/>
但这项立法在众议院和参议院都没有取得进展。</p>
<p>Danilo Zak is with Church World Service, a group that assists refugees. Zak said there are many Afghans who simply do not have money for, or cannot find, immigration assistance.<br/>
达尼洛·扎克是帮助难民的世界教会服务组织的成员。扎克说，许多阿富汗人根本没有钱或找不到移民援助。</p>
<p>Unlike some others, Jamalzada and her husband do have a path to a green card. They can request a Special Immigrant Visa. The Special Immigrant Visa is for translators, interpreters and others who assisted the U.S. government in the war in Afghanistan.<br/>
与其他人不同，贾马尔扎达和她的丈夫确实有获得绿卡的途径。他们可以申请特殊移民签证。特殊移民签证适用于在阿富汗战争中协助美国政府的翻译、口译员和其他人员。</p>
<p>But Jamalzada had to flee Afghanistan so suddenly that her visa was not fully processed. To get a green card, Jamalzada and her husband must attend a government interview on September 12. Until that time, she and her husband may not legally work.<br/>
但贾马尔扎达不得不突然逃离阿富汗，她的签证没有得到完全处理。为了获得绿卡，贾马尔扎达和她的丈夫必须在9月12日参加政府面试。在此之前，她和丈夫可能无法合法工作。</p>
<p>Jamalzada said she hopes the U.S. Congress passes the Afghan Adjustment Act. She said she wants her friends and family already in the U.S. to not have to worry about their ability to live and work in the country.<br/>
贾马尔扎达说，她希望美国国会能通过《阿富汗调整法案》。她说，她希望已经在美国的朋友和家人可以不必担心他们在美国的生活和工作能力。</p>
<p>"You never know what's gonna happen to you," she said.<br/>
她说：“你永远不知道在你身上会发生什么。”</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australian Vote Could Give 'Voice' to Indigenous Communities  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/australian-vote-could-give-voice-to-indigenous-communities.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Some of Australia's <strong>Indigenous</strong> communities are hoping a national vote that would change the country's constitution could give native people more of a voice in the government.</p>
<p>The vote, known as a referendum, would put in the nation's constitution a way for Indigenous people to advise Parliament on policies that affect their lives. The vote, officially called "Voice to Parliament," will be held on October 14.</p>
<p>Leaders of some Indigenous groups are looking to the process to help save their cultures and languages. Clark Webb is seeking to do that for his native, or Aboriginal, community, the Gumbaynggirr people.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Educator Clark Webb performs a song with children including his daughter Jayalaani, at the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School, a bilingual school teaching the Gumbaynggirr language, in Coffs Harbour, Australia June 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Alasdair Pal)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-fd73-08dbad6b3245_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Educator Clark Webb performs a song with children including his daughter Jayalaani, at the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School, a bilingual school teaching the Gumbaynggirr language, in Coffs Harbour, Australia June 1, 2023. (REUTERS/Alasdair Pal)</span></div>
<p>Webb recently led a class of schoolchildren as they danced to native songs. "Opening our own schools, that's <strong>sovereignty</strong> in action," Webb said.</p>
<p>He and others want to bring back the Indigenous language spoken in Coffs Harbor, a coastal town about 500 kilometers north of Sydney. "And so we need that 'Voice' there to <strong>lobby</strong> for that."</p>
<p>Webb started the Gumbaynggirr Giingana Freedom School last year. It was the first bilingual Indigenous school in Australia's most populous state of New South Wales.</p>
<p>The effort is part of an attempt to bring back dozens of languages that are close to dying out. It is being supported by federal and state governments.</p>
<p>Many of Australia's Indigenous people see the recovery of languages as very important to the survival of their cultures.</p>
<p><strong>Oldest culture</strong></p>
<p>Australia's Indigenous and Torres Strait Islander communities are perhaps the world's oldest. They have a history on the continent dating back tens of thousands of years.</p>
<p>After colonization by Great Britain in 1788, the people increasingly faced discrimination, which continued long after Australia became a nation in 1901.</p>
<p>Government officials often moved Indigenous people from their traditional lands, known as Country. They forcibly separated Indigenous children from their families, resulting in a "stolen generation" from the mid-19th century to the 1970s.</p>
<p>As late as the 1980s, officials punished Indigenous people for speaking their languages.</p>
<p>"I think, growing up, I knew there was something missing from my life," Webb said. "And as I got older, I realized that ... was our language."</p>
<p>Webb estimates there are now about 30 <strong>proficient</strong> or highly proficient speakers of Gumbaynggirr. Among them is his nine-year-old daughter.</p>
<p><strong>Language revival</strong></p>
<p>Australia has one of the world's highest rates of language loss in the world.</p>
<p>At the time of European colonization, more than 250 Indigenous languages, including 800 <strong>dialects</strong>, were believed to have been spoken on the continent.</p>
<p>But the most recent population data shows that more than 150 languages were still being spoken in 2021. However, just 9.5 percent of indigenous Australians reported speaking one or more languages at home.</p>
<p>Ray Ingrey is one of a handful of people fluent in Dharawal. It was the first language heard by British explorer Captain James Cook when he landed in Australia in 1770.</p>
<p>Ingrey heads the Gujaga Foundation. It was founded in 2019 to bring back the language. He said government policies in those days severely hurt the ability to pass the language on from one generation to the next.</p>
<p>Officials had barred the grandparents of Webb and Ingrey from speaking their native languages. And some relatives were threatened by the police for speaking it anywhere.</p>
<p>Author and teacher Jasmine Seymour is leading efforts to revive the Dharug Aboriginal language among hundreds of schoolchildren in Sydney. Most of the children are non-Indigenous.</p>
<p>Seymour is related to<strong> </strong>Maria Lock, the first Aboriginal person to marry a European settler and one of the first admitted to a school to learn English.</p>
<p>"To be at the other end of history, where my language is being <strong>revitalized</strong> in school, is completely <strong>profound</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters and The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>indigenous </strong><em>— adj. </em>produced, living, or existing naturally in a particular region or environment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sovereignty </strong><em>— n. </em>unlimited power over a country</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>lobby </strong><em>— v. </em>o try to influence government officials to make decisions for or against something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>proficient </strong><em>— adj. </em>good at doing something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dialect </strong><em>— n. </em>a form of a language that is spoken in a particular area and that uses some of its own words, grammar, and pronunciations</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>revitalize </strong><em>— v. </em>to make active, healthy, or energetic again</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>profound </strong><em>— adj. </em>having or showing great knowledge or understanding</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Discussing Artificial Intelligence  (2023/9/8)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/discussing-artificial-intelligence.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">07 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) has been the subject of many news reports this year. It has also been part of many everyday discussions.</p>
<p>It will likely continue to be a popular subject of discussion in the coming years, too.</p>
<p>So, how might one talk about artificial intelligence? What kinds of terms and structures should you use?</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: DIscussing Artificial Intelligence" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-d40f-08dbae161aba_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: DIscussing Artificial Intelligence</span></div>
<p>In this week's Everyday Grammar, we will explore a point of connection between grammar and technology. You will learn how to ask questions about artificial intelligence. You will also learn some ways to express your own opinions about AI.</p>
<p><strong>Questions – open ended </strong></p>
<p>Let's start with questions. Questions generally come in two forms – yes or no questions and open-ended questions.</p>
<p>Yes or no questions ask for a yes or a no answer.</p>
<p>Open-ended questions are seeking more information than a simple yes or no answer.</p>
<p>Open-ended questions are the secret to good discussions. By asking open-ended questions, you can learn much more about the thoughts and opinions of others.</p>
<p>We often use question words to ask open-ended questions. When we discuss artificial intelligence, a few question words will be especially useful. These are what, why, and how.</p>
<p>Consider these three questions:</p>
<p><em>What do you think of artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p><em>Why are people concerned about artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence affect our lives? </em></p>
<p>Note that there is a general structure to all of these questions. They begin with the question word. Then, they involve some kind of helping verb: do, be, or will. Then we have the subject of the sentence, the main verb, and the rest of the sentence. If we reduced these ideas into a kind of math formula, you might say the following:</p>
<p><em>Open-ended question = A question word + a helping verb + a subject + a main verb + the rest of the sentence </em></p>
<p>We can ask open-ended questions in different tenses. For example, we could ask about the past, as in:</p>
<p><em>How did you first hear about artificial intelligence?</em></p>
<p>In this case, we changed the helping verb do into its past form, did.</p>
<p>We can also ask about the future, as in:</p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence change our lives over the next 20 years? </em></p>
<p><strong>Answers</strong></p>
<p>We have explored questions. But how can we answer such questions?</p>
<p>One way to think of your answer is in terms of good, bad, and mixed. You might use terms such as positive, negative, optimistic or pessimistic.</p>
<p>Consider this question:</p>
<p><em>What do you think of artificial intelligence? </em></p>
<p>You might have a positive opinion and say something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am optimistic about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>You might have a negative opinion and say something like this:</p>
<p><em>I am pessimistic about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>If your views go both ways, you might say:</p>
<p><em>I have mixed opinions about artificial intelligence. </em></p>
<p>Of course, after all of these answers, you should be prepared to give more details. We often use the word "because" followed by a clause – a subject and predicate group.</p>
<p>So, you might say</p>
<p><em>I am optimistic about artificial intelligence because people will be more productive with it. </em></p>
<p>Or</p>
<p><em>I am pessimistic about artificial intelligence because I think it will hurt the labor force in a powerful way. </em></p>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts </strong></p>
<p>In today's lesson, we explored a few ways to ask questions and give answers about artificial intelligence. Such discussions could take place in an everyday discussion or as part of an English test.</p>
<p>Let's end today with a homework assignment. Write an answer to the question you heard earlier in the report:</p>
<p><em>How will artificial intelligence change our lives over the next 20 years? </em></p>
<p>Before writing your answer, be sure to consider what views you have. Ask yourself if you see the future in a positive way, a negative way, or in a mixed way. Send us your answers at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>formula</strong> –n. a fact or rule that is expressed in letters, numbers and symbols</p>
<p><strong>optimistic </strong>– adj. expecting good things to happen</p>
<p><strong>pessimistic </strong>– adj. expecting bad things to happen</p>
<p><strong>predicate </strong>– n. the part of a sentence that expresses what is said about the subject</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: This Summer Has Been the Hottest on Record  (2023/9/7)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/un-this-summer-has-been-the-hottest-on-record.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">06 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The World Meteorological Organization (WMO) says Earth just had its hottest summer ever in the Northern Hemisphere.</p>
<p>Summer ends on September 22 this year in the world's northern half.</p>
<p>Last month was the hottest August ever recorded with modern equipment since 1979. It was also the second hottest month ever measured, behind only July 2023. The WMO and the European climate service Copernicus made the announcement Wednesday.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A man cools off from the intense heat in Lisbon, Portugal on Aug. 6, 2023. UN weather agency says Earth had the hottest summer ever in the northern hemisphere. (AP Photo/Armando Franca, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/017c3712-daa9-4249-8f2b-52fede75652c_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A man cools off from the intense heat in Lisbon, Portugal on Aug. 6, 2023. UN weather agency says Earth had the hottest summer ever in the northern hemisphere. (AP Photo/Armando Franca, File)</span></div>
<p>August was about 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer than pre-industrial averages. That is the limit world leaders have said the world must not pass. Scientists, however, are more concerned about temperature increases over many years and not just a few months.</p>
<p>So far, Copernicus said 2023 has been the second hottest year that it has recorded, behind only 2016. But the University of Maine's Climate Reanalyzer, a website, reported that daily September temperatures are higher than those recorded for the same period in earlier years.</p>
<p>The WMO also said the world's oceans were the hottest ever recorded at nearly 21 degrees Celsius. Water covers more than 70 percent of the Earth's surface.</p>
<p>"The dog days of summer are not just <strong>barking</strong>, they are biting," United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said in a statement. "Dog days of summer" is an expression used to describe the time of hot and humid weather during the summer. The expression might have come from ancient Greece when extreme heat was said to drive both dogs and humans insane.</p>
<p>Scientists blame the heat on the burning of coal, oil and natural gas and the added influence from El Nino for the warming climate. El Nino is a temporary warming of the southern Pacific Ocean that affects weather worldwide. The weather event changes weather around the world and even more so in its second year.</p>
<p>Climatologist Andrew Weaver was not surprised by the numbers. He said governments have not taken global warming seriously enough. He expressed concern that the public will forget the issue when temperatures fall again.</p>
<p>"It's time for global leaders to start telling the truth," said Weaver who is a professor at the School of Earth and Ocean Sciences at the University of Victoria in Canada. "We will not limit warming to 1.5 Celsius; we will not limit warming to 2.0 Celsius. It's <strong>all hands on deck</strong> now to prevent 3.0 Celsius global warming."</p>
<p>Copernicus Climate Change Service Director Carlo Buontempo said the high temperatures were "not only new extremes" but continuing "record-breaking conditions."</p>
<p>While the world's air and oceans were setting records for heat, Antarctica continued to set records for low amounts of sea ice, the WMO, the United Nations weather agency, said.</p>
<p>"Antarctic sea ice extent was literally <strong>off the charts</strong>, and the global sea surface temperature was once again at a new record," WMO's secretary-general, Petteri Taalas, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Taalas added, "It is worth noting that this is happening BEFORE we see the full warming <strong>impact</strong> of the El Nino event."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Jamey Keaten and Seth Borenstein reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bark</strong><strong> </strong><em>–v. </em>to make a short, loud noise similar to the call of a dog</p>
<p><strong>all hands on deck</strong> <em>–idiomatic expression </em>to call for everyone in a group to become involved</p>
<p><strong>off the charts </strong><em>–idiomatic expression </em>an area that has not been explored or experienced before; unknown territory</p>
<p><strong>impact </strong><em>–n</em>. the influence of something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>India Removes the Poor to Prepare for G20 Gathering  (2023/9/7) | 印度赶走穷人迎接20国集团会议</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/india-removes-the-poor-to-prepare-for-g20-gathering.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>India has changed the look of its capital, New Delhi, substantially in preparation for a meeting of international leaders this week. The two-day meeting of the Group of Twenty (G20) opens Saturday.<br/>
印度大幅改变了首都新德里的面貌，为本周举行的国际领导人会议做准备。为期两天的二十国集团会议将于周六开幕。</p>
<p>The Indian government spent about $120 million on the New Delhi project. Prime Minister Narendra Modi called it a "beautification process." But, many of the city's poor say that process destroyed homes and small businesses, leaving them displaced and without a way to make money. They say they feel erased, treated like the many dogs and m<i>onkey</i>s removed from neighborhoods in the city.<br/>
印度政府在新德里项目上花费了约1.2亿美元。总理纳伦德拉·莫迪称之为“美化过程”。但是，该市的许多穷人表示，这一过程摧毁了房屋和小企业，使他们流离失所，没有办法赚钱。他们说，他们觉得自己被抹去了，受到了像城市里许多被赶出社区的狗和猴子一样的待遇。</p>
<p>About 20 million people live in New Delhi. India's total population is 1.4 billion.<br/>
大约有2000万人生活在新德里。印度总人口为14亿。</p>
<p>Since January, hundreds of houses and small roadside businesses have been destroyed, displacing thousands of people. Dozens of poor neighborhoods called shantytowns were crushed to the ground. In many cases, residents did not receive timely warnings about the planned destruction.<br/>
自1月份以来，数百所房屋和路边小企业被毁，数千人流离失所。数十个被称为棚户区的贫困社区被夷为平地。在多数情况下，居民没有及时收到关于计划破坏的警告。</p>
<p>Officials say they carried out the demolitions against illegal properties. Rights activists and the displaced citizens say the destruction has pushed thousands more into homelessness.<br/>
官员们表示，他们对非法财产进行了拆除。人权活动人士和流离失所的公民表示，这场破坏使成千上万的人无家可归。</p>
<p>Now, New Delhi roads are newly smooth and paths are brightly lit. The city's buildings have fresh paint and colorful flowers are everywhere.<br/>
现在，新德里的道路变得更加平坦，道路上灯火通明。这座城市的建筑刷上了新油漆，到处都是五颜六色的花朵。</p>
<p>The G20 includes the world's 19 wealthiest countries and the European Union. The leaders meeting, or summit, will take place at a new conference center near the famous India Gate monument.<br/>
二十国集团包括世界上最富有的19个国家和欧盟。这场领导人会议或峰会将在著名的印度门纪念碑附近的一个新的会议中心举行。</p>
<p>Similar shantytowns were also destroyed in other Indian cities where lower-level G20 meetings are taking place.<br/>
在印度其他正举行20国集团低级别会议的城市，类似的棚户区也被摧毁。</p>
<p>In July, a report by a rights activist group found that preparations for the G20 summit resulted in the displacement of nearly 300,000 people. Many were from neighborhoods where diplomats were expected to visit for G20 events.<br/>
7月，一个维权组织的报告发现，20国集团峰会的筹备工作导致近30万人流离失所。许多人来自外交官预计将前往参加20国集团活动的社区。</p>
<p>The report also said the government destroyed at least 25 shantytowns and night shelters to establish parks in their place. And, it said the government offered no shelters for the newly homeless.<br/>
报告还说，政府摧毁了至少25个棚户区和夜间避难所，在这些地方建造公园。它还说，政府没有为这些新近无家可归的人提供容身之地。</p>
<p>Abdul Shakeel is with the activist group Save Colony Forum. He said people's lives are being destroyed to better the city's "appearance."<br/>
阿卜杜勒·沙克尔是激进组织“拯救群居地论坛”的成员。他说，人们的生活正在被破坏，以改善城市的“外貌”。</p>
<p>"The money used for G20 is taxpayers' money. Everyone pays the tax," he said, including those made homeless by the demolitions.<br/>
他说：“G20用的是纳税人的钱。每个人都要纳税。”这里面就包括那些因拆迁而无家可归的人。</p>
<p>Rekha Devi lost her home in the project. She appealed to the government to save her house. She offered to provide documents to prove that generations of her family lived in the same house for almost 100 years.<br/>
瑞卡·德维在这个项目中失去了她的家。她呼吁政府保留她的房子。她主动提出提供文件，证明她家几代人在同一所房子里住了近100年。</p>
<p>The government refused to consider the papers and destroyed Devi's home.<br/>
政府拒绝考虑这些文件，并摧毁了德维的家。</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.<br/>
我是吉娜·贝内特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Artists Fight Back against AI Using Their Work  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/artists-fight-back-against-ai-using-their-work.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Kelly McKernan's paintings are often striking images of female figures in bright colors of green, blue, pink or purple.</p>
<p>The 37-year-old artist from Nashville, Tennessee calls her works "<strong>surreal</strong>." She says they are "dealing with <strong>discomfort</strong> in the human journey."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Refik Anadol's Unsupervised exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, Wednesday, Jan. 11, 2023, in New York. The new AI-generated installation is meant to be a thought-provoking interpretation of New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/800f0000-c0a8-0242-14b2-08dafd6113b3_cx7_cy17_cw87_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Refik Anadol's "Unsupervised" exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, Wednesday, Jan. 11, 2023, in New York. The new AI-generated installation is meant to be a thought-provoking interpretation of New York. (AP Photo/John Minchillo)</span></div>
<p>Surviving as an artist is difficult enough. The pandemic made it worse. But now McKernan faces another threat: artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<p>McKernan uses the pronoun they instead of his or her to call themself. About a year ago, McKernan began seeing online images strangely similar to their own. They soon learned that companies were feeding artwork into AI systems to train software programs to create similar images.</p>
<p>McKernan told the Associated Press, "I didn't give my <strong>consent </strong>for my name or work to be used this way."</p>
<p>McKernan said they even tried to contact some of the companies to say "Hey, little artist here, I know you're not thinking of me at all, but it would be really <strong>cool</strong> if you didn't use my work like this." But there was no answer.</p>
<p>In January, McKernan, and two other artists, Karla Ortiz and Sarah Andersen, started legal action against three image-<strong>generator</strong> companies: Stability AI, Stable Diffusion and Midjourney. They also named the online gallery DeviantArt in the case.</p>
<p>The artists are seeking to protect their <strong>copyrighted</strong> works and their careers. They say the AI image-generators violate the rights of millions of artists by using their artworks for training and then producing similar works that compete against the <strong>originals</strong>.</p>
<p>The artists are seeking damages and a court order to stop AI companies from using their works without permission.</p>
<p>McKernan said, "At the end of the day, someone's profiting from my work. I had <strong>rent</strong> due yesterday, and I'm $200 short... And it just doesn't feel right."</p>
<p>Stability AI would not comment to the <em>Associated Press </em>(<em>AP</em>) for the story. In a court document, the company said it uses simple words to create "new and <strong>unique</strong> images." The company added the program creates new works and does not violate copyright.</p>
<p>A Stability AI company official appeared before a U.S. Senate hearing in July. He said that artists are not paid for the images used to train AI software.</p>
<p>Midjourney and DeviantArt did not return emailed requests for comment.</p>
<p>Karla Ortiz works in the entertainment industry. Her work has been used in several well-known movies, including <em>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</em> and<em> Jurassic World</em>.</p>
<p>She feared that companies would think artists cost too much. Why, she asked, would companies employ artists if they can pay $30 a month for AI-generated works?</p>
<p>McKernan agreed: "Will I even have work a year from now?"</p>
<p>A federal judge in San Francisco will decide the case.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in a temporary win for human artists last month, another federal judge agreed with the decision by the U.S. Copyright Office not to issue copyright for AI-generated artwork.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett adapted this report for VOA Learning English from The Associated Press news report.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surreal </strong>– adj. like a dream, not real</p>
<p><strong>discomfort</strong> – n. a little unease or pain</p>
<p><strong>consent </strong>– v. permission</p>
<p><strong>cool</strong> – adj. pleasing, desired</p>
<p><strong>generator</strong> – n. something that creates or produces</p>
<p><strong>copyright</strong> – n. if something like a piece of art, music, or book has a copyright, it is illegal to produce, copy, or use it without permission</p>
<p><strong>original</strong> – n. not a copy; the first</p>
<p><strong>rent</strong> – n. money paid to live in a house or apartment</p>
<p><strong>unique</strong> – adj. different from everything else; the only one of its kind</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>TV Show Explores Teaching at an Urban Public School  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/tv-show-explores-teaching-at-an-urban-public-school.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>An American TV show called <em>Abbott Elementary</em> is a <strong>comedy</strong> about teachers in a Philadelphia elementary school.</p>
<p>The show has been praised for being funny, <strong>smart</strong> and heartwarming and for dealing with important education issues. Over two seasons of 35 <strong>episodes</strong>, the show has explored education issues like school budgets, <strong>charter schools</strong> and teacher mental health.</p>
<p>The show is on ABC, one of the biggest American television networks. The show is being aired at a time of teacher shortages and debates about how race issues and history should be taught.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Quinta Brunson plays second-grade teacher Janine on ABC's Abbott Elementary (ABC/Gilles Mingasson)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ddba-08db8c806273_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Quinta Brunson plays second-grade teacher Janine on ABC's Abbott Elementary (ABC/Gilles Mingasson)</span></div>
<p>The creator and star of the show is Quinta Brunson. Brunson's mother was a public school teacher in Philadelphia. Brunson plays a young, second-grade teacher named Janine at Abbott Elementary. The show follows several other teachers at Abbott, which is a badly supervised and majority-Black school that does not have enough money. Although the teachers often run into trouble with students and the administration, they care about their jobs and try to help their students.</p>
<p>Brunson said in an interview with <em>Education Week</em> that two writers on the show are former teachers. She said she wanted all the writers to have "a healthy relationship to education."</p>
<p>She added that since the COVID-19 pandemic, education has been a subject on the minds of everyone.</p>
<p>"Three years ago, no one was talking about teachers as much as they are now," Brunson said. "And now, everywhere we look, we're talking about education...I hope that it leads us into a better place in this country with our treatment of education, specifically public education."</p>
<p>Sara Jones is a professor of elementary education at Illinois State University. Next spring, she will be teaching a class on <em>Abbott Elementary</em>. At each class, students will watch an episode of the show then discuss an issue related to urban education that appeared in that episode. The class will also read related research papers from education experts.</p>
<p>Jones is a former elementary school teacher and has researched urban education. She said the show covers many issues that come up in her research like teacher shortages, teacher training and unfair use of public money.</p>
<p>"I immediately fell in love with the <strong>characters</strong> and the storytelling and that connection to my own teaching experience," Jones told VOA.</p>
<p>The class is part of the university's honors program instead of the education school, so it will have students from different areas of study. Jones added that the show is funny and interesting but deals with issues in a simple way that people who are not involved in education can understand.</p>
<p>A repeated issue in the show's second season is the charter school movement. Charter schools receive public money but operate outside the public school system. Charter schools also receive private money. Businessmen like Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg and former Microsoft chief Bill Gates have invested money in some charter schools. In <em>Abbott</em>, a group called Legendary Charter schools threatens to turn every public school in Philadelphia into a charter school.</p>
<p>Charter schools do not have the same operating requirements as local government-operated public schools. Critics argue that charter schools receive local tax money that could go to traditional public schools.</p>
<p>In one episode, the teachers discuss the threat of Legendary charter schools. One of the older teachers, Barbara, says, charters "take our funding. Not to mention the private money from wealthy donors with <strong>ulterior</strong> <strong>motives</strong>."</p>
<p>But the principal, Ava, who is often portrayed as foolish says, "<strong>Weird</strong> cash swirling around? Don't threaten me with a good time."</p>
<p>Jones said the story explores urban school issues better than most shows on television, including the news media.</p>
<p>"I hope students will get from (this class) a deeper understanding of those issues and perhaps a shift in <strong>perspective</strong> about particularly urban schools."</p>
<p>Brunson said she hopes people who watch the show will be more likely to support schools and teachers.</p>
<p>"It's a public service," Brunson said of teaching. "Who are we without teachers? Who are we without the people who teach us how to read?"</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>comedy</strong><strong> </strong><em>— n. </em>a kind of performance meant to make people laugh</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>smart </strong><em>–adj.</em> showing a sharp mind or clever way of looking at things</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>episode </strong><em>–n</em>. one in a series of television or radio shows</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>charter school </strong>–n. a school established under a charter (legal agreement) that is not part of the local government, but receives some public tax money as called for by local law</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>character </strong>–n. a person in a television show, play or other performance</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ulterior motive </strong>–n. an addition reason that something is done that is usually hidden</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>weird</strong><strong> </strong><em>— adj. </em>unusual or strange</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>perspective </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of looking at an issue as it relates to other things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>West Point Time Capsule Contains More Than Just Dirt  (2023/9/6) | 西点军校直播打开近200年历史的时光胶囊</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/west-point-time-capsule-contains-more-than-just-dirt.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Officials at the U.S. Military Academy West Point in New York state recently opened a time capsule that is 195 years old live on the internet.<br/>
纽约州西点军校官员最近通过网上直播打开了一个有195年历史的时间胶囊。</p>
<p>The event on August 28 caused disappointment because the container appeared to contain nothing more than dirt. But West Point officials said last Wednesday that the box did contain hidden treasure after all.<br/>
8月28日的这次活动让人们失望，因为盒子里似乎除了泥土什么都没有。但西点军校官员上周三表示，这个盒子里确实藏着宝藏。</p>
<p>A time capsule is a container that is filled with objects and buried or hidden. The capsule is meant to be opened by people living many years in the future.<br/>
时间胶囊是指装满物体并被掩埋或藏起来的容器。这个容器将被生活在多年之后的人们打开。</p>
<p>The lead box is believed to have been put in place by West Point military students. It was discovered inside the base of a memorial to Revolutionary War hero Thaddeus Kosciuszko.<br/>
据信，这个铅盒是西点军校学生放置的。它是在独立战争英雄撒迪乌斯·科希丘什科纪念碑的基座内发现的。</p>
<p>The capsule contained six silver American coins dating from 1795 and 1828 and a medal, West Point said in a news release. The ceremonial opening of the box happened at the military school in New York state.<br/>
西点军校在一份新闻稿中表示，这个容器内装有六枚1795年至1828年的美国银币和一枚奖章。开箱仪式在这所位于纽约州的军校举行。</p>
<p>Speaking of the event, West Point archeologist Paul Hudson said: "When I first found these, I thought, man, you know, it would have been great to have found these on stage." After the opening, he took the box back to his laboratory and began carefully looking through the remains.<br/>
西点军校考古学家保罗·哈德森在谈到这次活动时表示：“当我找到这些东西时，我想，要是能在台上（直播时）发现它们就好了。”打开盒子后，他把盒子带回了实验室，然后开始仔细查看残留物。</p>
<p>He said he then found the edge of a coin in the dust inside the box. "I thought, well that's OK. That's something, that's a start," Hudson said.<br/>
他称自己随后在盒子里的灰尘中发现了一枚硬币的边缘。哈德森说：“我想，好吧，没关系。这是一个开始。”。</p>
<p>He said he felt let down like everyone else by the lack of results from the live opening. The crowd that gathered at the U.S. Military Academy hoped to see historical military objects or documents when experts opened the top and pointed a camera inside.<br/>
他说，对于在直播打开时没有发现，他和其他人一样感到失望。聚集在这所美国军事学院的人群希望在专家打开盒盖并将相机对准内部时能够看到历史军事物品或文件。</p>
<p>It was probably better to remove the coins and medal in a controlled setting, added Hudson. He still plans to study the remains for possible answers to what else might be inside.<br/>
哈德森补充道，最好在可控的环境中移去硬币和奖牌。他仍然计划研究这些残留物，以期找到答案，弄清楚里面可能还有什么。</p>
<p>It appears that moisture and possibly dirt entered the box through a damaged edge. The conditions could have destroyed materials like paper or wood.<br/>
看上去水汽和泥土是通过损坏的边缘进入了盒子。这种情况可能会破坏纸张或木材等材料。</p>
<p>What did survive was a five-cent coin from the year 1795, an 1800 Liberty Dollar, an 1818 25-cent coin, 10-cent, and 1-cent coins from 1827, and an 1828 50-cent coin. There was also a medal remembering the Erie Canal from 1826.<br/>
残留下来的是一枚1795年的5美分硬币、一枚1800年的自由银币、一枚1818年的25美分硬币、1827年的10美分硬币和1美分硬币各一枚，以及一枚1828年的50美分硬币。还有一枚纪念1826年伊利运河的奖章。</p>
<p>The discoveries seem to confirm school officials' theory that the box was put in place by military students in 1828 or 1829. The monument to Kosciuszko, which included a statue of him, was completed at about that time.<br/>
这些发现似乎证实了学校官员推测的盒子是1828年或1829年由军校学生安放的。科希丘什科纪念碑，包括他的雕像，大约是在那个时候造好的。</p>
<p>A group of five military students, or cadets, was involved in the ceremony dedicating the monument. One of them was U.S. Civil War general Robert E. Lee who graduated in 1829.<br/>
一个由五名军校学员组成的小组参与了纪念碑的落成仪式。其中一位是1829年毕业的美国内战将领罗伯特·E·李。</p>
<p>Kosciuszko had designed wartime fortifications for the Continental Army at West Point during the Revolutionary War. He died in 1817. The statue of Kosciuszko was added to the monument in 1913.<br/>
科希丘什科在独立战争期间为大陆军在西点军校设计了战时防御工事。他于1817年去世。科希丘什科的雕像于1913年被添加到纪念碑中。</p>
<p>The historical preservation and research of the time capsule will continue.<br/>
对时间胶囊的历史保存和分析将继续进行。</p>
<p>"I think there's more that we can learn from this," Hudson said.<br/>
哈德森说：“我认为我们可以从中学到更多东西。”</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Extends Protection for Migrants from Six Countries  (2023/9/6)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/us-extends-protection-for-migrants-from-six-countries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">05 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>The administration of U.S. President Joe Biden recently announced it is extending temporary protection from <strong>deportation</strong> to migrants from six countries.</p>
<p>Nationals of Sudan, Ukraine, El Salvador, Honduras, Nepal and Nicaragua can remain in the United States under the extended policy.</p>
<p>The Temporary Protected Status (TPS) program permits migrants, whose home countries are considered unsafe, to live and work in the United States. They can do so under the program although they do not have normal legal permission to be in the country. However, they can only be in the U.S. for a set period of time, and they must meet U.S. government requirements.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Demonstrators participate in the March for TPS (Temporary Protected Status) Justice during a protest in support of permanent residency, outside the White House in Washington, Feb. 12, 2019. (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01460000-0aff-0242-4fb4-08da65d00dde_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Demonstrators participate in the March for TPS (Temporary Protected Status) Justice during a protest in support of permanent residency, outside the White House in Washington, Feb. 12, 2019. (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP)</span></div>
<p>Daniel Costa is director of immigration law and policy research at the Economic Policy Institute, an organization based in Washington, D.C. Costa said current TPS holders have high employment rates and add billions of dollars to the U.S. economy every year.</p>
<p>"TPS raises <strong>wages</strong> through...work <strong>authorization</strong> for people who don't have it...Higher wages also mean more spending back in the economy, which creates more jobs," he said.</p>
<p>The United States first gave Honduras, Nicaragua and El Salvador Temporary Protected Status more than 20 years ago. When the Biden administration extended TPS for those countries in June, it was for people who were current TPS holders.</p>
<p>If the Biden administration again gives those countries temporary protected status, it would expand TPS for many people. It would permit any qualifying migrant who entered the U.S. during the last 20 years to receive TPS.</p>
<p>A <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.niskanencenter.org/the-value-of-temporary-protected-status-as-a-u-s-policy-tool/" target="_blank">report by the Niskanen Center</a>, a Washington-based policy research organization, said the "<strong>vast</strong> majority" of TPS holders are employed.</p>
<p>"More than 94 percent of TPS holders were in the labor force as of 2017," the report stated. It said that they worked in industries including sales and health care. The 2017 report warned that ending TPS for just El Salvador, Honduras, and Haiti would cause the U.S. economy to lose over $160 billion over 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Adding new countries</strong></p>
<p>Immigrant organizations have called for the U.S. to give new TPS <strong>designations</strong>. They hope the government will add Mauritania and the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) to the program.</p>
<p>Nils Kinuani is the immigration coordinator for the Congolese Community of Washington Metropolitan. He told VOA the group had conversations with U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) officials in April.</p>
<p>"We have been also working with congressional leaders to push for this designation," Kinuani said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State says the DRC is suffering a humanitarian crisis marked by over 20 years of civil war and conflict.</p>
<p>Leaders of Black Mauritanians say the U.S. had an earlier policy of not deporting Mauritanians because of the country's human-rights record. Haddy Gassama is with the organization UndocuBlack Network. She wrote that the abuses "include the practice of enslaving Black people" and keeping a system of apartheid.</p>
<p>Apartheid is a political system of racial separation.</p>
<p>In January, Democratic Senator Sherrod Brown and Republican Representative Mike Carey sent a letter to Biden and other government officials to support TPS for Mauritanians living in the U.S. without legal permission.</p>
<p>Congress established TPS in 1990. Currently, 16 countries are <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.uscis.gov/humanitarian/temporary-protected-status" target="_blank">designated for the program</a>.</p>
<p>Current TPS holders who want to extend their protection must register again during the 60-day registration period for their country's designation. Re-registration opens soon for four countries, starting with El Salvador on September 10.</p>
<p>TPS designations are set for six, 12, or 18 months. About two months before a country's TPS ends, the DHS secretary has to decide if the U.S. will end or extend the TPS.</p>
<p>The TPS program does not lead to permanent U.S. <strong>residency</strong>. As of March, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/homesec/RS20844.pdf" target="_blank">about 610,000 foreign nationals</a> held temporary protected status.</p>
<p>TPS holders who leave the U.S. without first getting a travel authorization may lose their TPS status and may not reenter the country.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Aline Barros wrote this story for Voice of America. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>deportation </strong><em>–n.</em> the process of legally removing someone from a country who is not permitted by law to be in that country</p>
<p><strong>wages </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> money paid to a worker in exchange for the amount of time they worked</p>
<p><strong>authorization </strong><em>–n.</em> official permission to do, have or act as something</p>
<p><strong>vast </strong><em>–adj.</em> very large in size or extent</p>
<p><strong>designation </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of officially naming or choosing someone or something; the state of being named to a position or status under the law</p>
<p><strong>residency </strong><em>–n.</em> the status of legally being permitted to live in a place</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists: Maine’s Puffin Bird Population Is Recovering  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/scientists-maine-s-puffin-bird-population-is-recovering.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Scientists studying the Atlantic puffin population off the coast of Maine say the birds are now recovering after suffering major losses in 2021.</p>
<p>Atlantic puffins look and walk similarly to penguins. Wildlife officials say reproductions for the animals on islands off the coast of Maine fell sharply in 2021. But last year, about two-thirds of puffins in the area produced young. While the numbers did not reach that same level this year, the birds still had a better year than in 2021.</p>
<p>The main reason for the decreasing numbers is a drop in the population of small fish puffins feed on, such as herring. Two years ago, puffin colonies suffered one of the lowest reproduction rates in many years because of a lack of those fish. Only about one-quarter of the birds were able to raise young in 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="An Atlantic puffin brings a beak full of baitfish to feed its chick in a burrow under rocks on a small island off mid-coast Maine, Sunday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-352d-08dbaa2a9377_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">An Atlantic puffin brings a beak full of baitfish to feed its chick in a burrow under rocks on a small island off mid-coast Maine, Sunday, Aug. 5, 2023. (AP Photo/Robert F. Bukaty)</span></div>
<p>Environmental groups have linked the lower fish populations in the area to warming ocean temperatures. The Gulf of Maine, which has puffin colonies on its islands, is warming faster than most of the world's oceans. Some recent years have been especially warm and local climate officials have said this summer appears to have been "still unusually warm."</p>
<p>Bill Sydeman is the president and chief scientist at the Farallon Institute, a <strong>conservation</strong> organization based in California. He told The Associated Press the reasons for the puffin population drop include deadly heat waves, loss of food, loss of islands to sea level rise and an inability to reproduce, or breed.</p>
<p>"The problem with climate change is these breeding failures and low breeding productivity years are now becoming <strong>chronic</strong>," Sydeman said. "There will be fewer young birds in the population that are able to <strong>recruit</strong> into the breeding population."</p>
<p>Maine's puffins are the only breeding Atlantic puffins in the United States. Worldwide, the species lives in the North Atlantic from Maine and Canada to Europe. Other countries with large puffin populations, such as Iceland, have also seen their bird populations drop.</p>
<p>The Maine puffin population once fell to only about 70 pairs in an area known as Matinicus Rock. Hunters who went after the birds for their meat and feathers had nearly destroyed them by the early 1900s. Stephen Kress is a scientist with the Audubon Society who has sought to grow puffin colonies since the 1970s. His attempts included moving young puffins from Canada to Eastern Egg Rock, another small island in the area.</p>
<p>Wildlife officials say adult birds in the colonies appear fairly strong, and it's "likely the population is stable, and it could still be growing," said Don Lyons. He is the director of conservation science at the National Audubon Society's Seabird Institute in Bremen, Maine.</p>
<p>The difficulties facing seabirds make successful breeding seasons especially important, said P. Dee Boersma. She is a University of Washington professor of biology and director of the university's Center for Ecosystem Sentinels.</p>
<p>"What that means is we should be more <strong>cautious</strong> and concerned about reproductive failures and things like that to make sure that in good years everyone that wants to has a chance to breed, and do well," Boersma said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>______________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>conservation </strong><em>– n. </em>an organized effort that aims to protect animals, and natural resources</p>
<p><strong>chronic </strong><em>– adj. </em>something that continues for a long time</p>
<p><strong>recruit </strong><em>– v. </em>to try to persuade someone to work for a company or to join an organization</p>
<p><strong>cautious </strong><em>– adj. </em>taking care to avoid risks or danger</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Whole Genome Testing Finds Diseases Better in Children  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/study-whole-genome-testing-finds-diseases-better-in-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Brynn Schulte nearly died two times when she was a baby. At one point she needed emergency <strong>surgery</strong> for bleeding in her brain.</p>
<p>No one knew what was wrong. Then, a test that looked at her full genetic details found a rare bleeding disorder. Catching the disorder early saved her life.</p>
<p>"You have this hopeless feeling when you don't really know what's going on," said her father, Mike Schulte. He noted that the test made a difference in finding the cause and "getting her the right care that she needed almost immediately."</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Courtney Chase, a nurse at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, listens to 4-year-old Brynn Schulte's heart before the girl gets an infusion of medication to treat a rare genetic bleeding disorder, Aug. 3, 2023, in Cincinnati, Ohio. (AP Photo/Laura Ungar)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/39dbaf16-ac54-4538-8791-dd63710aaa49_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Courtney Chase, a nurse at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, listens to 4-year-old Brynn Schulte's heart before the girl gets an infusion of medication to treat a rare genetic bleeding disorder, Aug. 3, 2023, in Cincinnati, Ohio. (AP Photo/Laura Ungar)</span></div>
<p>Brynn, now 4, got the genetic testing as part of a <strong>clinical </strong>trial. The results of which were published recently in <em>The Journal of the American Medical Association</em>.</p>
<p>Testing all of the details of a person's genes is called "whole genome" testing. Whole genome tests are much better than narrowly targeted tests when it comes to finding genetic differences, called abnormalities, that can cause disease.</p>
<p>The study found 49 percent of these abnormalities, compared to 27 percent with more commonly used tests targeting only some genetic diseases.</p>
<p>Whole genome tests could solve the problem of doing several narrowly targeted tests on babies, which still might not find the disorder. Experts warn there are some problems because labs vary in how they understand results. Also, whole genome tests are costlier and less likely to be covered by <strong>insurance</strong>.</p>
<p>But researchers hope that whole genome tests will at some point be used for millions of hospitalized babies with rare and difficult conditions. The U.S. National Human Genome Research Institute has found that around 350 million people around the world live with rare disorders. And it found that about 80 percent of the more than 7,000 conditions are genetic.</p>
<p>"I've been doing clinical trials of babies for over 40 years," said study writer Dr. Jon Davis, chief of newborn medicine at Tufts Medical Center in Boston. "It's not often that you can do something that you feel is going to really change the world and change clinical practice for everyone."</p>
<p><strong>No one was sure about Brynn's condition</strong></p>
<p>The night Brynn was born, she had difficulty breathing. There was also some bleeding in her brain. So, doctors gave her blood <strong>transfusions</strong> and tests for different bleeding problems. When Brynn was a month old, she had surgery after a huge brain bleed.</p>
<p>Her mother Lindsay Schulte said no one was sure about her condition. "I don't think we slept. I mean, watching your child nearly die in front of your eyes <strong>twice</strong> is a memory I'll never <strong>erase</strong>," she said.</p>
<p>Then the Schulte family learned about the clinical trial. Brynn and both parents got the whole genome testing. The results came in less than a week later: She had a rare bleeding disorder. It affects an estimated 1 in 2 million to 1 in 3 million live births. She also had another condition that caused a severe reaction to some drugs.</p>
<p>Doctors said the correct results would likely have taken more time or even missed with several narrow, targeted tests.</p>
<p>That is because targeted tests cover maybe 1,700 out of 20,000 genes. But whole genome testing "captures more things," said Dr. Paul Kruszka of GeneDx. It is a company that provides whole genome testing but was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>Dr. Jill Maron is a study writer and a chief of children's medicine at Women &amp; Infants Hospital in Rhode Island. She said full genome tests generally cost about three times more than narrow tests and are not covered by public insurance in most U.S. states.</p>
<p>Experts like her say that greater <strong>access</strong> to full genome tests is necessary if more children are going to be helped.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for the Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted the story for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>surgery </strong><em>– n.</em> medical treatment in which a doctor cuts into someone's body in order to repair or remove damaged or diseased parts</p>
<p><strong>clinical </strong><em>– adj.</em> relating to or based on work done with real patients: of or relating to the medical treatment that is given to patients in hospitals or clinics</p>
<p><strong>insurance</strong> –<strong><em> </em></strong><em>n.</em> an agreement in which a person makes regular payments to a company and the company promises to pay money if the person is injured or dies, or to pay money equal to the value of something (such as a house or car) if it is damaged, lost, or stolen</p>
<p><strong>transfusion </strong><em>– n.</em> a medical treatment in which someone's blood is put into the body of another person</p>
<p><strong>twice </strong><em>– adv.</em> two times</p>
<p><strong>erase </strong><em>– v.</em> to remove any thought or memory of (something)</p>
<p><strong>access </strong><em>– n.</em> a way of being able to use or get something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>London Artist Paints Crushed Chewing Gum  (2023/9/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202309/london-artist-paints-crushed-chewing-gum.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 September 2023</span><br/>
<p>Lying on London's famous Millennium Bridge, British artist Ben Wilson paints on a piece of dried <strong>gum</strong>. It has been crushed flat into the ground.</p>
<p>"The important thing is the gum is below the metal<strong> tread</strong>," said the 60-year-old Wilson. "The beauty of it is they're all different shapes and sizes...," he continued, describing pieces of gum.</p>
<p>Wilson sees possibility in things most people avoid looking at. The flattened gum is a chance to turn a piece of waste into something beautiful.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ben Wilson, artist, paints on the Millennium Bridge, London, Britain, August 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Anna Gordon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/331959f3-3b17-4880-b14c-138894efe4a5_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ben Wilson, artist, paints on the Millennium Bridge, London, Britain, August 21, 2023. (REUTERS/Anna Gordon)</span></div>
<p>The artwork also is a way to surprise walkers and get them to take a closer look at the path they are on.</p>
<p>"By painting a picture which is so small, those that see it then discover a hidden world beneath their feet," Wilson said.</p>
<p>Back in his north London art room, Wilson paints on the surface of a small <strong>mosaic tile</strong>. It will be part of a collection that he is creating on the walls of London's Underground train platforms. The images are more personal than the chewing gum works, Wilson says, and represent a kind of "visual <strong>diary</strong>."</p>
<p>"The pictures are a celebration of my life and those that I care dearly about," he said. "They are a process of visual inquiry - trying to make sense of the world," he added.</p>
<p>Wilson was born in London to artist parents. He remembers working with <strong>clay</strong> from the age of three. He had his first art show when he was around 10 or 11 years old.</p>
<p>He began making sculptures and large pieces for display in nature settings. Then his interest turned to waste, also called trash. He has been painting gum and other pieces of trash for 19 years.</p>
<p>The top surface of the dried gum is not subject to local or national laws. As a result, the dried gum surface creates a space where Wilson says he can paint without damaging public property.</p>
<p>"I found this little space where I could create a form of art where I could be <strong>spontaneous</strong> and do something which evolves out of the place in which it's created," Wilson said.</p>
<p>Government officials have removed much of the artist's public street art. But the hundreds of gum paintings on Millennium Bridge remain for all to see.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Lucy Marks reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>gum</strong> –<em> n.</em> a type of soft candy that you chew on but do not swallow</p>
<p><strong>tread </strong><em>– n.</em> the raised surface that people walk on</p>
<p><strong>mosaic </strong><em>– n</em>. a decoration made by pressing small pieces of colored glass or stone into a soft material that then hardens</p>
<p><strong>tile</strong><em> – n</em>. a usually flat piece of hard clay or other material that is used for covering walls or floors</p>
<p><strong>diary</strong> –<em> n.</em> a book in which you write down your personal experiences and thoughts each day</p>
<p><strong>clay</strong> <em>– n.</em> a heavy, sticky material from the earth that is made into different shapes and that becomes hard when it is baked or dried</p>
<p><strong>spontaneous</strong> <em>– adj.</em> created in a natural and often sudden way</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
