<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Why Is Elon Musk Bringing Legal Action Against OpenAI?  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/why-is-elon-musk-bringing-legal-action-against-openai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Business leader Elon Musk is bringing a legal case against artificial intelligence (AI) company OpenAI and its chief Sam Altman.</p>
<p>Musk is chief of carmaker Tesla and SpaceX and also leads the social media service X. He said OpenAI is <strong>betraying</strong> its founder's aims by seeking to increase profits rather than helping the world.</p>
<p>Musk brought the legal action in San Francisco Superior Court. He said that, at first, he financially supported OpenAI, the maker of the AI tool ChatGPT. He said he had an agreement with Altman and Greg Brockman, the president. That agreement was to keep the artificial intelligence company as a nonprofit organization. Musk said the goal was to develop technology that would help the public.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Elon Musk addresses the European Jewish Association's conference, in Krakow, Poland, Monday, Jan. 22, 2024. Musk is suing OpenAI and its CEO Sam Altman over what he says is a betrayal of the ChatGPT maker's founding aims. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/46837636-89ef-493b-8889-928c9e067b1b_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Elon Musk addresses the European Jewish Association's conference, in Krakow, Poland, Monday, Jan. 22, 2024. Musk is suing OpenAI and its CEO Sam Altman over what he says is a betrayal of the ChatGPT maker's founding aims. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski, File)</span></div>
<p>Under its founding agreement, OpenAI would also make its <strong>code</strong> open to the public instead of making it the company's private property, the <strong>lawsuit</strong> says. Musk claims in the lawsuit that OpenAI went against the agreement by having a close relationship with Microsoft.</p>
<p>OpenAI did not comment on the lawsuit last week.</p>
<p>Musk's lawsuit says OpenAI broke a contract, failed in its financial responsibility, and used unfair business methods. Musk also wants to prevent anyone, including Microsoft, from profiting from OpenAI's technology.</p>
<p><strong>Musk was early supporter of OpenAI</strong></p>
<p>Anupam Chander is a law professor at Georgetown University in Washington, D.C. He said Musk's claims are unlikely to succeed in court. However, he said that might not be the point for Musk, who is getting his personal story on the record.</p>
<p>Chander said Musk claims he named OpenAI, employed an important scientist, and that he was the main financial supporter in its early years. He said, "In some sense, it's a lawsuit that tries to establish his own place in the history of <strong>generative</strong> AI."</p>
<p>Musk was an early investor in OpenAI when it was founded in 2015. He was a leader in the company alongside Altman. In the lawsuit, he said he invested "tens of millions" of dollars in the nonprofit research laboratory.</p>
<p>Musk left the company in early 2018 in a move that OpenAI said at the time would prevent conflicts of interest. Musk's Tesla car company was looking for people in AI to help develop self-driving car technology.</p>
<p>Musk has since said he disagreed with the company's direction but continued to give money to the nonprofit.</p>
<p>Later, OpenAI created a for-profit arm and began moving most of its workforce to that business. But it kept its nonprofit board of directors that oversaw the company.</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft investment</strong></p>
<p>Microsoft made its first $1 billion investment in the company in 2019. The next year Microsoft signed an agreement with OpenAI giving Microsoft the rights to OpenAI's AI models. That agreement is supposed to end once OpenAI has created artificial general intelligence (AGI), the company has said.</p>
<p>AGI is a sort of artificial intelligence that can perform just as well or even better than humans in different kinds of work.</p>
<p>The nonprofit board of directors fired Altman as chief executive officer late last year. But Microsoft helped bring Altman back and pushed most of the old board of directors to leave.</p>
<p>Musk's lawsuit claims that those changes caused the balance of power protecting the nonprofit aim of the company to "collapse overnight." One of Musk's claims is that the directors of the nonprofit have failed in their duty to support its nonprofit aim.</p>
<p>Dana Brakman Reiser is a professor at Brooklyn Law School. She questions whether Musk has standing, or a connection to the case, that a court would uphold.</p>
<p>She said it would be a problem if every person who cared about or gave money to a nonprofit group could bring a lawsuit against its leaders and officers. She said only other directors, or a government legal official could bring that sort of lawsuit.</p>
<p>Musk now has his own AI company. But his legal case against Altman could inform the public about private talks and decision-making that took place at OpenAI. The company's lawyers will likely fight to keep some of those documents from being released.</p>
<p>Investor Chamath Palihapitiya wrote on X, Musk's social media service: "The discovery will be <strong>epic</strong>." Discovery is the process by which lawyers request documents related to a legal case. Musk answered in his only public comments on the case so far: "Yes."</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan, Thalia Beaty, and Matt O'Brien reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>betray </strong><em>– v. </em>to ignore your principles or beliefs in order to achieve something or gain an advantage for yourself</p>
<p><strong>lawsuit </strong><em>– n. </em>a claim or complaint against somebody that a person or an organization can make in court</p>
<p><strong>code </strong><em>– n. </em>a system of computer programming instructions</p>
<p><strong>generate </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce or create something</p>
<p><strong>epic </strong><em>– adj.</em> very great or large and usually difficult or impressive</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Electrical Device in Brain Might Help with Depression  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/electrical-device-in-brain-might-help-with-depression.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Deep brain stimulation, or DBS, is an experimental treatment that involves having an electrical device placed in the brain.</p>
<p>The treatment gives patients' brains targeted electrical <strong>impulses</strong>.</p>
<p>Researchers say DBS could help some of the nearly 3 million Americans with depression that resists other treatments. It is approved for conditions like Parkinson's disease and epilepsy. Many doctors and patients hope it will become more widely available for depression.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Emily Hollenbeck stands for a portrait at the American Museum of Natural History's Rose Center in New York on Jan. 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Mary Conlon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/79c7f011-4328-4f7b-b8c9-ba767241aa2d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Emily Hollenbeck stands for a portrait at the American Museum of Natural History's Rose Center in New York on Jan. 12, 2024. (AP Photo/Mary Conlon)</span></div>
<p>Recent research suggests gains are possible and more research is planned. However, two earlier studies showed no gains using DBS for depression. Those results have slowed the treatment that involves a brain operation. Some scientists continue to raise concerns about DBS.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has agreed to speed up its study of Abbott Laboratories' request to use its DBS devices for treatment-resistant depression.</p>
<p><strong>"Nothing else was working"</strong></p>
<p>Emily Hollenbeck lived with severe depression. She compared it to a black hole. She felt as though her arms and legs could barely move. She knew both of her parents had taken their lives and that her condition was dangerous.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck, who grew up poor and sometimes homeless, suffered from signs of depression as a child. In college, after her father's suicide in 2009, she had her first period of major depression. Another happened while she was working. She was concerned she would lose her teaching job and become poor again. She went to the hospital.</p>
<p>"I ended up having sort of an on-and-off <strong>pattern</strong>," she said. Medication helped her for a while.</p>
<p>She was able to earn a doctoral degree in <strong>psychology</strong> although she lost her mom in her final year of graduate school. But the depression stayed with her. At times, she said, she thought about ending her life.</p>
<p>She was willing to try something extreme.</p>
<p>Her doctor then told her about DBS three years ago.</p>
<p>"Nothing else was working," she said.</p>
<p>She became one of a few hundred people to have her depression treated with DBS.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck is part of ongoing research at Mount Sinai West medical center in New York City. Her brain operation took place while she was <strong>sedated</strong> but still awake. Dr. Brian Kopell directs Mount Sinai's Center for Neuromodulation. He placed thin metal <strong>electrodes</strong> in the part of her brain believed to control emotional behavior and is thought to be involved in feelings of sadness.</p>
<p>The thin metal electrodes are connected by wires to a device placed under the skin of her <strong>chest</strong>. The device controls the electrical impulses sending current to her brain.</p>
<p>Doctors involved in DBS say the impulses help because the brain uses electricity to send signals.</p>
<p>In normal brains, Kopell said, electrical activity spreads through the brain unblocked to all areas. In depression, he said, the brain's emotional signals get blocked. He compared the problem to dancing. He said DBS seems to "unstick the circuit," permitting the brain to do what it normally would. A circuit is the path unblocked electrical current takes.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck said the effect on her was almost immediate.</p>
<p>"The first day after surgery, she started feeling a lifting of that <strong>negative</strong> mood, of the heaviness," said her <strong>psychiatrist</strong>, Dr. Martijn Figee.</p>
<p>For Hollenbeck, the biggest change was finding pleasure in music again.</p>
<p>She wishes her treatment had been available for her parents.</p>
<p><strong>The treatment's history</strong></p>
<p>DBS research has continued for at least 20 years. Brain expert Dr. Helen Mayberg led early research that was called promising. But large studies launched more than 12 years ago saw no difference in treated and untreated groups.</p>
<p>Dr. Katherine Scangos is a <strong>psychiatrist</strong> at the University of California, San Francisco. She is also researching DBS and depression. She said there could be two reasons for the major studies showing no effect.</p>
<p>She said one reason was that the treatment was not "personalized" for each individual in the two studies. The second was that researchers looked at outcomes over just a few weeks.</p>
<p>Recent research has shown more promising results for depression. A 2022 study said that on average 60 percent of depression patients showed improvement with DBS. A study from 2023 said that after six months of targeted DBS treatment, 90 percent of subjects showed improvements. Seventy percent were no longer considered medically depressed.</p>
<p>Treatments being tested by teams today target individual patients more closely. The team at Mount Sinai, for example, is using brain imaging to find the right place to put electrodes in the brain.</p>
<p>Mayberg is also with Mount Sinai. She said, "Everybody's brain is a little different, just like people's eyes are a little further apart or a nose is a little bigger or smaller."</p>
<p><strong>Looking ahead</strong></p>
<p>Medical devices manufacturer Abbott Laboratories is launching a large <strong>clinical trial </strong>on patients this year, ahead of a possible decision by the FDA.</p>
<p>Scangos said: "I'm hoping we will have approval within a short time."</p>
<p>But some doctors have concerns. They point to possible dangers of having a brain operation, which include bleeding, stroke and infection.</p>
<p>Dr. Stanley Caroff is a professor of psychiatry at the University of Pennsylvania. He said scientists do not know the exact pathways or systems in the brain that produce depression. That makes it difficult to send the impulses to the right place.</p>
<p>"I believe from a psychiatric point of view, the science is not there," he said of DBS for depression.</p>
<p><strong>Moving forward</strong></p>
<p>Hollenbeck said DBS has not cured her. She still takes medicines for depression and needs ongoing care.</p>
<p>She recently visited Mayberg of Mount Sinai in her office and discussed recovery. "It's not about being happy all the time," Mayberg told her. "It's about making progress."</p>
<p>Researchers are studying the progress patients make. Recent research by Mayberg and others published in <em>Nature</em> said scientists can study brain activity to see how someone is doing at any given time.</p>
<p>Study subjects can provide data from their homes about how they feel. Subjects answer questions and send data from their devices to researchers. They also send videos where researchers can observe speech and facial movements.</p>
<p>Additionally, patients go to Mount Sinai so researchers can collect more information about their body movements. Hollenbeck, for example, is showing faster movements as her condition improves.</p>
<p>The data gained, combined with other information like life events, records how she is doing. This helps guide doctors' decisions about treatment, like increasing the amount of electricity used — which they did once.</p>
<p>Hollenbeck showed AP the scars on her chest and head where doctors had placed the DBS devices. To her, they were signs of how far she had come.</p>
<p>She added, "...I'm able to see and remember, even on a bodily level, that I'm going to be OK."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>impulse </strong><em>– n. </em>a small amount of energy that moves from one area to another</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong><em>– n. </em>the regular and repeated way in which something happens or is done</p>
<p><strong>psychology </strong><em>– n.</em> the science or study of the mind and behavior</p>
<p><strong>sedate </strong><em>– v.</em> to give (a person or animal) drugs that cause relaxation or sleep</p>
<p><strong>electrode </strong><em>– n.</em> one of the two points through which electricity flows into or out of a battery or other device</p>
<p><strong>chest </strong><em>– n. </em>the front part of the body between the neck and the stomach</p>
<p><strong>negative </strong>– <em>adj</em>. harmful or bad: not wanted</p>
<p><strong>psychiatry </strong><em>– n.</em> a branch of medicine that deals with mental or emotional disorders</p>
<p><strong>clinical trial </strong><em>– n.</em> a research study in which a medical treatment is carefully tested on people to find out how safe and effective it is</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Locals Worried about Olympic Surfing Event in Tahiti  (2024/3/5)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/locals-worried-about-olympic-surfing-event-in-tahiti.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">04 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Summer Olympic Games this year are in Paris, France.</p>
<p>Paris does not have an ocean. So, how do organizers plan to present competition in the sport of surfing?</p>
<p>They are taking that Olympic event halfway around the world to the South Pacific country of French Polynesia. The athletes will compete on the island of Tahiti, in a small coastal village called Teahupo'o. The area is rural. It did not even have a road until the 1970s.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Tahitian-born surfer Kauli Vaast rides a wave in Teahupo'o, Tahiti, French Polynesia, Sunday, Jan. 13, 2024. (AP Photo/Daniel Cole)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e6989c0a-6001-447b-8bb5-ce80206c7faa_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Tahitian-born surfer Kauli Vaast rides a wave in Teahupo'o, Tahiti, French Polynesia, Sunday, Jan. 13, 2024. (AP Photo/Daniel Cole)
</span></div>
<p>Hundreds of people are expected to visit Teahupo'o to watch the sport, as the surfers go out onto the famous waves from July 27 to August 4.</p>
<p>Peva Levy is a Tahitian surfer. He said the Teahupo'o beach was a "secret spot" when he first rode the waves there more than fifty years ago. But, he added, it did not stay secret. Teahupo'o gained fame among surfers around the world in the years since.</p>
<p>Levy said the place has a special energy, a feeling known as "mana" in the local language.</p>
<p>And the people who live there want that special quality protected. There are concerns that a week of Olympic competition in Teahupo'o could destroy the "mana" and harm the environment that surrounds it.</p>
<p>Proposed preparations for the event included building temporary housing, roads, and even a large structure out on the water. The work called for drilling into a <strong>coral reef</strong>. Opposition to the plans quickly grew.</p>
<p>Environmentalists, locals and surfers joined forces to protect Teahupo'o's culture, its corals and other sea life.</p>
<p>"It was too much for us, a big change," said Levy, who also serves on a local environmental organization Vai Ara o Teahupo'o.</p>
<p>The group told the Olympic organizers they did not want new buildings or roads. And organizers are adjusting their plans as a result.</p>
<p>For example, they will not be building any Olympic housing. Instead, athletes will stay on a nearby boat. Homes of locals will serve other Olympic housing needs.</p>
<p>Organizers also shrunk the size of the planned structure, a platform, they will build in the ocean. Judges will watch the competition from the platform.</p>
<p>Some people worry that the <strong>drilling</strong> into the reef will disrupt the ecosystem and attract a dangerous <strong>algae</strong>. If fish eat the algae, people who eat the fish can become sick.</p>
<p>Twenty-two-year-old Mormon Maitei is concerned about the fish in the area. Maitei is a spearfisher who catches fish to feed his family. He sells what they do not need. The water is "where we get our dinner," he said.</p>
<p>Tahitians also worry that changing the reef could also change the shape of the famous waves.</p>
<p>Levy said if the reef cracks and breaks off "there will be no more wave over here, it will be finished for us."</p>
<p>In December, the worries of the locals were confirmed when a boat working on some Olympic construction hit a piece of the reef and broke it.</p>
<p>Cindy Otcenasek, the president of Via Ara o Teahupo'o, called the destruction deeply hurtful.</p>
<p>She said in Polynesian culture, people believe gods and spirits are everywhere, "in the coral, in the ocean. The ocean is considered to be our most sacred temple," she said.</p>
<p>Otcenasek said the fish live in and around the corals, "so if we break a coral, we break a home."</p>
<p>Barbara Martins-Nio is a senior event manager for the Paris 2024 Olympic and Paralympic Games Organization Committee. She called the accident "<strong>awful</strong>." She said Tahitians have a "special relationship with nature ... and it was like a bomb for us."</p>
<p>Since the incident, Martins-Nio said, the relationship between the organizers and locals has improved. The Olympic group is moving slowly and asking for more input from the local groups.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>coral reef </strong><em>–n.</em> a long section of material formed on the bottom of the sea by the skeletons of small creatures that is home to sea life and living coral</p>
<p><strong>drill </strong><em>–v.</em> to make a hole in something with a powerful tool</p>
<p><strong>algae </strong><em>–n.</em> a kind plant life that grows in water</p>
<p><strong>awful </strong><em>–adj.</em> something very bad or upsetting</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Supreme Court Rules Trump Can Stay on Ballots  (2024/3/5) | 美国最高法院裁定川普可参加大选</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-supreme-court-rules-trump-can-stay-on-ballots.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The United States Supreme Court ruled on Monday that former President Donald Trump can stay on 2024 presidential primary ballots.<br/>
美国最高法院周一裁定，前总统川普可以继续参加2024年的总统初选。</p>
<p>All nine justices ruled that individual states cannot use the 14th Amendment to prevent presidential candidates from appearing on ballots. They said that power "rests with Congress and not the states."<br/>
所有九名大法官都裁定，个别州不能利用第十四修正案阻止总统候选人出现在选票上。他们说，这项权力“归于国会而非各州”。</p>
<p>The ruling ended efforts in several states, including Colorado, Maine and Illinois, to remove Trump from ballots for presidential primary elections run by state governments.<br/>
这项裁决终止了几个州将川普从州政府举行的总统初选选票中除名的努力，这些州包括科罗拉多州、缅因州和伊利诺伊州。</p>
<p>Those state governments wanted to remove Trump, the leading candidate for the Republican Party nomination, from ballots because of his activities related to the 2020 presidential election. Trump is accused of trying to overturn his loss to Democrat Joe Biden. He is also accused of involvement in activities that led to the January 6 attack on the U.S. Capitol.<br/>
这些州政府希望将共和党提名的主要候选人川普从选票中除名，原因是他在2020年总统大选中的相关举动。川普被指控试图推翻他输给民主党人拜登的事实。他还被指控参与了导致1月6日美国国会大厦骚乱的活动。</p>
<p>Colorado's highest state court decided that Trump incited the January 6 attack. It also ruled that Section 3 of the 14th Amendment, which was passed shortly after the American Civil War, could be applied to Trump. The amendment aimed to prevent former officeholders of the U.S. who "have engaged in insurrection" or "given aid or comfort" to such activity from holding such office again.<br/>
科罗拉多州最高法院裁定川普煽动了1月6日的袭击。它还裁定，美国内战后不久通过的第14修正案第3条可以适用于川普。该修正案旨在防止“参与叛乱”或“为此类活动提供帮助或配合”的前美国官员再次担任此类职务。</p>
<p>In Monday's ruling, the U.S. Supreme Court did not deal with the issue of insurrection. All nine justices agreed that Trump should be on the ballot. But they offered different opinions on the ruling.<br/>
在周一的裁决中，美国最高法院没有处置暴动问题。所有九位大法官都同意川普应该参加投票。但他们对裁决提出了不同意见。</p>
<p>A five-justice conservative majority wrote, "The Constitution makes Congress, rather than the states, responsible for enforcing Section 3 against federal officeholders and candidates."<br/>
五名占多数优势的保守派法官写道：“宪法规定由国会，而不是由各州负责对联邦官员和候选人执行第3条。”</p>
<p>Three liberal justices, Sonia Sotomayor, Elena Kagan, and Ketanji Brown Jackson, jointly wrote, "Today, the majority goes beyond the necessities of this case to limit how Section 3 can bar an oathbreaking insurrectionist from becoming President."<br/>
三位自由派大法官索尼娅·索托马约尔、埃琳娜·卡根和凯坦吉·布朗·杰克逊共同写道：“今天，多数派超越了本案的必要性，限制了第3条如何禁止一名宣誓叛乱者成为总统。”</p>
<p>And Justice Amy Coney Barrett added that the majority should not have dealt with the "question whether federal legislation is the exclusive vehicle through which Section 3 can be enforced."<br/>
大法官艾米·科尼·巴雷特补充道，多数派不应该处理“联邦立法是否是执行第3条的唯一途径的问题”。</p>
<p>Trump posted on his social media network shortly after the decision was released: "BIG WIN FOR AMERICA!!!"<br/>
裁决发布后不久，川普在其社交媒体网络上发帖称：“美国的重大胜利！！！”</p>
<p>The case is the Supreme Court's latest direct involvement in a presidential election since Bush v. Gore. In that case, the court stopped the recount of votes in the state of Florida that effectively handed the 2000 election to Republican George W. Bush.<br/>
这是自小布什诉戈尔案以来，最高法院最新一次直接卷入总统选举。在那起案件中，最高法院阻止了佛罗里达州重新计票，这实际上将2000年的选举胜利交给了共和党人小布什。</p>
<p>The Supreme Court has an even more important case ahead that involves Trump directly on the week of April 22.<br/>
最高法院还有一起更重要的案件，将于4月22日这一周直接涉及川普。</p>
<p>A three-judge federal appeals court had ruled earlier that Trump could be put on trial for trying to undo the 2020 elections and actions leading to the January 6 attack. But the nation's highest court agreed last week to hear whether Trump could face criminal prosecution for actions taken while in office as president.<br/>
一家由三名法官组成的联邦上诉法院早些时候裁定，川普可能因试图撤销2020年的选举和导致1月6日国会袭击的行为而受审。但美国最高法院上周同意审理川普是否会因担任总统期间的行为而面临刑事起诉。</p>
<p>The decision effectively put on hold several federal cases against Trump and raised questions about whether Trump will be tried before the November election.<br/>
这一决定实际上搁置了几起针对川普的联邦案件，并引发了人们对川普是否会在11月大选前受审的质疑。</p>
<p>Recently, a jury in New York City found Trump guilty of defaming writer E. Jean Carroll. It ordered him to pay her $83 million. Last month, a New York judge presiding over Trump's civil fraud trial set a penalty and interest of $450 million and barred Trump from running a business in the state for three years. Later in March, Trump will face a trial for charges related to payments made to adult movie performer Stormy Daniels.<br/>
最近，纽约市的一个陪审团裁定川普诽谤作家简·卡罗尔罪名成立。陪审团命令川普赔付给她8300万美元。上个月，主持川普民事欺诈案审判的纽约法官设定了4.5亿美元的罚款和利息，并禁止川普在三年内在该州经营企业。3月晚些时候，川普将因向成人电影演员斯托米·丹尼尔斯付款而面临审判。</p>
<p>In addition to those ongoing cases, the former president is facing charges brought by the state of Georgia over his actions related to the 2020 presidential election. And the federal government has brought a case against Trump in the state of Florida for holding classified documents after leaving office.<br/>
除了这些正在进行的案件外，这位前总统还因其与2020年总统选举有关的行为而面临佐治亚州的指控。同时联邦政府已在佛罗里达州对川普提起诉讼，指控他在离任后持有机密文件。</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.<br/>
我是安娜·马泰奥。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: NASA Space Strike Might Have Reshaped an Asteroid  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/study-nasa-space-strike-might-have-reshaped-an-asteroid.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>A new study suggests that an <strong>asteroid</strong> strike by an American spacecraft likely changed the shape of the targeted object.</p>
<p>NASA crashed the DART spacecraft into the asteroid Dimorphos in 2022. The asteroid strike happened about 11 million kilometers from Earth.</p>
<p>The experiment tested a method for changing the orbit of some asteroids to prevent them from possibly crashing into our planet in the future.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This artist's illustration depicts NASA's DART spacecraft, which will be launched to crash into an asteroid to see how the crash affects the space object's path. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C27B36A6-BC02-4175-9B42-68C44C0D9969_cx6_cy3_cw93_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This artist's illustration depicts NASA's DART spacecraft, which will be launched to crash into an asteroid to see how the crash affects the space object's path. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL)</span></div>
<p>NASA has said its studies of the crash showed it was successful because the force of the strike changed the asteroid's orbit around a larger asteroid Didymos. NASA's measurements also found the strike reduced the orbital period of Dimorphos by 33 minutes.</p>
<p>Such a major crash would normally create a large <strong>crater</strong> in the targeted object. But a new study presents evidence that the crash made more than a hole – it likely changed the shape of the whole asteroid.</p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>Astronomers at the University of Bern, in Switzerland carried out the research. A <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-024-02200-3">study</a> detailing the findings recently appeared in the publication <em>Nature Astronomy</em>.</p>
<p>The team used a computer<strong> simulation</strong> system to study the changes to Dimorphos that resulted from the crash. The system aimed to recreate the breakup of space objects that have been hit.</p>
<p>The researchers said their simulation method has been used in the past to recreate space objects crashing into each other. For example, the team said it confirmed the results of a Japanese spacecraft collecting a sample from the Ryugu asteroid in 2019.</p>
<p>Sabina Raducan is with the Physics Institute of the University of Bern. She helped lead the project. Raducan <a class="wsw__a" href="https://mediarelations.unibe.ch/media_releases/2024/media_releases_2024/impact_of_the_dart_space_probe_could_have_deformed_an_asteroid/index_eng.html">described</a> the simulation process in a statement as "computationally intensive." In total, she said 250 simulations were completed, which reproduced the first two hours after the asteroid strike.</p>
<p>The researchers used all available information about NASA's operation. These included the predicted shape of Dimorphos, data on the strike itself, as well as the size of the cloud the crash left behind. In addition, the team aimed to estimate unknown details about the asteroid and the surrounding area.</p>
<p>"Then what we did is <strong>check</strong> which of the simulation run outcomes most closely match observed reality," Raducan said.</p>
<p>She added that results of the research provided clear evidence that the crash turned Dimorphos into a relatively weak "<strong>rubble pile</strong>" asteroid. Raducan explained this meant that the object is currently being held together "by the asteroid's extremely weak gravity" rather than a solid and strong mass.</p>
<p>The researchers noted that the results of the simulation and the team's examinations partly explain why the crash was so effective in changing the path of the asteroid.</p>
<p>Raducan said the results also persuaded the team that "the likelihood is that the crater grew to <strong>encompass</strong> the entire body itself, so that Dimorphos ended up being completely reshaped." It is therefore unlikely that a crater still exists after the crash.</p>
<p>The researchers said the existence of a crater can be investigated further by a European Space Agency (ESA) spacecraft. The spacecraft, called Hera, is preparing for a possible launch in October.</p>
<p>ESA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Space_Safety/Hera">says</a> Hera's cameras and instruments will carry out detailed studies of Dimorphos and the asteroid it orbits, Didymos. During the operation, the spacecraft will aim to collect the most data yet on such an asteroid system.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from the University of Bern, the European Space Agency, NASA and Nature Astronomy.</em></p>
<p><strong>_____________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong><em>– n. </em>a rocky object that goes around the sun like a planet</p>
<p><strong>crater </strong><em>– n. </em>a big hole left in the ground or an object by a force of impact</p>
<p><strong>simulate </strong><em>– v. </em>to do or make something that behaves or looks like something real but is not</p>
<p><strong>check </strong>–v. to look for something of interest or something that might be a mistake</p>
<p><strong>rubble </strong><em>– n. </em>pieces of broken bricks from a destroyed structure</p>
<p><strong>pile </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of substance in the shape of a small hill or a number of objects laying on top of each other</p>
<p><strong>encompass </strong><em>– v. </em>to include a lot of things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Life Inside Russia’s Prisons  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/life-inside-russia-s-prisons.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Vladimir Kara-Murza is a <strong>critic</strong> of the Russian government.</p>
<p>He was sentenced to 25 years in prison last year on charges of treason for speaking against Russia's war with Ukraine.</p>
<p>He is in Penal Colony Number 6, south of Moscow and not far from Kazakhstan.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A replica of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny's jail cell from last year that was installed on a square near the Louvre Museum in Paris is pictured on March 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-a8cf-08dc39435397_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A replica of Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny's jail cell from last year that was installed on a square near the Louvre Museum in Paris is pictured on March 14, 2023. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla, File)</span></div>
<p>Kara-Murza's wife, Yevgenia, spoke with <em>The Associated Press</em> about her husband's experiences.</p>
<p>She said her husband lives in a small cell with a <strong>cot</strong>, a sink, a stool and toilet. The only things he owns are a drinking cup and a toothbrush.</p>
<p>People are interested in what life is like inside of the prisons because another critic of President Vladimir Putin's government died at a prison in Russia's far north, close to the Arctic Circle. Alexei Navalny died February 16. He was the leader of a political group that campaigned against Putin. Forty-seven-year-old Navalny was sentenced to 19 years in prison in early 2021.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press </em>called life in Russia's prisons "<strong>grim</strong>" and noted the prisoners suffer from a lack of food, sleep, and healthcare. They also must deal with rules that change all the time.</p>
<p>Grigory Vaypan is a lawyer with Memorial, a group that started during the period of the Soviet Union. Memorial received the Nobel Prize in 2022. The group studies the experiences of political prisoners, and how Russia uses the threat of prison to quiet critics.</p>
<p>Vaypan said there are 680 political prisoners in Russia. He also said no one in the Russian prison system is safe, but the situation is worse for government critics.</p>
<p>"The state aims to additionally punish them, or additionally <strong>isolate</strong> them from the world, or do everything to break their spirit," Vaypan said.</p>
<p>Kara-Murza's sentence of 25 years is the longest in modern Russia. He is one of a growing number of critics held in prison for expressing their anti-Putin opinions.</p>
<p>Historians say the Russian prison system developed from the Soviet Union's "gulags." The prisons of that time were known for their bad conditions. Nobel Prize-winning writer Alexander Solzhenitsyn documented the prisons in his books <em>One Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich </em>and <em>The Gulag Archipelago</em>.</p>
<p>Yevgenia Kara-Murza, the wife of Vladimir Kara-Murza, described Russian prison life:</p>
<p><strong>Meals</strong></p>
<p>Meals are simple and not very satisfying. The first meal of the day is porridge, a liquid made from grains. The midday meal is soup with very little meat, along with mashed potatoes and a piece of meat or fish. For dinner, the meal is almost the same. Prisoners are permitted to eat two eggs per week. They can buy fruits and vegetables at small prison stores but not much is available.</p>
<p>Friends and family can send packages with other foods. But those in <strong>solitary cells</strong> are not permitted to receive packages.</p>
<p><strong>How do people spend their time?</strong></p>
<p>Some prisoners are told to spend most of their days doing tasks such as cleaning their rooms. Other times they are told to only "stand at attention." They sometimes must listen to recordings of prison rules for hours.</p>
<p>Others are told to work. There are not enough jobs for all the men in the prison. In women's prisons, the jobs often include <strong>sewing</strong> uniforms for the military, police and other workers. There are 30 to 40 women's prisons in Russia.</p>
<p>One woman, Nadya Tolokonnikova, was in prison for nearly 22 months. She was a member of the rock band Pussy Riot. Her prison time was from 2012 to 2013. She said she worked on uniforms for 16 to 18 hours at a time.</p>
<p>"It's a system of slavery and it is truly horrible," she said.</p>
<p>Inmates — another word for prisoners — are supposed to be paid at least minimum wage. That is about $200 per month. But experts say it is usually much less. Sasha Graf is an activist for better prison conditions. Graf said prisoners' pay can be as low as $3.20 per month. That is only enough to buy cigarettes at the prison store.</p>
<p><strong>Intimidation</strong></p>
<p>Tolokonnikova said, when she arrived at Penal Colony No. 14 in Mordovia, the head of the prison described himself as a "Stalinist."</p>
<p>She said he told her: "You may be a somebody outside of this colony, have a voice, people who support you and care for you, but here, you are completely in my power, and you need to understand this."</p>
<p>Zoya Svetova, a reporter and prisoner rights activist, said that in the past, prisons were overseen by commissions that were supposed to make sure the prisoners were treated with respect. However, she said, most of the people have been replaced with those loyal to Putin's government. The government uses the prisons, she said, for "<strong>intimidation</strong> and oppression."</p>
<p>Oleg Kozlovsky, of Amnesty International, said political prisoners can be safe from the abuse that regular prisoners suffer. But there are still ways to make political prisoners feel bad.</p>
<p>Navalny, he said, spent months in a cell on his own for breaking small rules such as not having his uniform buttoned the right way or not putting his hands behind his back at the right time.</p>
<p>The time in the small cell – where it could be very cold in winter or very hot in summer – was not good for Navalny's health. He had been poisoned in the past and was still suffering from the effects of the poison.</p>
<p>Kara-Murza's wife said her husband had also been poisoned. Although he is only 42, his health has worsened. She said he needs exercise and physical therapy to help his arms and legs.</p>
<p>Alexei Gorinov is 62. He criticized the war and was sent to prison for seven years.</p>
<p>He has breathing problems and had a medical operation to remove one of his lungs. He is now in a prison hospital, but his lawyer says he is mistreated. Guards wake him up every two hours. He considers it a form of torture.</p>
<p>There have been calls for prison reform in recent years. Vaypan of the Memorial group, said whatever led to Navalny's death shows the prison system has crossed a line.</p>
<p>It's a "worrying signal," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>critic </strong><em>–n.</em> a person who disagrees with something or someone and who speaks or writes in opposition to what they disagree with</p>
<p><strong>cot </strong>–n. a small bed that folds</p>
<p><strong>grim </strong><em>–adj.</em> unhappy and without hope</p>
<p><strong>isolate </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause someone to be kept apart from others, often as punishment</p>
<p><strong>solitary cell </strong><em>–n.</em> a room in a prison that is meant to hold only one person who is being kept apart from others as a more severe form of punishment</p>
<p><strong>sew </strong><em>–v. </em>to use thread and cloth to make or repair clothes</p>
<p><strong>intimidation </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of threatening someone with harm or trouble usually to prevent them from doing or saying something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Costs, Performance Influence Decisions on Electric School Buses  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/costs-performance-influence-decisions-on-electric-school-buses.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The first electric school buses in the United States began operating about 10 years ago in California. Fewer than one percent of the 489,000 school buses in the U.S. were electric at the end of 2023.</p>
<p>However, the number of electric school buses currently operating or that have been ordered from a manufacturer has more than tripled in the last two years. That information comes from the Electric School Bus Initiative of the non-profit World Resources Institute, or WRI, based in Washington D.C.</p>
<p>The WRI said that increase means 10 times as many students now ride electric school buses — from around 20,000 in 2020 to 200,000 three years later. The number of states with electric bus laws or goals also grew from two to 14 between 2020 and last year.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rock Creek Forest Elementary School students exit a diesel bus before attending school, Friday, Feb. 2, 2024, in Chevy Chase, Md. At right is an electric school bus. (AP Photo/Tom Brenner)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/29ae78dc-1e10-432b-8be1-e077840c8978_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rock Creek Forest Elementary School students exit a diesel bus before attending school, Friday, Feb. 2, 2024, in Chevy Chase, Md. At right is an electric school bus. (AP Photo/Tom Brenner)</span></div>
<p>People and organizations that want electric school buses can find it difficult to get local officials to find ways to pay for them.</p>
<p>"It's just a matter of breaking down these barriers," said Alicia Cox. She is a mother of two in Jackson, Wyoming. Her state is the only one that does not have a single <strong>school district</strong> with an electric bus operating or on order.</p>
<p>Cox's son, a second grader, often rides a diesel bus to school.</p>
<p><strong>Problems with electric buses </strong></p>
<p>Parents and local officials say one of the biggest problems with electric school buses is their cost. Even with the fuel and <strong>maintenance</strong> savings of an electric bus, they cost two to three times more than diesel fueled buses.</p>
<p>The Environmental Protection Agency says it has a $5 billion program for <strong>zero-emissions</strong> buses. The money comes from an infrastructure law passed by the U.S. Congress under the administration of President Joe Biden in 2021. Nearly 440 <strong>grants</strong> and <strong>rebates </strong>totaling about $1.8 billion have already been released. The goal of the federal money is to replace thousands of buses across several hundred school districts in the U.S.</p>
<p>Demand for the money has been "heartening," said Christine Koester. She is a director for the Clean School Bus Program at the EPA.</p>
<p>In addition to federal money, supporters have successfully pushed to use other money. That includes money from federal government legal cases, like the Volkswagen emissions settlement. In that case, the U.S. government brought legal action against the German carmaker for having a system that gave false car emissions results.</p>
<p>For school districts that are not receiving federal money, there are other possibilities. These include <strong>leasing </strong>buses from companies that supply the buses and the equipment needed. This method spreads costs out over time.</p>
<p><strong>Choices </strong></p>
<p>Dearborn Public Schools is a Detroit area school district in the Midwestern state of Michigan. Seventy percent of families in the district are poor. Communications director David Mustonen said the district was interested in new technology when it began operating its first electric bus in December 2022.</p>
<p>The district bought an electric school bus with a $300,000 federal grant. The bus has been operational only about three of the 12 months since then. That is because of maintenance needs and learning about the device. That is not <strong>discouraging </strong>Dearborn from moving forward with adding 18 additional electric school buses. But those problems represent a risk other school districts may not want to take.</p>
<p>There are other problems slowing the change to electric buses. School districts sometimes take a long time to approve electric buses. Manufacturing of the buses can be delayed, and electric buses require special electrical connections for charging. And, of course, electricity costs money, too.</p>
<p>Wyoming refused federal money from the EPA because of concerns about how far the buses could travel. There were also concerns about cold temperatures. Wyoming is a very large Western state where travel distances are big and, in the winter, temperatures can get very cold. Electric battery performance decreases in cold temperatures.</p>
<p>"Even though diesel is not as clean, it's getting the job done," Cox said schools and<strong> fleet </strong>managers tell her.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Alexa St. John reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>school district </strong>– n. an area established by a local government for the administration of public schools which has a budget and is supervised by local government officials</p>
<p><strong>maintenance </strong>– n. the act of keeping property or equipment in good condition by making repairs</p>
<p><strong>zero-emissions</strong> –adj. letting off no gasses that people do not like or considered harmful</p>
<p><strong>grant</strong> – n. an amount of money that is given by a government to be used for a particular purpose</p>
<p><strong>rebate</strong> – n. an amount of money that is paid back to you</p>
<p><strong>lease</strong> – v. to use (something) for a period of time in return for payment</p>
<p><strong>discourage</strong> – v. to make someone less likely to do something; to make someone less hopeful about doing something</p>
<p><strong>fleet</strong> –n. a group of vehicles that is supervised for an organization or force</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Three Lessons from the War in Ukraine  (2024/3/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/three-lessons-from-the-war-in-ukraine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 March 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A volunteer carries a woman as she is evacuated from a flooded Kardashynka village of the bank Dnipro river, in Kherson, Ukraine on June 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Evgeniy Maloletka)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-f994-08dc33d93e9d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A volunteer carries a woman as she is evacuated from a flooded Kardashynka village of the bank Dnipro river, in Kherson, Ukraine on June 9, 2023. (AP Photo/Evgeniy Maloletka)</span></div>
<p>My name is Kateryna Denysenko; I work at the Gymnasium of Veselianka.</p>
<p>War is always a tragedy.</p>
<p>It ruined lives, separated families, and destroyed cities.</p>
<p>Like many life-changing events, war could also be viewed as a way to teach us important things. Thucydides, an ancient Athenian historian and general, once wrote, "War is a stern teacher." And today, we are going to share three important lessons the war in Ukraine has taught us.</p>
<p><strong>Volunteer work and donations are important.</strong></p>
<p>If there was one important lesson to share, it would have been this: volunteer work and donations are important!</p>
<p>Let's be honest. We often pay little attention when someone asks us to donate money, clothes, food, or blood to someone in need. We may feel that our help would be too small. And we spend even less time on volunteer work, thinking that it takes time and energy and may not be useful.</p>
<p>Ukrainians may argue with that. We understand that even the smallest amount of money can help to buy armor and weapons for our army. And the more people decide to help, the safer our soldiers feel, and the more protected the country becomes.</p>
<p>But you should not forget about people in need. If you donate your clothes, food, or blood to those who were seriously wounded or lost their homes, you will help them survive. Your small act of kindness will also help them save some of their resources to move on.</p>
<p>Volunteer work also matters a lot for Ukrainians. You can help by removing parts of fallen buildings or by cooking free meals for soldiers. Your participation will greatly help others!</p>
<p><strong>If you want to do something, do it.</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes, we do not say good things to others. We may be too shy to give a compliment. Or we do not know if the person will like what we say. Maybe, our words will be out of place.</p>
<p>Sometimes, we do not get around to visiting certain places. Who needs to spend their time going to a historical place, a park, or an old café? These places have existed for so long. They would not disappear, would they?</p>
<p>Since the start of the war, Ukrainians have known the harsh reality.</p>
<p>We know that you may never see someone again. They may flee to another city for safety, their house may collapse, or they can go to war and never come back. And the place you always wanted to visit may be destroyed by a missile.</p>
<p>We rarely tell our family members and friends how happy we are to have them in our lives. You may never have another chance to tell them how much you love and value them. But if you tell them something kind, your words will support and encourage them in such uncertain times.</p>
<p>That is why we remember the rule: if you want to say something good or go somewhere nice, do it now. Do not wait until tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>There is always a reason to be grateful.</strong></p>
<p>Lastly, we take many things in our lives for granted. We expect to sleep well at night, eat healthy meals, have a place to live, and go to school or work. We get used to them so much that they become routine and even boring.</p>
<p>Before we know it, we are looking for something new and fresh and something unusual. But people in Ukraine know the value of routine and boring things in their daily lives.</p>
<p>When the noise from missiles keeps us awake, we begin to appreciate a good sleep. When we have to study remotely, or we lose our workplace due to the war, we appreciate the time with our classmates, teachers, or colleagues.</p>
<p>As we spend our days and nights in a bomb shelter or move far away from our homes, we begin to appreciate the place we live and the meals we cook and eat.</p>
<p>This may be one of the most important lessons from the war so far. We should appreciate these small, but very important things in our lives.</p>
<p>In his 28th song, Ukrainian songwriter Hryhorii Skovoroda wrote, "What you need is easy to get, what you do not need is hard to get." And now, after going through the war, and losing so many different things, we can agree that the simplest ones are the most important in our lives.</p>
<p>These were the three most important lessons from the war in Ukraine. We hope they will inspire you to value the simplest things in your life, to visit the places you always wanted to visit, to do small acts of kindness for people in need, and to show your love and gratitude to your closest people!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the writer</h2>
<p>Kateryna Denysenko was born in Donetsk, Ukraine. At the age of 13, she was forced to leave her hometown due to the invasion of the Russian Federation and move to the village of Veselianka, in the Zaporizhzhia area. In 2020, she graduated from the Zaporizhzhia Pedagogical College with professional qualification as a teacher of primary education and foreign language at primary school. Since 2020, she has been an English teacher at the Gymnasium of Veselianka.</p>
<p></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Did Human Ancestors Lose Their Tails?  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/how-did-human-ancestors-lose-their-tails.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Our very ancient animal ancestors had <strong>tails</strong>. Why don't we have them now?</p>
<p>From the time of Charles Darwin, a scientist from the 1800s who studied evolutionary biology, scientists have questioned why and how this happened.</p>
<p>The answer is somewhere around 20 million or 25 million years ago. That was the time apes, the group of animals humans are part of, split from another animal group, m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s. During that split, our branch of the tree of life lost its tail.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Skeletons of a human and a m&lt;I&gt;&lt;I&gt;onkey&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/I&gt; await installation at the Steinhardt Museum of Natural History in Tel Aviv, Israel on Monday, Feb 19, 2018. (AP Photo/Oded Balilty, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7770b6c8-b28b-45e7-9e8e-f8dd2c39c025_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Skeletons of a human and a m<i><i>onkey</i></i> await installation at the Steinhardt Museum of Natural History in Tel Aviv, Israel on Monday, Feb 19, 2018. (AP Photo/Oded Balilty, File)</span></div>
<p>Now, scientists have identified at least one of the genetic differences that led to this change.</p>
<p>"We found a single <strong>mutation</strong> in a very important gene," said Bo Xia. He is a geneticist at the Broad Institute and helped write the study recently released in the publication <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>The researchers compared the genomes of six kinds of apes, including humans, and 15 kinds of m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s with tails to find important differences between the groups. Once they identified an important mutation, they tested their theory by using the gene-<strong>editing</strong> tool CRISPR. They used it to change the same place in <strong>embryos </strong>of an animal often used in laboratories, mice. Those mice were born without tails.</p>
<p>Xia said, however, that other genetic changes may also play a part in losing tails.</p>
<p>Another mystery: Did having no tails help these ape ancestors – and eventually, humans – survive? Or was it just a chance mutation in a population that survived for other reasons?</p>
<p>"It could be <strong>random</strong> chance, but it could have brought a big evolutionary <strong>advantage</strong>," said Miriam Konkel. She is an evolutionary geneticist at Clemson University, who was not involved in the study.</p>
<p>As to why having no tails may have helped our ancestors, there are many interesting theories. They include some that link being tailless to learning to walk upright.</p>
<p>Rick Potts directs the Human Origins Project of the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C. He was not involved in the research. Potts suggests being tailless may have been a first step toward some apes standing upright, even before they left the trees.</p>
<p>Not all apes live on the ground today. Orangutans and gibbons are tailless apes that still live in trees. But Potts notes that they move very differently than m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s, who move along the tops of branches, using their tails for balance. Those apes hang below branches, holding onto the branches with their arms while hanging largely upright.</p>
<p>New York University biologist Itai Yanai helped write the study. He said that losing our tails was clearly a large change. But the only way to truly know the reason "would be to invent a time machine," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>tail </strong><em>– n. </em>the part of an animal's body that extends from the animal's back end</p>
<p><strong>mutation </strong><em>– n.</em> the part of an animal's body that extends from the animal's back end</p>
<p><strong>edit </strong><em>– v.</em> to make changes</p>
<p><strong>embryo </strong><em>– n.</em> a human or animal in the early stages of development before it is born or hatched</p>
<p><strong>random </strong><em>– adj. </em>in a way that does not follow a particular plan or pattern</p>
<p><strong>advantage </strong><em>– n.</em> something (such as a good position or condition) that helps to make someone or something better or more likely to succeed than others</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Health Officials Urge Older Adults to Get Latest COVID-19 Vaccine  (2024/3/3) | 美国疾控中心督促老年人再接种加强针</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/us-health-officials-urge-older-adults-to-get-latest-covid-19-vaccine.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>U.S. health officials are urging older adults to get an additional updated COVID-19 vaccine shot.<br/>
美国卫生官员敦促老年人再接种一针更新版新冠疫苗。</p>
<p>The advice for Americans 65 and older was recently issued by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).<br/>
美国疾控预防中心最近发布了针对65岁及以上美国人的建议。</p>
<p>A statement by CDC Director Mandy Cohen explained the new guidance. "Most COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations last year were among people 65 years and older. An additional vaccine dose can provide added protection ... for those at highest risk."<br/>
美国疾控预防中心主任曼迪·科恩在一份声明中对这份新的指导意见做出了解释。“去年新冠肺炎死亡和住院患者多数都是65岁及以上人群。对这些高危人群来说，接种一剂加强针可以提供更多防护。</p>
<p>The CDC said an additional dose of the vaccine can provide increased protection, even if older adults received the updated shot version launched last autumn.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心表示，即使老年人接种了去年秋天推出的更新疫苗，再接种一剂疫苗也可以提供更多的保护。</p>
<p>The new guidance suggests individuals who did receive the updated shot – which became available last September – should wait at least four months before getting the latest dose.<br/>
新的指导意见建议，接种了去年9月推出的更新疫苗的人群，应该至少等待四个月才能接种最新的疫苗。</p>
<p>The CDC's decision, or recommendation, came after much debate over whether to say older people "may" get the shots or "should" do so. That discussion demonstrates the ongoing debate among experts about how necessary additional COVID-19 shots are.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心的决定或建议，是在对老年人接种这剂疫苗是“可选择”，还是“应该”进行了大量辩论之后做出的。这一讨论表明，专家们正在就额外接种新冠疫苗的必要性进行辩论。</p>
<p>Some doctors have said they think most older adults are effectively protected after getting the shot last autumn. And studies have suggested the shots stay effective for six months.<br/>
一些医生表示，他们认为大多数老年人在去年秋天接种疫苗后得到了有效的保护。研究表明，这些疫苗的有效期为六个月。</p>
<p>But health officials have noted the body's vaccine-activated defenses can decrease over time, especially in older people. The CDC had recommended additional COVID-19 shots, called boosters, for older adults in 2022 and 2023.<br/>
但卫生官员指出，随着时间的推移，疫苗激活的人体防御能力会下降，尤其是在老年人中。美国疾控预防中心在2022年和2023年建议为老年人额外接种新冠疫苗加强针。</p>
<p>COVID-19 can still present serious health risks, especially to older people and those with existing medical conditions. The CDC says there are still more than 20,000 hospitalizations and more than 2,000 deaths each week from COVID-19. Individuals 65 years and older have the highest hospitalization and death rates.<br/>
新冠肺炎仍可能带来严重的健康风险，尤其是对老年人和既有病患。美国疾控预防中心表示，新冠肺炎每周仍然导致2万多人住院，2000多人死亡。65岁及以上人群的住院率和死亡率最高。</p>
<p>Some members of the CDC group that approved the latest advice said the word "should" in the guidance is meant to persuade more doctors and drug stores to offer the shots.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心批准这一最新建议的小组的一些成员表示，指南中的“应该”一词旨在说服更多的医生和药店提供疫苗。</p>
<p>"Most people are coming in either wanting the vaccine or not," Dr. Jamie Loehr told The Associated Press. He is a member of the CDC's deciding committee and a family doctor in Ithaca, New York. "I am trying to make it easier for providers to say, ‘Yes, we recommend this.'"<br/>
詹米·勒尔博士告诉美联社：“大多数人要么想接种疫苗，要么不想接种。”他是美国疾控预防中心决策委员会的成员，也是纽约伊萨卡的一名家庭医生。“我试图让提供疫苗者更容易说出，‘是的，我们建议这样做。’”</p>
<p>In September, the government ordered a new COVID-19 shot based on a version of the virus called XBB.1.5. That single-target vaccine replaced combinations that had targeted both the first COVID-19 version and a much earlier Omicron version.<br/>
去年9月，美国政府下令接种一剂新的新冠疫苗，该疫苗是基于XBB.1.5病毒版本。这种单靶点疫苗取代了针对第一种新冠肺炎版本和更早的奥密克戎版本的组合。</p>
<p>The CDC recommended that vaccine version for everyone 6 months and older. It also urged people with weak immune systems to get a second shot up to two months after the first.<br/>
美国疾控预防中心建议6个月及以上人群接种该疫苗。它还敦促免疫系统较弱人群在接种第一针后两个月内接种第二针。</p>
<p>But most Americans did not listen to that advice. The latest CDC data shows that 13 percent of U.S. children got the shots, while 22 percent of U.S. adults did. The vaccination rate for adults 65 and older is higher, at nearly 42 percent.<br/>
但大多数美国人没有听从这个建议。美国疾控预防中心的最新数据显示，接种了这剂疫苗的美国儿童为13%，而美国成年人为22%。65岁及以上人群的疫苗接种率更高，接近42%。</p>
<p>"People are tired of getting all these shots all the time," Dr. David Canaday told the AP. He is an infectious diseases expert at Case Western Reserve University in Cleveland, Ohio.<br/>
大卫·卡纳迪博士告诉美联社：“人们已经厌倦了一直接种这些疫苗。”他是俄亥俄州克利夫兰市凯斯西储大学的传染病专家。</p>
<p>Canaday, who does not serve on the CDC's advisory group, added, "We have to be careful about over-recommending the vaccine."<br/>
卡纳迪不在美国疾控预防中心的咨询小组任职，他补充道，“我们必须对过度推荐疫苗保持谨慎。”</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Professors’ Group Speaks Out about Changes at Florida College  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/professors-group-speaks-out-about-changes-at-florida-college.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>College professors and their students often say they should be permitted to <strong>pursue</strong> knowledge without too many restrictions from the government.</p>
<p>One organization that supports the idea of <strong>academic</strong> freedom is the American Association of University Professors (AAUP). The AAUP is a non-profit group based in Washington D.C. that aims to support academic freedom and <strong>tenure</strong>. The group is concerned that national and state political leaders are interfering too much with colleges and universities.</p>
<p><strong>AAUP expresses concern </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A student makes her way past the sign at New College of Florida, Jan. 20, 2023, in Sarasota, Fla. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/700a7e3e-1475-46c6-a43e-572aea5df5f3_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A student makes her way past the sign at New College of Florida, Jan. 20, 2023, in Sarasota, Fla. (AP Photo/Chris O'Meara, File)</span></div>
<p>In early February, the AAUP <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.aaup.org/news/time-now-resist-political-interference">spoke out</a> about what it said were attempts to control "what may be said, taught, or thought" in American colleges and Universities.</p>
<p>It pointed to hearings at the U.S. Congress in December that brought the presidents of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Harvard University and the University of Pennsylvania to Washington. They each were asked if they would punish speech calling for genocide against the Jewish people.</p>
<p>In the days and weeks after the hearing, the presidents of the University of Pennsylvania and Harvard stepped down from their jobs. Some said the answers they gave to Congress played a part.</p>
<p>At first, Harvard president Claudine Gay received support from a number of Harvard professors. But she decided to leave her job after being accused of <strong>plagiarism</strong> in her academic writing. After Gay left her position, the AAUP spoke out about the way influential people worked to push her out.</p>
<p>Irene Mulvey is the head of AAUP. She said the way Gay was pushed out of her job "(did) not <strong>bode</strong> well for academic freedom."</p>
<p><strong>Research into New College of Florida</strong></p>
<p>On February 26, AAUP released a statement about its concerns over academic freedom. It said actions at the New College of Florida, a small school in Florida's State University System, did not meet "widely accepted <strong>standards</strong> of academic government."</p>
<p>The group said Ron DeSantis, the Florida governor, had changed the college's top leadership group to restrict academic freedom. AAUP described some of the changes that began in early 2023 in a report released last December. The report is called "Political Interference and Academic Freedom in Florida's Public Higher Education System."</p>
<p>After studying the report, AAUP's top leaders, known as the governing council, voted to speak out against, or <strong>sanction</strong>, what it called "an <strong>unprecedented</strong> politically motivated takeover" of the school. The group has only sanctioned 12 other universities in its history.</p>
<p>The December report said DeSantis targeted New College of Florida because he believed it was too "woke." The report says conservatives now define the word as: "politically liberal or progressive...especially in a way that is considered unreasonable or extreme."</p>
<p>The governor appointed a group of six new people to the college's board of trustees. The board is a college or university's top leadership group.</p>
<p>That group pushed out New College of Florida's president and worked to restrict the kinds of study programs the school could offer. The new trustees also worked to change the way professors applied for tenure, which guarantees those who have it a job for life. Many of the new trustees had written papers and made comments criticizing critical race theory (CRT). The theory centers on the idea that racism is systemic in the country's institutions and that most social interactions can be explained by race.</p>
<p>The board members also spoke against DEI, or diversity, equity and inclusion, a movement aiming to change how society is made up.</p>
<p><strong>No longer safe</strong></p>
<p>One law professor in Florida, LeRoy Pernell, told AAUP what was happening in the state was a "reign of terror." Pernell teaches law at Florida A&amp;M University. That term was first used to describe the French Revolution, which took place more than 225 years ago.</p>
<p>New College is a state school, which means Florida provides part of its <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/harvard-president-s-ouster-leads-to-concerns-about-academic-freedom/7427004.html">budget</a> and it is governed under state laws. For years, New College had been permitted to be "<strong>quirky</strong>." That means it welcomed students and professors who had unusual interests and wanted to follow study programs outside of normal ones.</p>
<p>Many students who felt uncomfortable at more traditional colleges went to New College of Florida and said they felt happy and safe. LBGTQ students say they chose the school because it was open to those who did not follow traditional sexual or gender ideas.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Leininger is a science professor. In a 2023 story, she called New College "one of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/small-florida-college-worries-about-government-involvement/7037843.html#comments">most unique places</a> ... that exists in American higher education."</p>
<p>The AAUP talked with professors at other Florida universities who said they were concerned about the changes at New College of Florida. They said professors are worried about their own ability to seek academic freedom. Some are looking for jobs in other states.</p>
<p>Carolyne Ali-Khan is an education professor at the University of North Florida. "These governmental attacks from the State of Florida have made us unsafe," she told the AAUP.</p>
<p>Kenneth Nunn is a former law professor at the University of Florida. He said good job candidates who are Black are no longer considering Florida schools, "because they see attacks on CRT as attacks on what they do."</p>
<p><strong>What comes next?</strong></p>
<p>In its report, the AAUP said it offered the chancellor, or top leader, of the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fldoe.org/schools/higher-ed/fl-college-system/about-us/colleges.stml" target="_blank">Florida College System</a>, a chance to present Florida's side of the story. The chancellor, Kathy Hebda, said no because, she said, the AAUP would not "fairly and fully consider any testimony."</p>
<p>When the sanction came out, a representative from New College of Florida noted that the AAUP's decision has no ability to force changes or prevent a university from operating. In a statement to the <em>Tampa Bay Times</em>, New College spokesman Nathan March called the report an attempt to get attention.</p>
<p>The AAUP did say it is not too late to prevent what happened at New College of Florida from happening in other places.</p>
<p>"The time for intervention has not passed—yet. We call on all professional organizations, unions, faculty, students, staff, administrators, and communities across the country to fight such "reforms"," it wrote. The group called academic freedom an important part of democratic societies.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for VOA Learning English based on AAUP's report and news reports and information.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pursue </strong>–<em>v</em>. to seek something that is difficult to find or catch</p>
<p><strong>academic </strong>–<em>adj</em>. related to education especially college education; something that is found in schools but not in professional life or the real world</p>
<p><strong>tenure </strong>–<em>n</em>. the right to have a job for life that exists mainly in academic jobs</p>
<p><strong>plagiarism </strong>–<em>n</em>. the charge of having copied someone's writings without their permission, outside of normal rules</p>
<p><strong>bode </strong>–v. to be a sign of the future</p>
<p><strong>standards </strong>–<em>n</em>. (pl.) a level of quality or ability that must be reached and maintained</p>
<p><strong>sanction </strong>–<em>v</em>. to speak out against something</p>
<p><strong>unprecedented </strong>–<em>adj</em>. something that has never happened before</p>
<p><strong>quirky </strong>–<em>adj</em>. having unusual qualities that are not generally considered normal</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you worried about restrictions on academic freedom? Do you feel there is academic freedom where you live? </em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Read the Riot Act  (2024/3/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/read-the-riot-act.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>In life, there are times when we must tell others about their bad behavior or unsafe actions. Sometimes that means giving them a strongly worded warning or <strong>scolding </strong>them. We can also <u>read them the riot act.</u></p>
<p>A riot is a violent public disorder. And that is where the expression comes from.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Students clash with riot police in front of the Greek Parliament during a demonstration against the government's plans for private universities, in Athens, Feb. 1, 2024. (Photo by Angelos TZORTZINIS / AFP)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-85a7-08dc2355e3e6_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Students clash with riot police in front of the Greek Parliament during a demonstration against the government's plans for private universities, in Athens, Feb. 1, 2024. (Photo by Angelos TZORTZINIS / AFP)
</span></div>
<p>The <em>Merriam-Webster</em> online dictionary says it dates back to the early 1700s England, when opponents of King George I began a series of protests.</p>
<p>The British government wanted to stop the protests. So, they passed a law called the "Riot Act." It permitted officials to break up gatherings of 12 or more people by reading a speech out-loud. If the protestors did not leave, they would be guilty of a crime punishable by death. By 1819, "riot act" was also being used more generally for any severe warning or <strong>reprimand.</strong></p>
<p>The law is no longer enforced <strong>across the pond</strong>, as we sometimes refer to Britain. But the term <u>to read the riot act</u> is still alive and well today.</p>
<p>We read someone the riot act to severely scold them. Reading the riot act can include some shouting – and, in fact, often does.</p>
<p>We can use this expression in just about any situation where someone has made a big mistake – at work, with our friends, and with our family.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear it used between two friendly coworkers who are talking about a family situation.</p>
<p><em>A: Wow, who was that on the phone? I could hear her yelling at you all the way over here. </em></p>
<p><em>B: It was my aunt reading me the riot act. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Why? What did you do?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Well, I forgot to go to her house for dinner last night. And she made all my favorite dishes.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Oh. That is a big mistake. I'm not surprised she read you the riot act. </em></p>
<p><em>B: And it was her birthday.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Oh wow. I'm surprised she is still speaking to you.</em></p>
<p><em>B: I know! I feel awful! So, to make it up to her, I'm taking her out to dinner at a restaurant that serves HER favorite dishes. </em></p>
<p>If VOA Learning English stopped teaching English, our listeners would have every right to read us the riot act.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories.</em></p>
<p>Until next time ... I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scold </strong><em>– v.</em><strong> </strong>to find fault noisily or angrily : to criticize severely or angrily</p>
<p><strong>reprimand </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>severe or formal criticism</p>
<p><strong>across the pond </strong><em>– idiomatic expression </em>the other side of the Atlantic Ocean</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Cyprus, Former Pilot Makes Halloumi Cheese the Old Ways  (2024/3/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/in-cyprus-former-pilot-makes-halloumi-cheese-the-old-ways.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>On a recent cold winter night in the Cypriot capital Nicosia, long lines of people began to form in a public parking area. The crowd was gathering for the arrival of cheesemaker Pantelis Panteli and the load of Halloumi he had for sale.</p>
<p>Panteli is a relative newcomer to the tradition of Halloumi-making. He had a career as a pilot with Cyprus Airways until 2013, He lost the job as the former company started closing down. Panteli decided to try a very different line of work: cheese-making. The man had found his new career.</p>
<p>But, now the newcomer has become an unlikely defender of traditional cheese-making for Cyprus's prized Halloumi.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Pantelis Panteli (R) and a worker prepare halloumi on his farm in Kokkinotrimithia, Cyprus February 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Yiannis Kourtoglou)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-2a0e-08dc37c92cd7_cx0_cy8_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Pantelis Panteli (R) and a worker prepare halloumi on his farm in Kokkinotrimithia, Cyprus February 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Yiannis Kourtoglou)</span></div>
<p>The European Union named Halloumi a product of Protected Designation of Origin (PDO) in 2021. That means that only approved producers from Cyprus can market the cheese under that name. In exchange for the PDO, Cyprus agreed to increase the quantity of ewe or goat milk to just over 50 percent by July 2024.</p>
<p>But Cypriot farmers are protesting the agreement over a dispute about the <strong>ingredients</strong>. Industry <strong>stakeholders</strong> say ewe and goat's milk is highly seasonal, and could therefore affect production levels. Cheese makers had threatened to shut their operations because there was not enough milk. And cattle-raising farmers were angered at the threat to the milk cow market.</p>
<p>So Cyprus officials now plan to delay the agreement to 2029.</p>
<p><strong>Halloumi debate</strong></p>
<p>Soft, rubbery Halloumi can be eaten raw. There are also many ways to cook it --- over a fire or heated in liquid or oil. The cheese keeps its shape well in cooking. It is a popular food and the island's second largest export. Medicines are first.</p>
<p>But there is a dispute within Cyprus about what makes true Halloumi cheese. Should it be made from cow's milk which has a <strong>mellower</strong> taste? Or should it be made from goat and ewe milk, as traditionalists argue?</p>
<p>Panteli started making Halloumi with guidance from a family member. "It was all trial and error with a small pot, then a bigger pot - and just like Steve Jobs - in our <strong>garage</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>He uses ewe's milk to make his Halloumi. He cooks the milk in <strong>rennet</strong> which thickens the liquid to a solid form called a curdle. After resting, curdles are cut and reheated. Panteli adds salt and puts them in a solution called brine for a few hours. Then, they are done and he prepares for market.</p>
<p>Panteli only has a permit to sell directly to <strong>consumers</strong>. And he is limited to producing 150 liters of milk a day.</p>
<p>But his product is popular. He makes videos on TikTok and the social media service X to let people know where to find him. He usually sells all his cheese within two hours of opening sales.</p>
<p>"Nobody is making the real thing anymore, and that is our aim," Panteli said. He spoke to the Reuters news agency while standing near about 300 noisy sheep at his farm west of Nicosia.</p>
<p>But some farmers on the Mediterranean island say that Panteli's method is not workable for all.</p>
<p>Nicos Papakyriakou is head of the organization that represents cow farmers. He said that based on an older 1985 trade agreement, Halloumi cheese is made out of not only goat and ewes' milk but cows' milk as well.</p>
<p>He says the mellow taste of cows' milk has permitted Halloumi to capture overseas markets. "The PDO says it should smell like a farm," he said. He questioned if people would buy it if it smelled "like goats!"</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Michelle Kambas reported this story for Reuters. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ingredient</strong> - n. things that are used to make a food product</p>
<p><strong>stakeholder</strong> - n. person or business that invests money in something</p>
<p><strong>mellow</strong> - adj. having a pleasing flavor</p>
<p><strong>garage</strong> - n. part of a building in which a car is kept</p>
<p><strong>rennet</strong> - n. a substance used in cheese-making to separate milk into curdles</p>
<p><strong>consumer</strong> - n. a person who buys goods and services</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Harmful Waste Creation Set to Increase  (2024/3/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/report-harmful-waste-creation-set-to-increase.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>The United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP) said in a report on Wednesday that public waste creation will greatly increase by 2050. The rise will cause hundreds of billions of dollars of damage through <strong>biodiversity</strong> loss, climate change, and deadly pollution, UNEP reports.</p>
<p>UNEP's Global Waste Management Outlook 2024 says worldwide waste creation would greatly increase unless governments take urgent preventative measures. The world's fastest-growing economies will drive much of the increase in waste. These include some countries in Asia and sub-Saharan Africa that are already struggling to deal with current public waste levels.</p>
<p>The report predicts municipal solid waste generation will grow from 2.3 billion tonnes in 2023 to 3.8 billion tonnes by 2050. UNEP projected the yearly cost of waste treatment by the middle of the century would rise to $640 billion worldwide. That represents a more than 75 percent increase from 2020. That year, the world produced an estimated 2.1 billion tonnes of public solid waste, which excludes industrial waste.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A woman walks through a landfill looking for salvageable items, in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, Saturday, July 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Odelyn Joseph)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-ac9a-08db7e901def_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A woman walks through a landfill looking for salvageable items, in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, Saturday, July 1, 2023. (AP Photo/Odelyn Joseph)</span></div>
<p>Damage caused by the growing waste would account for about $443 billion of the total cost.</p>
<p>The report, called <em>Beyond an Age of Waste: Turning Rubbish into a Resource</em>, was released during the U.N. Environment Assembly in Kenya this week. The writers argue that humanity has "moved backwards" over the past ten years. They say humans are creating more waste, more pollution, and more climate changing gases.</p>
<p>Waste prevention measures and improved waste treatment could reduce those costs, the report said. But it notes, there are major barriers to such reforms, including weak enforcement systems.</p>
<p>Negotiators are working toward a treaty to deal with the especially damaging and dangerous pollution from plastics. They are beginning a fourth round of talks in April. UNEP Executive Director Inger Andersen said she is hopeful they will complete the agreement by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Environmentalists and <strong>fossil fuel</strong> producers continue to disagree about the terms of the agreement. They especially dispute whether the deal should center on reducing plastics production or increasing <strong>recycling </strong>and re-use.</p>
<p>"There is an interest, and especially among the countries that are producing raw polymer, but as I keep telling them, this is not an anti-plastic treaty," Andersen told Reuters, noting there would still be a need for plastics in vehicles and medical equipment.</p>
<p>Raw polymers are used in the creation of plastic materials.</p>
<p>Andersen said she hopes no delegations would work to block progress on the treaty, but instead "find a way forward that actually takes into account the fact that we are drowning in plastic."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Aaron Ross reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>biodiversity </strong><em>– n. </em>the existence of many different kinds of plants and animals in an environment</p>
<p><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>– n.</em> a fuel (such as coal, oil, or natural gas) that is formed in the earth from dead plants or animals</p>
<p><strong>recycle </strong><em>– v.</em> to make something new from (something that has been used before)</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Must’ or ‘Have To’?  (2024/3/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202403/must-or-have-to.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 March 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on Ask a Teacher, we answer a question from Mequanent Antigegn.</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>"Must vs have to"--I find it difficult to differentiate them.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="'Must' or 'Have To'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-a3df-08dc396cb585_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">'Must' or 'Have To'</span></div>
<p><em>You must wear your <strong>uniform</strong> in the classroo</em>m. Or <em>You have to wear your uniform in the classroom</em>.</p>
<p>Which one is correct?</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for this question. "Must" and "have to" can have the same meaning. We have talked about "must" and "have to" in an earlier <em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/ask-a-teacher-must-and-have-to/4686883.html" target="_blank">Ask a Teacher</a></em>.</p>
<p>Both of the sentences you provide are correct. Sometimes it is better to choose "must" over "have to" or "have to" over "must."</p>
<p><strong>Must</strong></p>
<p>When we use must in spoken English, usually it is to express something we think is likely. In that case, it is similar in meaning to the word "probably."</p>
<p><em>You <u>must</u> be cold after working all day in the rain.</em></p>
<p>You are probably cold after working all day in the rain.</p>
<p><em>My supervisor <u>must</u> not care about the budget cuts.</em></p>
<p>My supervisor probably doesn't care about the budget cuts.</p>
<p>But, we also use it as we use "have to," although more commonly in writing.</p>
<p><em>Climate change <u>must</u> be stopped.</em></p>
<p><em>You <u>must</u> see the doctor before Friday.</em></p>
<p><strong>Have to</strong></p>
<p>"Have to," "have got to" and its reduced form "gotta," are used very often in spoken language to communicate requirement.</p>
<p><em>I <u>have to</u> get up at 5am tomorrow.</em></p>
<p><em>You <u>gotta</u> relax.</em></p>
<p>So, which sentence should you use? It depends on the context. Are you wanting to express a probability? Or are you trying to give an order or announce a rule?</p>
<p>And now we must say goodbye! We have to check the mail for new questions about American English! If you have one, send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Caty Weaver wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>uniform</strong>—<em>n</em>. a special set of clothes someone has to wear to work or school</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Dubai, a Race for ‘Iron Men’ Wearing Jet Suits  (2024/3/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/in-dubai-a-race-for-iron-men-wearing-jet-suits.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The pilots started their jet engines on a runway in the United Arab Emirates city of Dubai on Wednesday. But they were not preparing to fly an aircraft. They themselves would fly — in the first-ever "jet suit race."</p>
<p>The seven pilots with jet engines on their backs raced along the tall buildings of Dubai like a <strong>scene</strong> from the movie <em>Iron Man</em>.</p>
<p>"The closest <strong>analogy</strong> would be that dream of flying... and then going wherever your mind is taking you," said Richard Browning. He is the founder and chief test pilot for Gravity Industries, the company that held the race with Dubai.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Jet suit pilots race in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, Wednesday, Feb. 28, 2024. Dubai on Wednesday hosted what it called its first-ever jet suit race. (AP Photo/Jon Gambrell)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-5fd1-08dc3949262a_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Jet suit pilots race in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, Wednesday, Feb. 28, 2024. Dubai on Wednesday hosted what it called its first-ever jet suit race. (AP Photo/Jon Gambrell)</span></div>
<p>Browning added that the movie created the scene using computer technology, but his company did it "for real."</p>
<p>The pilots wore 1,500-<strong>horsepower</strong> jet suits for the race. Those engines have more mechanical power than most sports cars and use the same fuel as the Airbus A380 and Boeing 777 passenger jets.</p>
<p>Then came what pilot Issa Kalfon called "the moment of truth." The engines <strong>roared</strong> and pilots jumped and <strong>leaned</strong> forward. And they took off like a helicopter.</p>
<p>Organizers said they took off from the runway next to the water to enable higher speeds. The jet suit currently can reach speeds of 128 kilometers an hour, Gravity Industries said. It is also safer for the pilots to fly short distances above water.</p>
<p>Kalfon, who won the race, said he was nervous before his flight. "Everything's hot, it's running, the engines are screaming at you," Kalfon said. But he said the jet suit was safe and easy to <strong>handle</strong>.</p>
<p>There was one crash during Wednesday's race.</p>
<p>Emirati pilot Ahmed al-Shehhi smashed into the water, going feet first but immediately came to the surface to give a <strong>thumbs-up</strong> to rescuers. An announcer described him as having just 12 days of training before the race.</p>
<p>"It's pretty amazing to see that they can do this in Dubai, and they have these guys flying over the water," said Jennifer Ross, an American who lives in Dubai. "It's kind of like astronauts flying around in space."</p>
<p>With its beaches, bars and buildings, Dubai has long been a city known for its love of aviation. The city is home to the world's busiest airport for international travel. It also has been developing the idea of flying taxis for several years.</p>
<p>There are risks to jet suit travel, however.</p>
<p>In 2020, Vincent Reffet died in a crash during training for a different flying project. He was famous for once flying alongside a two-level Emirates A380 jet.</p>
<p>I'm Dorothy Gundy.</p>
<p><em>Jon Gambrell reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>scene</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a part of a movie or play</p>
<p><strong>analogy</strong> <em>–n.</em> a comparison between two things that share some quality that is meaningful</p>
<p><strong>horsepower </strong><em>–n.</em> a traditional measure of mechanical power that is used in the United States and Britain</p>
<p><strong>roar </strong><em>–v.</em> to make a load noise similar to the sound a lion or tiger makes</p>
<p><strong>lean </strong><em>–v.</em> to position oneself at an angle rather than straight up and down</p>
<p><strong>handle </strong><em>–v.</em> to control, drive or manage the direction of something</p>
<p><strong>thumbs-up </strong><em>–n.</em> a sign given by people to show they are safe or in good condition which involves raising the thump of the hand upward</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. </em></p>
<p><em>Our comment policy is </em><a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html" target="_blank" title="https://www.51voa.com/p/5378.html"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Arctic Vault Gets More Seeds  (2024/3/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/arctic-vault-gets-more-seeds.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Svalbard Global Seed <strong>Vault</strong> is on an island halfway between Europe and the North Pole. It contains frozen seeds of food crops from around the world.</p>
<p>The vault opened in 2008 to help keep crops safe from <strong>extinction</strong>.</p>
<p>This week, the vault received seeds from the largest number of new <strong>contributors</strong> ever. Contributors give seeds from their collections of seeds, called seed banks.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The entrance to the international gene bank Svalbard Global Seed Vault (SGSV) is pictured outside Longyearbyen on Spitsbergen, Norway, February 29, 2016. (REUTERS/Heiko Junge/NTB Scanpix)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-ea08-08dc388643ed_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The entrance to the international gene bank Svalbard Global Seed Vault (SGSV) is pictured outside Longyearbyen on Spitsbergen, Norway, February 29, 2016. (REUTERS/Heiko Junge/NTB Scanpix)</span></div>
<p>Twenty-three seed banks took part, nine of them for the first time. The new contributors came from Bosnia and Herzegovina, Cameroon, Indonesia, Kazakhstan, Kenya, Madagascar, Nigeria and Zambia.</p>
<p>Crop Trust is a non-profit group that operates the vault along with Norwegian officials. Crop Trust said the boxes of seeds arrived on Tuesday. They contained crop seeds such as beans, barley, cowpea, maize, rice, millet and sorghum.</p>
<p>Stefan Schmitz is Executive Director of Crop Trust. He said that keeping the seeds frozen in the Arctic helps <strong>guarantee</strong> food security for the future.</p>
<p>The vault is set in permafrost caves. The seeds are kept at temperatures around -18 degrees Celsius.</p>
<p>Between 2015 and 2019, the vault helped rebuild seed collections that were damaged during the war in Syria.</p>
<p>Crop Trust said many of the seeds given on Tuesday were the result of a worldwide 10-year <strong>biodiversity</strong> project known as BOLD. The project aims to support <strong>global</strong> food and nutrition security, the trust added.</p>
<p>Norway's ministry of agriculture and food said 111 seed banks in 77 countries now have crop seeds in Svalbard.</p>
<p>The Crop Trust website says the vault currently has over 1 million seed <strong>samples</strong>. It also says the vault has room to hold 4.5 million varieties of crops.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting from Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>vault </strong><em>-n. </em>A secure room to where valuable things can be kept safely.</p>
<p><strong>extinction </strong><em>-n. </em>the death and end of existence of all the remaining members of a species</p>
<p><strong>contributor </strong><em>-n. </em>a person or organization supplying money, goods, work, and the like.</p>
<p><strong>guarantee </strong><em>-v. </em>to make sure something will happen or be the case</p>
<p><strong>biodiversity </strong><em>-n. </em>the existence of a large variety of species</p>
<p><strong>global </strong><em>-adj. </em>describing the entire world</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Army Announces New Structure, Reduced Positions  (2024/3/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-army-announces-new-structure-reduced-positions.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The U.S. Army recently announced new structuring plans for its forces. The plans involve cutting many unfilled jobs after hiring efforts failed to bring in enough soldiers to fill all job openings.</p>
<p>The Army is cutting about 24,000, or almost 5 percent, of jobs, and restructuring to be better prepared for the future.</p>
<p>The cuts will mainly be in already-unoccupied jobs — not soldiers. These include jobs related to <strong>counterinsurgency</strong>. Those jobs grew in number during the Iraq and Afghanistan wars. About 3,000 of the cuts would come from Army special operations forces.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - U.S. Army soldiers march during a joint military drill of South Korea and the United States in Paju, South Korea, Friday, Jan. 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Ahn Young-joon)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/58bd1b1d-e517-4feb-b82b-ca91a47ddda7_cx8_cy4_cw88_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - U.S. Army soldiers march during a joint military drill of South Korea and the United States in Paju, South Korea, Friday, Jan. 13, 2023. (AP Photo/Ahn Young-joon)</span></div>
<p>However, the new plan will add about 7,500 troops in other missions. These include air-defense and counter-drone units and five new task forces around the world with increased <strong>cyber-</strong>, intelligence and long-distance strike capabilities.</p>
<p>Army Secretary Christine Wormuth said she and General Randy George, the Army chief, reduced the number of openings.</p>
<p>"We're moving away from counterterrorism and counterinsurgency. We want to be<strong> postured</strong> for large-scale combat operations," Wormuth told reporters recently. "So, we looked at where were there pieces of force structure that were probably more associated with counterinsurgency, for example, that we don't need anymore."</p>
<p>George added that Army leaders did a lot of careful study to choose the places to cut.</p>
<p>"The things that we want to not have in our <strong>formation</strong> are actually things that we don't think are going to make us successful on the battlefield going forward," he said.</p>
<p>An Army document said the cuts are "spaces" not "faces," and the Army will not be asking soldiers to leave the force.</p>
<p>Instead, the decision reflects the reality that for years the Army has not been able to fill thousands of empty jobs. While the Army can have up to 494,000 soldiers, the total number of active-duty soldiers right now is about 445,000. Under the new plan, the goal is to bring in enough troops over the next five years to reach a level of 470,000.</p>
<p>The measures come after more than 20 years of war in Iraq and Afghanistan forced the Army to change. The changes included counterinsurgency forces to fight al-Qaida, the Taliban, and the Islamic State group.</p>
<p>The military's attention has moved to "great power competition" from countries such as China and Russia, and threats from Iran and North Korea. The war in Ukraine has shown the need for greater attention to air-defense systems and the latest ways to use and to counter <strong>drones</strong> in the air and in the sea.</p>
<p>Army leaders said they looked carefully at all the service's job specialties in search of places to cut. They examined the ongoing effort to modernize the Army with new high-technology weapons and to make decisions about additional forces.</p>
<p>The changes are partly a result of the <strong>recruiting</strong> problems all military services are facing.</p>
<p>In the last U.S. government budget year, which ended September 30, the Navy, Army, and Air Force all failed to meet their recruitment goals. The Marine Corps and the very small Space Force did meet their goals. The Army recruited a little over 50,000 soldiers, falling short of the publicly stated goal of 65,000.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Lolita C. Baldor reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>counterinsurgency<em> </em></strong><em>– n. </em>action by an army, etc., against people who are fighting to take control of a government</p>
<p><strong>cyber </strong><em>–prefix</em> related to computers, computer networks and securing the information on them</p>
<p><strong>posture </strong><em>– v.</em> to position</p>
<p><strong>formation</strong> –<em> n.</em> an arrangement of people, ships, or airplanes</p>
<p><strong>drone</strong><em> –n.</em> a vehicle that is operated remotely which has no pilot or driver</p>
<p><strong>recruit </strong>–<em> v.</em> to find suitable people and get them to join the armed forces</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Cuba Cuts Internet, Surveils Journalists  (2024/3/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/report-cuba-cuts-internet-surveils-journalists.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>There was a time when activists and reporters in Cuba had to speak in <strong>code</strong> or meet in European embassies to avoid government observation.</p>
<p>Now, the internet and <strong>encrypted</strong> messaging services offers some assistance. But as technology has made private communicating easier, Havana has found ways to interfere with, or block, messages.</p>
<p>Cuba's independent reporters<strong> </strong>take care to protect their phones so they do not go into the hands of officials. If government agents seize an individual's phone, they will search through its data for evidence of wrongdoing.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Young people use a hotspot to connect to the internet, in Havana, Cuba, June 06, 2019. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/9f463533-913f-46cb-8ac7-0b17585bf44a_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Young people use a hotspot to connect to the internet, in Havana, Cuba, June 06, 2019. </span></div>
<p>The Cuban Institute for Freedom of Expression and Press, or ICLEP, says it documented at least 210 incidents of internet restriction cases in the country in 2023.</p>
<p>Those restrictions can include cutting internet <strong>access</strong>, blocking social media sites, or <strong>hacking</strong> the accounts of reporters or the media websites they work for, the ICLEP report found.</p>
<p>Normando Hernandez is founder and director general of Miami, Florida-based ICLEP. He said the government tries to "silence independent journalists."</p>
<p>"It is historically well known that the Cuban state listens and spies on all the <strong>conversations</strong> it wants to," Hernandez said. "Cubans have no way to defend themselves against any <strong>breach</strong> of their rights."</p>
<p>Reporter Henry Constantin says his internet was cut suddenly after La Hora de Cuba, the media site for which he works, began criticizing the Cuban government.</p>
<p>La Hora de Cuba is published on Facebook and Instagram. Its team of 15 reporters has an audience of between 46,000 and 48,000 on social media.</p>
<p>Constantin says disconnecting journalists' telephone lines or internet access is designed to limit free speech. Hernandez said the government controls all access to digital expression.</p>
<p>Havana controls the Cuban telecommunications company ETECSA, which controls all digital communications on the island.</p>
<p>Access to the network for users represents both a threat to Havana and an instrument of control for officials. But with that control, said Hernandez, officials can easily "cut communication in general at historically important moments ... or when something is happening in the island of interest to Cuban society."</p>
<p>That appears to be the case with Constantin.</p>
<p>In 2021, he was detained for 10 days for public disorder after reporting on demonstrations against the government over food shortages and medicinal problems.</p>
<p>ICLEP has documented digital <strong>harassment</strong> since 2016.</p>
<p>In 2021, the activity was especially strong. ICLEP documented 1,129 violations of freedom of expression that year. During that year, protests against the Cuban government and Communist Party were the biggest since the 1959 revolution.</p>
<p>Prisoners Defenders International is a Spain-based human rights group. It said Cuba's government has been spying on reporters and activists for many years. Javier Larrondo is president of Prisoners Defenders. He said the government monitors text messages for "sensitive words."</p>
<p>Using encrypted services like WhatsApp or Telegram is not always enough. When reporters or opposition activists are arrested, their phones are always seized and the memory inspected by experts.</p>
<p>"As such, it is <strong>essential</strong> never to go out with a mobile phone but to leave it at home, hidden." Or to go out with a second phone without memory, he said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Graham Keeley wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>code </strong><em>— n. </em> a set of letters, numbers, symbols, etc., that is used to secretly send messages to someone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>encrypted </strong><em>— adj. </em>to change from one form to another especially to hide its meaning</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>access </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of being able to use or get something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hack </strong><em>— v. </em>to secretly get access to the files on a computer or network in order to get information, cause damage, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breach </strong><em>— v. </em>a failure to do what is required by a law, an agreement, or a duty : failure to act in a required or promised way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>harass </strong><em>— v. </em>to annoy or bother in a constant or repeated way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>essential </strong><em>— adj. </em>extremely important and necessary</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Breaking the Rules with Miley Cyrus’ ‘Flowers’  (2024/3/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/breaking-the-rules-with-miley-cyrus-flowers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Jill Robbins</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Every year, the Recording Academy in the United States gives awards to the performers and songwriters with the most outstanding <strong>achievements</strong> from the year before. The Academy calls those awards "the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://newsroom.ap.org/detail/GrammyAward/c4cf1e8a33aa407e81a41363730f51da">Grammys</a>."</p>
<p>At the 2024 Grammy awards, the Song of the Year award went to Miley Cyrus for her song <em>Flowers</em>. In today's lesson, we will look at some grammar rules Cyrus follows in the song and one rule she breaks. The song begins with the story of a break-up:</p>
<p><em>We were good, we were gold</em><br/>
<em>Kinda dream that can't be sold</em><br/>
<em>We were right 'til we weren't</em><br/>
<em>Built a home and watched it burn</em></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar: Breaking the Ruke With Miley Cyrus' 'Flowers'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b31f-08dc37a9b0c2_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar: Breaking the Ruke With Miley Cyrus' 'Flowers'</span></div>
<p><em>Mm, I didn't wanna leave you</em><br/>
<em>I didn't wanna lie</em><br/>
<em>Started to cry, but then remembered I... </em></p>
<p>In this first part, Cyrus uses an informal adverb, "kinda," to describe the dream she and her partner had. In formal language, she would say, "It was the <em>kind of</em> dream that can't be sold." We expect to hear informal language in songs, so this is not really breaking any rules.</p>
<p>She follows with another informal word, the verb form "wanna," in "I didn't wanna leave you, I didn't wanna lie." It is very common to hear this pronunciation in spoken English of the words "want to."</p>
<p><strong>Reflexive pronoun rule</strong></p>
<p>Next, we get to where Cyrus follows and breaks the same rule. She describes the expressive actions of a romantic partner that she can do for herself. Her song tells us about the kinds of things a romantic partner might do, but Cyrus says she, as an independent woman, can do those things without the partner.</p>
<p>Listen for the <strong>reflexive</strong> pronoun "myself" in these lines:</p>
<p><em>I can buy myself flowers</em></p>
<p><em>Write my name in the sand</em></p>
<p><em>Talk to myself for hours</em></p>
<p><em>Say things you don't understand</em></p>
<p><em>I can take myself dancing</em></p>
<p><em>And I can hold my own hand</em></p>
<p><em>Yeah, I can love me better than you can</em></p>
<p>Did you catch the place where she broke the rule about when to use a reflexive pronoun? The rule is: when the object and the subject of the verb are the same, use the reflexive pronoun to describe the object.</p>
<p>Cyrus follows this rule when she sings, "I can buy myself flowers," "talk to myself for hours" and "I can take myself dancing." But she breaks it when she sings, "I can love me better than you can."</p>
<p>Let's take a moment for a little quiz here. Can you say or sing the same line with the reflexive pronoun? Take a moment so you can think.</p>
<p>Following the rule, this should be "I can love myself better than you can." Cyrus probably uses "me" to match the beat of the music. Often, that is more important to singers than following grammar rules!</p>
<p><strong>Adjective "own"</strong></p>
<p>In one line of the song, Cyrus uses the adjective "own" to refer to things belonging to herself. Let's listen to that line:</p>
<p>And I can hold my own hand</p>
<p>Here, "own" is correct because it makes the action clear. If she had not used "own," we might not understand. She could be singing about holding her hand up, for example. "Hold my own hand" makes it clear to us that she is using one hand to hold another.</p>
<p>What do you think of Miley Cyrus' song? Are there any singers in your country who sing about their independence in this way?</p>
<p>Write to us at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a> and tell us about them.</p>
<p>And that's Everyday Grammar!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Jill Robbins wrote this lesson for Learning English.</em></p>
<span class="c-sticky-element__close-el c-sticky-element__swipe-el ta-c" title="close">
<span class="ico ico-close m-0"></span>
</span>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>achievement </strong>– <em>n.</em> something accomplished, especially by superior ability, special effort, or great courage</p>
<p><strong>reflexive (pronoun)</strong> <em>– adj. </em>a class of pronouns that refer back to the subject of a sentence or clause</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How to Use AI Tools to Improve Quality of Internet Searches  (2024/2/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/how-to-use-ai-tools-to-improve-quality-of-internet-searches.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Internet search companies have already built artificial intelligence (AI) tools into their systems. And the use of AI systems to support internet searches is expected to grow sharply in coming years.</p>
<p>Some technology experts feel this change can greatly improve the overall search experience for users. But experts also have concerns.</p>
<p>One early user, or adopter, of AI search is Google. The American-based company's search engine currently processes an estimated 80 percent of the world's internet search requests.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. Google said Thursday, Feb. 22, 2024,. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-eb47-08dc37e441aa_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Google logos are shown when searched on Google in New York, Sept. 11, 2023. Google said Thursday, Feb. 22, 2024,. (AP Photo/Richard Drew, File)</span></div>
<p>Microsoft's search engine Bing also includes AI-powered results. Bing's AI system is linked to the company's Copilot service. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/copilot">Copilot</a> is an AI tool designed to operate across a series of Microsoft business products.</p>
<p>Copilot is based on OpenAI's ChatGPT, which launched in late 2022. ChatGPT is a computer-powered AI tool designed to interact smoothly with humans.</p>
<p>Such AI tools – known as "chatbots" or "generative AI" – are trained on massive amounts of internet data. They have shown an ability to perform human-level writing and create high-quality images and videos based on short, written descriptions.</p>
<p>But these AI systems have also demonstrated possible risks. One risk is the tools can present false or misleading information as truth. They can also produce results that represent long-standing biases against minorities or underrepresented communities.</p>
<p>Here, we offer some guidance for users seeking new systems to provide improved and <strong>relevant</strong> search results.</p>
<p><strong>Where do I find AI search tools?</strong></p>
<p>Some major search companies have made it easy to find AI search engines on their main search pages.</p>
<p>Google's search system is powered by its own chatbot tool, called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://gemini.google.com/app">Gemini</a>. It can easily be found directly on desktop or mobile phone browsers. Gemini can be used to perform other chatbot actions as well as providing search assistance.</p>
<p>Google also has been testing a new search offering, called "Search Generative Experience." It replaces links with AI-produced briefs containing basic facts about a subject. This system is currently limited to U.S. users who sign up through Google's experimental Labs site.</p>
<p>To use AI with Microsoft's Bing search engine, simply click the Chat or Copilot button underneath the main search window. This should pull up an information box where users can enter their search requests.</p>
<p>New AI search sites have also launched. But they are not as easy to find. The Associated Press reports one way to find them is to perform searches for tools on Copilot or Gemini. Some to look out for include Perplexity, HuggingChat, You.com, Komo, Andi, Phind, Exa and AskAI.</p>
<p><strong>Do I have to sign up for or pay for these services?</strong></p>
<p>Most of these services have free versions. But generally, there are limits on how many searches a user can make. Users can also <strong>upgrade</strong> from basic services to higher levels providing smarter AI tools and more search possibilities.</p>
<p>Gemini users, for example, can pay $20 for an upgraded version that offers its "most<strong> capable</strong>" model, called Ultra 1.0.</p>
<p>Most of the startup sites are largely free to use and don't require setting up an account. Many also have upgrade possibilities.</p>
<p><strong>What are the results like?</strong></p>
<p>Unlike a traditional Google search, results from AI tools usually produce a longer, readable collection of information. Sometimes, the <strong>original</strong> source of information is also included. And in some cases, messages are included to warn users about possible misinformation appearing in the results.</p>
<p>It is a good idea to try out different AI tools. Results from each can differ, sometimes wildly. The AP reports that results from AI-assisted search tools can be especially useful when searching for more <strong>obscure</strong> facts or information.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><strong>________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>relevant </strong><em>– adj. </em>related to or useful to what is happening or being talked about</p>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– n. </em>an improvement to something that is higher quality or a newer model</p>
<p><strong>capable </strong><em>– adj. able to do something </em></p>
<p><strong>original </strong><em>– adj. </em>where something begins<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>obscure </strong><em>– adj. </em>not known by many people</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Nizhyn Pickles  (2024/2/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/nizhyn-pickles.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 February 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<p>My name is Liudmyla Shylova and I have been teaching English for 21 years in Nizhyn, Ukraine.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Nizhyn pickle monument in Nizhyn, Ukraine. (Courtesy photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-025c-08dc324cfa51_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Nizhyn pickle monument in Nizhyn, Ukraine. (Courtesy photo)</span></div>
<p>Nizhyn is a small city in northern Ukraine with more than a thousand years of history. But the city is, perhaps, best known for a small food item that can be found around the world: pickles.</p>
<p>If you ever taste Nizhyn pickles, you will understand why that small cucumber represents 300 years of the history, tradition, and taste of Ukrainian cuisine.</p>
<p>In the 17th century, Nizhyn was a Cossack city on the border of the Russian Empire. At that time, some Greeks sailed down the Oster River to escape from the Ottoman occupation. They brought their culture, traditions and, among other things, a recipe for salting cucumbers.</p>
<p>The Greeks valued the rich soil of Nizhyn and grew cucumbers to make pickles. The pickling process took place in wooden barrels that were bought from Nizhyn craftsmen. Their secret recipe contained spices from eastern markets and local water from the artesian springs.</p>
<p>The Greeks also paid much attention to the quality of cucumbers. The vegetables had to be the same size, neither big nor small. This permitted the cucumbers to be evenly salted and have a special crunch.</p>
<p>Eventually, Nizhyn pickles made by the Greeks found their admirers among the Cossacks, local people and even the royals. When Empress Catherine II of Russia traveled south through Nizhyn, she ordered pickles to her table. The Queen of Britain was also known to feast on those crunchy cucumbers.</p>
<p>In the 19th century, Nizhyn pickles became popular in many European countries. Traders made a lot of money selling them to people in Denmark, France, Sweden, Germany and Great Britain.</p>
<p>Nowadays, Nizhyn pickles can be found on supermarket shelves all over the world.</p>
<p>The product has since become a part of Ukrainian culture. In 2005, a monument to Ukraine's fruit and vegetable culture was opened near the local food factory. And a Nizhyn pickle was included in the list of winners of an international project on the food culture of Ukraine.</p>
<p>So, welcome to Nizhyn, and go ahead and taste our pickles!</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>___________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the writer</h2>
<p>Liudmyla Shylova has been teaching English for 21 years to both primary and secondary school students. Her motto is the expression of the American journalist Sydney J. Harris, "The whole purpose of education is to turn mirrors into windows." As a teacher, she tries to open a window to the children into the future, not just drill them in dry language. Shylova loves incorporating technology into her lessons and seeking innovative ways to engage her students.</p>
<p>_____________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Lesson Plan</h2>
<a href="/a/7497100.html">
<img alt="Lesson Plan - Nizhyn Pickles" src="https://gdb.51voa.com/01000000-0a00-0242-134e-08dc34999b69_w100_r0.png"/>
<span class="ico ico-document ico--media-type"></span>
</a>
<span class="caption">Nizhyn Pickles - Lesson Plan</span>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korea’s Fertility Rate Falls Again as Women Worry about Jobs  (2024/2/29) | 韩国生育率再次下降</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-korea-s-fertility-rate-falls-again-as-women-worry-about-jobs.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>South Korea's fertility rate, which already is the world's lowest, dropped again in 2023.<br/>
韩国的生育率已经是全球最低，但在2023年却再次下降。</p>
<p>This means that the number of babies a South Korean woman is expected to have during her reproductive years dropped from 0.78 in 2022 to 0.72 in 2023.<br/>
这意味着，韩国女性在生育期预计生育的婴儿数量从2022年的0.78下降到2023年的0.72。</p>
<p>Concerns about missing out on long-term jobs and the cost of raising a child are reasons given for the low rate.<br/>
人们担心失去长期工作和抚养孩子的成本是造成低生育率的原因。</p>
<p>The fertility number is much lower than the rate of 2.1 per woman that would be needed to keep South Korea's population stable.<br/>
韩国的生育率远低于保持人口稳定所需的每名女性生育2.1人。</p>
<p>In 2015, when the cost of housing and education were lower, the rate was 1.24. That means South Korea's population has been shrinking for a long time.<br/>
2015年，当住房和教育成本较低时，该比率为1.24。这意味着韩国的人口在很长一段时间内一直在减少。</p>
<p>The South Korean government is trying to encourage men and women to start families. Since 2018, the nation has been the only member of a group of large economies to have a rate below one. The Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development (OECD) includes a wide group of nations such as Britain, the United States, Australia, New Zealand as well as Mexico and Chile.<br/>
韩国政府正在努力鼓励男性和女性组建家庭。自2018年以来，韩国一直是某大型经济体组织中唯一生育率低于1的成员国。经济合作与发展组织包括英国、美国、澳大利亚、新西兰以及墨西哥和智利等众多国家。</p>
<p>Among OECD nations, South Korea has the largest difference in pay between men and women. Balancing motherhood with a job is a concern for South Korean women.<br/>
在经合组织国家中，韩国的男女薪酬差距最大。平衡母亲身份和工作是韩国女性关注的问题。</p>
<p>Jung Jae-hoon is a professor at Seoul Women's University. Jung noted that women have trouble moving their careers forward after taking leave to care for children.<br/>
郑在勋是首尔女子大学的教授。郑指出，女性在请假照顾孩子后，很难推进自己的事业。</p>
<p>An example of this is Gwak Tae-hee who is 34. She is concerned about missing career opportunities if she stops working to start a family. She has been married for three years and works as a manager for a company that makes milk products.<br/>
34岁的郭泰希就是一个例子。她担心如果自己停止工作去生头胎，会失去职业机会。她结婚三年了，在一家生产乳制品的公司担任经理。</p>
<p>"Having a baby is on my list, but there's windows for promotions and I don't want to be passed over," she said.<br/>
她说：“生孩子一直在我的考虑当中，但目前有晋升的机会，我不想被忽略。”</p>
<p>Gwak said she considered starting medical treatments last year that would help her have a child. However, she decided against it because she wanted to take on work projects that would help her career.<br/>
郭说，她去年考虑开始接受有助于受孕的治疗。然而，她决定放弃这样做，因为她想从事有助于她的职业生涯的工作项目。</p>
<p>"I hope it's not too late when I try next year or the year after," Gwak said.<br/>
郭说：“我希望明年或后年尝试时不会太晚。”</p>
<p>If the birth rate continues to drop, South Korea's population of about 51 million will be cut in half by 2100.<br/>
如果出生率继续下降，到2100年，韩国约5100万人口将减少一半。</p>
<p>In Seoul, the largest city and capital, the fertility rate is only 0.55.<br/>
在韩国最大城市和首都首尔，生育率只有0.55。</p>
<p>The nation has an election in April, and politicians have been offering ideas to make it easier for young adults to consider having children. The ideas include more housing and financial support for people thinking of having a family.<br/>
韩国将于4月举行大选，政客们一直在提出让年轻人更容易考虑生孩子的想法。这些想法包括为头胎家庭提供更多的住房和经济支持。</p>
<p>An official at Statistics Korea said there are some people who are a couple but do not get married. In South Korea, many people see marriage as a requirement to have children, so that reduces the number of babies. But the official told Reuters that right now the group is centering its work on trying to help married people feel better about starting families.<br/>
韩国统计局的一位官员说，有些人是情侣，但没有结婚。在韩国，许多人将结婚就要生孩子，所以这样做减少了婴儿的数量。但这位官员告诉路透社，目前该组织的工作重点是帮助已婚人士对生头胎感觉更踏实。</p>
<p>Politicians are worried that additional social spending has not encouraged more families. Since 2006, the government has spent about $270 billion in areas such as helping families pay for childcare, but the fertility numbers are still falling.<br/>
政客们担心，额外的社会支出并不能鼓励更多的家庭。自2006年以来，政府在帮助家庭支付育儿费用等领域花费了约2700亿美元，但生育率仍在下降。</p>
<p>South Korea, however, is not the only nation concerned about falling birth rates. China and Japan also recorded all-time low rates in 2022.<br/>
然而，韩国并不是唯一一个担心出生率下降的国家。2022年，中国和日本的生育率也创下历史新低。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: Famine Is Certain in Gaza without Cease-fire  (2024/2/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/un-famine-is-certain-in-gaza-without-cease-fire.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A United Nations official warned Tuesday that the Gaza Strip is at high risk of famine, an extreme lack of food, if the war there does not stop soon.</p>
<p>Ramesh Rajasingham is director of the coordination division in the U.N. <strong>humanitarian</strong> office.</p>
<p>"If nothing is done, we fear widespread famine in Gaza is almost <strong>inevitable</strong>, and the conflict, which since October has claimed the lives of almost 30,000 people and injured more than 70,000 ... will have many more victims," he said.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="Displaced Palestinian children wait to receive free food at a tent camp as the conflict between Israel and Hamas continues, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip, Feb. 27, 2024. (REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa
)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a60e-08dc37f96644_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">Displaced Palestinian children wait to receive free food at a tent camp as the conflict between Israel and Hamas continues, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip, Feb. 27, 2024. (REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa
)</span></div>
<p>Rajasingham spoke at a meeting of the U.N. Security Council requested by members Algeria, Guyana, Slovenia and Switzerland. There are rising concerns that hunger is being used as a weapon in the war.</p>
<p>Rajasingham said at least 576,000 people in Gaza — 25 percent of the population — are very close to famine. Almost the entire population is depending on food aid to survive, he said.</p>
<p>"Gaza is seeing the worst level of child malnutrition anywhere in the world," said Carl Skau, an official with the U.N.'s World Food Program (WFP).</p>
<p><strong>Agricultural production collapsing</strong></p>
<p>Maurizio Martina is assistant director-general of the U.N.'s Food and Agriculture Organization. He explained how the entire food supply chain has been impacted by the war. He said Israel has forced farmers to leave their land or flee shelling that has destroyed crops. Farm animals are dying from hunger or killed in bombings. Fishing is banned and ground water is polluted.</p>
<p>"In the most likely scenario, agricultural production will have collapsed in the north by May 2024," Martina said. "We are already seeing this collapse."</p>
<p><strong>Flow of aid 'unpredictable,' 'insufficient'</strong></p>
<p>Martin Griffiths is the U.N. humanitarian chief. He said humanitarians continue to face serious difficulties in providing aid.</p>
<p>"These include border crossing closures, serious movement restrictions, access denials, <strong>onerous</strong> <strong>vetting</strong> procedures, security risks, incidents by desperate civilians, a breakdown of law and order, and restrictions on communications and protective equipment," Griffiths wrote.</p>
<p>Israel denies it is restricting or limiting the delivery of aid to Gaza.</p>
<p>"Israel is doing all it can to care for civilians, going above and beyond what is expected, let alone required," Israel's deputy U.N. envoy Jonathan Miller told the council.</p>
<p>Miller said Israel has helped the delivery of 254,000 tons of relief supplies into Gaza since the start of the war, including 165,000 tons of food. He blamed Hamas for <strong>diverting</strong> aid and the U.N. for failing to properly manage and distribute it.</p>
<p><strong>Famine 'imminent' in northern Gaza</strong></p>
<p>The situation is most serous in northern Gaza, which remains cut off by the Israeli military.</p>
<p>About 300,000 people are believed to have ignored Israel's earlier <strong>evacuation</strong> order and remained through months of heavy fighting between the Israel Defense Forces and Hamas.</p>
<p>"If nothing changes, a famine is <strong>imminent</strong> in northern Gaza," WFP's Skau said.</p>
<p>The U.N. agency that assists Palestinians, UNRWA, delivers most of the relief supplies. It says the last time it was able to get food aid to northern Gaza was on January 23. On February 20, the World Food Program suspended its deliveries to the north because of a lack of security in the area. The World Health Organization last reached Gaza City's largest hospital, Al Shifa, on January 22 with medical supplies.</p>
<p>One week ago, the 15-nation Security Council failed to pass an agreement calling for an immediate humanitarian cease-fire because of a veto from the United States. Several council members repeated their call for a cease-fire at Tuesday's meeting.</p>
<p>Even Israel's closest ally, the United States, displayed its growing displeasure with the slow delivery of aid. It urged Israel to keep border crossings open and to open new ones.</p>
<p>"Simply put, Israel must do more," Ambassador Robert Wood said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Margaret Besheer wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>humanitarian </strong><em>— adj. </em>concerned with or seeking to promote human welfare</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inevitable </strong><em>— adj. </em>sure to happen</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>onerous </strong><em>— adj. </em>difficult and unpleasant to do or deal with</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>vet </strong><em>— v. </em>to check carefully to make sure it is acceptable</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>divert </strong><em>— v. </em>to change the direction or use of</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>evacuate </strong><em>— v. </em> to remove from a dangerous place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>imminent </strong><em>— adj. </em>happening very soon</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Large Study Details Years of Brain Changes in Alzheimer’s Patients  (2024/2/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/large-study-details-years-of-brain-changes-in-alzheimer-s-patients.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A long-term study in China has shown that a series of changes take place in the brains of people who get Alzheimer's disease long before they present signs of the sickness.</p>
<p>The large study followed middle-aged and older adults for 20 years. The individuals were examined on a regular basis during that period. The researchers used brain imaging, spinal fluid checks and other tools to collect data.</p>
<p>The researchers reported that the study subjects who later developed Alzheimer's showed high levels of disease-linked protein in their spinal fluid. The higher levels were recorded as much as 18 years before the patients were identified as having Alzheimer's.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A closeup of a human brain affected by Alzheimer's disease, is displayed at the Museum of Neuroanatomy at the University at Buffalo in Buffalo, New York, in 2003. (AP Photo/David Duprey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/dfb2f56e-4c19-401f-a6c2-e3d302c2b837_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A closeup of a human brain affected by Alzheimer's disease, is displayed at the Museum of Neuroanatomy at the University at Buffalo in Buffalo, New York, in 2003. (AP Photo/David Duprey)</span></div>
<p>Then every few years, the study <strong>detected</strong> another so-called biomarker of coming trouble.</p>
<p>Scientists still do not know exactly how Alzheimer's forms. The disease slowly destroys the brain, interfering with the ability to think. Alzheimer's patients develop proteins called beta-amyloid and tau, which over time build up into <strong>plaques</strong> that block brain processes.</p>
<p>The new research, published in the New England Journal of Medicine, offers a timeline for how these proteins develop.</p>
<p>The study's importance "cannot be overstated," said Dr. Richard Mayeux, an Alzheimer's specialist at Columbia University who was not involved in the research.</p>
<p>"Knowledge of the timing of these <strong>physiological</strong> events is critical" for testing new ways of treating and maybe even preventing Alzheimer's, he wrote in a piece published alongside the study report.</p>
<p>Scientists already knew that in rare, genetic forms of Alzheimer's that affect young people, a poisonous form of amyloid starts developing about 20 years ahead of symptoms. At some point after that, tau develops as well.</p>
<p>The new findings show the order of such biomarker changes common to age-related Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Researchers with Beijing's Innovation Center for Neurological Disorders compared 648 people who were later found with Alzheimer's to an equal number who remained healthy. The amyloid finding in future Alzheimer's patients was the main discovery.</p>
<p>Differences in tau were found next, followed by a marker of trouble in how neurons communicate. A few years after that, the study found differences in brain shrinkage and <strong>cognitive</strong> test scores between the two groups.</p>
<p>"The more we know about <strong>viable</strong> Alzheimer's treatment targets and when to address them, the better and faster we will be able to develop new <strong>therapies</strong> and preventions," said Claire Sexton, director of scientific programs with the Alzheimer's Association. She noted that blood tests are coming soon that promise to also help by making it easier to find amyloid and tau.</p>
<p>More than 6 million Americans, and millions more worldwide, have Alzheimer's. There is no cure.</p>
<p>But last year, Leqembi became the first approved drug that could slow the worsening of early Alzheimer's for a few months. The drug works by clearing away some of the amyloid protein. Other drugs are being developed to target tau.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in this Story</h2>
<p><strong>detect </strong>- <em>v. </em><strong> </strong>to discover or determine the existence, presence, or fact of something</p>
<p><strong>plaque </strong>- <em>n. </em>(medical) a histopathologic lesion of brain tissue that is characteristic of Alzheimer's disease and consists of a dense proteinaceous core composed primarily of beta-amyloid that is often surrounded and infiltrated by a cluster of degenerating axons and dendrites</p>
<p><strong>physiological </strong>- <em>adj. </em>of or relating to the organic processes and phenomena of an organism or any of its parts or of a particular bodily process</p>
<p><strong>cognitive </strong>- <em>adj. </em>of, relating to, being, or involving conscious intellectual activity (such as thinking, reasoning, or remembering)</p>
<p><strong>viable </strong>- <em>adj. </em>capable of working, functioning, or developing adequately</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong>- <em>n. </em><strong> </strong>treatment of an abnormal state of the mind or body</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Schools Want More Therapy for Students, Not All Parents Agree  (2024/2/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/schools-want-more-therapy-for-students-not-all-parents-agree.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Derry Oliver was in fifth <strong>grade</strong> when she first talked to her mother about seeing a <strong>therapist</strong>.</p>
<p>They were moving to New York City. Derry had to live with family members in another state while her mother, also named Derry Oliver, found a job and <strong>apartment</strong>. (In this story, we will call the daughter by her first name, Derry, and her mother by her family name, Oliver.)</p>
<p>It was a difficult year. A school worker suggested therapy. Derry's mother questioned the advice and disagreed with therapy.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Derry Oliver, 17, right, hugs her mother, also Derry Oliver, during a visit to a playground near home, Friday, Feb. 9, 2024, in New York. (AP Photo/Bebeto Matthews)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5cb6-08dc36f68dae_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Derry Oliver, 17, right, hugs her mother, also Derry Oliver, during a visit to a playground near home, Friday, Feb. 9, 2024, in New York. (AP Photo/Bebeto Matthews)</span></div>
<p>"You're so young. There's nothing wrong with you. These are <strong>growing pains</strong>," Oliver told her daughter.</p>
<p>However, Derry's depression got worse during the COVID-19 pandemic. She struggled with the loneliness of at-home learning. She reached out to her high school for help.</p>
<p>In New York, school-based mental health professionals like social workers can provide some <strong>counseling</strong> without parental permission. But therapy requires a parent's agreement.</p>
<p>"It was very emotional for both of us because I understood her <strong>frustrations</strong> and fears," Derry remembered. "But at the same time, it's sometimes best for your child to be able to <strong>access</strong> this rather than hold it away from them."</p>
<p><strong>Difficulties in getting therapy</strong></p>
<p>Using federal money from the pandemic, schools around the U.S. have employed more mental health specialists. They also add telehealth and online counseling to reach as many students as possible.</p>
<p>As treatments have become more readily available and more young people talk openly about mental health issues, schools are now facing difficulties in getting parents to agree to treatment.</p>
<p>Chelsea Trout is studying social work at New York University and is doing her training at a school in Brooklyn. She called it a "disconnect" between parents and children.</p>
<p>"The kids are all on TikTok or the internet and understand therapy-speak and that this is something that could be helpful for their mental health and are interested in...," said Trout. But she added that they may not have support from their parents.</p>
<p>Politics can also play a part. Some states are looking to make getting therapy without parental permission easier while others are proposing more restrictions.</p>
<p>The states of California and Colorado have recently lowered the age of consent for treatment to 12. But in some states like North Carolina, the issue is part of larger political debates on the input parents can have on school teachings as well as the rights of <strong>transgender</strong> students.</p>
<p>Cost is another issue. Therapy is rarely free. And paying for it often requires parental support.</p>
<p><strong>Parental support</strong></p>
<p>Research suggests that the need for parental permission can keep young people from getting treatment.</p>
<p>Jessica Chock-Goldman is a social worker at Bard Early College High School in New York City. She said that she has seen many cases where mental health issues turn severe partly because young people did not get earlier access to therapy.</p>
<p>For Derry and her mother, years of talking have led to some progress. Several years ago, her mother agreed to a compromise.</p>
<p>They found a Black female therapist, which was important to both of them as a Black family. Oliver agreed that her daughter could start therapy — as long as she could sit in on the meetings.</p>
<p>"It has to be someone trustworthy," Oliver said of a possible therapist for her daughter. But the therapist changed jobs after a month and Derry has not seen another therapist since.</p>
<p>Trout, the school social worker in training, said she has met many parents who, like Oliver, have trust issues.</p>
<p>"If we're thinking about <strong>predominantly</strong> Black and brown communities, if your interactions with social workers or mental health services or anything in that <strong>realm</strong> thus far have not been <strong>positive</strong>," Trout said, "how could you trust them with your kids?"</p>
<p><strong>Racial divide</strong></p>
<p>Statistics also show a racial divide.</p>
<p>In 2021, 14 percent of white children reported seeing a therapist at some point during that year. This number is compared to 9 percent of Black children, 8 percent of Hispanic children, and 3 percent of Asian American children. These numbers come from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p>
<p>Without access to therapy, Derry has sought advice about dealing with her emotions through friends, school social workers, and the Internet. But she feels that she could gain more with professional help.</p>
<p>Derry has already gotten into several colleges. One thing she is considering is what the school offers for therapy.</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Michael Elsen-Rooney reported this story for AP. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>grade</strong> <em>– n.</em> a level of study in an elementary, middle, or secondary school that is completed by a student during one year</p>
<p><strong>therapist </strong><em>– n. </em>a person trained in methods of treatment other than the use of drugs or surgery</p>
<p><strong>apartment </strong><em>– n. </em>a room or set of rooms used as a dwelling</p>
<p><strong>growing pains </strong><em>– n. </em>emotional difficulties or confusion experienced by a young person during the time between being a child and an adult</p>
<p><strong>counseling</strong> <em>– n. </em>professional guidance of the individual by utilizing psychological methods especially in collecting case history data, using various techniques of the personal interview, and testing interests and aptitudes</p>
<p><strong>frustration </strong><em>– n. </em>a deep chronic sense or state of insecurity and dissatisfaction arising from unresolved problems or unfulfilled needs</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> <em>– n. </em>freedom or ability to obtain or make use of something</p>
<p><strong>transgender</strong> <em>– adj. </em>of, relating to, or being a person whose gender identity is opposite the sex the person was identified as having at birth</p>
<p><strong>predominantly </strong><em>– adv. </em>for the most part</p>
<p><strong>realm</strong> <em>– n. </em>field of influence or activity</p>
<p><strong>positive </strong><em>– adj. </em>marked by or indicating acceptance, approval, or affirmation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>In Japan, Fewer Births, Marriages a Cause for Concern  (2024/2/28) | 日本低出生率和低结婚率成隐患</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/in-japan-fewer-births-marriages-a-cause-for-concern.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>The number of babies born in Japan last year fell to a new low for an eighth straight year, government data shows. In addition, the number of marriages continues to drop.<br/>
政府数据显示，去年日本出生人口数量连续第八年降至新低。此外，结婚人数继续下降。</p>
<p>The Health and Welfare Ministry reported Tuesday that 758,631 babies were born in Japan in 2023. That represented a 5.1 percent decline from the year earlier. It was the lowest number of births since Japan started recording the statistics in 1899.<br/>
日本厚生福利省周二报告称，2023年日本共有758631名婴儿出生。这比去年同期下降了5.1%。这是自1899年日本开始统计以来出生人口最低的一次。</p>
<p>The number of marriages fell by 5.9 percent to 489,281 couples, falling below a half-million for the first time in 90 years. Fewer marriages are one of the reasons for fewer births. Having children outside of marriage is rare in the East Asian country.<br/>
结婚人数下降了5.9%，降至489281对，近90年来首次降至50万对以下。结婚人数减少也是出生人数减少的原因之一。在东亚国家，婚外生子的情况很少见。</p>
<p>Opinion studies show that many younger Japanese do not want to marry or have families. They note the lack of good jobs and high cost of living as reasons. Some say the working culture in Japanese businesses makes it hard for both parents to work. Young parents say they often feel isolated as people do not want to hear crying babies or children playing outside.<br/>
民意调查显示，许多日本年轻人不想结婚或成家。他们指出原因是没有好工作以及生活成本高昂。有人说，日本企业的工作文化让父母双方都感觉工作艰难。年轻的父母说，他们经常感到被孤立，因为人们不想听到婴儿哭声或孩子在外面打闹。</p>
<p>Chief Cabinet Secretary Yoshimasa Hayashi called the ongoing declining birth rate "critical." He said, "The period over the next six years or so until (the) 2030s, when the younger population will start declining rapidly, will be the last chance we may be able to reverse the trend."<br/>
日本内阁官房长官林芳正称持续下降的出生率“非常严重”。他说，“在未来六年左右的时间里，直到21世纪30年代，年轻人口将开始迅速下降，这将是我们扭转这一趋势的最后机会。”</p>
<p>Prime Minister Fumio Kishida called the low birth numbers "the biggest crisis Japan faces." He has introduced several measures to give financial support for childbirth, children, and their families.<br/>
日本首相岸田文雄称低出生率是“日本面临的最大危机”。他推出了几项措施，为分娩、儿童及其家庭提供经济支持。</p>
<p>But experts say they doubt whether the government's efforts will work because they have largely centered on people who already are married or are planning to have children. The measures do not deal with a growing population of young people who are not getting married or planning to have a family.<br/>
但专家称他们怀疑政府的措施是否有效，因为这些措施主要集中在已经结婚或计划生育的人身上。这些措施并没有针对越来越多的没有结婚或计划组建家庭的年轻人。</p>
<p>The number of births in Japan has been falling for 50 years after a peak of about 2.1 million. The decrease to a yearly number below 760,000 has happened faster than expected. Experts had predicted that it would take place by 2035.<br/>
日本出生人口在达到210万左右的峰值后，近50年来一直在下降。出生人口下降到每年76万以下的速度远超预期。专家们曾预测这个数字将在2035年出现。</p>
<p>Japan's population of more than 125 million is expected to drop to 87 million by 2070, with four out of every 10 people at age 65 or older.<br/>
日本超过1.25亿的人口预计将在2070年降至8700万，并且其中每10人就有4人年龄在65岁或以上。</p>
<p>A shrinking and aging population has a big effect on the economy and national security. Recently, Japan lost its spot as the world's third-largest economy, falling behind Germany.<br/>
人口的萎缩和老龄化对经济和国家安全有很大影响。最近，日本失去了世界第三大经济体的地位，掉到了德国后面。</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.<br/>
我是小马里奥·里特。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Would Happen without Leap Day?  (2024/2/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-would-happen-without-leap-day.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>This year, 2024, is a leap year. February 29 is known as "leap day." But what is behind this rare extra day on the <strong>calendar</strong>?</p>
<p>Everyone knows the Earth takes 365 days to travel around the sun. Well, that is not exactly correct. The Earth really takes 365 days, five hours, forty-eight minutes and forty-six seconds to complete its orbit around the sun.</p>
<p>So, almost every four years an extra day occurs and it is represented on the calendar.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photograph taken in Paris on February 26, 2024, shows the tear-off calendar page for the February 29 leap year 2024. (Photo by Martin BUREAU / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fbe34def-6f14-4896-8362-df0ef2dba2d8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photograph taken in Paris on February 26, 2024, shows the tear-off calendar page for the February 29 leap year 2024. (Photo by Martin BUREAU / AFP)</span></div>
<p>The Jet Propulsion Laboratory at the California Institute of Technology says the extra day is used to be sure the months stay connected to yearly events such as <strong>equinoxes</strong> and <strong>solstices</strong>.</p>
<p>NASA says that over time, our seasons would fall out of order without the leap day. Each calendar year is about six hours longer than 365 days.</p>
<p>However, a leap day is not added every four years. That would lengthen the calendar by 44 minutes, say experts at the National Air and Space Museum in Washington, D.C. Over time, that would mean summer would arrive in November, said Younas Khan, a physics instructor at the University of Alabama, Birmingham.</p>
<p>So a leap day is added nearly every four years, but not in years including 1700, 1800 and 1900. There was a leap day in 2000 because it was a year divisible by both 100 and 400. Over the next 500 years, there will be no leap day in 2100, 2200, 2300 and 2500.</p>
<p>There will be leap days in 2028, 2032 and 2036.</p>
<p>Without a leap day, farmers might have trouble planting in the correct season, Khan said. "Christmas would be in summer. There will be no snow. There will be no feeling of Christmas," he said.</p>
<p>You might wonder who came up with the idea of leap day. Experts say the calendar change developed over time.</p>
<p>Ancient civilizations planned their years based on either the moon or the sun. By the time Julius Caesar controlled the Roman Empire, things had gotten more complicated. People had written down the calendars but seasons were "<strong>drifting</strong>." For example, the weather in July was not always the same. So in that time, they added months to the calendar. But that did not really fix the problem.</p>
<p>The Romans fixed the problem in the year 46 BCE. The year became 365-and-one-fourth days long. So an extra day was added every four years. The Romans came close, but a year is actually 365 plus 0.242 days, says Nick Eakes, an astronomy professor at the University of North Carolina in Chapel Hill.</p>
<p>There have been multiple calendars used by western societies. The Athenian and the Julian calendars were used thousands of years ago. The Athenian calendar, however, ran into problems when holidays were not falling in the correct seasons, said Thomas Palaima, a <strong>classics</strong> professor at the University of Texas at Austin.</p>
<p>Over time, the current calendar also changed because of holidays. The leader of the Roman Catholic Church, Gregory XIII, fixed the calendar again in the late 1500s. He wanted to be sure the Christian holiday of Easter happened in early spring. So Gregory and his advisors did the difficult math to come up with something very close to the calendar we use today.</p>
<p>"If the solar year was a perfect 365.25 then we wouldn't have to worry about the tricky math involved," said Eakes, the astronomy professor.</p>
<p><strong>Special birthdays</strong></p>
<p>After the calendar, the main concern for leap day centers on those born on that day, February 29. It only comes around once every four years (for the most part.)</p>
<p>It is a conversation starter for many. It can be an administrative headache – some people must fill out official documents and say their birthday is either February 28 or March 1. Some computer systems have not yet been updated to include February 29 as a choice.</p>
<p>Only about 5 million of the 8 billion people worldwide were born on February 29. Shelly Dean of Seattle, Washington is one of them. Growing up, she said, she had normal birthday parties each year, but every fourth year, she had a special party.</p>
<p>She is now 23, but has not had too many "special" birthdays. So this year, she is planning one. She missed celebrating with her family four years ago, because she was attending school in New York. So on Thursday, she gets to celebrate her special day for the first time in eight years with her family.</p>
<p>"It's a very big day," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>calendar </strong><em>–n.</em> a document, chart, etc., that shows the days, weeks, and months of a year</p>
<p><strong>equinox </strong><em>–n.</em> a day in the year where there is an equal amount of sunlight and darkness</p>
<p><strong>solstice </strong><em>–n.</em> the longest day of the year</p>
<p><strong>classics </strong><em>–n.</em> a study area that includes material that has been looked at for hundreds of years</p>
<p><strong>drift </strong><em>–v.</em> to move slowly but not with a clear direction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>South Korea Warns Striking Doctors to Return or Face Punishment  (2024/2/27) | 韩国警告罢工医生返岗否则面临处罚</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/south-korea-warns-striking-doctors-to-return-or-face-punishment.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>South Korea's government has warned young doctors to return to work before February 29 or face possible punishments.<br/>
韩国政府警告年轻医生在2月29日之前返回工作岗位，否则可能面临惩罚。</p>
<p>About 9,000 young doctors started walking off the job early last week to protest a government plan to increase the number of students accepted to medical schools.<br/>
上周早些时候，约9000名年轻医生开始离职，以抗议政府扩大医学生招生人数的计划。</p>
<p>The doctors are in the early part of their careers. They are known as residents or interns. These young professionals generally assist or observe more experienced doctors in their work.<br/>
这些医生正处于职业生涯的早期阶段。他们被称为住院医生或实习生。这些年轻的专业人员通常在工作中协助或观察更有经验的医生。</p>
<p>The government wants to expand the yearly number of new medical student admissions by 2,000. The plan also offers incentives to doctors if they specialize in areas facing shortages, such as doctors who treat children or work in emergency rooms.<br/>
政府希望将每年新招收的医学生人数增加2000人。该计划还为专门从事面临短缺领域的医生提供激励，例如在儿科或急诊室工作的医生。</p>
<p>Officials have said the plan is necessary to serve South Korea's aging population. The country's current doctor-to-patient ratio is among the lowest in the developed world.<br/>
官员们表示，这项计划是服务韩国老龄化人口所必需的。该国目前的医患比例是发达国家中最低的。</p>
<p>But the striking doctors say the nation's universities are unprepared to deal with additional students. They have also said the change would not solve doctor shortages in some areas of the profession.<br/>
但罢工的医生们表示，韩国的大学没有做好应对新增学生的准备。他们还表示，这一改变不会解决该行业某些领域的医生短缺问题。</p>
<p>
Under South Korean law, the government can order doctors and other medical workers back to work if there is a major risk to public health. Refusal to obey such an order can result in the suspension of licenses and up to three years in prison or a $22,480 fine. Those who receive prison sentences would have their medical licenses canceled.<br/>
根据韩国法律，如果公众健康面临重大风险，政府可以命令医生和其他医务工作者重返工作岗位。拒绝遵守此类命令可能导致执照被吊销、最高三年监禁或22480美元罚款。那些被判入狱的人士将被吊销行医执照。</p>
<p>South Korea's Vice Health Minister, Park Min-soo, told reporters Monday the government would not seek any punishments against striking doctors who returned by February 29. "If they return to the hospitals they had left by then, we won't hold them responsible" for any damage caused, Park said. He added, "It's not too late. Please, return to patients immediately."<br/>
韩国保健福祉部副部长朴敏守星期一告诉记者，政府不会寻求对2月29日前返岗的罢工医生施加任何惩罚。朴敏守说，“如果他们回到当时离开的医院，我们不会对他们造成的任何损失的追究责任。”他补充道：“现在还不算太晚。请立即回到病人身边。”</p>
<p>The government said those who do not return to work by the end of the month could be punished with at least a three-month suspension of their medical licenses. Doctors who continue to strike could also face additional legal steps and possible court trials.<br/>
政府表示，月底之前没有返岗的人士可能会被处以吊销医疗执照至少三个月的处罚。继续罢工的医生还可能面临额外的法律措施和可能的法庭审判。</p>
<p>Hyeondeok Choi is a partner at the law firm Daeryun, which specializes in medical law. He told the Associated Press it would be highly unlikely the government would suspend the licenses of all striking doctors because of the possible harm that could cause. Some industry observers said a more likely action would be for the government to only punish strike leaders.<br/>
崔德贤是Daeyun律师事务所的合伙人，他专攻医疗法。他告诉美联社，政府极不可能因为可能造成的伤害而暂停所有罢工医生的执照。一些行业观察人士表示，政府更可能采取的行动是只惩罚罢工领头人。</p>
<p>The AP reports there are about 13,000 medical interns and residents working in South Korea. These workers represent about 30 to 40 percent of all the doctors at some major hospitals.<br/>
据美联社报道，韩国约有13000名实习医生和住院医生。这些人员在一些大医院约占所有医生人数的30%到40%。</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the government announced it would permit universities to admit 2,000 more medical students starting next year. Officials say the plan calls for adding up to 10,000 new doctors by 2035.<br/>
本月早些时候，政府宣布将允许大学从明年开始多招收2000名医学生。官员们表示，该计划要求到2035年新增1万名医生。</p>
<p>Public opinion studies have shown that about 80 percent of South Koreans support the government's plan. But striking doctors have said they worry that doctors facing increased competition could start treating patients for conditions they do not have. This, they added, could put new financial pressures on the country's medical system, which would have to pay for the additional costs.<br/>
民意调查显示，大约80%的韩国人支持政府的计划。但罢工医生表示，他们担心医生面临日益激烈竞争，可能会开始对患者进行过度治疗。他们补充道，这可能会给该国的医疗系统带来新的财政压力，该系统将不得不支付额外的费用。</p>
<p>Critics have noted doctors currently receive one of the highest pay rates of any workers in South Korea. They argue that increasing numbers creates greater competition and can lower doctor incomes.<br/>
批评人士指出，目前医生的工资是韩国所有职工中最高的。他们认为，人数的增加会带来更大的竞争，并可能降低医生的收入。</p>
<p>Vice Health Minister Park said the country's services for emergency and critical patients remain stable. He noted that public hospitals had extended their working hours and military hospitals were opening their emergency rooms to civilian patients.<br/>
韩国保健福祉部副部长朴表示，韩国的急诊和危重症患者服务保持稳定。他指出，公立医院延长了工作时间，同时军队医院向平民患者开放了急诊室。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What is the Brain Condition Frontotemporal Dementia?  (2024/2/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-the-brain-condition-frontotemporal-dementia.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>A brain wasting disease called frontotemporal dementia has gained attention after television and film personalities said they suffered from it.</p>
<p>In a statement, caregivers said doctors told talk show <strong>host</strong> Wendy Williams that she had the unusual form of dementia. It said Williams had undergone many medical tests to identify the condition. Actor Bruce Willis is also reportedly affected by the condition.</p>
<p><strong>What is frontotemporal dementia?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - TV talk show host Wendy Williams attends a ceremony honoring her with a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame on Thursday, Oct. 17, 2019, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5149e42d-2cde-4796-9b29-f8067e43a5a7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - TV talk show host Wendy Williams attends a ceremony honoring her with a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame on Thursday, Oct. 17, 2019, in Los Angeles. (Photo by Willy Sanjuan/Invision/AP, File)</span></div>
<p>Frontotemporal dementia, or FTD, is a rare disease that affects parts of the brain controlling behavior and language. These parts of the brain shrink as the disease gets worse.</p>
<p>FTD usually can affect people in their 40s through their early 60s. It can change a person's <strong>personality</strong>, causing a loss of control or wild behavior. It is sometimes mistaken for mental health disorders like depression or bipolar disorder. It can take years for doctors to <strong>diagnose</strong> the condition.</p>
<p>Brenda Rapp is a scientist at Johns Hopkins University. Rapp described signs of the disease this way: "Maybe you're doing things that are <strong>bothering</strong> people and you don't really understand why they're bothering people."</p>
<p>The disease is linked to primary progressive aphasia, which is a condition affecting a person's ability to communicate. A person with this sort of FTD may have trouble finding words or understanding speech.</p>
<p><strong>What causes FTD?</strong></p>
<p>Damage to neurons, the brain's information carriers, is believed to be part of the problem but the root reasons for a case are often unclear. People with a family history of the condition are more likely to develop it. But most people with FTD have no family history of dementia.</p>
<p><strong>Can FTD be treated?</strong></p>
<p>There is no cure for FTD, but there are different ways to try to deal with it. People might get speech <strong>therapy</strong> if they have the kind that affects language. They might get physical therapy to improve movement.</p>
<p>Some patients receive antidepressants or drugs for Parkinson's, a nervous system disease, which has some of the same <strong>symptoms</strong> as FTD.</p>
<p><strong>How fast does FTD progress?</strong></p>
<p>FTD can be a long illness, lasting two to 10 years. People with FTD will need caregiving or nursing support as their symptoms get worse.</p>
<p>"The disease will spread throughout the brain," Rapp said. "The rate at which it does that is extremely unpredictable. So, it's very hard to know...how quickly someone will <strong>deteriorate</strong>."</p>
<p>The financial costs for a family can be high. The Alzheimer's Association estimates that it costs $10,000 a year, on average, in the United States for health and long-term care for a person with dementia.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Carla K. Johnson reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>____________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>host </strong><em>– n. </em>a person who talks to guests on a television or radio show</p>
<p><strong>personality </strong><em>– n. </em>the set of emotional qualities or ways of behaving that makes a person different from other people</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong><em>– n.</em> the treatment of physical or mental illnesses</p>
<p><strong>symptom </strong><em>– n.</em> a change in the body or mind which shows that a disease is present</p>
<p><strong>deteriorate </strong><em>– v</em>. to become worse as time passes</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Approves Asthma Drug to Treat Food Allergies  (2024/2/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-approves-asthma-drug-to-treat-food-allergies.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>From VOA Learning English, this is the Health &amp; Lifestyle report.</p>
<p>The U.S. food and drug agency has approved a medication already used to treat the breathing condition <strong>asthma</strong> to treat people for food <strong>allergies</strong>.</p>
<p>On February 16, the United States Food and Drug Administration (or FDA) approved Xolair for a new use. Xolair has become the first medication approved by the FDA to reduce allergic reactions caused by food allergies.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The U.S. food and drug agency has approved a medication already used to treat the breathing condition asthma to treat people for food allergies." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2cbd0bb7-8bfc-4e5b-aa40-c71aea270fba_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The U.S. food and drug agency has approved a medication already used to treat the breathing condition asthma to treat people for food allergies.</span></div>
<p>Xolair is the brand name, or <strong>commercial</strong> name, for the drug omalizumab.</p>
<p>Many people who suffer from allergies — and their families —worry about <strong>exposure</strong> to things that cause allergic reactions. They might avoid eating at restaurants. They also might avoid social situations in which they might come into contact with something that causes their allergy.</p>
<p>Dr. Robert Wood is director of the pediatric allergy division at Johns Hopkins Children's Center. The FDA based its decision on research that Wood led. And the National Institutes of Health supported the allergy study.</p>
<p>One hundred sixty-eight people with allergies to peanuts and at least two other foods took part in the study. It found that 68 percent of the people injected with Xolair were able to have about 600 milligrams of peanut protein without serious problems. That number compares to only six percent of those who received an inactive substance instead of the drug.</p>
<p>The results of the study were similar for other allergens, or things that commonly cause allergies, such as tree nuts, milk, eggs, and wheat. Full results from the study are expected to be presented at a meeting and released in a <strong>peer-reviewed</strong> publication in the near future.</p>
<p>Wood said: "To have this protection is going to be life changing."</p>
<p>Wood estimated that 25 to 50 percent of people with food allergies, especially children and young adults, would choose to use Xolair.</p>
<p>Patients as young as one year of age with food allergies can take the drug by injection<strong> </strong>every two to four weeks. This depends on their weight and their body's response to allergens.</p>
<p>People who use Xolair must continue to avoid the foods that cause allergic reactions. These foods are often peanuts, cashews, hazelnuts, walnuts, milk products, and eggs. However, the medication appears to permit exposure to higher amounts of allergy-causing foods without causing major reactions.</p>
<p>Until now, doctors have used the drug to treat food allergies although that has not been its officially approved use, said Dr. Ruchi Gupta. Such a second use for a drug is called "off-label." Gupta is director of the Center for Food Allergy &amp; Asthma Research at Northwestern University in Chicago. She welcomed full approval of the product.</p>
<p>Xolair works by blocking the body's natural response to allergens. It is known as a monoclonal antibody. The FDA first approved the drug in 2003. It is used to treat asthma, growths in the nose, and long-term skin problems known as chronic hives.</p>
<p>Swiss drug companies Novartis and Roche produce Xolair, and it is <strong>distributed</strong> by a part of Roche, called Genentech.</p>
<p>The most common side effects<strong> </strong>of Xolair are injection <strong>site</strong> reactions and high body temperatures. However, the FDA noted that the drug has also caused joint pain, <strong>rash</strong>,<strong> </strong>infections, <strong>malignancies,</strong> and abnormal laboratory tests.</p>
<p>Xolair also comes with a warning. The treatment itself can cause anaphylaxis, a life-threatening reaction that causes breathing and blood pressure problems. For that reason, the treatment must be started in a health care center with equipment that can deal with such emergencies. In addition, the drug is not approved as an emergency treatment for allergic reactions.</p>
<p>Genentech says Xolair is expected to cost about $2,900 a month for children and $5,000 a month for adults. The company said patients usually pay less because their health insurance often pays most of the cost of many drugs.</p>
<p>And that's the Health &amp; Lifestyle report. I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>JoNel Aleccia reported this story for Associated Press. Anna Matteo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>The Associated Press Health and Science Department receives support from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute's Science and Educational Media Group. The AP is solely responsible for all content.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"><strong>Words in This Story</strong></h2>
<p><strong>asthma </strong>–n. a long-term condition involving problems with breathing</p>
<p><strong>allergy </strong>–n. a strong reaction to a substance that does not normally cause a reaction in most people</p>
<p><strong>commercial </strong>–adj. related to business and aimed at making a profit</p>
<p><strong>exposure</strong> --n. an incident in which a person is in the presence of some substance and comes in contact with it or breathes it in</p>
<p><strong>peer-reviewed</strong> –adj. research that has undergone a process of being studied by independent professionals of similar knowledge who judge it to be up to the level required by a publication</p>
<p><strong>site </strong>–n. an exact place such as a place on the body where an injection is made</p>
<p><strong>rash</strong> –n. a skin condition that involves pain, swelling, redness or itchiness</p>
<p><strong>distribute </strong>–v. to provide a produce to businesses which then sell it for use by the public</p>
<p><strong>malignancy </strong>–n. a growth that is the product of disease or cancer</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Experts Say Productivity Increases Might Explain US Economy’s Strength  (2024/2/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/experts-say-productivity-increases-might-explain-us-economy-s-strength.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Worker shortages in the United States have led some companies to invest in machines to do some of the work they cannot find people to do. The companies have also been training workers to use new technology so they can produce more with less.</p>
<p>The result has been an unexpected increase in productivity, a measure of economic performance. Productivity compares two sets of data: outputs and inputs. Outputs are the goods and services produced, while the inputs are what is needed to create those goods and services.</p>
<p><strong>Productivity increase</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A worker at Reata Engineering and Machine Works programs a Mazak Variaxis machine used to make semiconductor pieces, Thursday, Feb. 15, 2024, in Englewood, Colo. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/95982b90-8b15-4f2c-9e48-e45bb0500758_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A worker at Reata Engineering and Machine Works programs a Mazak Variaxis machine used to make semiconductor pieces, Thursday, Feb. 15, 2024, in Englewood, Colo. (AP Photo/David Zalubowski)</span></div>
<p>The productivity increase represents a change from the years before the COVID-19 pandemic years. Yearly productivity growth averaged around 1.5 percent, business advisory company RSM estimates.</p>
<p>Things changed when the economy moved out of the 2020 recession. Businesses had difficulties bringing back the many workers they had lost.</p>
<p>The resulting worker shortage sent pay higher. Inflation increased for a number of reasons. One was that factories and ports had problems meeting rising product orders while shipping slowed. Shortages of parts were also reported.</p>
<p>Many companies turned to automation. Investment in equipment and in research and development and other forms of intellectual property grew. The Associated Press reports that the efficiency effects began to arrive almost a year ago.</p>
<p>The U.S. government's Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) reports on productivity. The BLS released its most recent productivity numbers on February 1. The bureau said: "Nonfarm business sector labor productivity increased 3.2 percent in the fourth quarter of 2023."</p>
<p><strong>One company's story</strong></p>
<p>Batesville Tool &amp; Die is a company based in the Midwestern state of Indiana. Trying to keep up with customer demand, Batesville Tool &amp; Die began looking for 70 people to hire last year. It was not easy. Getting factory workers to move to a small community of 7,300 people in the Indiana countryside was difficult.</p>
<p>Job seekers were rare there.</p>
<p>"You could count on one hand how many people in the town were unemployed," said Jody Fledderman, the company chief.</p>
<p>Batesville Tool &amp; Die filled just 40 of its job openings.</p>
<p>But then the company invested in machines that could work like human workers and in vision systems, which helped its robots "see" what they were doing.</p>
<p><strong>Productivity: not well understood</strong></p>
<p>Austan Goolsbee is president of the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago. He has compared increasing productivity to "magic...for the economy...You can have faster income increases, faster wage growth, faster GDP without generating inflation.''</p>
<p>Joe Brusuelas is chief economist at RSM. He said, "The last time we saw anything like this was the late 1990s."</p>
<p>At that time, Brusuelas said, a productivity increase — an early result from the sudden use of laptops, cellphones, and the internet — helped keep borrowing rates low. Inflation remained under control even as the economy and the job market were strong.</p>
<p>This time, the U.S. central bank has increased the interest rates it controls 11 times starting in March 2022. That has played a part in easing inflation from a 40-year high of 9.1 percent to around 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>"I would have said it's not possible,'' said Sal Guatieri who is an economist at BMO Capital Markets. "But that's exactly what happened.''</p>
<p>A year ago, many economists warned that a recession was very likely. Jerome Powell leads the U.S. Federal Reserve Bank. Powell warned in 2022 that beating inflation would result in "some pain" in the form of widespread job losses and unemployment.</p>
<p>Last month, Powell said something different. With unemployment near a 50-year low, Powell told reporters, "We've had a very strong labor market, and we've had inflation coming down."</p>
<p>He did warn that the central bank wants to see further progress in slowing inflation. But the Fed is so optimistic that inflation is heading toward its two percent goal that it has not raised rates since July. Some experts expect the central bank to cut its interest rates several times this year.</p>
<p>At a news conference this month, Powell was asked whether he believed higher productivity helps explain why the economy has kept growing even while inflation has fallen.</p>
<p>"That's one way to look at it — yeah," Powell replied.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Paul Wiseman reported on this story for the Associated Press. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>automate</strong> <em>– v.</em> to do something by using machines, computers, etc., instead of people</p>
<p><strong>efficiency</strong> <em>– n. </em>the ability to do something or produce something without wasting materials or time</p>
<p><strong>wage</strong> <em>–n.</em> money paid workers — especially for work by the hour</p>
<p><strong>GDP (Gross Domestic Product)</strong> <em>–n.</em> a measure of a country's economy that is the value of all the goods and services produced in one year</p>
<p><strong>recession</strong> <em>– n.</em> a period of time in which there is a decrease in economic activity</p>
<p><strong>optimistic</strong><em> – adj. </em>having hope for the future</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How Do Whales 'Sing?'  (2024/2/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/how-do-whales-sing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>It is one of Earth's loudest sounds in the ocean: the "singing" of whales.</p>
<p>Now scientists think they have an idea of how <strong>baleen</strong> whales do it. They say the large air-breathing sea animals use a special voice box that enables them to make sound underwater.</p>
<p>Scientists say the discovery is based on a very small study. But it will direct future research into how whales communicate.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - This photo provided by Samuel Lam shows a humpback whale and her calf in Papeete, French Polynesia in September 2022. Humpbacks are known to compose elaborate songs that travel across oceans and whale pods. (Samuel Lam via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-5e56-08dc33e381a8_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - This photo provided by Samuel Lam shows a humpback whale and her calf in Papeete, French Polynesia in September 2022. Humpbacks are known to compose elaborate songs that travel across oceans and whale pods. (Samuel Lam via AP)</span></div>
<p>The new findings are in a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07080-1">study published recently</a> in the scientific publication <em>Nature</em>. Coen Elemans of the University of Southern Denmark and other international scientists studied the voice boxes, or larynxes, of three dead whales from the beaches of Denmark and Scotland. The three were humpback, minke and sei whales. All three are part of the family of baleen whales, a group that includes the blue whale, the largest animal that ever existed on Earth.</p>
<p><strong>Voice box</strong></p>
<p>In the laboratory, the scientists blew air through the voice boxes under controlled conditions to see what tissues might <strong>vibrate</strong>. They also created computer models of the sei whale's <strong>vocalizations</strong> and matched them to recordings of similar whales taken in the wild.</p>
<p>Whales' ancestors were land animals that moved into the oceans about 50 million years ago. Elemans said the animals' voice box changed over tens of millions of years in order to make sounds underwater.</p>
<p>Baleen whales do not have teeth or vocal cords like humans and other mammals. Instead, they have U-shaped tissue in their voice boxes that permits them to breathe a lot of air very quickly. Their voice boxes also contain a large "<strong>cushion</strong>" of fat and muscle not seen in other animals. Whales "sing" by pushing the tissue against the fat and muscle cushion.</p>
<p>Elemans said baleen whales depend on the production of sound to communicate in the dark of the deep oceans. "For example, humpback females and their <strong>calves</strong> communicate with each other by voice, and humpback males sing to attract females," he added.</p>
<p>Jeremy Goldbogen is a professor of oceans at Stanford University, who was not involved in the research. He said, "This is the most <strong>comprehensive</strong> and <strong>significant</strong> study to date on how baleen whales vocalize, a long-standing mystery in the field."</p>
<p>The whale voice boxes tested were from younger animals, not adult males, who do the singing. Because of that, whale expert Joy Reidenberg said further experiments on adult males are needed to confirm the study's findings.</p>
<p>Reidenberg works for the Center for Anatomy and Functional Morphology at the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai in New York City. She noted that the research is probably as close as we can get to reproducing how whales sing.</p>
<p>"Right now, our technology involves sticking a <strong>scope</strong> into a whale to see what exactly is vibrating," she said. "Since you're never going to be able to do that in a wild animal, these experiments are the next best thing."</p>
<p><strong>Shipping noise</strong></p>
<p>As loud as whales' songs are, the study suggests that whales cannot produce sounds louder than noise from the shipping industry, Elemans said.</p>
<p>"They're really affected by (shipping noise) and it significantly reduces their ability to communicate," he said. "There's just no way for them to get louder."</p>
<p>Because some whales sing as a mating call, the shipping industry's interference with those songs is a concern, said Michael Noad. He is director of the Center for Marine Science at the University of Queensland in Australia. He also was not part of the <em>Nature</em> study.</p>
<p>"For whale populations that are really <strong>dispersed</strong>, like the Antarctic blue whales, they might not be able to find mates in a noisy ocean environment," he said. However, whales like humpbacks that gather in big numbers are more likely to ignore such noise pollution.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter, Jr.</p>
<p><em>Maria Cheng reported this story for the Associated Press. Hai Do adapted it for VOA Learning English with additional reporting from Reuters.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>baleen</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>a hard material in the mouth of some kinds of whales that permits them to eat very small shrimp in the ocean</p>
<p><strong>vibrate</strong> <em>–v.</em> to move back and forth quickly, often producing sound</p>
<p><strong>vocalization </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of making a sound, such as speech or singing, using the throat</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Identify Possibly Brightest Object in the Universe  (2024/2/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/scientists-identify-possibly-brightest-object-in-the-universe.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Astronomers say they may have discovered the brightest object ever observed in the universe.</p>
<p>The discovery involves a distant space object known as a quasar. The American space agency NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nasa.gov/universe/nasas-webb-will-use-quasars-to-unlock-the-secrets-of-the-early-universe/">describes</a> quasars as "very bright, distant and active supermassive black holes that are millions to billions of times the mass of the Sun."</p>
<p>A quasar's light "outshines" all other stars and "its jets and winds shape" its galaxy, NASA adds.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This illustration provided by the European Southern Observatory in February 2024, depicts the record-breaking quasar J059-4351. (M. Kornmesser/ESO via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9c69-08dc33dd2675_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This illustration provided by the European Southern Observatory in February 2024, depicts the record-breaking quasar J059-4351. (M. Kornmesser/ESO via AP)</span></div>
<p>A team led by Australian researchers identified the super bright quasar. The European Southern Observatory's (ESO's) Very Large Telescope, based in northern Chile, collected most of the data. Additional data came from Australia's Siding Spring Observatory.</p>
<p>The researchers estimate the record-breaking quasar is at least 500 trillion times brighter than our own sun. The team also noted the black hole powering the object is more than 17 billion times larger than our sun.</p>
<p>The quasar is about 12 billion light years away from Earth. It is thought to have existed since the early days of the universe. A light year is the distance light travels in a year – about 9.5 trillion kilometers.</p>
<p>The object was already known and had been studied before. But scientists say it was misidentified in the past as a star. The newly identified quasar is so large that its black hole could easily swallow at least one sun per day, the team said.</p>
<p>The researchers recently reported their finding <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-024-02195-x">in a study</a> in the publication <em>Nature Astronomy</em>.</p>
<p>The quasar appears only as a small dot in images. But scientists say they imagine it to be a very powerful and active place. The team says the black hole is thought to have a circulating <strong>disk</strong> containing gas and other matter from swallowed stars. The disk spins continuously like an intense, active storm.</p>
<p>"This quasar is the most violent place that we know in the universe," said the lead writer of the study, Christian Wolf. He is an astronomer and professor in the College of Science at Australian National University.</p>
<p>The ESO first found the object, known as J0529-4351, in 1980. At the time, it was identified, or classified, as a star. Then last year, it was identified as a quasar.</p>
<p>The latest observations and computer modeling suggest the quasar is taking in amounts of material equal to about 370 suns a year, or about one per day. The team says more observations will be needed to fully understand the object's growth rate.</p>
<p>Priyamvada Natarajan is a professor of astronomy and physics at Yale University. She was not part of the latest study. But Natarajan told the Associated Press, "The exciting thing about this quasar is that it was hiding in plain sight and was misclassified as a star previously."</p>
<p>Study co-writer Christopher Onken added, "It is a surprise that it has remained unknown until today, when we already know about a million less <strong>impressive</strong> quasars."</p>
<p>The researchers say finding and studying distant supermassive black holes could help astronomers learn important details about the birth and development of the early universe. But study leader Wolf noted that he also gets enjoyment out of the search itself.</p>
<p>"Personally, I simply like the chase," he <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.eso.org/public/news/eso2402/">said</a> in a statement. "For a few minutes a day, I get to feel like a child again, playing treasure hunt. And now, I bring everything to the table that I have learned since."</p>
<p>Future research is expected to center on the history of the quasar and measuring its growth and development. The team noted that some of this data should be easier to collect after the Very Large Telescope receives an instrument <strong>upgrade</strong>. The upgrade, known as Gravity+, is designed to provide more exact measurements of the mass of distant black holes.</p>
<p>In addition, the ESO plans to launch a future observer, called the Extremely Large Telescope (ELT), in Chile's Atacama Desert. That telescope, the researchers say, will improve on current identification and study methods to identify such distant objects.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press and the European Southern Observatory. </em></p>
<p><strong>___________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>disk </strong><em>– n. </em>a flat, round object</p>
<p><strong>impressive </strong><em>– adj. </em>something considered noteworthy or causing admiration or respect</p>
<p><strong>upgrade </strong><em>– n. </em>to improve something that is higher quality of a newer model</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Prepares for a Cicada Invasion Last Seen in 1803  (2024/2/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-prepares-for-a-cicada-invasion-last-seen-in-1803.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Do you remember all those cicada videos from the United States in 2021?</p>
<p>Well, prepare for a repeat performance this year. The insect show begins as early as April.</p>
<p>Two groups of cicadas, <strong>brood </strong>XIII and brood XIX, are expected to come out from the ground to mate and lay eggs this year. Their appearance in the same year is rare. The last time it happened was 1803.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A cicada is seen on a wooden sign on the porch of a house in Arlington, Virginia, May 20, 2021. (REUTERS/Will Dunham)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-81ee-08dc32e4452d_cx0_cy4_cw99_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A cicada is seen on a wooden sign on the porch of a house in Arlington, Virginia, May 20, 2021. (REUTERS/Will Dunham)</span></div>
<p>Brood XIII is on a 17-year cycle. They will be found in the Midwestern states of Illinois, Iowa, Wisconsin and Kentucky. Brood XIX is on a 13-year cycle. They will come out in an area stretching from Indiana and Illinois southeast to the southern states of Alabama and Georgia.</p>
<p>Scientists expect more than one trillion cicadas to appear in some small areas where the two broods are close to each other. The insects will begin to climb out of the ground when the soil warms to about 18 degrees Celsius. So they will be seen in warmer southern areas as early as April. It will be closer to summer, sometime in June, before the cicadas arise to the north in Wisconsin, Indiana and other Midwestern states.</p>
<p>Cicadas are large, noisy insects, from about 2.5 to 5 centimeters long. Like most insects, they have wings. They also have big "bulging" eyes. There are thousands of species of cicada around the world.</p>
<p>The huge majority of cicada species arise each year, or annually. Then there are the periodicals which arrive after numerous years in the ground.</p>
<p>The periodical cicadas emerge to mate.</p>
<p>The male cicadas make a <strong>thrumming</strong> sound with their wings on their bodies to call for mating. The "singing" appeals to females. The insects mate and leave their fertilized eggs on trees. The resulting young fall to the ground after breaking out of their shells. They dig down into the ground where they live for years, feeding on the liquid that comes from tree roots.</p>
<p>Seven of the nine known periodical cicadas live in North America. Of the other two groups, one is in India and one is found only on the island country of Fiji.</p>
<p>Floyd Shockley is an insect scientist, or entomologist, with the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, D.C. He said this year's group of cicadas will include four different Magicada species within the XIX brood.</p>
<p>The next time brood XIX and brood XIII will come out in the same year will be in 2245.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>brood </strong><em>–n.</em> a group of young (in this case insects) all born at the same time</p>
<p><strong>thrum </strong><em>–v.</em> to make a low, steady sound</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>–n.</em> a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Have you seen the cicadas before? What do you remember about them?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>The Moment that Changed Our Lives  (2024/2/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/the-moment-that-changed-our-lives.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By VOA</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 February 2024</span><br/>
<p><em><strong>Editor's note: </strong>This story is one of the winning entries from the "Teach Us about Ukraine" writing contest sponsored by VOA Learning English and GoGlobal.</em></p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Ukrainian servicemen check newly build anti-tank fortifications and razor wire, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine, near Russian border in Chernihiv region, Ukraine, January 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Gleb Garanich)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a3d26e5f-4c65-4d5f-9f3d-07911451ed74_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Ukrainian servicemen check newly build anti-tank fortifications and razor wire, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine, near Russian border in Chernihiv region, Ukraine, January 10, 2024. (REUTERS/Gleb Garanich)</span></div>
<p>I'm Olena Zamorska and I teach English in Sophia Rusova Lyseum in Oleshnia, Ukraine.</p>
<p>It was early morning, exactly at 4:20 am, when I was awakened from my sleep by the sounds of explosions. My family and I rushed outside and watched with fear. We saw flashes in the sky and heard explosions and sounds of military vehicles. We were only thirty kilometers from the Russian border. That moment changed our lives, because we understood that the war had started.</p>
<p>I did not know what to do. I thought about my work and my students. I was a lead teacher in the eighth grade. I organized a meeting to calm my students. We had to learn to live and work remotely in a new dangerous situation. I gave my students schoolwork through their mobile phones and checked everything by collecting the exercise books. They brought them to the nearest shop. It was the place of meeting and communication at that time.</p>
<p>Our village was in a "grey" zone. Neither Ukrainian nor Russian troops were there. We did not have electricity, internet connection or food. And we could not communicate with people outside.</p>
<p>I rode my bicycle to visit students at their homes and keep in touch with their parents. I was a local authority in the village at that time and people listened to my words. I baked bread in a wood stove and brought it to people in need. People were very grateful because there was not enough food at the time.</p>
<p>Each night we heard and watched Russian airplanes and helicopters bringing bombs to Chernihiv and providing their troops with food and weapons. We believe they flew at night time to frighten and keep people from sleeping. The helicopters flew so low that we could see the pilot. It was very scary. We did not know what would happen next and prepared for the worst.</p>
<p>We organized villagers to defend ourselves. We made bombs and set up blockades with trees. We were ready to fight against our enemies and meet them at our land.</p>
<p>When we did not have electricity and connection, I rode my bicycle for 10 kilometers to stand on a hill and phone our relatives to inform them that we were alive. From that high place, I could use an expensive cell phone connection to try to get a short message across to family in occupied places. It was our only way to contact each other.</p>
<p>When Russian troops finally left Chernihiv, we resumed remote studying for the students. I tried yoga and started breathing exercises with my students. And I studied how to deal with traumas and manage difficult situations.</p>
<p>Nowadays my students and I live a normal life. We help our soldiers by making candles, knitting nets, warm socks, mats, collecting money and painting pictures and writing letters.</p>
<p>We hope our victory will be soon.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">About the writer</h2>
<p>Olena Zamorska was born in the Chernihiv region, Ukraine to a working-class family. After completing secondary school, she worked as a school librarian. Then she studied at Kharkiv aviation institute and became an engineer in Oleshnia. Finally, she earned a teaching degree in 1999 and became an English teacher. She has found it more rewarding to work with children than with airplanes.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Hot Seawater Hurts Coral Restoration Effort in Florida Keys  (2024/2/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/hot-seawater-hurts-coral-restoration-effort-in-florida-keys.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Government scientists are aiming to replace <strong>coral</strong> at seven places off the Florida Keys island group. But <em>The Associated Press</em> reports three fourths of the newly <strong>cultivated</strong> coral has died because of warm water temperatures.</p>
<p>The scientists are with the U.S. agency known as the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or NOAA. They planted staghorn and elkhorn coral as part of the agency's Mission: Iconic Reefs effort, first announced in 2019. The corals are being grown on structures in shallow water.</p>
<p>The two <strong>species</strong> of coral are considered threatened. The scientists wanted to see how the cultivated species were doing. They visited five places where they had planted coral earlier. They hoped the coral had survived water temperatures reaching 30 degrees Celsius or more during the summer and fall.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shows dead elkhorn coral on Feb. 9, 2024, at Carysfort Reef, northeast of Key Largo, Fla. (Ben Edmonds/NOAA via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-a93b-08dc33bad8a9_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">This image provided by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shows dead elkhorn coral on Feb. 9, 2024, at Carysfort Reef, northeast of Key Largo, Fla. (Ben Edmonds/NOAA via AP)</span></div>
<p>Last summer, students and volunteers tried to rescue the corals by removing them and temporarily putting them in tanks.</p>
<p>But most of the coral did not survive. NOAA said only 22 percent of the 1,500 repopulated staghorn corals that they saw were still alive. Only five percent of 1,000 replanted elkhorn corals were alive. At Looe Key, the southernmost of the reefs they looked at, "we did not find any live elkhorn or staghorn coral, not wild, not planted," said coral biologist Katey Lesneski. She is research and <strong>monitoring</strong> coordinator for NOAA's effort.</p>
<p>"It's really horrible to witness," Lesneski said just two days after the dives to observe coral had finished.</p>
<p>Scientists blame human-caused climate change. They also note that the natural El Nino Pacific Ocean current affects weather in North America. They said these conditions are making the water too warm for the coral. Corals are small animal colonies that build rocky formations as they grow.</p>
<p>"There's still a lot of data to be collected to really understand..." Lesneski said. She added: "But we certainly have not seen something like this in recorded human history."</p>
<p>Staghorn and elkhorn populations are important because they provide a "structural framework" for coral, Lesneski said.</p>
<p>The scientists did see some wild coral alive and well, she said. Brain or boulder corals seemed to be doing better.</p>
<p>The U.S. government and private groups plan to spend at least $97 million to place coral species grown on land or in the ocean in seven places off the Florida Keys the AP reports. Some of the species are native and others have been <strong>crossbred</strong> to be <strong>heartier</strong>, Lesneski said. It is too early to tell which ones are better able to survive.</p>
<p>Lesneski said NOAA measured water temperatures of 34 degrees Celsius at the planting places. Mark Eakin is with the International Coral Reef Society. He said, "They were actually seeing temperatures that they didn't think were possible."</p>
<p>Eakin and the University of Victoria coral biologist Julia Baum said the findings raise concerns about trying to repopulate coral reefs by cultivating coral in very warm water.</p>
<p>Lesneski said she understands that concern and researchers are looking to see what they could do to <strong>breed</strong> more heat-resistant coral.</p>
<p>"But for now, if we want to have...reefs, we do have to do our best to <strong>conserve</strong>, be good <strong>stewards</strong> and restore to the degree we can," she said.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>coral </strong>–n. a simple sea animal that forms colonies which build up rocky structures of great size under the sea</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>cultivate </strong><em>— v.</em> to raise, care for and develop something like a living thing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>species </strong>–n. (sing., pl.) a kind of animal or plant that can breed with others of its kind to produce young</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>monitor </strong>–v. to carefully observe and measure the development of a living thing or of some activity</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>crossbreed </strong><em>— v. </em>to breed two different but related kinds of animals together to form a new kind</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>hearty </strong><em>— adj. </em>healthy and strong</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>breed</strong> <em>— v. </em>to cause a kind of animal to reproduce especially with the idea that the offspring will have certain qualities</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>conserve </strong><em>— v. </em>to preserve things so that they last into the future in good condition and are not used up</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>steward </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who oversees and protects property and is responsible for it</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>How International Students Should Think about Writing, AI  (2024/2/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/how-international-students-should-think-about-writing-ai.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Students must learn <strong>academic</strong> writing and research methods when moving from high school to college. That is why universities require a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/not-all-college-classes-lead-to-degrees-/6996181.html">first-year writing class</a>. As experienced students move on to higher degrees, they continue learning how to do research and to write for academic publications.</p>
<p>But learning the new writing methods can be difficult for international students, said Nat Smitobol. He is a counselor for IvyWise, a company that helps students prepare their applications for top-level American universities.</p>
<p><strong>Different "academic culture"</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="One student believes those working on getting better at writing in English should limit their use of AI tools." src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/fafacb65-81f4-424c-b386-90e1a9b4b5bc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">One student believes those working on getting better at writing in English should limit their use of AI tools.</span></div>
<p>In the United States, Smitobol said, most students have a basic understanding that they must give credit to, or <strong>cite</strong>, the <strong>sources</strong> of the words and ideas in their academic writing. For those who come from other countries, this can be new.</p>
<p>Smitobol said one of the most important lessons students new to the U.S. learn is: "this academic culture of really making sure you give other people credit in a formal way."</p>
<p>Using another person's words without giving them credit is considered <strong>plagiarism</strong>. VOA Learning English recently prepared a <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/defining-plagiarism-how-to-avoid-it/7451640.html">guide for international students</a> who need to learn more about plagiarism and why it is a serious concern. A plagiarism accusation recently led to Harvard University's president having to step down from her position.</p>
<p>Smitobol said the reason citations are difficult for international students is that teachers and professors overseas are more often concerned that students provide the correct answer to a question than showing the information source.</p>
<p>Amjad Binshahbain agrees. He is a student at the English Language Center, or ELC, at Old Dominion University in Virginia. Binshahbain is from Yemen and also attended school in the United Arab Emirates. In Virginia, he takes classes with students from places like Greece, Spain and Japan. They often discuss the academic differences between the U.S. and their countries.</p>
<p><strong>AI tools</strong></p>
<p>He said one of the first things ELC students learn is how to follow American university guidelines for recording source material. They also talk about writing papers without the help of <strong>artificial intelligence</strong>, or AI, tools.</p>
<p>Binshahbain said it is easy for students who are learning how to write papers in English to depend on generative AI tools. These tools can change their grammar or make their writing easier to understand. However, after nearly a year at the ELC, he has, in his words, "progressed a lot."</p>
<p>"I have been improving since then, since the summer in 2023. Now I can write a whole <strong>assignment</strong> without any outside source. I can read an <strong>article</strong> and understand it and write it in my own words. That's one of the techniques that I got since I come to the U.S."</p>
<p>He said it is better to struggle with writing and adding citations to academic work early in college than to find out that you do not know how to do it later on.</p>
<p>Smitobol noted that many universities will show students how to use tools such as the RefWorks citation manager. The computer tool permits students to carry out research online and collects all of the source material necessary.</p>
<p><strong>High stakes</strong></p>
<p>Meredith Bricker teaches in the English Language Institute at the University of Michigan. Many of her students are working on advanced degrees. That means they are learning and doing research on difficult academic subjects. She said the citation tools are both good and bad. On the one hand, they permit students to easily create a source list. On the other hand, they can prevent students from finding or understanding the best sources for a project.</p>
<p>"They're like, ‘OK, fine. I'll just put whatever comes up (in my search) on my citation list,'" Bricker said.</p>
<p>Students who come to Bricker's class are doing their own research, she added. They hope that they can make a discovery or create a new idea and be published in a <strong>journal</strong>. So, the <strong>stakes</strong> are high for master's or Ph.D. students compared to those just beginning college. She said it is likely the people cited in a paper by one of her students will read it.</p>
<p>"In some ways it's (citations) more relevant. You know, like, almost easier for them to see the purpose and the point. But I think it's also the <strong>flip side</strong> of that is if they do it incorrectly, it could have such devastating effects on their futures, you know, pretty immediately."</p>
<p>International students who are caught using other people's ideas without citing them can be expelled or removed from school. That would cause them to be in violation of their F1 student visa. At higher levels, a young researcher who is caught plagiarizing may have trouble finding another job.</p>
<p><strong>AI is ‘not going away'</strong></p>
<p>Bricker believes students should also give credit to AI tools whenever they use them. "Gen-AI is not going away," she said. "Part of our job as writing teachers...is to make sure students know the boundary between <strong>appropriate</strong> and inappropriate use."</p>
<p>She said some academic journals will permit the use of artificial intelligence and others will not. "It depends on the field," she said, noting that a linguistics journal might have different rules than an engineering journal.</p>
<p>Bricker said she tells her students that it is difficult for teachers to know if their students are using AI tools. But as a writing teacher, it is her goal to help them learn to write on their own, without help from a machine.</p>
<p>"I'm a teacher of writing. So, letting my students know ‘I want to see your writing, you.' I want to see what you're doing as a writer, and I want to help you grow as a writer...So I can do that with you using this and without you using this. But it's your choice."</p>
<p>Binshahbain said international students who are learning English in the U.S. are tempted by AI tools. But he advises students that they should use AI only for some things, like searching for sources.</p>
<p>"When I first came here, I was using it for everything," he said. "But I stopped because I understand the best thing to do (is) to put the effort on learning. It's going to pay off in the future."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>academic </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to work done at schools or colleges but not in businesses or government</p>
<p><strong>cite </strong><em>–v. </em>to report where a piece of writing or other intellectual property came from, showing where a reader could find the original work</p>
<p><strong>source </strong><em>–n. </em>a piece of writing or art that is referred to</p>
<p><strong>plagiarism </strong><em>–n.</em> the act of claiming someone else's written work as your own</p>
<p><strong>assignment </strong><em>–n.</em> a task given by a teacher to a student in school</p>
<p><strong>article </strong><em>–n.</em> a piece of writing usually on one subject that is not too long</p>
<p><strong>journal </strong><em>–n.</em> a magazine about a large subject that is regularly published and contains several articles and opinions written by academic authors</p>
<p><strong>stakes </strong><em>–n. (pl.)</em> something that could be won or lost</p>
<p><strong>flip side </strong><em>–n.</em> the other side of an argument</p>
<p><strong>appropriate </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that is right for the situation</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Keeper Wants You to Know Vatican’s Secrets  (2024/2/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/keeper-wants-you-to-know-vatican-s-secrets.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Roman Catholic Church has been trying for years to inform the public that its "secret" collection of documents is not secret.</p>
<p>The Vatican has opened documents of World War II-period Pope Pius XII to researchers. It even changed the official name of the <strong>archive</strong> to remove the word "Secret."</p>
<p>Recently the chief of what is now called the Vatican Apostolic Archive, Archbishop Sergio Pagano, spoke to the Associated Press. Pagano told some of the secrets he had uncovered in the 45 years of working in the archive. The Vatican's archive is one of the world's most important stores of documents.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Prefect of the Archivio Apostolico Vaticano, Bishop Sergio Pagano poses in his office at The Vatican, Wednesday, Feb. 14, 2024, after an interview with The Associated Press. (AP Photo/Domenico Stinellis)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1e1c3433-d3e5-424b-adde-6135d9cedfe6_cx5_cy7_cw86_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Prefect of the Archivio Apostolico Vaticano, Bishop Sergio Pagano poses in his office at The Vatican, Wednesday, Feb. 14, 2024, after an interview with The Associated Press. (AP Photo/Domenico Stinellis)</span></div>
<p>In a new book-length <strong>interview</strong> called "Secretum," Pagano explained some of the largely unknown details of the history of the Vatican and its relations with the outside world over the past 1200 years.</p>
<p>The interviews took place as discussions over a year with Italian reporter Massimo Franco. Pagano explains everything from French leader Napoleon taking documents to the 1922 financial support for the election of a pope from Catholics in the U.S.</p>
<p>"It's the first time and it will also be the last because I'm about to leave," said Pagano who is 75. He also spoke to the AP before his expected retirement later this year.</p>
<p>Pope Leo XIII first opened the archive to researchers in 1881. Until then, it had only been used to serve the pope and <strong>preserve</strong> documentation of the head of the Catholic Church dating from the 8th century.</p>
<p>The archive has 85 kilometers of space for books, much of it underground in a two-story, fireproof secure area. It also holds documents from Vatican embassies around the world and collections from powerful families and religious orders.</p>
<p>The archive works much as any national or private archive would. Researchers request permission to visit and then request documents to study in reading rooms.</p>
<p>Most recently, researchers have been going to the archive to read through the documents of Pope Pius XII. He was the pope who has been criticized for not speaking out against the Holocaust during WWII.</p>
<p>Pope Francis ordered the documents of his office opened earlier than planned, in 2020, so researchers could have a full picture of the papacy.</p>
<p>In the book, Pagano criticizes incomplete research into the process of confirming the <strong>sainthood</strong> of Pius XII. Researchers are now examining newly available documents.</p>
<p>Aside from old stories, "Secretum" also shares new ones. They include an important financial relationship between Catholics in the U.S. and the Vatican that continues today and dates back to 1922.</p>
<p>Pagano said that after Pope Benedict XV died, a financial official found that the Vatican had no money. The book shares secret messages in which the Vatican asked its ambassador in Washington D.C. to send "what you have in the safe" so that the vote for a new pope could take place.</p>
<p>The messages say the Vatican embassy sent $210,400.09 collected from the American Catholics. That permitted the vote to elect Pope Pius XI.</p>
<p>Pagano suggests that Francis' 2019 decision to remove the word "Secret" from the archive's name and rename it the Vatican Apostolic Archive was possibly a choice to gain donations. The U.S.-based group Treasures of History is aiming to support the newly renamed archive.</p>
<p>At the end of the interview, Pagano showed visitors one of the archive's prized possessions. It is the 1530 letter from British <strong>nobles</strong> urging Pope Clement VII to permit King Henry VIII to end his marriage, so he could marry Anne Boleyn.</p>
<p>Clement refused. Henry got married anyway. He broke ties with the Catholic Church in Rome and established the Church of England.</p>
<p>"You can say that here we are at the birth of the Anglican Church," Pagano said.</p>
<p>Pagano explained how the document survived. He said when Napoleon Bonaparte, the ruler of France, took documents from the Vatican archives in 1810, the chief archivist at the time hid the letter.</p>
<p>"The French never found it," Pagano said, showing that he believed an archivist's main job is to preserve the archive.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Nicole Winfield reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>archive </strong>– <em>n</em>. a place in which public records or historical materials (such as documents) are kept</p>
<p><strong>interview </strong>–n. a discussion in which one person talks with another to get information to learn more about them or what they know</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong><em>– v.</em> to keep (something) in its original state or in good condition</p>
<p><strong>saint </strong><em>– n.</em> a person who is officially recognized by the Roman Catholic Church as very holy and who is credited with holy acts called miracles</p>
<p><strong>nobility </strong><em>– n.</em> the group of people who are members of the highest social class in countries which observe such customs</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Influence Others from a 'Bully Pulpit'  (2024/2/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/influence-others-from-a-bully-pulpit.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>Today we talk about a way to share ideas, thoughts, and opinions – a bully pulpit. This common two-word noun sounds aggressive. But is it? Let's explore!</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Preachers have pulpits. Presidents have bully pulpits. Here, U.S. President Joe Biden delivers remarks at the St. John Baptist Church in Columbia, South Carolina, on January 28, 2024. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/e29a616d-e45c-41cc-a564-4d1b5af2f389_cx4_cy0_cw82_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Preachers have pulpits. Presidents have bully pulpits. Here, U.S. President Joe Biden delivers remarks at the St. John Baptist Church in Columbia, South Carolina, on January 28, 2024. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin)
</span></div>
<p>We'll start with the word "bully."</p>
<p>Usually when we use the word "bully," we are talking about a person who is cruel or threatening to others.</p>
<p>As a verb, if you bully someone you treat them in a cruel, insulting, or aggressive way. Bullies usually threaten those who are weaker or smaller than them.</p>
<p>Now the word "pulpit." A pulpit is a raised platform used in preaching or conducting a worship service.</p>
<p>So, together a bully pulpit sounds like a preacher who is bullying others. But that is not what it means.</p>
<p>A <u>bully pulpit</u> is a public-facing position – especially a political office. It provides a way to share or spread your ideas widely. If you have a <u>bully pulpit</u> you have a position of influence or power.</p>
<p>Experts say that <u>bully pulpit</u> comes from the 26th president of the United States, Theodore Roosevelt. When he was in office, he once said, "I suppose my critics will call that <strong>preaching</strong>, but I have got such a bully pulpit!"</p>
<p>Roosevelt observed that his time in office at the White House was a <strong>platform</strong> for speaking out for what he believed in. He could influence others. He understood that his presidency was his bully pulpit.</p>
<p>When then President Roosevelt used the term "bully," he meant something excellent or first-rate. This is an older meaning of the word. And these days we often use it an as<strong> interjection</strong>, saying "Bully for you!" to cheer another's success.</p>
<p>Now, let's hear this term used in a short <strong>conversation</strong>.</p>
<p><em>A: Hey, what are doing this evening? What to grab a bite?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I wish I could. But I have a <strong>board </strong>meeting for my swimming pool. </em></p>
<p><em>A: I thought you <strong>quit</strong> that board?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I did. But I have to attend one last meeting to hand off my notes to the new secretary. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Why are you quitting? I never heard the full story.</em></p>
<p><em>B: I'm quitting because of the board president. She uses her position as a bully pulpit. Instead of making the pool better, she <strong>lectures</strong> the rest of us on all kinds of issues. </em></p>
<p><em>A: It's a swimming pool? What issues come up?</em></p>
<p><em>B: Oh, you name it! We have to hear her views on everything from recycling to dog parks to the evils of potato chips. Hey, if you have time would like to replace me on the board?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Yeah ... no thanks. </em></p>
<p>While today, bully pulpit is most often used in the world of politics, we can also use it in other areas. The president of a company can use that position as a bully pulpit -- so can the principal of a school, leaders of media sites, interest groups and more.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>preach </strong><em>– v. </em>to deliver a sermon</p>
<p><strong>interjection </strong><em>– n. </em>a word or cry expressing sudden or strong feeling</p>
<p><strong>conversation </strong><em>– n. </em>oral exchange of sentiments, observations, opinions, or ideas</p>
<p><strong>board</strong> <em>– n. </em>a group of persons having managerial, supervisory, investigatory, or advisory powers</p>
<p><strong>quit</strong> <em>– v.</em> to bring to an end</p>
<p><strong>lecture </strong><em>– v. </em>to reprove formally</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Private Spacecraft Makes First US Moon Landing in More than 50 Years  (2024/2/24) | 美国私营航天器登月成功</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/private-spacecraft-makes-first-us-moon-landing-in-more-than-50-years.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>A private spacecraft has successfully touched down on the moon, marking the first U.S. lunar landing in more than 50 years.<br/>
一艘私人航天器成功着陆月球，这标志着美国50多年来首次登月。</p>
<p>The American space agency NASA confirmed the Odysseus moon lander, built by Texas company Intuitive Machines, had landed on the moon's surface Thursday.<br/>
美国宇航局证实，由德克萨斯州直觉机器公司建造的奥德修斯月球着陆器已于周四降落在月球表面。</p>
<p>Flight controllers said earlier that difficulties with the lander's navigation equipment had forced them to activate an experimental landing system at the last minute. Officials from Intuitive Machines also reported communication problems but said a signal was received from the lander after a delay.<br/>
飞行控制人员早些时候表示，着陆器导航设备出现的难题迫使他们在最后一刻启动了一个实验着陆系统。直觉机器公司的官员还报告了通信问题，但表示在延迟后收到了来自着陆器的信号。</p>
<p>"What we can confirm, without a doubt, is our equipment is on the surface of the moon," said Intuitive Machines project director Tim Crain. He was speaking to flight controllers at the company's operations center in Houston, Texas.<br/>
直觉机器项目总监蒂姆·克雷恩表示：“我们可以确认的是，毫无疑问，我们的设备在月球表面。”他在该公司位于得克萨斯州休斯顿的运营中心与飞行管制员交谈。</p>
<p>The company's chief, Steve Altemus, added, "I know this was a nail-biter, but we are on the surface, and we are transmitting. Welcome to the moon." In a message published Thursday night on X, Intuitive Machines said flight controllers had "confirmed Odysseus is upright and starting to send data."<br/>
该公司首席执行官斯蒂芬·阿尔特莫斯补充道，“我知道这是一个棘手的问题，但我们（的航天器）在月球表面，我们正在传输数据。欢迎来到月球。”周四晚上直觉机器公司在X上发布的一条消息中表示，飞行控制人员已“确认奥德修斯是直立的，并开始发送数据。”</p>
<p>The spacecraft targeted a landing spot about 300 kilometers from the moon's south pole. The area is mostly flat, but also includes large rocks, hills and craters. Officials from Intuitive Machines were not immediately able to provide details about whether Odysseus had reached its target landing area.<br/>
该航天器瞄准了距离月球南极约300公里的着陆点。该地区大部分平坦，但也包括大型岩石、山丘和火山口。直觉机器公司的官员无法立即提供奥德修斯是否到达目标着陆区的详细信息。</p>
<p>Another U.S. company, Astrobotic Technology, attempted a lunar landing last month. But that privately built lander, called Peregrine, developed a fuel leak shortly after launch and did not make it to the moon.<br/>
另一家美国公司航天机器人技术公司上个月试图登月。但这艘名为“游隼”的私营建造的着陆器在发射后不久就出现了燃料泄漏，未能成功登月。</p>
<p>Officials from Astrobotic were quick to send congratulations to the Odysseus mission team. "An incredible achievement. We can't wait to join you on the lunar surface in the near future," the company wrote on X.<br/>
航天机器人技术公司的官员很快向奥德修斯任务团队表示祝贺。该公司在X上写道：“这是一项令人难以置信的成就。我们迫不及待地想在不久的将来和你们一起登上月球表面。”</p>
<p>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson also reacted on Twitter, writing that Intuitive Machines had "aced the landing of a lifetime."<br/>
美国国家航空航天局局长比尔·纳尔逊也在推特上做出了回应，他写道，直觉机器“取得了终生难遇的成功”。</p>
<p>The last time the United States landed on the moon was in 1972, with NASA's Apollo 17 mission. So far, five nations have successfully landed spacecraft on the moon: the United States, China, the Soviet Union, Japan and India. Japan's landing came just last month.<br/>
美国上一次登月是在1972年，当时是美国宇航局的阿波罗17号任务。到目前为止，已有五个国家成功地将航天器降落在月球上：美国、中国、苏联、日本和印度。日本上个月刚刚着陆成功。</p>
<p>In addition to being the first U.S. lunar landing since 1972, the Odysseus mission marked the first time a privately built spacecraft has touched down on the moon.<br/>
奥德修斯号任务是自1972年以来美国首次登月，也是私营建造的航天器首次登月。</p>
<p>Odysseus is carrying scientific instruments and technology demonstrations for NASA and several private organizations. Experiments are to include observations of space weather activity and radio waves. The spacecraft is designed to operate for seven days on solar energy before the sun sets over the landing area.<br/>
奥德修斯号搭载了美国宇航局和几家私营组织的科学仪器和技术演示。实验将包括对空间天气活动和无线电波的观测。该航天器的设计目的是在着陆区太阳落山之前，利用太阳能运行七天。</p>
<p>NASA has said data from the lunar lander's mission will be used to help prepare for the agency's future Artemis space program. That program aims to return astronauts to the moon. NASA recently announced that its planned mission to land humans on the moon, called Artemis III, was set for September 2026.<br/>
美国宇航局表示，这次月球着陆器任务的数据将用于为该机构未来的阿尔忒弥斯太空计划做准备。该计划旨在让宇航员重返月球。美国宇航局最近宣布，其计划于2026年9月执行其人类登月的“阿耳忒弥斯3号任务”。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cuban Biologists Solve Mysteries of Bird Migration  (2024/2/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/cuban-biologists-solve-mysteries-of-bird-migration.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Researchers from Cuba are working with a Canadian partner to learn more about <strong>migratory</strong> birds that travel between North America and Cuba each year.</p>
<p>Daniela Ventura is a bird biologist at the University of Havana in Cuba. On a recent day, she caught a catbird with a net in the capital city's botanical gardens. The small, gray animal is one of the <strong>species</strong> of migratory birds that fly from the United States and Canada to Cuba each winter.</p>
<p>Ventura calls out observations to her students, who take notes nearby. She describes the species, its weight and its estimated body fat.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="University of Havana professor Daniela Ventura speaks to students at Havana's Botanical Garden, in Havana, Cuba, February 9, 2024. (REUTERS/Norlys Perez)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/771ddfaa-70dd-498b-9de9-fe0ff0439bf8_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">University of Havana professor Daniela Ventura speaks to students at Havana's Botanical Garden, in Havana, Cuba, February 9, 2024. (REUTERS/Norlys Perez)</span></div>
<p>The information provides new data for a joint project between Canada and Cuba. Ventura and the other project researchers hope to learn more about how and where the birds spend their winters in Cuba.</p>
<p>"We know a lot about their <strong>ecology</strong> in the breeding <strong>zone</strong> (in North America) but very little about what happens in their wintering zone," Ventura said.</p>
<p>Part of the problem is politics, said Lourdes Mugica. She is an expert on birds and helped organize the research.</p>
<p>A long-lasting U.S. <strong>embargo</strong> has made cooperation between the United States and Cuba difficult. That includes scientific research.</p>
<p>Migratory birds, of course, are indifferent to the restrictions.</p>
<p>"Birds don't understand embargoes or <strong>geographic</strong> borders, they don't need a visa to enter our country," Mugica said. "I hope there comes a time when relations are normal and that we can have joint projects between (the U.S. and Cuba.)"</p>
<p>Mugica says the project – with partnership from Environment and Climate Change Canada – suggests what is possible. Martin Acosta, another leading bird expert in Cuba, agrees.</p>
<p>The Canadian and Cuban partners put up a radio telemetry <strong>antenna </strong>in Cuba. The antenna operates as part of an international research network called MOTUS. It is the first time Cuba has been included in the MOTUS network.</p>
<p>The antenna can follow birds that have been <strong>radio</strong>-<strong>tagged</strong> in other parts of North America. It recently found in Cuba a small Swainson's thrush. The bird was first tagged in Canada's British Columbia – 5,000 kilometers away from the Caribbean nation.</p>
<p>"We never thought we'd reach the level of sophistication we now enjoy," said Acosta.</p>
<p>"Sophistication" means highly developed and complex.</p>
<p>Both Mugica and Acosta remember the hard days during their careers in science. Mugica said she lost over 30 kilograms doing research many years ago, at a time when food in Cuba was hard to find.</p>
<p>It is still hard to carry out their research some days, they say. Their 20-year-old truck needed a push start on a recent morning, for example.</p>
<p>But the teams celebrate small victories.</p>
<p>The catbird that Ventura recently captured had been given an identifying leg band back in November at the same place, data showed. The bird had gained body fat in the three months since, ahead of its migration north across the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>Ventura said, "To think these little birds, which weigh less than 10 grams, cross the sea and come back and survive is <strong>spectacular</strong>."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Dave Sherwood and Alien Fernandez reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>migrate </strong><em>– v. </em>to move from one area to another at different times of the year</p>
<p><strong>species </strong><em>– n. </em>a group of animals or plants that are similar and can produce young animals or plants</p>
<p><strong>ecology </strong><em>– n. </em>a science that deals with the relationships between groups of living things and their environments</p>
<p><strong>zone </strong><em>– n.</em> an area that is different from other areas in a particular way</p>
<p><strong>embargo </strong><em>– n.</em> a government order that limits trade in some way</p>
<p><strong>geography </strong><em>– n.</em> an area of study that deals with the location of countries, cities, rivers, mountains, or lakes</p>
<p><strong>antenna </strong><em>– n. </em> a device (such as a wire or a metal rod) for sending or receiving radio or television signals</p>
<p><strong>radio-tag </strong><em>– v. </em>to attach a radio transmitter to (an animal)</p>
<p><strong>spectacular </strong>– <em>adj</em>. causing wonder and admiration: very impressive</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Poland’s Traditional Dance Honored by UNESCO  (2024/2/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/poland-s-traditional-dance-honored-by-unesco.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The polonaise is a traditional Polish dance that was once banned in the country. Now, the United Nations is honoring the dance.</p>
<p>UNESCO stands for the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization. On December 5, the polonaise entered UNESCO's List of Intangible Cultural Heritage. The U.N. organization noted that the dance "<strong>symbolizes</strong> cooperation, <strong>reconciliation</strong>, and equality."</p>
<p>The dance is believed to have started in the 18th century. It has been performed at parties for the rich and powerful and at village celebrations. The polonaise has <strong>inspired</strong> music by <strong>composers</strong> such as Johann Sebastian Bach and Frederic Chopin. And it remains an important part of school and family celebrations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Dancers of the WARSZAWIANKA ensemble of the University of Warsaw dance Poland's national polonaise dance in 18th century costumes during dress rehearsal in Warsaw, Poland, on Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-069a-08dc325e4c2c_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Dancers of the WARSZAWIANKA ensemble of the University of Warsaw dance Poland's national polonaise dance in 18th century costumes during dress rehearsal in Warsaw, Poland, on Feb. 8, 2024. (AP Photo/Czarek Sokolowski)</span></div>
<p>Poland's Ministry of Culture and National Heritage asked for the Polonaise to be included on UNESCO's list. The ministry said its request received huge public support.</p>
<p>"Thousands of people on Facebook and on other social media were supporting the (UNESCO) entry," Joanna Cicha-Kuczynska of the ministry's Department of Monuments Protection, told <em>The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>She said there is a huge community, including whole families, that dance the polonaise and pass the tradition on.</p>
<p>In the polonaise, a whole group can dance together, explained Marcin Pracki, a dancer of the Warsaw University's Dance Theater.</p>
<p>Another dancer, Monika Fiugajska, said the dance's simplicity is its strength. She added that the polonaise can express emotions in a special way.</p>
<p>The dance developed from a traditional form called the "walking dance." By the 18th century, it had become popular at royal European balls, or dance parties.</p>
<p>The word polonaise is French for "Polish."</p>
<p>Szymon Paczkowski is a musicology professor at the University of Warsaw. He agrees that the dance should be on UNESCO's list. "It is a dance with not only Polish but an international tradition," he said.</p>
<p>In the late 18th century, Russia, Prussia, and Austria divided and controlled Poland for more than 100 years. Russia banned the polonaise in the areas it took over.</p>
<p>During this time, the polonaise became an important connection to Poland for Polish people, especially those in foreign countries. This included Chopin, who left Poland in 1830 and moved to Paris the following year. Today, Chopin's polonaises remain among the most popular pieces for <strong>classical</strong> piano.</p>
<p>In Poland, the polonaise has now become the opening dance at high school pre-graduation balls. After World War II, Poland's communist officials banned it from schools. The officials worried about its connection to Polish patriotism and former rulers.</p>
<p>Nineteen-year-old Gabrysia Kosmal was among the students at one of Warsaw's high schools who performed the polonaise this month. She noted that although there are conflicts between students, when they dance the polonaise, they come together. "It's a magical moment," she said.</p>
<p>The polonaise is regularly performed during national anniversaries, including the November 11 Independence Day. On this day, people are invited to dance in the streets with officials.</p>
<p>Natalia Berna is an 18-year-old student who took part in a large street dance in the central city of Lodz last month. She said the polonaise brings people together at a time when the community needs it. She added that it is important to keep the tradition alive.</p>
<p>The leader of the Lodz street dance, Janusz Wielgosz, said the polonaise is about beauty.</p>
<p>"It is a dance that is really very simple, with beautiful music and beautiful <strong>costumes</strong>. It is worth a try," he said.</p>
<p>I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Monika Scislowska and Rafal Neidzielski reported this story for the Associated Press. Andrew Smith adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>symbolize </strong><em>–v.</em> to represent an idea or belief</p>
<p><strong>reconciliation </strong><em>–n</em>. the act of bringing people together to put aside their earlier differences or troubles</p>
<p><strong>inspire </strong><em>–v.</em> to cause people to want to do something or to be hopeful about the future</p>
<p><strong>composer </strong><em>–n.</em> a person whose job it is to write and arrange music</p>
<p><strong>classical </strong><em>–adj.</em> related to music and other art forms of a time period in Europe that embodied certain ideals believed to be from ancient times that were accepted and liked by educated people</p>
<p><strong>costume </strong><em>–n. </em>a kind of clothing that is different from things worn daily and is linked to cultural activities</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>'Do' for Emphasis  (2024/2/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/do-for-emphasis.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Teacher Sahraoui.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>My student answered a question I asked in a written test as follows:</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: 'Do' for emphasis" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-db55-08dc32f28daa_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: 'Do' for emphasis</span></div>
<p><em>Yes, consumers do adopt new habits.</em></p>
<p>Shall I consider the answer grammatically incorrect because of the use of auxiliary do, even though the rest of the sentence is ok?</p>
<p>Thanks for answering.</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for writing, Sahraoui. Your question points out an important purpose for "do" in statements.</p>
<p>We know that "do" does many things in English. It can serve as an auxiliary verb in negative statements. For example:</p>
<p><em>I <u>do</u>n't have any money.</em></p>
<p>It can also serve as an auxiliary verb in questions:</p>
<p><em><u>Does</u> Brent have to work on weekends?</em></p>
<p><em>What <u>do</u> you think?</em></p>
<p>Or it can provide a short answer to a yes/no question.</p>
<p><em>Yes, I <u>do</u>.</em></p>
<p><em>No, I <u>do</u>n't.</em></p>
<p>In addition to all that, it can make imperatives, or commands, more polite.</p>
<p><em><u>Do</u> come in.</em></p>
<p>"Do" can also be used to make sentences clearer and shorter.</p>
<p><em>Bill likes to swim, and so <u>does</u> Betty.</em></p>
<p>You asked if the sentence your student wrote is grammatically incorrect because of the use of "do." Well, there is one <strong>function</strong> of "do," which we have not yet discussed: <strong>emphasis</strong>.</p>
<p>"Do" is one way users of English bring attention to a whole or part of a message.</p>
<p>A whole sentence can be emphasized by adding "do." For example:</p>
<p><em>It <u>does</u> taste good!</em></p>
<p><em>We <u>did</u> enjoy the play.</em></p>
<p><em>I <u>do</u> want to learn.</em></p>
<p>The sentence you ask about is grammatically correct. The use of "do" shows emphasis.</p>
<p>I'm not sure if this is what your student meant when he wrote "do." He might need a little more help with answering questions. But the sentence is grammatically correct.</p>
<p>Please let us know if this explanation has helped you, Sahraoui.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>function</strong>—<em>n</em>. the part that a thing plays; a purpose</p>
<p><strong>emphasis</strong>—<em>n</em>. special importance, value, or attention</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Science Celebrating 200 Years of Dinosaur Research  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/science-celebrating-200-years-of-dinosaur-research.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>On February 20, 1824, British scientist and Christian clergyman William Buckland spoke before the Geological Society of London. He described the find of a huge jaw and other bones at a rock mine in the village of Stonesfield near Oxford, England.</p>
<p>Buckland recognized that these <strong>fossils</strong> belonged to a huge reptile of the long past. He gave it the scientific name Megalosaurus, meaning "great lizard."</p>
<p>With that, the first dinosaur was officially recognized, although the word dinosaur did not come for several more years.</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A Tyrannosaurus rex skeleton is seen at the Smithsonian Natural History Museum dinosaur and fossil hall in Washington, U.S., June 4, 2019. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/a6876986-3e65-4026-9731-f6ff8773ba4e_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - A Tyrannosaurus rex skeleton is seen at the Smithsonian Natural History Museum dinosaur and fossil hall in Washington, U.S., June 4, 2019. (REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Buckland's talk "was the beginning of our <strong>fascination</strong> with dinosaurs," says University of Edinburgh paleontologist Steve Brusatte.</p>
<p>"His announcement opened the flood gates," he said, and many people launched their own fossil hunts.</p>
<p>"People went out looking for other <strong>giant</strong> bones in England and beyond," Brusatte said.</p>
<p>In the almost 200 years since, dinosaur science has ballooned. Researchers have learned much about how these creatures looked, lived and developed, or evolved. Scientists also learned what caused the disappearance of the ancient animals.</p>
<p>Dinosaurs lived from about 231 million years ago to 66 million years ago during the Mesozoic Era. They are ancestors to birds of today. Science has identified over 2,000 species of dinosaur.</p>
<p>"Our understanding of dinosaurs has changed <strong>significantly</strong> since the 19th century," said paleontologist Emma Nicholls of the Oxford University Museum of Natural History. It is home to the Megalosaurus fossils that Buckland studied.</p>
<p>By the 1840s, other dinosaur researchers were learning that some dinosaurs walked on four legs and others walked on two legs. The Megalosaurus belongs to a group known as theropods. The group also includes meat-eaters Tyranosaurus and Spinosaurus, animals which "<strong>scampered</strong>" on their legs. Both species grew to about 9 meters tall and used their sharp <strong>claws</strong> and strong, toothy jaws to overpower <strong>prey</strong>, Brusatte said.</p>
<p>Evidence of dinosaurs has been found all around the world. The first complete dinosaur <strong>skeletons </strong>were set up in the 1870s.</p>
<p>In the 1960s, the discovery of a small dinosaur changed popular thinking about the animal group. Deinonychus was a fast-moving meat-eater. Some smaller dinosaurs, like Archaeopteryx, were found to be very much like early birds in body structure. The new research confirmed how birds evolved from small, feathered dinosaurs.</p>
<p>In the years that followed, scientists used new imaging tools to learn more about how dinosaurs grew and moved. Other tools permitted them to make good guesses about their colors, because some dinosaur remains had small pieces of skin or feathers that contained pigment, or color.</p>
<p>Thomas Holtz is a paleontologist at the University of Maryland. He said all of the research created "a more <strong>dynamic</strong> and biological view of dinosaurs as living things."</p>
<p>In recent years, fossils have been found in China, Argentina, Brazil, South Africa and Mongolia.</p>
<p>Hans-Dieter Sues is a paleontologist at the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History in Washington, D.C. He said the most important recent discovery is that the theropods were covered with feathers although they could not fly. He said the feathers kept the dinosaurs warm and were used for show.</p>
<p>One question that concerned scientists from the beginning was why the dinosaurs died. They came up with many theories. One scientist even said small mammals might have eaten all the dinosaur eggs.</p>
<p>Scientists have since settled on an answer. They believe an asteroid that hit the Earth in what is now southern Mexico was to blame for the disappearance of dinosaurs. Experts believe the event destroyed about 75 percent of life on Earth, including all its dinosaurs.</p>
<p>But what if there had been no asteroid? Would dinosaurs still rule the world today?</p>
<p>Holtz of the University of Maryland says "almost certainly, yes." He notes that some mammals existed at the time of dinosaurs but they were all small. He said dinosaurs would have needed to evolve as the Earth cooled and some forests dried out.</p>
<p>In the last 200 years, scientists also have a better idea of the largest and smallest dinosaurs. One 2023 study said the largest dinosaur was Argentinosaurus, which measured about 35 meters long and weighed 76 tonnes.</p>
<p>But Holtz said there is still more research to be done.</p>
<p>He said many areas of the world have not been explored by paleontologists. That offers hope of more dino finds.</p>
<p>"There are almost assuredly entire groups of dinosaurs which we currently know nothing about waiting to be discovered," Holtz said.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver. And I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Will Dunham reported this story for Reuters. Dan Friedell adapted the story for Learning English based on a report by Reuters.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fossil </strong><em>–n.</em> something (such as a leaf, skeleton, or footprint) that is from a plant or animal which lived in ancient times and that you can see in some rocks</p>
<p><strong>fascination </strong><em>–n.</em> a great interest in something</p>
<p><strong>giant </strong><em>–adj.</em> extremely large</p>
<p><strong>significantly </strong><em>–adj.</em> to a large and notable degree</p>
<p><strong>scamper </strong><em>–v.</em> to run very fast, but usually related to a small creature</p>
<p><strong>claw </strong><em>–n.</em> a sharp nail attached to a hand or finger of an animal</p>
<p><strong>prey </strong><em>–n.</em> an animal that is the food of another animal</p>
<p><strong>skeleton </strong><em>–n.</em> the connected bones of an animal without skin</p>
<p><strong>dynamic </strong><em>–adj.</em> something that has a lot of energy and interest</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US State Court Rules Embryos Can Be Considered Children  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/us-state-court-rules-embryos-can-be-considered-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Supreme Court of Alabama has ruled that frozen embryos can be considered children under state law.</p>
<p>The ruling immediately influenced the way fertility treatment services operate in the southeastern U.S. state. On Wednesday, the University of Alabama Birmingham Hospital said it paused all fertility treatments while it considers the ruling's significance.</p>
<p>The court decision involved two wrongful death cases brought by three <strong>couples</strong> who had frozen embryos destroyed in an accident at a fertility center.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The exterior of the Alabama Supreme Court building in Montgomery, Ala., is shown Tuesday, Feb. 20, 2024. (AP Photo/Kim Chandler)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-71b5-08dc33c6e1df_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The exterior of the Alabama Supreme Court building in Montgomery, Ala., is shown Tuesday, Feb. 20, 2024. (AP Photo/Kim Chandler)</span></div>
<p>In their decision, the justices noted recent and longstanding parts of the Alabama Constitution. The justices ruled that an 1872 state law permitting parents to bring legal action over the death of a minor child "<strong>applies</strong> to all unborn children, regardless of their location."</p>
<p>"Unborn children are ‘children' ... without exception based on developmental stage, physical location, or any other...<strong>characteristics</strong>," Justice Jay Mitchell wrote. The high court released the ruling on February 16.</p>
<p>Mitchell said the court had ruled earlier that fetuses killed while a woman is pregnant are covered under Alabama's Wrongful Death of a Minor Act. Nothing excludes "<strong>extrauterine</strong> children from the Act's coverage," he wrote.</p>
<p>The ruling is likely to influence fertility treatments and the activity of freezing of embryos, which are fertilized eggs. A court <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.fairfaxcounty.gov/circuit/sites/circuit/files/assets/documents/pdf/opinions/cl-2021-15372-honeyhline-heidemann-v-jason-heidemann.pdf">opinion</a> in Virginia last year said that frozen embryos can be considered property.</p>
<p>Barbara Collura is chief of RESOLVE: The National Infertility Association, a non-profit group based in Virginia. Collura told the Associated Press that the ruling raises questions for "in vitro fertilization," or IVF, the method of fertilizing eggs in a laboratory.</p>
<p>She said the "ruling is stating that a fertilized egg, which is a clump of cells, is now a person. It really puts into question, the practice of IVF." The group called the Alabama high court's decision "terrifying" for people affected by infertility.</p>
<p>She said the ruling also raises questions for providers of IVF services and for patients. It is unclear whether they can freeze embryos created during fertility treatment or if patients could ever donate or destroy unused embryos.</p>
<p>Sean Tipton is a spokesman with the American Society for Reproductive Medicine. He said at least one Alabama fertility center was told to stop IVF treatments by the hospital overseeing it since the decision.</p>
<p>Dr. Paula Amato is president of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine in Washington D.C. She said: "No health care provider will be willing to provide treatments if those treatments may lead to civil or criminal charges."</p>
<p>The couples in the Alabama case had undergone IVF treatments that led to the creation of several embryos. Some of the embryos were <strong>implanted</strong> and resulted in healthy births. The couples paid to keep the other embryos frozen in a storage center at the Mobile Infirmary Medical Center. A patient in 2020 entered the area and removed several embryos, dropping them on the floor and "killing them," the ruling said.</p>
<p>The justices then ruled that couple's wrongful death legal case could go forward. The clinic and hospital that are defendants in the case could ask the court to reconsider its decision.</p>
<p>One group that opposes abortion, the non-profit Live Action, supported the decision. "Each person, from the tiniest embryo to an elder nearing the end of his life...deserves and is guaranteed legal protection," said President Lila Rose in a statement.</p>
<p>Justice Greg Cook wrote the only full <strong>dissent</strong> to the majority opinion. He said the 1872 law did not define "minor child" and the meaning of the term was being extended to cover frozen embryos.</p>
<p>He added the ruling "almost certainly ends the creation of frozen embryos through in vitro fertilization (IVF) in Alabama."</p>
<p>The Alabama Supreme Court decision partly depended on language added to the Alabama Constitution in 2018. It states it is the policy of the "state to ensure the protection of the rights of the unborn child."</p>
<p>In Alabama, supreme court justices are elected officials who serve six-year terms. Currently, all are members of the Republican Party.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>couple </strong><em>— n. </em>two people linked by a relationship or marriage</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>apply </strong><em>— v. </em>to cover under law</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>characteristic </strong><em>— n. </em>a quality that makes something different from something else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extrauterine </strong><em>— adj. </em>outside of a woman's womb and body</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>implant </strong>–v. to put into the womb by medical operation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>dissent </strong><em>— n. </em>an opinion in disagreement to the majority opinion in a court which can serve other legal cases and future legal findings</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Report: Language, Traditions Central to National Identity  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/report-language-traditions-central-to-national-identity.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Luciana de Oliveira considers herself transnational. That means she is more than one nationality. de Oliveira grew up in Brazil, but she moved to the United States for her studies. She became a U.S. citizen in 2017.</p>
<p>de Oliveira has some strong feelings about national identity. She believes speaking a country's majority language is a very important part of one's national identity. de Oliveira speaks both Portuguese and English.</p>
<p>A new study found that most people around the world share those feelings about language and national identity.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Daughters of imprisoned women celebrate their 15th birthday, a tradition called quinceanera, at the San Marta Acatitla rehabilitation in the Iztapalapa neighborhood of Mexico City, Friday, Aug. 18, 2023. (AP Photo/Arnulfo Franco)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/5c824fe2-c696-421e-9d60-5ac0b7578ba7_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Daughters of imprisoned women celebrate their 15th birthday, a tradition called quinceanera, at the San Marta Acatitla rehabilitation in the Iztapalapa neighborhood of Mexico City, Friday, Aug. 18, 2023. (AP Photo/Arnulfo Franco)</span></div>
<p>The Pew Research Center carried out the study and released the results last month. Pew's study centered on people's ideas about national identity. It included answers from people in more than 20 countries.</p>
<p>Pew researchers asked study <strong>participants</strong> about four aspects, or parts, of national identity: language, traditions, birthplace and religion. They found that language is by far the most valued aspect of national identity.</p>
<p>In fact, a median of 91 percent of people across 21 countries said that speaking a country's most common language is "important for being considered a true national."</p>
<p>Traditions and <strong>customs</strong> are also <strong>key</strong> to national identity, the study found. Beliefs about the other two aspects – birthplace and religion – were more divided.</p>
<p>VOA Learning English spoke with several people who live in countries that were included in the study. Among them is Jorge Catalan. He has lived in Mexico most of his life. The Pew study found that 93 percent of <strong>respondents</strong> from Mexico said that speaking the country's main language – Spanish – is important to national identity.</p>
<p>Catalan said he agrees that speaking Spanish is very important. But he added that it is regrettable.</p>
<p>He said, "Mexico is a place where we have around 68 spoken languages besides Spanish." He noted that the government has pushed Spanish as the main language throughout history and has turned it into a "must-have tool."</p>
<p>Agatha Janzen was born and raised in Canada. Pew researchers found that more than 80 percent of Canadians say that speaking the country's language is important to national identity. In Canada, both French and English are official languages.</p>
<p>Janzen said that "speaking one of the official languages is important to being Canadian for <strong>practical</strong> reasons."</p>
<p>Traditions and customs are also a central aspect of national identity, the study found. Results showed 81 percent of people believe sharing their country's customs and traditions is somewhat or very important to national identity.</p>
<p>The Pew study found that 67 percent of Brazilians consider practicing customs and traditions an important part of national identity. That is the fourth lowest percentage of all the countries included in the study.</p>
<p>But customs and traditions are important to de Oliveira. To feel closer to her Brazilian identity, she said she wears jewelry and shoes from Brazil and follows and supports Brazilian soccer.</p>
<p>Mexico is tied with the highest percentage of respondents who answered that customs and traditions are an important aspect of national identity. But for Catalan, they are not so important. He noted that Mexican traditions have changed over time. He added that he does not take part in many Mexican traditions, "but I still feel <strong>proudly</strong> Mexican."</p>
<p>Beliefs about the two other aspects of national identity – birthplace and religion – were more mixed. A median of 58 percent of respondents from 23 countries said that being born in a country is important to national identity. An even lower number of respondents – 42 percent – said that being a member of the country's main religion is important to national identity.</p>
<p>Respondents from Mexico and Indonesia had the strongest feelings about the importance of birthplace as central to national identity, at 91 percent.</p>
<p>Calatan, who was born and lived most of his life in Mexico, agrees somewhat. "If you are born outside of Mexico and never lived in it, it would be difficult to get a real sense of what being Mexican means."</p>
<p>But Janzen, the Canadian, said, "Being born in Canada has nothing to do with being Canadian." For her, Canada is a <strong>melting pot</strong> and offers refuge to those who need it.</p>
<p>These ideas match the results of the study. Countries where immigrants make up a smaller share of the population tend to see birthplace as a more important aspect of national identity. Countries with a greater share of immigrants are more willing to accept those born outside of the country as true nationals.</p>
<p>Less than half of people in most of the countries in the study do not feel religion is important to national identity. All of those who spoke with Learning English said they agreed that religion is not an important part of national identity.</p>
<p>Christine Huang is a research associate at the Pew Research Center. She is one of the writers of the study. She told Learning English, "This question of belonging in a country is related to other work we have done to measure how connected people feel to each other."</p>
<p>Huang added, "When looking at how people relate to others in their community, in their country, and all over the world, people most frequently report feeling close to others in their country."</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this story for Learning English with reporting from Pew Research Center.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>respondent</strong>—<em>n</em>. a person who answers questions</p>
<p><strong>customs</strong>—<em>n</em>. the traditionally accepted behaviors of a culture</p>
<p><strong>key</strong>—<em>adj</em>. most important</p>
<p><strong>participants</strong>—<em>adj</em>. people who take part in an activity</p>
<p><strong>practical</strong>—<em>adj</em>. real situations and events, not just theory or ideas</p>
<p><strong>proud</strong>—<em>adj</em>. feeling pleasure or satisfaction about something</p>
<p><strong>melting</strong> <strong>pot</strong>—<em>figure of speech</em>. a place where different people, beliefs, and cultures melt into one</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Is Popular in Different Countries?  (2024/2/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/what-is-popular-in-different-countries.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In a recent <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/what-is-popular-in-your-country-/7488370.html" target="_blank">lesson</a>, we asked our readers and listeners to write to us about what is popular in their country.</p>
<p>In today's lesson, we will explore some of what was written to us. Our audience will be the guides of our imaginative tour of cultures around the world. We will learn about English grammar on the way.</p>
<p><strong>Turkey </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Everyday Grammar " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-8477-08dc33422395_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Everyday Grammar </span></div>
<p>Let's start with a message from a friend in Turkey.</p>
<p><em>Greetings from Turkey, I am Furkan. </em></p>
<p><em>I think, K<i></i>305;vanc Tatl<i></i>305;tug is a popular in Turkey. Because the whole country knows him. </em></p>
<p>Furkan wrote a very clear message. Our main suggestion is to remove a couple of words and add a little more explanation.</p>
<p>We can take out the words "I think." We can also remove the part about the "whole country knows him."</p>
<p>When we say someone is popular, we can <strong>assume</strong> that many or most people in a place know about the person.</p>
<p>You could also explain a little more deeply why Kivanc Tatlitug is popular. For example, you might say he is handsome, talented, and so on.</p>
<p>So, you might update the message to something like this:</p>
<p><em>K<i></i>305;vanc Tatl<i></i>305;tug is popular in Turkey <u>because he is handsome, talented, and wealthy</u>. </em></p>
<p><strong>Venezuela </strong></p>
<p>Now let's examine part of a message from Gorka in Venezuela. Gorka says this about baseball, a popular sport in the country:</p>
<p>
<em>... this sport is practiced by people of all ages and in all the states of the country. There are many baseball schools, some of them <strong>sponsored</strong> by American baseball organizations.<br/>
Every year more that one hundred Venezuelan baseball players go to USA to play in the MLB or other related leagues.<br/>
Not surprisingly these players inspire younger baseball players to follow their steps. </em></p>
<p>Gorka wrote an excellent description. Our main suggestion is to pay careful attention to short words.</p>
<p>Instead of "that" we can use "than," as in "more than one hundred Venezuelan baseball players." And we want to add "the" in front of "USA" like this:</p>
<p><em>Every year, more <u>than</u> one hundred Venezuelan baseball players <u>go to the USA</u> to play in the MLB or other related leagues. </em></p>
<p>A final word about the last sentence from Gorka. While it is correct to say "follow their steps," in this situation, we often say "follow in their footsteps." We use "follow in their footsteps" when someone does something before us and we follow what they did. For example:</p>
<p><em>If your father is a doctor and you become a doctor, you could say that you are <u>following in your father's footsteps</u>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Japan </strong></p>
<p>Now let's turn to Japan. An unnamed reader sent us this note about a popular food.</p>
<p><em>Most popular food in Japan is RAMEN. I think because Ramen has huge kinds of taste. </em></p>
<p>The message is clear and to the point. Once again, we need to pay special attention to short words and remove a few other words. We need to include the word "the" at the beginning of the message, as in:</p>
<p><em><u>The</u> most popular food in Japan is ramen. </em></p>
<p>While the meaning of "huge kinds of taste" is understandable, we might instead use different structures to express the same idea. For example, English speakers might say that the taste is complex, bold, or rich. We might update the entire message to something like this:</p>
<p><em>The most popular food in Japan is ramen because it <u>has a rich, complex taste. </u></em></p>
<p><strong>Spain </strong></p>
<p>Finally, Rafael from Spain writes to us. He notes that he does not like the most popular sport, soccer. Rafael ends his message with the following:</p>
<p><em>... Since I don't like soccer, I feel a little weirdo. But not as much as you, John, who are in love with grammar!<br/>
Thank you very much for your teaching, John,<br/>
See you soon! </em></p>
<p>Rafael wrote a very light-hearted, humorous message. The main correction needed is to add the word "like" after the verb "feel" and remove the word "little." So, the statement could become:</p>
<p><em>Since I don't like soccer, I feel <u>like</u> a weirdo. </em></p>
<p>A quick note about the term "weirdo." We often use it in a negative, or disapproving, way. So, you should be careful about using it. If you choose to use the term, make sure that the person it is directed at understands that you are not being serious.</p>
<p>Rafael's message, for example, clearly used the word in a joking manner. Still, his point is correct:</p>
<p><em>I am a grammar weirdo.</em></p>
<p>And that's Everyday Grammar.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>assume </strong><em>– v.</em> to think that something is true or probably true</p>
<p><strong>sponsor </strong><em>– v.</em> to give money to an athlete for training, clothes, equipment, etc.,</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
