<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>VOA Special English</title>
        <link>https://www.51voa.com/VOA_Special_English/</link>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <itunes:category>ESL</itunes:category>
        <itunes:author>VOA</itunes:author>
        <description>美国之音（以下称VOA）的英语节目，按播音速度可分为两种：Standard English （标准英语）和 Special English（特别英语）。

Special English 又叫“慢速英语”，是VOA 专为全世界非英语国家初学英语的听众安排的一种简易、规范的英语广播节目。该节目创始于50年代末期，是VOA 的专家们研究如何与世界各地的英语学习者进行交际的产物。它正式开播于1959年10月。当时只面向欧洲和中东，但由于这个节目适合许多国家英语学习者的需要，所以它的广播对象不久就扩大到世界其他地区，并很快在全世界范围内产生了广泛的影响。现在这个节目对欧洲、非洲和拉丁美洲每晚广播一次，对加勒比地区每晚广播一次（星期天除外），对东南亚广播次数最多，每天上午两次，晚上三次。

30多年来，VOA 为了办好Special English节目，进行了大量的调查研究工作，对播音速度、内容及用词范围都作了具体规定，基本上达到了既能为英语学习者提供信息，又不损害英语本身风格的目的，使之成为VOA 独具特色，拥有最大量听众的节目。

美国著名词汇学家S. B. Flexmer 指明了Special English的三条标准，也就是它所“特别”的地方：

1、它是一种由美国人最常用的1500个基本单词为主体构成的美国英语；

2、它用简短、明晰的句子写作和广播；

3、它以每分钟90个单词的速度，即2/3的Standard English（标准英语）速度进行广播。

Special English的节目可分为两大类：一类是新闻节目；一类是专题节目。

1．新闻节目

VOA Special English 的新闻广播向听众提供世界范围内的政治、经济、军事、外交、国际关系、宗教、天气以及各种重大事件和珍闻奇事等各个方面的信息，每天向东南亚地区广播五次，早上两次，晚上三次，每逢半点播出。

Special English新闻节目每次长约十分钟，大都播出十条左右新闻，近一千个单词，每条新闻多为一分钟，但偶尔也有长达两分钟的要闻。除头条新闻外，每条新闻都由一个电头引导，这样显得结构分明，条理清晰，适宜初学英语的人收听。在节目结束之前，播音员常常用三四句话重播其中三条新闻的提要以加深听众对要闻的印象。

Special English新闻中70%左右的内容与同时整点播出的Standard English新闻相同，但相同新闻的先后次序有所变动。每次节目的开头和结尾大同小异，格式比较固定。

2．专题节目（一）

Special English的专题节目（Feature Programs）,从时间上看，可分为两大类：一是每五分钟一次的专题，二是每十五分钟一次的专题。本节先介绍每项五分钟一次的专题材节目。

Special English五分钟一次的专题材节目安排在Special English新闻节目之后和（或）每十五分钟一次的专题材节目之前播出，每星期播七次。根据内容，可分为三个小类，即：Science Report（科学报道），逢星期一、三、五播出，每天播六遍；Agriculture Report（农业报道），逢星期二、四播出，每天播六遍；Words And Their Stories（词语掌故），逢星期六和星期天播出，每天播五遍。这三个专题材各具特色，具有相对的独立性，听众每听完一个节目，都会获得一个完整的印象。

Science Report（科学报道）这一专题材节目每周向听众介绍三篇有关现代科学技术最新发展情况的报道，涉及物理、化学、天文至高无上理、生物、环卫、心理、教育、医学和计算机等方面。适宜理工科大学生和科技工作者收集信息，积累资料，学习科技英语。

Agriculture Report（农业报道） Agriculture Report是为农业科技工作者和生产者安排的一个专题。它专门报道世界各国，特别是美国现代农业生产的最新成文汇报总务科 学家对农业生产某一方面的研究进展，以及他们对影响农业生产的某一自然现象进行分析和研究的近况。此外，它还经常向听众介绍发展中国家家业生产的一些有益经验等内容。

Words And Their Stories（词语掌故）这一专题节目，旨在向学习英语的听众介绍美国英语中生动有趣的词语和惯用法，并从科学研究和通俗词源学的角度来解释它们的含意、产生的背景及其在使用过程中的演变情况等。它通过讲故事的形式讲解每一个词语。这是VOA Special English中的优秀节目之一，是学习美国英语的极好材料。通过收听这一节目，听众不仅能学到娓娓动听的掌故和地道的美国英语，而且能增加美国的社会文化背景知识，历史传统与现状的了解。

VOA 为了更好地办好这个节目，便于听众收听学习，于1978年编辑出版了一本名为Words And Their Stories的书，共收集一百篇故事，作者是Herbert Sutcliffe, Harold Bermen 及VOA 该节目的部分编辑人员。在每次的实际广播中，播音员都以此书为蓝本，再根据需要对原稿进行适当增删。按每周两个故事计算，此书的一百个故事还不能满足一年的播音需要。于是编辑们就是重播部分词语掌故的同时，不断增加许多新的词语掌故，及时将词源学家的最新研究成果和不断增加的新词汇介绍给听众。收听实践证明，初学者在收听过程中必然会遇到许多人名、地名和一些较难的句子，有时甚至在听完之后还很难理解所播词语的确切含义及其汉语意思，为此，听众可参看1983年由中国对外翻译出版公司出版的该书英汉对照本中的有关部分。

3．专题节目（二）

VOA Special English的专题节目，除上节谈的五分钟一次的以外，还有本节要介绍的每十五分钟一次的节目。这类节目共有七个不同的小专题，以星期为单位循环，每天分四次复播出一个专题，但星期日和星期六的两个专题材每晚只播三遍，每次节目约十分钟，继每次五分钟的专题节目之后播出。

这类专题节目的基本结构是，在特定的伴声中先报告当次节目的名称，并扼要介绍其主要内容，然后播送节目正文。最后，在伴乐声中报告节目主持人和撰稿人的姓名，以邀请听众在下周的这个时间继续收听该节目而结束。

People in America（美国人物志） 这是有关美国历史名人的一个专题节目，每逢星期天晚上播出。它向听众介绍在美国历史上产生过重大影响、起过重要作用、作出了突出贡献的科学、文学、政治、或其他各方面的历史人物。节目一般都对他们的生平事迹进行简要的叙述，对其贡献作出评介，类似人物小传。有的重要人物事迹很多，必须用两次或几次的节目时间进行联播。对这样的节目要坚持收听，才会获得完整的印象。

TThis is America（今日美国） This Is America向听众介绍美国人民的生活、学习、工作和娱乐情况，是英语学习者解美国社会的一条渠道。该专题大都一个节目一个整体，每逢星期一晚播出。

Science in the News（科学新闻） 这一专题材主要对新近的科学技术新闻进行综述或摘要广播。向听众介绍世界各国在自然、医学、疾病、原子能、航天等方面的科研动态、成果、突破性进展及存在的困难。涉及当今世界人们普遍关心的重大问题，如核事故、航天飞机爆炸、自然灾害、环境污染和爱滋病等等。每逢星期二播出，每次播一到五条新闻摘要。

Explorations（自然探索） 每逢星期三晚上，听众可以收听到Explorations这一专题节目。该专题既涉及人类遨游太空、探索原子、研究自身、改造自然的现代技术，也报道发展中国家开发新资源，利用新工艺改善人民生活等方面的成就，其侧重点在各种科技实验和简易实用技术方面。该节目一般安排一段时间播一个系列，每次播出一个主题，以便能将某项新技术的研究和应用的全过程介绍给听众，电台还乐意为感兴趣的听众提供所需的文字材料。

The Making of a Nation（建国史话） 这一专题节目向听众介绍美利坚合众国从十三个殖民地区域到现代工业国的孕育、诞生以及形成超级大国的历史过程，并以历史为线索，特定的历史时期为单位，以重大的历史事件为主题材来叙述各个党派、各届总统和政府的历史作用与贡献。这是每个英语学习者都应了解的基本知识。The Making of a Nation每逢星期四播出。这是个系列节目，坚持收听，则有助于系统了解美国的历史概况。

American Mosaic（美国万花筒） American Mosaic是一个radio magazine（广播杂志）节目。该节目题材广泛、内容丰，展示着美国社会文化生活中比较轻松愉快的生活画面；听众收听该节目就如同在阅读一本图文并茂的杂志。它每次有三到五个小节目，涉及音乐、图书、技术和教育等方面的内容。我们既可以从中欣赏到著名歌唱的优秀歌曲，对美国音乐有所了解，又可以获取一些生动有趣的现代美国社会生活知识，随着播音员那亲切悦耳的声音步入美国风景如画的大好河山；同时还能听到世界各地的听众提出的有关英语语方文学等方面的问题和电台的解答。

American Stories（美国故事） 这一专题材节目安排在每星期六晚上播出。这样能使听众在学习和工作之余，得以轻松一下头脑。我们可以通过这一美国文学的“窗口”，接触各种流派、各类名家的文学作品。了解美国英语的时代特色，欣赏、学习美国人民运用语方的技巧，并从那些佳作名篇中获得艺术享受。该节目对短篇故事采取一次播一篇的方式，对中、长篇小说则先进行简写加工，再分几次播出全文。在播出故事正文之前，播音员常常先介绍故事的主要情节。对需要分几次节目时间播出的中长篇，在播第二或以后各部分之前，主持人还先重述已播部分的故事梗概，以唤起听众的回忆，使故事听起来更加连贯。</description>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          <item>
            <title>Webb Telescope Captures Images of 19 Spiral Galaxies  (2024/2/4) | 韦伯太空望远镜拍下19个螺旋星系图片</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/webb-telescope-captures-images-of-19-spiral-galaxies.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Newly released images captured by the James Webb Space Telescope show 19 spiral galaxies relatively close to our Milky Way. The images offer new information on star formation, galaxy structure and evolution.<br/>
詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜最新发布的图像显示了距离我们银河系相对较近的19个螺旋星系。这些图像提供了关于恒星形成、星系结构和演化的新信息。</p>
<p>The images were made public on Monday by a team of scientists involved in a project called Physics at High Angular resolution in Nearby GalaxieS (PHANGS). The project operates across several major astronomical observatories.<br/>
周一，一个名为“邻近星系高角分辨率物理学”的项目下的科学家团队公开了这些图像。该项目在几个主要的天文台运行。</p>
<p>The closest of the 19 galaxies is called NGC5068. It is about 15 million light years from Earth. The most distant is NGC1365, about 60 million light years from Earth. A light year is the distance light travels in a year, which is equal to about 9.5 trillion kilometers.<br/>
19个星系中距离最近的一个被称为NGC50068。它距离地球大约1500万光年。最遥远的是NGC1365，距离地球约6000万光年。一光年是光在一年中传播的距离，约等于9.5万亿公里。</p>
<p>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) was launched in 2021 and began collecting data in 2022. It has shaped understanding of the early universe while taking pictures of space.<br/>
詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜于2021年发射，并于2022年开始收集数据。它在拍摄太空照片的同时，塑造了人们对早期宇宙的理解。</p>
<p>The orbiting telescope looks at the universe mainly in the infrared. The Hubble Space Telescope, which was launched in 1990 and is still in use, has examined the universe mostly at optical and ultraviolet wavelengths.<br/>
轨道望远镜主要在红外波段观察宇宙。哈勃太空望远镜于1990年发射，目前仍在使用中，主要在光学和紫外线波长下对宇宙进行了探测。</p>
<p>Spiral galaxies are a common galaxy type. Our Milky Way is one.<br/>
螺旋星系是一种常见的星系类型。我们的银河系就是其中之一。</p>
<p>The new observations came from Webb's Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) and Mid-Infrared Instrument (MIRI). They show about 100,000 star clusters and millions, or even billions, of individual stars.<br/>
这一新的观测结果来自于韦伯太空望远镜的近红外相机和中红外仪器。它们展示了大约10万个星团和数百万甚至数十亿颗恒星。</p>
<p>"These data are important as they give us a new view on the earliest phase of star formation," said University of Oxford astronomer Thomas Williams. He led the team's data processing on the images.<br/>
牛津大学天文学家托马斯·威廉姆斯说：“这些数据很重要，它们让我们对恒星形成的最早阶段有了新的认识。”他领导团队对图像进行数据处理。</p>
<p>Williams added, "Stars are born deep within dusty clouds that completely block out the light at visible wavelengths - what the Hubble Space Telescope is sensitive to - but these clouds light up at the JWST wavelengths. We don't know a lot about this phase."<br/>
威廉姆斯补充道，“恒星诞生在尘土飞扬的云层深处，这些云层完全阻挡了可见光波长的光线——哈勃太空望远镜对此很敏感——但这些云层以JWST波长发光。我们对这个阶段了解不多。”</p>
<p>About half of spiral galaxies have a straight structure, called a bar, coming out from the center. The spiral arms attach to this structure.<br/>
大约一半的螺旋星系有一个直的结构，称为棒，从中心出来。螺旋臂连接到该结构上。</p>
<p>Williams said the commonly held thought is that galaxies form from the inside out. That way, they "get bigger and bigger over their lifetimes."<br/>
威廉姆斯说，人们普遍认为星系是由内而外形成的。这样，它们“在生命中变得越来越大”。</p>
<p>The images let scientists for the first time determine the structure of the clouds of dust and gas from which stars and planets form at a high level of detail.<br/>
这些图像使科学家首次能够以高水平的细节确定恒星和行星形成的尘埃和气体云的结构。</p>
<p>The images are in galaxies beyond the Large Magellanic Cloud and Small Magellanic Cloud. Those two galaxies are near the Milky Way.<br/>
这些图像属于大麦哲伦星系和小麦哲伦星系之外的星系。那两个星系在银河系附近。</p>
<p>Webb's observations build on Hubble's.<br/>
韦伯太空望远镜的观测建立在哈勃望远镜的基础上。</p>
<p>Erik Rosolowsky is an astronomer at Canada's University of Alberta. He said, "Using Hubble, we would see the starlight from galaxies, but some of the light was blocked by the dust of galaxies."<br/>
Erik Rosolowsky是加拿大阿尔伯塔大学的天文学家。他说：“使用哈勃望远镜，我们可以看到来自星系的星光，但有些光被星系的尘埃阻挡了。”</p>
<p>Rosolowsky added, "This limitation made it hard to understand parts of how a galaxy operates as a system. With Webb's view in the infrared, we can see through this dust to see stars behind and within the enshrouding dust."<br/>
Rosolowsky补充道，“这种限制使得人们很难理解星系作为一个系统是如何运作的。根据韦伯太空望远镜在红外波段的观测，我们可以透过这些尘埃，看到尘埃背后和内部的恒星。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.<br/>
我是丹·诺瓦克。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Student Academy Awards Provide ‘Momentum’ for Young Filmmakers  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/student-academy-awards-provide-momentum-for-young-filmmakers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>While most people know about the Academy Awards in Hollywood — the awards known as the Oscars — few know about the Student Academy Awards.</p>
<p>But to those who know about the industry, they are a big deal.</p>
<p>A top-three finish at the Student Academy Awards can lift a young filmmaker's <strong>career</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A replica of the Academy Awards statuette on display prior to the 96th Academy Awards nominations announcement on Tuesday, Jan. 23, 2024, at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Beverly Hills. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7a200008-d55b-475b-92c8-d63b86d48a8d_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A replica of the Academy Awards statuette on display prior to the 96th Academy Awards nominations announcement on Tuesday, Jan. 23, 2024, at the Samuel Goldwyn Theater in Beverly Hills. (Photo by Jordan Strauss/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>Freddy Macdonald knows this.</p>
<p>His short movie, <em>Shedding Angels</em>, placed third in the <strong>narrative</strong> film category in 2022. It was his thesis film after two years of study at the American Film Institute (AFI) in Los Angeles. A thesis is a big project that is needed to complete a study program.</p>
<p>Just being selected as a finalist was a dream come true, Macdonald said.</p>
<p>"Having that <strong>stamp</strong> from the Academy helped give me so much <strong>momentum</strong> to create my first feature film."</p>
<p>Macdonald is 23. He said the recognition from the Academy helped launch his career. After the award, he said, investors paid more attention to him, and he was able to create excitement for a full-length movie.</p>
<p>That movie is a longer version of another one of his short films called <em>Sew Torn</em>. He directed it when he was 19.</p>
<p><em>Sew Torn</em>, he said, tells the story of a <strong>seamstress</strong> who gets involved in a violent drug deal.</p>
<p>The full-length movie will be shown at film festivals this year and Macdonald hopes it will be shown in theaters sometime in the near future.</p>
<p><strong>History of success</strong></p>
<p>Macdonald could be one of the more recent filmmakers to go on to a successful career in Hollywood after receiving a student award from the Academy.</p>
<p>The awards program celebrated its 50<sup>th</sup> year in 2023. Some of the past winners include Spike Lee, known for his movies, <em>Do the Right Thing</em>, <em>Malcolm X</em>, <em>He Got Game</em> and others. Lee won an Oscar in 2019 for <em>BlacKkKlansman.</em></p>
<p>Lee won his student award in 1983 when he was studying at New York University (NYU). His film was <em>Joe's Bed-Stuy Barbershop: We Cut Heads</em>.</p>
<p>Other student winners include Robert Zemeckis, who won an Oscar for directing <em>Forrest Gump</em> in 1994. Pete Docter won a student award, too. He later earned Oscars for his <strong>animated</strong> films <em>Up</em>, <em>Inside Out</em> and <em>Soul</em>.</p>
<p>Kendra Carter is a Vice President at the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, which runs both awards programs. She said the Academy hopes to open the film industry to people from many different backgrounds and "create a pool of highly skilled, <strong>diverse</strong> talent."</p>
<p><strong>Serious exposure</strong></p>
<p>In 2023, 640 members of the Academy voted on the awards, which means the student work was seen by hundreds of people in Hollywood. In addition to the award, many students come away from the event with a business agent who can help them get more work.</p>
<p>But that's not all. The gold-medal winners can choose to have their work submitted for the Academy Awards. Last year, an animated short film by a student from Australia, <em>An Ostrich Told Me the World Is Fake and I Think I Believe It</em>, was considered for an Oscar.</p>
<p>"Once your name is tied to a Student Academy Award, it just opens all of these doors," the Academy's Carter said. "It's so <strong>transformative</strong> for <strong>emerging</strong> filmmakers."</p>
<p>The program is now open to young filmmakers from around the world. Giorgio Ghiotto of Italy is a student at NYU. He won the gold medal in October for his documentary short film <em>Wings of Dust</em>.</p>
<p>"Everyone thinks it's impossible to be a documentary filmmaker unless you're rich, or super lucky," Ghiotto said. He called his success "an impossible dream."</p>
<p>Macdonald said the opportunity to compete with student filmmakers from around the world was both "extremely <strong>daunting</strong> and exciting." He said it was a great experience to go to the awards ceremony and meet so many creative people from around the world.</p>
<p><strong>School experience</strong></p>
<p>He would not have gotten that experience without going to film school. Macdonald said he thought about going to an undergraduate film program first.</p>
<p>"And then towards the end of high school, kind of, I knew I wanted to be a filmmaker, but the big question came what college am I gonna go to? Where should I be <strong>applying</strong>? And so, I started looking at all the different paths in terms of film school and the American Film Institute always jumped off the page to me...But I didn't think that would be a possibility because it is a graduate program, and I was applying as a high school senior."</p>
<p>Macdonald applied and was the youngest person ever accepted into the directing program. He was qualified because by then, he had already made a short film and done other directing jobs. But because he did not have a college degree, AFI gave him a "certificate of completion" at the end.</p>
<p>While in school, he learned more about the business side of filmmaking than he expected. He learned how to write a proposal that aimed to make investors excited to finance a film.</p>
<p>"And that was really helpful for me to kind of wrap my head around the different ways you can make movies."</p>
<p><strong>‘An honor'</strong></p>
<p>Before being nominated for a Student Academy Award, Macdonald had everything he needed to enter the film industry. He had strong experience before attending AFI. He learned even more in school. He even got attention from some film studios. But the Student Academy Award experience gave him something more. It gave him the sense that other people believed in what he was doing.</p>
<p>"The Academy recognizing it (my film) really gave me belief in myself that the stories that I want to tell are worth telling and that I should keep <strong>pursuing</strong> them."</p>
<p>The lesson, Macdonald added, was that the Academy liked his work and he, in his words, "should keep fighting to make movies."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press and his interview with Macdonald.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>career </strong><em>–n.</em> a job or profession that a person has for a long time</p>
<p><strong>narrative </strong><em>–adj.</em> telling a story</p>
<p><strong>stamp </strong><em>–n.</em> a mark of approval</p>
<p><strong>momentum </strong><em>–n.</em> a push that continues movement into the future</p>
<p><strong>seamstress </strong><em>–n. </em>a woman who sews or repairs clothing</p>
<p><strong>animated </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving moving pictures or cartoons rather than live-action film</p>
<p><strong>diverse </strong><em>–adj.</em> involving many different examples of something</p>
<p><strong>transformative </strong><em>–adj.</em> causing complete change</p>
<p><strong>emerging </strong><em>–adj.</em> just beginning to develop into something fully</p>
<p><strong>pursue </strong><em>–v.</em> to chase, follow or simply continue doing something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Do You Have a 'Doppelgänger'?  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/do-you-have-a-doppelganger.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><span class="byline">By Anna Matteo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories, </em>from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>English borrows from many other languages. And today we talk about a word that comes from German – doppelganger.</p>
<p>The word "doppelganger" comes from German <strong>folklore</strong>. The online dictionary <em>Merriam-Webster </em>describes the old story. All living creatures have a <strong>spirit</strong> who is <strong>invisible</strong> but exactly the same as the living person. But just because you can't see them, doppelgangers are not <strong>ghosts</strong>. They are sometimes described as "the spiritual opposite or <strong>negative</strong> of their human <strong>counterpart</strong>."</p>
<div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this photo provided by Zooparc de Beauval, twin panda cubs Yuandudu and Huanlili take their first steps in public, at the Beauval Zoo in Saint-Aignan-sur-Cher, France, Dec. 11, 2021. (Zooparc de Beauval via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/BB0D17A2-D48D-49F1-9AF0-9B7BB7E2F378_cx5_cy11_cw89_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/>
<span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this photo provided by Zooparc de Beauval, twin panda cubs Yuandudu and Huanlili take their first steps in public, at the Beauval Zoo in Saint-Aignan-sur-Cher, France, Dec. 11, 2021. (Zooparc de Beauval via AP)</span></div>
<p>Even though the word comes from spiritual folklore, we use it in a very real way. When two people look very similar, we can call them doppelgangers.</p>
<p>English has other expressions that have a similar meaning. If someone looks like someone else, you can call them a look-alike, spitting image or mirror image.</p>
<p>Let's hear two friends use some of these expressions.</p>
<p><em>A: Were you at the airport yesterday?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. I haven't been to the airport in over a year. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Are you sure about that? </em></p>
<p><em>B: I think I would know if I were at the airport. Why do you ask?</em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, if you weren't there, then I ran into your doppelganger. She was a mirror image of you!</em></p>
<p><em>B: Wow, I've heard about doppelgangers. But I didn't think I really had a look-alike out there in the world. </em></p>
<p><em>A: Well, you do. And they are on their way to Costa Rica. </em></p>
<p><em>B: I wish I could trade places with my doppelganger!</em></p>
<p>If you know someone who looks exactly like another person, you can also call them a dead ringer.</p>
<p>Experts say this expression comes from American horse racing, and usage began in the late 19<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>Sometimes, racehorse owners would race a horse under a false name and <strong>pedigree</strong>. They did this to trick people who bet money on race results. These horses were called "ringers."</p>
<p>Here is how to use this expression in a sentence: My best friend in college is a dead ringer for George Clooney. When we're out in public, he gets asked for his autograph all the time.</p>
<p>In the expression "dead ringer," the word "dead" does not mean lifeless. In this case, it means exact or <strong>precise</strong>. It is a way to add <strong>emphasis, </strong>or highlight something. For example, if I am sure that my friend is right about something, I can say she is dead right. We can also say someone is "dead wrong" if they are most certainly wrong.</p>
<p>The next time you want to describe two people who look the same, you can choose any of these expressions.</p>
<p>And that's all the time we have for this <em>Words and Their Stories</em>. Until next time ...</p>
<p>I'm Anna Matteo.</p>
<p><em>Anna Matteo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>folklore </strong><em>– n.</em><strong> </strong>customs, beliefs, stories, and sayings of a people handed down from generation to generation</p>
<p><strong>spirit</strong> <em>– n. </em>a force within a human being thought to give the body life, energy, and power</p>
<p><strong>invisible </strong><em>– adj. </em>incapable by nature of being seen<strong>: </strong>not perceptible by vision</p>
<p><strong>ghost </strong><em>– n. </em>the soul of a dead person believed to be an inhabitant of the unseen world or to appear to the living in bodily likeness</p>
<p><strong>negative</strong> <em>– adj. </em>extending or measured in a direction opposite to one chosen as positive</p>
<p><strong>counterpart </strong><em>– n. </em>one remarkably similar to another: a thing that fits another perfectly</p>
<p><strong>pedigree </strong><em>– n. </em>lineage or line of ancestors of a person or animal: purity of breed recorded by an ancestral line</p>
<p><strong>precise </strong><em>– adj. </em>exactly or sharply defined or stated</p>
<p><strong>emphasis </strong><em>– n. </em>the act or fact of giving stress to a word or syllable when speaking: special attention or importance given to something</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Is Elon Musk Worth $55.8 Billion to Tesla?  (2024/2/4)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/is-elon-musk-worth-55-8-billion-to-tesla.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">03 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Tesla chief Elon Musk wants to move the company's incorporation, or registration, from the American state of Delaware to Texas. Musk said he will ask Tesla shareholders to vote on the move after a Delaware judge ruled against his 2018 pay deal valued at $55.8 billion.</p>
<p>"Never incorporate your company in the state of Delaware," Musk posted on social media service X shortly after the ruling.</p>
<p>Tesla and many major companies, including Amazon, Google, Disney, and Walmart, keep their headquarters in other states. But they all register in the small eastern state of Delaware because of its tax laws and business courts.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Tesla Chief Executive Officer Elon Musk gets in a Tesla car as he leaves a hotel in Beijing, China May 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Tingshu Wang)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/2351c59a-5972-4a74-b6c7-314047701fd5_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Tesla Chief Executive Officer Elon Musk gets in a Tesla car as he leaves a hotel in Beijing, China May 31, 2023. (REUTERS/Tingshu Wang)</span></div>
<p>The financial publication <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/business/incorporating-in-delaware/"><em>Forbes </em>reports</a> that 68 percent of the top American businesses are incorporated in Delaware. Companies that are registered in Delaware do not pay corporate income tax if they do not do business in the state. Even if they do business in the state, companies can also avoid paying corporate tax by setting up what is called a "shell" company. A shell company legally owns property but does not carry out any business.</p>
<p>Dan Coatsworth is an expert at AJ Bell, a British investment company. He told Reuters that Musk's plan is the kind of behavior from someone "who always looks for an <strong>alternative</strong> if he can't get what he wants."</p>
<p>Musk's idea, should he go through with the vote, is not without risk. Legal experts said investors might take legal action if he tried to move the state of incorporation to Texas. Legal action is even more likely if it was seen as a move to get his pay deal rather than to help Tesla.</p>
<p><strong>Musk's pay package</strong></p>
<p>In 2022, the research firm Equilar carried out a study for <em>The Associated Press.</em> The study said that the <strong>median</strong> pay deal for a chief executive officer, or CEO, of a company in the Standard &amp; Poor 500, an index of top companies, was valued at $14.8 million.</p>
<p>It would take an average worker at one of those companies more than 185 years to earn what their chief executive gets in just 12 months.</p>
<p>Musk's pay package of $55.8 billion, set in 2018, was much larger than usual. So, a shareholder brought legal action. His lawyer argued that it was proposed by company directors with ties to Musk. And shareholders were given misleading and incomplete information.</p>
<p>In 2018, Tesla estimated the value of Musk's compensation package at $2.28 billion. But its value has grown as Tesla's stock price increased. Under the plan, Musk would receive <strong>stock options</strong> each time Tesla's market value rose by $50 billion. That means Musk would have the chance to buy nearly 304 million shares for $23.34 each.</p>
<p>Tesla stock is now trading at about $190 a share compared with $21 at the start of 2018. By comparison, in 2022 the median worker at Tesla made $34,084.</p>
<p>Last week, Chancellor Kathaleen St. Jude McCormick of Delaware ruled that the process to set Musk's pay package was "<strong>flawed</strong>" and the price "unfair." She ruled that Tesla's directors lacked independence from Musk and the big pay package was not needed for Tesla to keep Musk or meet its performance goals.</p>
<p>McCormick's ruling moved Musk out of the top spot on the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.forbes.com/real-time-billionaires/#38acc5d43d78"><em>Forbes</em> list of wealthiest people</a>. The publication removed $25 billion from his wealth putting him below French businessman Bernard Arnault.</p>
<p><strong>How do companies decide on CEO pay?</strong></p>
<p>To decide how much to pay their CEO, company directors often look at how much other companies are paying theirs. General Motors, for example, looks at Boeing, Ford, IBM, and other large companies to set its pay.</p>
<p>In 2022, General Motors gave its CEO, Mary Barra, a pay package valued at $29 million. And Jim Farley, the CEO of Ford, another car company, received $22 million that year.</p>
<p>Although Tesla makes automobiles, investors often compare its stock with technology companies. Musk is often compared to Mark Zuckerberg of Meta and Apple's Tim Cook.</p>
<p>In 2023, Cook's pay was valued at $63.2 million. A year earlier, Cook received about $99 million.</p>
<p>Musk's supporters argue that he is not like any other CEO and should not be paid like other CEOs. They said he has built Tesla into the most valuable automaker in the world. Last year, Tesla sold more electric vehicles than any other company. And the company's success has forced the rest of the auto industry to plan for electric vehicles.</p>
<p>Business law experts say any new pay package for Musk will likely be back in court again without independent directors or changes in the decision process for pay.</p>
<p>Before the ruling, however, Musk wrote on X that he wanted Tesla company directors to double his share to give him 25 percent voting control of the company. If not, Musk said he would develop artificial intelligence and robotic software outside of the company.</p>
<p>I'm Mario Ritter Jr. And I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from The Associated Press, Reuters and other sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>alternative</strong><strong> </strong><em>–n. </em>another possible choice that is different from the one currently under consideration</p>
<p><strong>median</strong> <em>–n.</em> the middle value in a group of numbers</p>
<p><strong>stock option </strong><em>–n.</em> a contract that gives the owner the right to buy stock at a set price</p>
<p><strong>flawed </strong><em>–adj.</em><em> </em>containing a mistake or something that should not be there</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Remembering Chita Rivera  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/remembering-chita-rivera.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Groundbreaking American performer Chita Rivera died on January 30 in New York. She was 91 years old.</p>
<p>The famed dancer, singer and actor won many awards and honors in her long career on Broadway and beyond. Her work also broke through ethnic and racial barriers in American entertainment, helping to shape a path for Latin performers.</p>
<p>Her daughter, Lisa Mordente, announced her mother's death. She said Rivera died after a brief sickness.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this Aug. 2, 2015 file photo, Chita Rivera performs during the Chita Rivera: A Lot of Livin' to Do segment of the PBS 2015 Summer TCA Tour held at the Beverly Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, California. (Photo by Richard Shotwell/Invision/AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3d5d4547-28a2-4dba-bdfb-007572369914_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this Aug. 2, 2015 file photo, Chita Rivera performs during the "Chita Rivera: A Lot of Livin' to Do" segment of the PBS 2015 Summer TCA Tour held at the Beverly Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, California. (Photo by Richard Shotwell/Invision/AP)</span></div>
<p>Rivera first gained wide notice in 1957 as Anita in the <strong>original</strong> production of the musical play <em>West Side Story</em>. She was still dancing on New York's Broadway stages a half-century later in 2015's <em>The Visit</em>.</p>
<p>"I wouldn't know what to do if I wasn't moving or telling a story to you or singing a song," she told the <em>Associated Press</em> at the time. "That's the spirit of my life, and I'm really so lucky to be able to do what I love, even at this time in my life."</p>
<p>Dolores Conchita Figueroa del Rivero was born January 23, 1933, in Washington, D.C. Her Puerto Rican father, Pedro del Rivero, was a musician who played in the United States Navy Band. He died when Chita was seven. Her mother Katherine was of Scottish and Italian ancestry.</p>
<p>Chita studied dance as a young girl and was accepted to a highly respected school for ballet. She was 17 when she won her first part in a musical.</p>
<p>"She was a true Broadway <strong>legend</strong>," playwright Paul Rudnick said on social media service X. "She always <strong>delivered</strong> and audiences adored her. The moment she stepped onstage, the world became more exciting and <strong>glorious</strong>."</p>
<p>Rivera rose from <strong>chorus line</strong> performer to star. Along the way, she worked with many of Broadway's other greatest playmakers, including Jerome Robbins, Leonard Bernstein, Bob Fosse, and Harold Prince.</p>
<p>She won two Tonys, the highest award for live theater in the United States. Her first came in 1984 with the production <em>The Rink</em>. She won again in 1993 for the play <em>Kiss of the Spider Woman</em>. An <em>Associated Press</em> theater critic wrote at the time that Rivera was "more than a musical theater star. She's a force of nature...."</p>
<p>The second Tony was an especially sweet victory for the star. Just five years earlier, Rivera had been in a serious car accident that crushed her right leg. It could have ended her career. After months of physical <strong>therapy</strong> to regain her dancing skills, she returned to the stage singing and dancing as energetically as ever.</p>
<p>She told the <em>AP</em>: "It never entered my mind that I wouldn't dance again. Never. I can't explain to you why. It's hard work getting back but that's what I'm doing."</p>
<p>When accepting a Special Tony Award for Lifetime Achievement in 2018, Rivera said "I wouldn't trade my life in the theater for anything, because theater is life."</p>
<p>In August 2009, U.S. President Barack Obama honored Rivera with the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian award of the United States. At the presentation of the medal, Rivera put her hand over her heart and shook her head in wonderment.</p>
<p>Rivera was married to dancer Tony Mordente from 1957 until 1966. Their daughter Lisa also became a performer and has appeared on Broadway.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Caty Weaver adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>original </strong><em>– n. </em>not copied or imitated from something else; the first</p>
<p><strong>legend </strong><em>– n. </em>a person or thing that inspires legends; someone widely respected and praised for certain skills or successes</p>
<p><strong>deliver </strong><em>– v. </em>to produce the promised, desired, or expected results</p>
<p><strong>glorious </strong><em>– adj. </em>extremely good;<em> </em>wonderful</p>
<p><strong>chorus line </strong><em><strong>– </strong>n. </em>a group of dancers and singers supporting the featured players in a musical comedy or revue</p>
<p><strong>therapy </strong><em>– n. </em>medical treatment of impairment, injury, disease, or disorder</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Women to Take Center Stage at the Grammys  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/women-to-take-center-stage-at-the-grammys.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>The American music industry holds its highest honors Sunday night in Los Angeles at the 67th Grammy Awards ceremony.</p>
<p>Artists including Taylor Swift and SZA, as well as songs from the Oscar-nominated movie <em>Barbie</em> lead the competition in nominations. And mostly women are nominated for Album of the Year, the top Grammy. Just one of the eight nominees is male.</p>
<p>SZA has the most nominations of any artist this year: nine in all.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - SZA performs at day one of the Astroworld Music Festival in Houston on Nov. 5, 2021. (Photo by Amy Harris/Invision/AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-b053-08dc23522627_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - SZA performs at day one of the Astroworld Music Festival in Houston on Nov. 5, 2021. (Photo by Amy Harris/Invision/AP, File)</span></div>
<p>The wide female representation in nominations follows a year of huge success for women in the mostly male music business.</p>
<p>Swift's Eras Tour broke the record for <strong>ticket</strong> sales, passing that of British singer-songwriter Elton John. Beyoncé also played to full <strong>stadiums</strong>. And, Swift's concert film, also was a huge hit, earning more than $180 million in ticket sales.</p>
<p>"Women had a <strong>phenomenal</strong> year, not just in music, but in <em>Barbie</em> being the biggest-<strong>grossing</strong> movie," said Billboard magazine reporter Paul Grein. "Women dominated pop culture."</p>
<p>In addition to Swift and SZA, the other women nominated for this year's album prize are Miley Cyrus, Lana Del Rey, Olivia Rodrigo, Janelle Monae and boygenius. The group boygenius is musicians Julien Baker, Phoebe Bridgers, and Lucy Dacus. The single male artist nominated for Album of the Year is Jon Batiste.</p>
<p>It is just the 12th time in the Grammys' 66-year history, Grein said, that women received the majority of nominations for album of the year.</p>
<p>In other<strong> </strong>award fields, music from the <em>Barbie</em> movie received 12 Grammy nominations, including one for song of the year: Billie Eilish's, <em>What Was I Made For?</em></p>
<p><strong>Recording Academy recruits women</strong></p>
<p>The Recording Academy has been admitting an increasing number of female music makers as members in recent years. The Academy is the group of musicians, producers, engineers and others who vote on the Grammy nominees and winners. Since 2019, the percentage of female members has gone from 30 percent to 36 percent.</p>
<p>"They are <strong>infusing</strong> the membership with a lot of members who will probably see things differently," Grein said.</p>
<p>Some of the male artists normally in competition were between projects. Harry Styles, Bad Bunny and other past Grammy winners did not release new music during the <strong>eligibility</strong> period. Still, a University of Southern California study shows the percentage of women artists on Billboard Magazine's Hot 100 list at the end of 2023 reached 35 percent, a 12-year high.</p>
<p>Women also made gains behind the scenes, with women of color driving the first increase in female songwriting credits in 12 years. Almost 20 percent of songwriters are women, up from 14 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>Female musicians made a lot of progress in just a few years, Smith said.</p>
<p>"When you look at the data, you see that the collective action across the music industry is moving toward women," she said. "That we haven't seen before."</p>
<p>The number of female producers increased but remain mostly male. In 2023, women received 6.5 percent of producer credits. No women were nominated for the producer of the year Grammy.</p>
<p>But, on Sunday, several women could make history at the ceremony, including Swift and SZA.</p>
<p>Swift could become the first artist to win album of the year four times if her work <em>Midnights </em>wins the big prize. And, if SZA wins for her recording "<em>SOS</em>," she will be the first Black woman to win album of the year as lead artist since Lauryn Hill.</p>
<p>Hill received the honor 25 years ago.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ticket </strong><em>— n. </em>a piece of paper that allows you to see a show, participate in an event, travel on a vehicle, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stadium </strong><em>— n. </em>a very large usually roofless building that has a large open area surrounded by many rows of seats and that is used for sports events, concerts, etc.</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>phenomenal </strong><em>— adj. </em>very good or great : unusual in a way that is very impressive</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>gross </strong><em>— n. </em>the amount of money earned before taxes, expenses, etc., are taken away</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>infuse </strong><em>— v. </em>to cause to be filled with something</p>
<p><strong>eligible</strong><em>— n. </em>able to be chosen for something</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Reduction and Assimilation  (2024/2/3)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/reduction-and-assimilation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">02 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hi there! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question about reduced syllables and assimilation.</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong></p>
<p>Hello,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-830c-08dc233deee0_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>I would like you to explain to me in detail, if that is possible...</p>
<p>In spoken English, why do native speakers change or omit these letters, for example:</p>
<ol>
<li>I want to go. (I wanna go)</li>
<li>Handbag (hambag)</li>
<li>A and B (A n B)</li>
</ol>
<p>What's the rule behind this?</p>
<p>Thanks,</p>
<p>Adam</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong></p>
<p>Thanks, Adam, for your question.</p>
<p>You have found that people do not always say words the same way all the time. They sometimes change sounds to make them easier to say.</p>
<p>One example is <strong>syllable</strong> dropping, which we discussed in an earlier <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/syllable-dropping-in-speaking/6997962.html" target="_blank">Ask a Teacher</a>. <strong>Assimilation</strong> and reduction are other ways sounds can change when people are speaking quickly.</p>
<p>Two different sounds can start to sound the same when they are said quickly. This is called "assimilation."</p>
<p>This is what is happening in the word "handbag."</p>
<p>The /n/ sound is a nasal sound, which is made by air moving through our nose. The sound/b/ is produced by pressing the lips together. So, the /n/ sound is affected by the /b/ sound in "bag." The sound becomes /m/, a combination of a nasal sound and the <strong>labial</strong> sound.</p>
<p>The /d/ sound is then dropped.</p>
<p>/Handbag/</p>
<p>/Hambag/</p>
<p>Sometimes it is not just one sound within a word that is reduced, but a whole word, like in the examples of "wanna" or "A n' B."</p>
<p>Function words, like "to" and "and" are often reduced in everyday speech. This helps us to pay more attention to the more important words that carry meaning.</p>
<p>Most unstressed syllables and function words become shorter, softer and less clear. The vowel sound in "to," /oo/, gets reduced to another vowel sound "schwa," /<i></i>601;/.</p>
<p>"Want to" becomes "wanta," /<i></i>601;/. The two /t/ sounds drop off in fast speech. So, "want ta" becomes "wanna."</p>
<p>In "A and B," the "and" gets reduced to /<i></i>601;n/. So, <strong>phrases</strong> like "A and B" or "<strong>cream</strong> and sugar" become "A ‘n B" and "cream ‘n sugar."</p>
<p>Please let us know if these explanations and examples have helped you, Adam.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com">learningenglish@voanews.com</a>.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Faith Pirlo wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>__________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>syllable </strong><em>– n. </em>a unit of spoken language that consists of one or more vowel sounds alone or with one or more consonant sounds preceding or following</p>
<p><strong>assimilation</strong> – <em>n</em>. a sound changes in which some sounds (typically consonants or vowels) change to become more similar to other nearby sounds</p>
<p><strong>labial </strong><em>–adj. </em>involving one or both lips</p>
<p><strong>phrase</strong><em><strong> </strong></em><em>– n.</em> a word or group of words forming a syntactic constituent with a single grammatical function</p>
<p><strong>cream</strong> – <em>n</em>. a thick white liquid taken from milk used in cooking, baking and coffee</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Why Is Canada Limiting Foreign Students?  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/why-is-canada-limiting-foreign-students.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Canada recently announced a two-year limit on the number of foreign students given permission to study in the country. The move is partly to ease a growing housing shortage.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency recently reported on some of the details of the plan:</p>
<p><strong>What are the details?</strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-6941-08dbcb2ac7cd_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People walk on the grounds of the University of Toronto in Toronto, Ontario, Canada September 9, 2020. (REUTERS/Carlos Osorio/File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Marc Miller is Canada's immigration minister. Miller said the government led by the Liberal Party of Canada will introduce a temporary, two-year limit on student visas. That will result in about 364,000 student visas in 2024. The government said that is a cut of 35 percent from the year before.</p>
<p>The new proposals will also set limits on <strong>postgraduate</strong> work permits issued to foreign students. The new limits will likely cause many postgraduate students to return to their home countries.</p>
<p>The permits were formerly seen as an easy path to securing permanent <strong>residency</strong>. People in master's or post-doctoral programs will be <strong>eligible </strong>for a three-year work permit.</p>
<p>However, people who are married to foreign students in undergraduate and lower-level college programs will no longer be able to receive work permits. The acceptance of new study permit requests in 2025 will be reconsidered at the end of the current year, Miller said.</p>
<p><strong>Why has the government changed its policy?</strong></p>
<p>Canada has become a popular place for international students. It has been easy to receive work permits after finishing study programs in the country. But the increase in international students has led to a shortage of <strong>rental</strong> homes. This has caused the price of rent to go up. In December, the cost of rent nationwide rose 7.7 percent from a year earlier, government data shows.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's popularity has decreased partly because of increasing living costs. Opposition Conservative Party leader Pierre Poilievre has taken a lead over Trudeau in public opinion studies. Elections are expected to be held next year.</p>
<p>The government has also been concerned about the quality of education offered by some schools.</p>
<p><strong>Who will this affect?</strong></p>
<p>Canada's government says international students bring in about $16.4 billion to the nation's economy. The new policy will hurt many colleges and universities.</p>
<p>Ontario, the most populous area, or province, has the biggest share of international students. Some businesses, including restaurants and <strong>retail</strong> industries, have warned that a limit on foreign students will create a shortage of temporary workers.</p>
<p>For example, restaurants across Canada are dealing with a worker shortage. It is estimated there are nearly 100,000 available jobs. International students made up 4.6 percent of the 1.1 million workers in the food service industry in 2023, an unnamed industry group told Reuters.</p>
<p>Canadian banks will gain from the new rules for international students. Each student will be required to have a Guaranteed Investment Certificates (GIC) of more than $15,000. The amount is required for international students to be able to cover living costs. The new GIC is more than double the amount from the earlier policy.</p>
<p>Many of Canada's foreign students, about 40 percent, come from India. China coming in second with about 12 percent, official data from 2022 shows.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Wa Lone reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>postgraduate</strong><strong> </strong>– <em>adj</em>. of or relating to studies done after earning a bachelor's degree or other degree</p>
<p><strong>residency </strong>– <em>n</em>. legal permission to live in a place</p>
<p><strong>eligible </strong>– <em>adj</em>. able to do or receive something</p>
<p><strong>rent </strong>– <em>v</em>. money that you pay in return for being able to use property and especially to live in an apartment or house that belongs to someone else</p>
<p><strong>affordable </strong>– <em>v</em>. to be able to pay for (something)</p>
<p><strong>retail </strong>– <em>adj</em>. relating to the business of selling things directly to customers for their own use</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>It Has Never Been More Costly to See the Super Bowl  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/it-has-never-been-more-costly-to-see-the-super-bowl.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p><strong>Tickets</strong> for the American football Super Bowl game are among the hardest to get in all of sports. Because of that, some websites that buy and re-sell tickets have set prices for the upcoming game in Las Vegas, Nevada at almost $10,000.</p>
<p>The National Football League championship game between the Kansas City Chiefs and San Francisco 49ers is on Sunday, February 11.</p>
<p>The Chiefs won last year's Super Bowl. They feature star quarterback Patrick Mahomes and Travis Kelce, the boyfriend of singer Taylor Swift. Many people believe Swift will fly to the game after performing in Japan only one day earlier.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Kansas City Chiefs players and staff celebrate after the NFL Super Bowl 57 football game against the Philadelphia Eagles, February 12, 2023, in Glendale, Arizona. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/15bbfd37-1b4f-47c8-8a70-57ecf60ea954_cx0_cy10_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Kansas City Chiefs players and staff celebrate after the NFL Super Bowl 57 football game against the Philadelphia Eagles, February 12, 2023, in Glendale, Arizona. (AP Photo/Seth Wenig)</span></div>
<p>The 49ers are one of the most popular teams in the western part of the U.S. Las Vegas is a busy, <strong>tourist</strong> city known for its hotels and <strong>casinos</strong>. It is the first-ever Super Bowl in Las Vegas. For many years, the league did not want to have games in Las Vegas because the city permits sports gambling. That changed when the Oakland Raiders moved to Las Vegas to play in a new stadium before the 2020 season.</p>
<p>The combination of two well-known teams plus a city that many people like to visit means tickets on a website called TickPick are in high demand. They are re-selling for almost double last year's cost. The Chiefs defeated the Philadelphia Eagles in the Super Bowl last year near Phoenix, Arizona.</p>
<p>Before this year, the Super Bowl with the highest re-sale ticket price was in 2021 when the Tampa Bay Buccaneers defeated the Chiefs in Tampa, Florida. That year, however, tickets were limited because of restrictions connected to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>TickPick said the highest prices for a non-COVID Super Bowl came in 2020 when the Chiefs and 49ers played in Miami, Florida. The average ticket that year was over $6,000. TickPick, however, noted that prices for this year might go down as the game gets closer.</p>
<p>Brett Goldberg is the co-CEO for TickPick. In a message to the Associated Press, he wrote: "<strong>Location</strong> has always <strong>impacted</strong> demand for a Super Bowl, but Vegas takes things to a whole other level." He said Las Vegas is already "the <strong>entertainment</strong> capital of the world."</p>
<p>Sometimes, Goldberg wrote, two successful teams push down demand, because the average fan is tired of seeing them play again. However, he noted prices are high this year because "fans want to experience their team winning a Super Bowl in Vegas."</p>
<p>StubHub is another ticket-selling website. Prices on that site were over $9,000. StubHub said tickets are selling faster this year than in recent years.</p>
<p>"The demand has far surpassed the last time Kansas City and San Francisco met in Miami," said a spokesperson from StubHub.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>ticket </strong>–n. a piece of paper or digital proof that gives the holder the right to see an event or performance</p>
<p><strong>tourist </strong>–n. a person who travels for pleasure and not business</p>
<p><strong>casino </strong>–n. a place where people play games of chance in an effort to win money</p>
<p><strong>location </strong>–n. the place where something is</p>
<p><strong>impacted </strong><em>–adj.</em> affected or influenced</p>
<p><strong>entertainment </strong>–n. the industry aimed at providing performances, activities and services to give people pleasure</p>
<p><em>We want to hear from you. Are you planning to pay attention to this year's Super Bowl?</em></p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Australian Filmmaker Shows Japanese Single Mothers, Children Face Poverty  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/australian-filmmaker-shows-japanese-single-mothers-children-face-poverty.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>In wealthy countries, like Japan, poverty is sometimes considered a <strong>taboo </strong>subject. But an Australian filmmaker, Rionne McAvoy, wants to share the stories of women and children in poverty in Japan in his documentary film <em>The Ones Left Behind</em>.</p>
<p>The film was released last year. It shows single mothers raising their children in poverty. The women work hard. They sleep a few hours at night. And they try to balance working with childcare and housework.</p>
<p>McAvoy said he wanted to deal with a <strong>topic</strong> that no one wanted to discuss. The film shows discussions with poor women and experts on poverty. He said the film also shows a different side of Japanese <strong>society</strong>, where getting married and becoming a stay-at-home mother is normal for many women.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This photo provided by Japan Media Services shows a scene from The Ones Left Behind: The Plight of Single Mothers in Japan, directed by Rionne McAvoy. " src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/28524da2-5501-45e1-beed-c0e09774c9ae_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This photo provided by Japan Media Services shows a scene from The Ones Left Behind: The Plight of Single Mothers in Japan, directed by Rionne McAvoy. </span></div>
<p>"In Japan, it's very taboo. I think it's a very <strong>apt</strong> title because I feel that single mothers and their children have really been left behind in society."</p>
<p>The film shows one woman who works almost twelve hours a day and earns less than $1,350 a month. That amount is low for a county where the cost of living is high. Monthly <strong>rent</strong> for one small room can cost one third of that amount.</p>
<p>Tomiko Nakayama is one of the women in the film. She said, "I have to do everything on my own." Another woman almost cries when she describes how her child stopped asking her to come to "take-your-parent-to-school" days.</p>
<p>Japan has one of the highest rates of childhood poverty although it is one of the wealthiest nations. One in seven children live in poverty in Japan. Almost half of single-parent homes are considered poor.</p>
<p>Japanese society often favors men who work full-time. Women sometimes receive lower pay and fewer benefits than their male counterparts, while working full-time and overtime.</p>
<p>Ayuri McAvoy produced the film and is also McAvoy's wife. She was formerly a single mother. But they say that is not why they made the film.</p>
<p>Rionne McAvoy said that the country's traditional culture makes women accept their difficult lives and makes them <strong>ashamed</strong> to ask for help. He told the Associated Press that the women are "keeping their public face and private face separate."</p>
<p>Akihiko Kato is a professor at Meiji University in Tokyo. He appears in the film. Kato said that Japan does not have a system to legally force fathers to pay for their children if the parents are separated. The Japanese government has promised to give money to people with children, but this is slow to come, he said.</p>
<p>Kato said that this is partly why birth rates in Japan have been so low. There were 1.2 million births in the year 2000 compared to fewer than 800,000 births in 2022.</p>
<p>Some people believe the modern idea of the <strong>nuclear family</strong> means that single parents, mostly mothers, have to do everything on their own. People like grandparents, neighbors and extended family members no longer seem to be able to help with children.</p>
<p>Yanfei Zhou is a social science professor at Japan Women's University in Tokyo who also appears in the film. She said that these changes have serious effects on children. The divide between rich and poor is growing, and children will end up in poverty, she said.</p>
<p>The film won the Best Documentary prize at the Miyakojima Charity International Film Festival last year. It was also officially chosen for the Yokohama International Film Festival.</p>
<p>McAvoy said he has long been interested in telling the story of those who society had forgotten and who do not have a voice. He said that being on the outside of Japanese culture has helped him to share stories with a new viewpoint and without <strong>bias</strong>. He said his next film will be about young people dying by suicide in Japan.</p>
<p>McAvoy said, "It's one thing we can do more of in society: to try recognize people's cries for help."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Andrew Smith.</p>
<p><em>Yuri Kageyama reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>taboo</strong> – <em>n</em>. something that is not acceptable to talk about or do</p>
<p><strong>topic </strong>–n. the subject of writing or a discussion</p>
<p><strong>society </strong>–n. people who live together in a large area under the same rules, traditions and values</p>
<p><strong>apt</strong> – <em>adj</em>. likely to do something</p>
<p><strong>rent</strong> <em>–</em><em> </em><em>n.</em> a regular payment for the use of property such as the use of a place to live like an apartment or home</p>
<p><strong>ashamed<strong> </strong></strong>– <em>adj. </em>feeling regret and embarrassment for what you have done</p>
<p><strong>nuclear families</strong> – <em>n</em>. a family group consisting of parents and their children living in one home</p>
<p><strong>bias </strong>– <em>n</em>. a tendency to support one side of an argument over another</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>European Farmers Keep Up Protests During EU Meeting  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/european-farmers-keep-up-protests-during-eu-meeting.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>European farmers held protests Thursday to demand government help in dealing with rising costs and environmental rules.</p>
<p>One of the protests happened in Brussels, Belgium, where EU leaders gathered for a <strong>summit</strong> meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some farmers drove tractors onto the grounds of the European Parliament building to bring attention to their demands. Protesters also lit off fireworks and threw eggs and bottles at police in the area, The Associated Press reported.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Farmers gather outside the European Parliament for a protest as European leaders meet for an EU summit in Brussels, Thursday, Feb. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-9958-08dc2356d92f_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Farmers gather outside the European Parliament for a protest as European leaders meet for an EU summit in Brussels, Thursday, Feb. 1, 2024. (AP Photo/Thomas Padilla)</span></div>
<p>Smoke could also be seen around parts of Brussels as some farmers set pieces of <strong>hay</strong> on fire, the news agency said. Security forces put out the fires and moved in to protect EU buildings.</p>
<p>In Paris, French farmers continued to block traffic on major roadways around the city. Farmers in several European nations have been holding mostly peaceful protests in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The farmers say it is harder to make a good living because of high operating costs. Costs for fuel and <strong>fertilizer </strong>have risen sharply in Europe since Russia's invasion of Ukraine. They also say they have been hurt by increased competition and weather conditions.</p>
<p>France's government sent in armored vehicles to Paris' large Rungis food market, which was targeted by demonstrators. French police told Reuters news agency they arrested 79 people who entered a storage center at the market.</p>
<p>The market is an important supplier of fruits and vegetables to France and other nations. Rungis has repeatedly become a target for European farmers, many of whom traveled a long way to bring their tractors there.</p>
<p>One farmer who traveled to Brussels to protest was 26-year-old Luca Mouton. He told Reuters, "Time is up. (EU leaders must) think of the farmers. Talk to the farmers rather than about the farmers, discuss what is possible. We are open to <strong>dialogue</strong>."</p>
<p>Jean-Francois Ricker is a farmer from southern Belgium who spent the night in the cold near EU headquarters. He told the AP he hoped a lot of protesters would show up to demonstrate how important the issues are to farmers across Europe. "We are going to show that we do not agree...," said Ricker.</p>
<p>The purpose of Thursday's EU summit was mainly to approve a proposal to provide Ukraine with a new $54 billion aid deal. But Belgian Prime Minister Alexander De Croo urged EU leaders to also hear the farmers' demands. Belgium currently holds the EU presidency.</p>
<p>De Croo said governments "need to make sure that (farmers) can get the right price for the high-quality products that they provide." He also urged an easing of some environmental rules that farmers have said can hurt their profits.</p>
<p>Farmers are an important voting group within the EU as well as in their own countries. This has led some leaders to offer some new proposals.</p>
<p>The European Commission announced plans Wednesday to offer protections to farmers facing increased competition from low-cost imports from Ukraine. The body also proposed easing restrictions on how much of a farmer's own land he can use while still receiving support from the EU.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week, France's government promised to provide farmers emergency aid and some new controls on imported food. On Thursday, French Prime Minister Gabriel Attal offered more measures. They included a move to permit farmers to use more <strong>pesticides</strong> if other nations do the same and an offer to increase financial aid and tax breaks.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press and Reuters reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>summit </strong><em>–n.</em> a meeting of high-level officials or national leaders</p>
<p><strong>hay </strong><em>–n. </em>dried grass</p>
<p><strong>fertilizer </strong><em>– n. </em>a natural or chemical substance you put on land in order to make plants grow well</p>
<p><strong>dialogue </strong><em>– n. </em>an official discussion between countries or groups of people</p>
<p><strong>pesticide </strong><em>– n. </em>a chemical that is used to kill insects that damage plants</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>A Trip Around the World  (2024/2/2)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202402/a-trip-around-the-world.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">01 February 2024</span><br/>
<p>Pack your bags, make sure your travel documents are in order.</p>
<p>Today we are taking a trip around the world — if only in our imagination.</p>
<p>For this Everyday Grammar lesson, we will leave behind our grammar books. We will instead look at messages from friends who are in Pakistan, Spain, Belgium, and Japan.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-e19c-08dc229cb586_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Our goal: to learn more about the populations of different countries. We will learn about English along the way.</p>
<p>Let's begin our journey...</p>
<p><strong>Background </strong></p>
<p>In a recent lesson about the noun "population," we asked our listeners the following questions:</p>
<p><em>What is the population like in your country or city? Is the population increasing or decreasing?</em></p>
<p>Here are some of the answers we received:</p>
<p><strong>Pakistan </strong></p>
<p>Saeed wrote to us from Lahore, Pakistan. Saeed noted:</p>
<p><em>City Lahore – Pakistan </em></p>
<p><em>Increasing </em></p>
<p><em>In 2023 was 13,979,000, a 3.23% increase from 2022. </em></p>
<p>Saeed presented some exact numbers about the city of Lahore.</p>
<p>Our suggestion is to use complete sentences. In other words, Saeed could update the statement to something like this:</p>
<p><em>The population of Lahore, Pakistan, is increasing. </em></p>
<p><em>In 2023, the population was 13,979,000, a 3.23% increase from 2022. </em></p>
<p><strong>Spain </strong></p>
<p>Now that we have learned some information about a big city in Pakistan, we can learn about a major European city. Rafael writes to us from Barcelona, Spain.</p>
<p>Here is part of the message:</p>
<p><em>...The populacion in my city is decreasing due to low birth rate, although the total count is maintained thanks to inmigration....The arrival of people from very different cultures creates some integration problems, but it helps to solve other important ones derived from the general aging.... </em></p>
<p>
Rafael wrote an excellent message. Our main suggestion is to double <strong>check</strong> the <strong>spelling</strong> of a few words: population and immigration.</p>
<p>In terms of grammar, one idea is to include an article such as "the" before "birth rate." Definite and indefinite articles help show the difference between a specific and a general noun.</p>
<p>So, we could update Rafael's statement to something like this: "The population in my city is decreasing due to the low birth rate..."</p>
<p><strong>Belgium </strong></p>
<p>Now let's look at part of a message from Jean Claude, in Belgium.</p>
<p><em>...The population of Belgium was 11.67 million inhabitants on January 2023. The Belgian population increased by 0.98% compared to the previous year... </em></p>
<p>Jean Claude's message was clear and to the point. There is one suggestion we have. It is in the first sentence. We have the <strong>phrase </strong>"on January 2023" but instead we should use the short word "in," like this:</p>
<p><em>The population of Belgium was 11.67 million<strong> inhabitants</strong> in January 2023. </em></p>
<p>We usually use the short word "on" for an exact date, such as "on January 4th" or "on January 27th"</p>
<p>Next, we are in for a long trip to the other side of the world. A friend from Japan would like to tell us about the population of the island country.</p>
<p><strong>Japan </strong></p>
<p>Here is part of a message from an unnamed reader:</p>
<p><em>According to the national statics, Japan's population has been decreasing almost 600,000 people per a year. There are more than 120,000,000 people in Japan now. However, I heard the population will be under 100,000,000 in 30 years. </em></p>
<p>We suggest the following changes to the first sentence. The term "statics" should be changed to "<strong>statistics</strong>." In addition, we often use the short word "by" after decreasing. We can then remove "a" from its position before "year." So, we might update the sentence to something like this:</p>
<p><em>According to national statistics, Japan's population has been decreasing by almost 600,000 people per year. </em></p>
<p><strong>Lessons </strong></p>
<p>That brings us to the end of our imaginative trip around the world.</p>
<p>We received many wonderful pieces of writing – those that were included in today's lesson and many others that were not.</p>
<p>Overall, the general recommendations are to pay careful attention to spelling and to double check short words – prepositions, articles, and so on.</p>
<p>We hope that you have learned a little more about the world, as well as some ideas to use when you write in English.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>__________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>check </strong><em>–v. </em>to make sure something is correct by looking at it or reading it again</p>
<p><strong>spelling </strong><em>–n.</em> the way the letters in a word are correctly written, or spelled</p>
<p><strong>phrase </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of two or more words that express a single idea but do not usually form a complete sentence</p>
<p><strong>inhabitant</strong> <em>– n.</em> a person that lives in a particular place</p>
<p><strong>statistic</strong> <em>– n.</em> (often plural) a number that represents a piece of information</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Elon Musk’s Neuralink Announces First Human Implant  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/elon-musk-s-neuralink-announces-first-human-implant.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Elon Musk says his company Neuralink has placed an experimental brain device in a person in the first human test of the technology.</p>
<p>Neuralink describes the coin-sized device as a "brain-computer <strong>interface</strong>." It is designed to be <strong>implanted</strong> inside the brain through a medical operation.</p>
<p>Musk announced the news on the social media service he owns, X. The billionaire businessman is also the owner of Tesla and SpaceX. His company Neuralink aims to establish direct communication links between the brain and computers.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="The Neuralink logo and Elon Musk are seen in this illustration taken, December 19, 2022. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-0edb-08dc22109779_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">The Neuralink logo and Elon Musk are seen in this illustration taken, December 19, 2022. (REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration)</span></div>
<p>"The first human received an implant from @Neuralink (Sunday) and is recovering well," Musk <a class="wsw__a" href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk">wrote</a>. He added that first results of the implanted device showed "promising neuron <strong>spike</strong>" activity.</p>
<p>A spike is a term for a method neurons use to communicate with each other. The <em>Cambridge Learner's Dictionary</em> <a class="wsw__a" href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/dictionary/learner-english/neuron">defines</a> a neuron as "a nerve cell that carries messages between your brain and other parts of your body."</p>
<p>The device includes an extremely small computer and extremely thin wires that connect to a part of the brain that controls <strong>intent </strong>of movement.</p>
<p>Neuralink says the implant is designed to treat brain disorders and help serious back injury victims regain body movement. Company officials also say it might be used one day to help <strong>blind</strong> people see again.</p>
<p>The company has said an early goal of the brain-computer interface will be to give people the ability to control basic computer tasks using thoughts alone. Musk says that in the future, the device might also be used to improve human intelligence in an effort to keep up with supercomputers and artificial intelligence (AI) technology.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/us-approves-testing-of-neuralink-brain-implant-in-humans/7117607.html">approved</a> human testing of the Neuralink device last May.</p>
<p>Neuralink reposted Musk's statement about the implant in a message on X.</p>
<p>In another message on X, Musk wrote that the first Neuralink product is called "Telepathy." He said the goal of the product is to permit users to control smartphones or computers "just by thinking." Musk also noted the first users would be people who have lost the use of their arms or legs.</p>
<p>It remains unclear how well the brain-computer interface system or similar devices will work in humans. FDA-approved trials, like the one permitted for Neuralink, aim to collect data on the safety and effectiveness of proposed products.</p>
<p>Neuralink is not alone in developing systems designed to link the human nervous system to computers. The website clinicaltrials.gov <a class="wsw__a" href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/search?cond=brain%20computer%20interface&amp;aggFilters=status:not%20rec%20enr%20act">reports</a> there are currently more than 40 brain computer interface trials going on in places around the world.</p>
<p>Reuters reported that in the past, Neuralink was fined by the U.S. Department of Transportation for violating rules covering the movement of dangerous substances. The fines against Neuralink totaled $2,480 and the company agreed to fix its problems concerning the violations, the news agency said.</p>
<p>Neuralink carried out earlier trials of the implant using m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s, pigs and sheep. Reuters has also reported on the company's animal experiments in the past.</p>
<p>Some Neuralink employees told Reuters in 2022 the company had made mistakes in its animal testing. They said the mistakes came because the process was hurried. This led to more animal deaths than necessary, the employees said.</p>
<p>In one 2021 case, Reuters reported that Neuralink implanted 25 out of 60 pigs with the wrong-sized devices. All the pigs were later killed. Employees told the news agency such mistakes could have been easily avoided with more preparation.</p>
<p>Last September, Musk wrote in a social media message that "no m<i><i>onkey</i></i> has died as a result of a Neuralink implant." He added that the company chose "<strong>terminal</strong>" m<i><i>onkey</i></i>s to limit risks to healthy animals.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters, Agence France-Presse and Neuralink.</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>interface </strong><em>– n. </em>a connection between two pieces of electronic equipment, or between a person and a computer</p>
<p><strong>implant </strong><em>– n. </em>a device placed inside the body in a medical operation</p>
<p><strong>spike </strong><em>– n. </em>a sudden change or rise in something</p>
<p><strong>intent </strong><em>– n. </em>what a person wants and plans to do</p>
<p><strong>blind </strong><em>– adj. </em>lacking or deficient in sight</p>
<p><strong>terminal </strong><em>– adj. </em>nearing or close to death: being in the final stages of a deadly disease</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Garden Group Names 2024 ‘Year of African Violet’  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/garden-group-names-2024-year-of-african-violet.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The African violet, a plant from Tanzania that came to the U.S. in the late 1800s, received a special honor from the National Garden Bureau (NGB).</p>
<p>The organization named 2024 "The Year of the African Violet." Other plants, flowers and vegetables for 2024 include: squash, Angelonia, lily, buddleia and hosta. Past years honored amaryllis, orchids and broccoli.</p>
<p>Jessica Damiano is the garden writer for the Associated Press news service. She recently wrote about the African violet.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated image provided by the National Garden Bureau shows a bi-color African violet plant. The NGB has named 2024 as the Year of the African Violet. (National Garden Bureau via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/f0a22700-c5b4-400f-a8c1-0dfe3c61952c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated image provided by the National Garden Bureau shows a bi-color African violet plant. The NGB has named 2024 as the Year of the African Violet. (National Garden Bureau via AP)</span></div>
<p>Damiano said the violet has been one of the most popular house plants in the U.S. since it arrived. She said the plant, however, is not a violet. It only has the name because of its colorful, purple and white leaves.</p>
<p>In fact, she noted, they are related to the Saintpaulia <strong>genus</strong>. They are named for German Walter von Saint Paul.</p>
<p>The popularity of the plant is one reason why the NGB chose the violet as the "houseplant" of the year, said Diane M. Blazek, the organization's director. She said the plant's name has appeared over 300,000 times on social media.</p>
<p>Beyond popularity, Blazek noted, the violets are easy to grow and people who <strong>breed</strong> flowers are working on creating new <strong>varieties</strong>. Blazek said, "they are coming through the pipeline."</p>
<p>Blazek said people once thought of the violets as "Grandma's plants," or that they were no longer popular. But, she said, the violet "has not gone out of favor at all."</p>
<p>The NGB started in 1920. The group aimed to give <strong>reliable</strong> gardening information to Americans, many of whom had only recently started growing plants at home. The founder was James Burdett. He helped develop the idea of "victory gardens." The gardens started during World War I as way for Americans to grow some of their own food.</p>
<p>Today, the NGB continues the work started by Burdett. It recommends plants, flowers and vegetables each year.</p>
<p>Many people like the African violet because it is easy to grow. It does not need direct sunlight; it does not need too much water and does not need a lot of fertilizer. However, it must receive special care to do extremely well.</p>
<p>Blazek said the plants like <strong>moisture</strong> in the air. So, if you live in a very dry place, they might not do well. If you bring them inside during winter, Damiano suggests, you should run a device that adds moisture to the air – a humidifier – before you take them back outside. They need warmth but do not do well in high heat. Be sure to consider your climate before planting them.</p>
<p>In spring and summer, Damiano said, if the plants are indoors, place them near a window that faces north or east. That way they do not get too much sun. In the winter, the plants may be placed closer to windows because the sun is not too strong at that time for people who live in mid-northern climates.</p>
<p>Feed the plants only every two to three months. Be sure to use a <strong>fertilizer</strong> for African violets. And do not worry about their roots getting <strong>crowded</strong> by other plants – they like <strong>cozy</strong> pots.</p>
<p>With good care, the violets may show their colors all year.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>genus </strong>–<em>n</em>. a group of plants or animals that is bigger than a species but smaller than a family</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong>–<em>v</em>. to raise animals and plants so they reproduce and have offspring with similar or better qualities</p>
<p><strong>variety </strong>–<em>n</em>. a different form of a similar group of things</p>
<p><strong>reliable </strong>–<em>adj</em>. able to be trusted or depended upon</p>
<p><strong>moisture </strong>– <em>n. </em>the amount of liquid in the air or in soil or in a piece of cloth</p>
<p><strong>fertilizer </strong>– <em>n. </em>food and nutrients made to help plants grow</p>
<p><strong>crowded </strong>– <em>adj. </em>a number of things together in a small space</p>
<p><strong>cozy </strong>– <em>adj. </em>comfortable, soft and close together</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Renewed Interest in Amelia Earhart’s Final Flight  (2024/2/1)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/renewed-interest-in-amelia-earhart-s-final-flight.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">31 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>An unclear <strong>sonar</strong> image recorded by a private pilot has renewed interest in a past mystery: What happened to Amelia Earhart, the pilot who disappeared in 1937 with her plane?</p>
<p>Many searches have found nothing. But Tony Romeo now believes his new South Carolina-based sea exploration company captured a partial image of Earhart's famous plane.</p>
<p>Researchers and explorers are hopeful. But whether Earhart's plane lies at about 4,800 meters beneath the ocean remains to be seen.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Amelia Earhart's plane is seen at the Smithsonian's National Air and Space Museum in Washington, Tuesday, Nov. 16, 2010, after an overhaul of one of the museum's original galleries, the Pioneers of Flight exhibit. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/3da668ae-0272-4f7f-be55-2feedf2cecac_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Amelia Earhart's plane is seen at the Smithsonian's National Air and Space Museum in Washington, Tuesday, Nov. 16, 2010, after an overhaul of one of the museum's original galleries, the "Pioneers of Flight" exhibit. (AP Photo/Jacquelyn Martin, File)</span></div>
<p><strong>How was the object found?</strong></p>
<p>Romeo said he had long held interest in the Earhart mystery. So, he bought a $9 million underwater <strong>drone</strong> from a Norwegian company. The drone is called the Hugin 6000. It includes the newest technology. It can dive down to 6,000 meters.</p>
<p>A 16-person crew began a search in the western Pacific Ocean in September 2023. They searched over 13,400 square kilometers of seafloor. The crew searched around Howland Island between Papua New Guinea and Hawaii.</p>
<p>But it was not until the team looked at the sonar data in December that they saw the unclear yellow outline of what looked like a plane.</p>
<p>"In the end, we came out with an image of a target that we believe very strongly is Amelia's <strong>aircraft</strong>," Romeo told the <em>Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>The next step is taking a camera underwater to better examine the unidentified object. If camera images confirm the explorers' hopes, Romeo said the goal would be to raise Earhart's airplane.</p>
<p>Romeo said his team undertook the trip to "solve <strong>aviation's</strong> greatest unsolved mystery." Depending on what they find, they might answer if Earhart and her <strong>navigator</strong>, Fred Noonan, escaped after hitting the ocean, or learn more about what went wrong.</p>
<p><strong>The mystery of Earhart</strong></p>
<p>Earhart and Noonan disappeared while flying from New Guinea to Howland Island. That trip was part of her attempt to become the first female pilot to fly around the world. She had radioed that she was running low on fuel.</p>
<p>The Navy searched but found nothing. The U.S. government's official position has been that Earhart and Noonan went down with their plane.</p>
<p>Since then, there have been many theories. They include that Earhart was taken by <strong>aliens</strong>, lived in New Jersey under another name, she was killed by the Japanese, or died on an island.</p>
<p>"Amelia is America's favorite missing person," Romeo said.</p>
<p><strong>‘We need to see more'</strong></p>
<p>Sea <strong>archaeologist</strong> James Delgado said Romeo's possible find would change the story, but "we need to see more."</p>
<p>"Let's drop some cameras down there and take a look," said Delgado. He is senior vice president of the archaeological company SEARCH.</p>
<p>Delgado said Romeo's search used the newest technologies that were once only available to the government.</p>
<p>But he said Romeo's team must provide detailed documentation to prove it is Earhart's plane.</p>
<p>If the object really is the historic aircraft, the question for the team is if it is safe to raise. How much of the plane is left would be decided by how smoothly Earhart landed," said Dorothy Cochrane of the National Air and Space Museum.</p>
<p>"That's where you have to really look at this image and say, ‘What have we got here?'" said Cochrane.</p>
<p><strong>What if Earhart's plane has been found?</strong></p>
<p>If the discovery turns out to be her plane, international rules for underwater archaeology would suggest that the aircraft remain where it is, said Ole Varmer. He is a retired lawyer with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and an advisor at The Ocean Foundation, an environmental group based in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Less damaging research can still be carried out to find why the plane crashed, Varmer said.</p>
<p>Varmer added, "You <strong>preserve</strong> as much of the story as you can." And he said, "When you <strong>salvage</strong> it, you're destroying part of the site, which can provide information."</p>
<p>Raising the plane and showing it to the public would likely cost hundreds of millions of dollars, Varmer said. And while Romeo could possibly make a salvage claim in a court, the plane's owner has the right to deny it.</p>
<p>Earhart bought the plane with money raised, at least in part, by the Purdue Research Foundation, Purdue University in Indiana said in a blog. She planned to return the aircraft to the school.</p>
<p>Romeo said the team believes the plane belongs in the Smithsonian. He said the issue likely presents a new kind of legal case. He said his exploration company will "deal with those as they come up."</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>James Pollard and Ben Finley reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>sonar </strong>– <em>n</em>. a device used for finding things that are underwater by using sound waves</p>
<p><strong>drone </strong>– <em>n</em>. a type of small aircraft that flies without a pilot</p>
<p><strong>aircraft </strong><em>– n. </em>a machine (such as an airplane or a helicopter) that flies through the air</p>
<p><strong>aviation </strong><em>– n. </em>the business or practice of flying airplanes or helicopters</p>
<p><strong>navigate </strong><em>– v.</em> to find the way to get to a place when you are traveling in a ship, airplane, or car</p>
<p><strong>alien </strong><em>– n. </em>a creature that comes from somewhere other than the planet Earth</p>
<p><strong>archeology </strong>– <em>n</em>. a science that deals with past human life and activities by studying the bones or tools of ancient people</p>
<p><strong>preserve </strong>– <em>v</em>. to keep (something) in its original state or in good condition</p>
<p><strong>salvage </strong><em>– v. </em>to remove (something) from a place so that it will not be damaged, destroyed, or lost</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Researchers Announce Successful Rhino Embryo Transfer  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/researchers-announce-successful-rhino-embryo-transfer.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists in Berlin announced recently the first successful embryo <strong>transfer</strong> in a white rhinoceros.</p>
<p>The transfer, which occurred in a southern white rhinoceros, offers hope for saving the northern white rhino from completely dying off.</p>
<p><strong>Two kinds of white rhinoceros </strong></p><div class="contentImage"><img alt=" FILE - Keeper Zachariah Mutai attends to Fatu, one of only two northern white rhinos left in the world, in the pen at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Laikipia county in Kenya. (AP Photo/Sunday Alamba, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/7c45acc8-d93e-4863-a367-918b44541b3f_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"> FILE - Keeper Zachariah Mutai attends to Fatu, one of only two northern white rhinos left in the world, in the pen at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Laikipia county in Kenya. (AP Photo/Sunday Alamba, File)</span></div>
<p>The white rhinoceros includes two different <strong>subspecies</strong>, the northern and the southern. The last male northern white rhino died in 2018. Only two female members of the subspecies remain. Neither of them can carry a baby.</p>
<p>Southern white rhinos are more numerous.</p>
<p>Researchers hope to use eggs and sperm from northern white rhinos to produce embryos that will be put into southern white rhino surrogate mothers.</p>
<p>A surrogate is something that performs the duties of something else.</p>
<p>To test the plan, scientists said they transferred the embryo of a southern white rhino into a surrogate southern white rhino mother at the Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Kenya on September 24, 2023.</p>
<p>However, the research team only learned of the pregnancy after the surrogate mother died of a bacterial infection in November 2023. The embryo was discovered during an examination of the body after death.</p>
<p>Even with the death, researchers found reasons to be hopeful.</p>
<p>The international BioRescue team, a group backed by the German government, confirmed recently that the operation had produced a successful pregnancy of 70 days, with a well-developed 6.4-centimeter-long male embryo.</p>
<p>"We <strong>achieved</strong> together something which was not believed to be possible," said Thomas Hildebrandt of the Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research.</p>
<p>"That is really a <strong>milestone</strong> to allow us to produce northern white rhino calves in the next two, two and a half years," Hildebrandt said.</p>
<p><strong>Too late?</strong></p>
<p>The northern white rhinoceros subspecies has only two known examples left in the world. The Ol-Pejeta Conservancy in Kenya says that Najin, a 34-year-old, and her 23-year-old offspring, Fatu, both cannot naturally reproduce.</p>
<p>In 2018, the last male white rhino, Sudan, was 45 when he was <strong>euthanized</strong> because of age-related problems. He was Najin's father. Scientists stored his semen and that of four other dead rhinos.</p>
<p>Some conservation groups have argued that it is probably too late to save the northern white rhino using the method known as <strong>in vitro </strong>fertilization.</p>
<p>The species once lived in Chad, Sudan, Uganda, Congo and Central African Republic, but human conflict has caused the creature to disappear. Critics say the efforts made to save the northern white rhino should instead go to save at-risk species that have a better chance to survive.</p>
<p>About 20,000 southern white rhinos remain in Africa. That subspecies and another species, the black rhino, are increasing in number after illegal hunting nearly caused their disappearance.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell adapted this story from AP and Reuters report.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>transfer </strong><em>– v.</em> to move something from one place to another</p>
<p><strong>subspecies </strong><em>– n.</em> a group of related plants or animals that is smaller than a species</p>
<p><strong>achieve</strong> <em>–v.</em> to do something that you were trying to do</p>
<p><strong>milestone</strong> <em>– n. </em>an important point in the progress or development of something</p>
<p><strong>euthanize</strong> <em>– v.</em> to put to death in a humane way</p>
<p><strong>in vitro</strong><em> –adj.</em> (scientific) taking place in a laboratory or outside of normal biological methods</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>What Are Enlarged Prostate and Prostate Cancer?  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/what-are-enlarged-prostate-and-prostate-cancer.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Britain's King Charles was treated recently for a medical condition called enlarged prostate. American Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin recently spent two weeks in a hospital for treatment following an operation for prostate cancer.</p>
<p>The 70-year-old Austin did not share any news of his medical condition publicly, at first. He also did not inform President Joe Biden of what the defense department described as a "<strong>minimally</strong> invasive" operation on Austin's prostate on December 22.</p>
<p>On January 1, the defense chief developed severe pain and was taken by ambulance to the hospital. He was placed in the intensive care department with an infection linked to the operation. Austin was released two weeks later.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Britain's King Charles III and Queen Camilla leave The London Clinic in central London, on Monday, Jan. 29, 2024. King Charles III was in hospital to receive treatment for an enlarged prostate. (AP Photo/Alberto Pezzali)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/c8b9c319-4f9d-42e0-b06b-4a25ce433171_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Britain's King Charles III and Queen Camilla leave The London Clinic in central London, on Monday, Jan. 29, 2024. King Charles III was in hospital to receive treatment for an enlarged prostate. (AP Photo/Alberto Pezzali)</span></div>
<p>The delay in informing the president and the public led to widespread criticism. A spokesman for Austin said at the time, "... discussions about (prostate cancer) screening, treatment and support are often deeply personal and private ones."</p>
<p>King Charles, however, announced on January 17 that he would undergo a "corrective procedure" for an enlarged prostate. His announcement came on the same day the 75-year-old king learned of his medical condition. On January 29, he left London Clinic after spending the weekend there for treatment.</p>
<p>It is unusual for members of the British <strong>royal</strong> family to share details about their health. However, King Charles decided to share his news publicly to <strong>encourage</strong> other men to have their prostates checked as called for by medical experts. The palace said the king sought treatment "in common with thousands of men each year."</p>
<p><strong>What is the prostate?</strong></p>
<p>The prostate is a small organ of the male reproductive system.</p>
<p>It is about the size and shape of a walnut. It sits below the bladder, an organ that stores urine temporarily.</p>
<p>The prostate helps make semen, the fluid that carries sperm cells required for human reproduction. The prostate surrounds part of the urethra, a tube that carries sperm from the testicles or urine out of the bladder through the penis.</p>
<p>As a man gets older, the prostate tends to grow larger. Medical experts say it could grow from the size of a walnut to the size of an apricot by the age of 40, and then to the size of a lemon by age 60. The larger prostate then may press against the urethra and cause problems in passing urine.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cancer.gov/types/prostate/understanding-prostate-changes">U.S. National Institute of Health (NIH) says</a> men in their 30s and 40s may begin to have problems with passing urine. The agency advises men to seek medical help if they experience any of the four conditions. They are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Passing urine more frequently day and night</li>
<li>Having an urgent need to pass urine</li>
<li>Having difficulty passing urine or passing urine very slowly</li>
<li>Feeling pain or burning while passing urine</li>
</ul>
<p>The NIH says the three most common prostate problems are prostatitis (or inflammation of the prostate), enlarged prostate (also known as BPH, or benign prostatic hyperplasia), and prostate cancer.</p>
<p><strong>Prostatitis</strong></p>
<p>Prostatitis is an inflammation of the prostate that may result from a bacterial infection. It affects at least half of all men at some time during their lives.</p>
<p>In the U.S., this condition is most common among younger men. Most cases can be treated with antibiotics medicine. Sometimes, doctors also give drugs to control <strong>inflammation</strong> and pain.</p>
<p><strong>Enlarged prostate (BHP)</strong></p>
<p>King Charles was treated for an enlarged prostate or BPH.</p>
<p>BPH stands for benign prostatic hyperplasia. Benign means "not cancer," and hyperplasia means unusual cell growth. BPH is not linked to cancer and does not increase your risk of getting prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Those with mild cases of enlarged prostate could simply limit drinking in the evening and use the restroom more often to empty their bladders. Some take drugs that help ease muscles that affect urine flow.</p>
<p>People with moderate cases of enlarged prostate could take drugs that help reduce the size of the prostate. The drugs called "5 alpha-reductase inhibitors" help shrink the prostate, reduce blockage and limit the need for invasive medical operations called surgeries.</p>
<p>In more severe cases, surgery is needed when drug treatment does not work.</p>
<p>The most common surgical treatment is to cut away extra prostate tissue using an instrument, radio wave, or laser. In rare cases, when the prostate is very large, doctors might consider a complete removal of the organ.</p>
<p><strong>Prostate cancer</strong></p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.cancer.org/cancer/types/prostate-cancer/about/key-statistics.html">American Cancer Society says</a> prostate cancer is the second most common cancer among men. Skin cancer is the most common.</p>
<p>The group estimates that about 1 in 8 American men will be diagnosed with prostate cancer during their lifetime. The number rises to 6 in 10 among those who are 65 or older. The risk is also higher among those with a family history of prostate cancer and among Black Americans than men of other ethnicities.</p>
<p>In 2024, the group estimates there will be 299,010 new cases of prostate cancer with about 35,250 deaths from prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Prostate cancer tends to grow slowly compared with most other cancers. Cell changes may begin many years before a tumor gets big enough to cause noticeable signs.</p>
<p>In addition to difficulties with passing urine, other symptoms of prostate cancer include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blood in the urine or semen</li>
<li>Painful ejaculation</li>
<li>And <strong>constant</strong> pain in the back, hips or pelvis area</li>
</ul>
<p>There are several screening tests to look for signs of possible prostate cancer. They include urine tests, physical examinations and prostate-specific antigen (or PSA) tests.</p>
<p>If symptoms or tests suggest possible prostate cancer, a prostate biopsy is advised. Doctors remove several small tissues from the prostate and examine the material for cancer cells. Any treatment that might follow depends on how far the cancer has developed.</p>
<p>Most men who have biopsies after prostate cancer screening exams do not have cancer.</p>
<p>In the case of Defense Secretary Austin, doctors said on Jan. 26 that "his cancer was treated early and effectively" and no further treatments will be needed.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Caty Weaver .</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this story for Learning English with information from the National Institute of Health and the American Cancer Society. Additional reporting came from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>minimally</strong> - adv. very small or slight in sizr=e or amount</p>
<p><strong>royal</strong> - adj. relating to a king or queen</p>
<p><strong>encourage</strong> - v. to make someone more likely to do something</p>
<p><strong>inflammation</strong> - n. a condition in which a part of your body is swollen and painful</p>
<p><strong>constant</strong> - adj. happening all the time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Study Finds Myanmar Religious Buildings Damaged  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-study-finds-myanmar-religious-buildings-damaged.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>New research provides evidence that attacks by Myanmar's military government have damaged religious centers in the country.</p>
<p>Religious leaders and human rights workers say the reported attacks are part of a wider campaign to attack religious communities across the nation.</p>
<p>A civil war broke out in Myanmar after the military seized power from the elected government of former leader Aung San Suu Kyi in February 2021.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Debris is seen in the St. Peter Baptist Church-Kanan, which was struck by the suspected military's aerial attacks in Kanan village, Khampat town, Sagaing region on Jan. 8, 2024. (David Htan via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0a00-0242-1260-08dc21980074_cx0_cy9_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Debris is seen in the St. Peter Baptist Church-Kanan, which was struck by the suspected military's aerial attacks in Kanan village, Khampat town, Sagaing region on Jan. 8, 2024. (David Htan via AP)</span></div>
<p>Human rights agencies and United Nations investigators say they have found evidence of Myanmar security forces targeting civilians. The evidence includes details about bomb attacks, mass executions and detentions and the burning of private homes.</p>
<p>One group, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://aappb.org/">Assistance Association for Political Prisoners</a>, accuses security forces in Myanmar of killing at least 4,416 people since the 2021 military takeover.</p>
<p>The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.myanmarwitness.org/">Myanmar Witness</a> project completed the new report on the destruction of religious centers. The project is part of the Britain-based Centre for Information Resilience.</p>
<p>Myanmar Witness examined claims of five airstrikes that caused major damage to religious centers over several months in 2023. The attacks happened in Myanmar's western Chin state.</p>
<p>Religious buildings are given special protection under international law.</p>
<p>Another group, the <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.chinhumanrights.org/">Chin Human Rights Organization</a>, reported that the military has destroyed at least 107 religious buildings in Chin state since 2021. Those included attacks against 67 <strong>churches</strong> and five Buddhist <strong>monasteries</strong>, the group said.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>A 2023 report by the International <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.icj.org/">Commission of Jurists</a> said 94 Buddhist religious centers and 87 Christian ones had been destroyed or damaged nationwide.</p>
<p>The Myanmar Witness group collects evidence including pictures, video and witness accounts found on social media services. The group compares this evidence with satellite images or other methods to confirm human rights abuses.</p>
<p>Matt Lawrence is director of Myanmar Witness. He said the main goal of the project is to give evidence of "<strong>atrocities</strong>" to international groups for further investigation.</p>
<p>Many human rights activists have accused the military of aiming for religious buildings.</p>
<p>"Bombing churches is much more than just <strong>collateral damage</strong>," wrote Benedict Rogers. He is a former East Asia team leader for the human rights organization <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.csw.org.uk/home.htm">Christian Solidarity Worldwide</a>. He wrote in an email to The Associated Press, "Targeting them is part of a <strong>deliberate strategy</strong>."</p>
<p>Rogers said the military government discriminates against non-Burmese ethnic minorities and non-Buddhist religious minorities.</p>
<p>In 2017, the military carried out a <strong>counterinsurgency</strong> campaign in Rakhine state. The campaign drove almost 740,000 members of the Muslim Rohingya minority to flee to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The military government offered no immediate comment on the new report.</p>
<p>But in the past, military leaders have repeatedly stated that security forces only attack permissible targets of war.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>church </strong><em>– n. </em>a building where Christians go to worship</p>
<p><strong>monastery </strong><em>– n. </em>a building where people live as part of a specific religious group</p>
<p><strong>atrocity </strong><em>– n. </em>an extremely violent and shocking attack</p>
<p><strong>collateral damage </strong><em>– n. </em>unintentional deaths, injuries and destruction caused during a war to non-military members</p>
<p><strong>deliberate </strong><em>– adj. </em>intentional or planned<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>strategy </strong><em>– n. </em>a careful plan to complete something or achieve a goal over a period of time</p>
<p><strong>counterinsurgency </strong><em>– n. </em>a military action taken by a government to prevent attacks by small groups of soldiers or fighters that are opposed to it</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Businesses Plan $8 Billion Investment in Vietnam  (2024/1/31)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/us-businesses-plan-8-billion-investment-in-vietnam.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">30 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Fifteen American businesses, including <strong>semiconductor </strong>companies, have expressed interest in investing $8 billion in Vietnam in clean energy projects, a senior U.S. official said recently.</p>
<p>However, their interest depends on the country's progress on <strong>renewable </strong>energy rules.</p>
<p>Vietnam is seeking to bring in computer <strong>chip</strong> companies. And it wants to build up its renewable energy industries. But it has so far struggled to pass rules that would permit the expansion of renewable energy industries. Those industries include solar and onshore wind and the development of offshore wind farms, of which it has none now.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration//File Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/0839a524-e3cc-4e0f-91ce-20a946bb627f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. (REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration//File Photo)</span></div>
<p>Jose Fernandez is an undersecretary for economic growth at the U.S. State Department. When asked if U.S. companies want to invest in Vietnam, he told reporters in Hanoi last Friday, "They are prepared to invest as much as $8 billion."</p>
<p>Fernandez did not name the companies. But he noted the investment would deal with clean energy <strong>infrastructure.</strong></p>
<p>Fernandez said that those companies made commitments to "use only renewable energy." So the investment would depend on the progress of rules on renewable energy in Vietnam. He added that the companies were also waiting for permits before they could go ahead with their investment plans.</p>
<p>Vietnam is considering rules that would permit factories to negotiate electricity prices directly with producers rather than buy it from the country's state-owned power network operator.</p>
<p>It is also working to pass rules for offshore wind, including creating an area for their operation in the sea. But delays in passing these rules have slowed progress.</p>
<p>An increase in renewables in Vietnam has been driven by the widespread use of <strong>solar panels </strong>and onshore wind farms. But problems connecting the projects to the electrical network, which also needs improvements to deal with the renewable energy, have partly undone this progress.</p>
<p>Fernandez's trip to Vietnam is part of U.S. plans to begin agreements reached last September. That was when the two countries officially raised their relationship to Vietnam's top diplomatic listing, called "comprehensive strategic partnership."</p>
<p>Fernandez had meetings with senior Vietnamese officials during the trip, including with Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh. During those meetings, he mostly discussed chips, critical minerals, and clean energy, he told reporters.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Francesco Guarascio reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>semiconductor </strong><em>– adj.</em> a material or object that allows some electricity or heat to move through it and that is used especially in electronic devices</p>
<p><strong>renewables </strong><em>– adj. </em>restored or replaced by natural processes: able to be replaced by nature</p>
<p><strong>chip </strong><em>– n. </em>a very small piece of hard material (called silicon) in a computer or other device that contains many electronic circuits</p>
<p><strong>infrastructure </strong><em>– n.</em> the basic equipment and structures (such as roads and bridges) that are needed for a country, region, or organization to function properly</p>
<p><strong>solar panel </strong>– <em>n</em>. a large, flat piece of equipment that uses the sun's light or heat to create electricity</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japanese Spacecraft Regains Power after Moon Landing  (2024/1/30) | 日本月球探测器恢复运行</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japanese-spacecraft-regains-power-after-moon-landing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Japan's space agency says a spacecraft that landed on the moon earlier this month has regained power and is continuing its mission.<br/>
日本的太空机构表示，本月早些时候登陆月球的一艘航天器已经恢复动力，并正在继续执行任务。</p>
<p>Officials from the Japan Exploration Agency (JAXA) said Monday they had successfully reestablished communication with the SLIM moon explorer.<br/>
日本宇宙航空研究开发机构（JAXA）的官员周一表示，他们已经成功地与SLIM月球探测器重新建立了通信。</p>
<p>SLIM touched down on the moon on January 20. But the spacecraft landed the wrong way up. Its solar equipment was unable to see the sun. JAXA said SLIM was likely able to regain power because of a change in the sun's direction.<br/>
SLIM于1月20日登陆月球。但飞船降落的方向不对。它的太阳能设备无法接受到阳光。JAXA表示，由于太阳朝向的改变，SLIM很可能能够重新获得动力。</p>
<p>After the landing, JAXA used the spacecraft's battery power to gather as much data as possible about the touchdown and the surrounding area. The power was then turned off to wait for the sun to rise higher in the lunar sky.<br/>
着陆后，日本宇宙航空研究开发机构利用航天器的电池电量收集了尽可能多的关于着陆点和周围区域的数据。然后关闭电源，等待太阳在月球上空升起得更高。</p>
<p>Mission officials have said the explorer landed within 55 meters of its target near the lunar equator. It also landed in between two craters in an area covered in volcanic rock. JAXA said these results demonstrated progress in what it calls "pinpoint" landing technology.<br/>
任务官员表示，该探测器在月球赤道附近距离目标55米以内着陆。它还降落在覆盖着火山岩的两个火山口之间。日本宇宙航空研究开发机构表示，这些结果证明了其所谓的“精确定位”着陆技术的进步。</p>
<p>Past moon missions generally aimed to hit flat areas at least 10 kilometers wide. But the ability to land on very exact targets is expected to help support future space vehicles traveling to the moon and other places.<br/>
过去的月球任务通常旨在抵达至少10公里宽的平坦区域。但是，降落在非常精确的目标上的能力预计将有助于支持未来前往月球和其他星球的太空飞行器。</p>
<p>The main purpose of the mission was to test the possibility that spacecraft can land on very specific targets. But SLIM is also capturing images and released two small explorers. The explorers are designed to examine mineral-rich rocks and collect data on the moon's development.<br/>
这次任务的主要目的是测试航天器能够降落在非常特定的目标上的可能性。但SLIM也在拍摄图像，并释放了两台小型探测车。探测车的任务是检查富含矿物质的岩石，并收集有关月球发展的数据。</p>
<p>JAXA has not named a specific date for when SLIM will end its operations on the moon. But the agency has said in the past that the lander was not designed to survive a lunar night. The next lunar night begins on Thursday.<br/>
日本宇宙航空研究开发机构尚未确定SLIM结束其月球使命的具体日期。但该机构过去曾表示，着陆器的设计不适用于月夜生存。下一个月夜从星期四开始。</p>
<p>The mission made Japan the fifth country in the world to successfully land on the surface of the moon, after the United States, the Soviet Union, China and India.<br/>
这次任务使日本成为继美国、苏联、中国和印度之后，世界上第五个成功登上月球表面的国家。</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.<br/>
我是布莱恩·林恩。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Studies: Gene Treatment Lets Children Deaf at Birth Hear  (2024/1/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/studies-gene-treatment-lets-children-deaf-at-birth-hear.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Gene treatments are being credited with permitting several children born with deafness to hear again.</p>
<p>Gene therapy is a medical treatment that aims to change a few of a patient's genes to cure a genetic disease.</p>
<p>A small study recently published in <em>The Lancet</em> reported improvements in the hearing in five of six children who were treated in China.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this photo provided by researchers in January 2024, Dr. Yilai Shu examines a young patient at the Eye &amp; ENT Hospital of Fudan University in Shanghai, China, after a gene therapy procedure for hereditary deafness. (Courtesy Dr. Yilai Shu via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/14f4bc8b-c3b2-4500-aa69-c5bc2683e1ae_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this photo provided by researchers in January 2024, Dr. Yilai Shu examines a young patient at the Eye &amp; ENT Hospital of Fudan University in Shanghai, China, after a gene therapy procedure for hereditary deafness. (Courtesy Dr. Yilai Shu via AP)</span></div>
<p>Around the same time, the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia in the U.S. eastern state of Pennsylvania announced similar improvements in an 11-year-old boy treated there. And earlier, Chinese researchers published a study showing similar improvements in two other children.</p>
<p>The experimental methods, or therapies, target only one rare condition. But scientists say similar treatments could someday help many more children with other kinds of deafness caused by genes.</p>
<p>Around the world, 34 million children have deafness or hearing loss. And information from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention says genes are responsible for up to 60 percent of cases.</p>
<p>Deafness caused by genes is passed down from parents to children. It is called <strong>hereditary</strong> deafness. It is the latest condition scientists are targeting with gene therapy. Gene therapy is already approved to treat illnesses such as sickle cell disease and severe hemophilia.</p>
<p>Children with hereditary deafness often get a device called a cochlear <strong>implant</strong> that helps them hear sound.</p>
<p>"No treatment could <strong>reverse</strong> hearing loss...That's why we were always trying to develop a therapy," said Zheng-Yi Chen of Boston's Mass Eye and Ear, a treatment center for eye and ear problems. He is a writer of the study published in <em>The Lancet</em>. "We couldn't be more happy or <strong>excited</strong> about the results."</p>
<p><strong>Treatment results</strong></p>
<p>The team recorded videos of patients. One shows a baby, who formerly could not hear at all, looking back in response to a doctor's words six weeks after treatment. Another shows a little girl 13 weeks after treatment repeating father, mother, grandmother, sister, and "I love you."</p>
<p>All the children in the experiments have a condition that is believed to cause two to eight percent of hereditary deafness. It is caused by changes in a gene responsible for an inner ear protein called otoferlin, which helps hair cells send sound signals to the brain.</p>
<p>The researchers say that the one-time therapy gives a working copy of that gene to the inner ear during a medical operation. Most of the children were treated in one ear, although one child in the two-person study was treated in both ears.</p>
<p>The study with six children took place at Fudan University in Shanghai. Dr. Yilai Shu helped lead the study and trained in Chen's laboratory. Chen was involved in the research. Chinese science organizations and biotechnology company Shanghai Refreshgene Therapeutics helped provide financial support.</p>
<p>Researchers observed the children for about six months. They do not know why the treatment did not work in one of them. But the five others, who were completely deaf, can now hear a normal discussion, the researchers said.</p>
<p>Chen estimated they now hear at a level 60 percent to 70 percent of normal. The therapy caused no major side effects.</p>
<p>Early results from other research have shown similar results.</p>
<p>Regeneron Pharmaceuticals is a biotech company based in New York state. It announced in October that a child under two years old showed improvements six weeks after gene therapy. The results came from a study Regeneron did with support from Decibel Therapeutics, a company in Boston.</p>
<p>Columbia University's Dr. Lawrence Lustig is involved in the Regeneron study. He said although the children in these studies do not end up with very good hearing, "even a moderate hearing loss recovery in these kids is <strong>pretty astounding</strong>."</p>
<p>He added that many questions remain. They include how long the therapies will last and if hearing will continue to improve in the children.</p>
<p>Some people question if gene therapy for deafness is <strong>ethical</strong>.</p>
<p>Teresa Blankmeyer Burke is a professor who is deaf and who deals with medical ethics. She teaches at Gallaudet University, a university for deaf people in Washington, D.C. She said that there is no agreement about the need for gene therapy targeting deafness.</p>
<p>She also pointed out that deafness does not cause severe or deadly illness. Blankmeyer Burke said that it is important to work with deaf community members about the importance of gene therapy. She added gene therapy is seen by many as a possible threat to "signing Deaf communities."</p>
<p>However, Chen said: "This is real proof showing gene therapy is working." And he added, "It opens up the whole field."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo. And I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Laura Ungar reported this story for The Associated Press. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>hereditary </strong><em>–adj.</em> passed down from one generation to the next</p>
<p><strong>implant </strong><em>–n. (medical)</em> something connected to a person's body through a medical operation</p>
<p><strong>reverse </strong><em>– v.</em> to change (something) to an opposite state or condition</p>
<p><strong>excited </strong>– <em>adj</em>. very enthusiastic and eager about something</p>
<p><strong>pretty </strong>– <em>adv</em>. to a great degree or extent: very</p>
<p><strong>astounding </strong><em>– adj.</em> causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder</p>
<p><strong>ethical </strong>– <em>adj</em>. following accepted rules of behavior: morally right and good</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>X Blocks Taylor Swift Search after ‘Deepfake’ Image Spread  (2024/1/30)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/x-blocks-taylor-swift-search-after-deepfake-image-spread.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">29 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The social media site X has blocked some searches for Taylor Swift in reaction to an online spread of <strong>pornographic </strong>deepfake images of the singer.</p>
<p>A "deepfake" is an image, sound recording, or video created to make it appear that people in it are saying or doing things that they did not say or do.</p>
<p>Attempts to search for her name without <strong>quotation </strong>marks on the site Monday resulted in a failure<strong> </strong>message. It asked users to retry their search. "Don't <strong>fret</strong> — it's not your fault," also appeared.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Taylor Swift wears a Kansas City Chiefs tight end Travis Kelce jacket as she arrives before an NFL wild-card playoff football game between the Chiefs and the Miami Dolphins, Saturday, Jan. 13, 2024, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Ed Zurga, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/32622053-6b89-4d2d-a493-7adc976ae8f3_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Taylor Swift wears a Kansas City Chiefs tight end Travis Kelce jacket as she arrives before an NFL wild-card playoff football game between the Chiefs and the Miami Dolphins, Saturday, Jan. 13, 2024, in Kansas City, Mo. (AP Photo/Ed Zurga, File)</span></div>
<p>However, putting quotation marks around her name permitted posts to show where her name appeared.</p>
<p>The images of Swift began spreading widely on X last week. She is now the most famous victim of a danger that technology companies and anti-abuse groups have struggled to fix.</p>
<p>"This is a temporary action and done with an <strong>abundance</strong> of <strong>caution</strong> as we <strong>prioritize</strong> safety on this issue," Joe Benarroch, head of business operations at X, said in a statement.</p>
<p>After the images began spreading, the singer's loyal fan base, called "Swifties," quickly came to her defense. They launched a protective movement and flooded the site with more positive images of the singer. They used the hashtag #ProtectTaylorSwift on their posts. Some said they were reporting accounts that were sharing the deepfakes.</p>
<p>The deepfake-search group Reality Defender said it followed many posts of pornographic material of Swift. Many of the posts were found on X, formerly known as Twitter. Some images also made their way to Facebook and other social media sites.</p>
<p>The researchers found at least 20 different images created by artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<p>Researchers have said the number of pornographic deepfakes has grown in the past few years. The increase continues as the technology used to produce such images has become more available and easier to use.</p>
<p>In 2019, a report released by the AI company DeepTrace Labs showed these images were mainly weaponized against women. Most of the victims, it said, were Hollywood actors and South Korean singers.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>pornographic </strong><em>– adj.</em> showing or describing naked people or sex in a very open and direct way in order to cause sexual excitement</p>
<p><strong>quotation mark </strong><em>– n. </em>one of a pair of punctuation marks " " or ‘ ' that are used to show the beginning and the end of a quotation, to show that something is a title, to show that a word or phrase is being used in a special way, etc.</p>
<p><strong>fret </strong><em>– v. </em>to worry or be concerned</p>
<p><strong>abundance </strong><em>– n.</em> a large amount of something: an abundant amount of something</p>
<p><strong>caution </strong><em>– n. </em>carefulness in regard to danger</p>
<p><strong>prioritize </strong>– <em>v</em>. to organize (things) so that the most important thing is done or dealt with first</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>New Evidence Suggests Large Water Ice Supply near Mars’ Equator  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/new-evidence-suggests-large-water-ice-supply-near-mars-equator.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A Mars explorer has discovered new evidence of a large amount of water ice buried near the planet's <strong>equator</strong>.</p>
<p>The discovery was made with data collected by the Mars Express orbiter. The spacecraft is operated by the European Space Agency (ESA). The American space agency NASA is a partner on the orbiter's <strong>mission</strong>.</p>
<p>ESA launched Mars Express in 2003 and it has been studying the Red Planet ever since. The mission's main goal is to use its seven scientific instruments to search for signs of water underneath the surface of Mars.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This high-resolution image, taken by a camera aboard ESA's Mars Express spacecraft, shows part of the Medusa Fossae formation and surrounding areas near the equator of Mars. (ESA/DLR/FU Berlin (G. Neukum))" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-86f9-08dc1e0c9cb0_cx0_cy1_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This high-resolution image, taken by a camera aboard ESA's Mars Express spacecraft, shows part of the Medusa Fossae formation and surrounding areas near the equator of Mars. (ESA/DLR/FU Berlin (G. Neukum))</span></div>
<p>Scientists involved in the new research say data suggesting the presence of newly discovered ice <strong>deposits</strong> could mean Mars may have once supported life.</p>
<p>The Mars Express orbiter collected data around an area of the planet known as the Medusae Fossae Formation (or MFF). NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/images/pia03770-medusae-fossae-formation">describes</a> this formation as "a soft, easily <strong>eroded</strong> deposit that extends for nearly 1,000 kilometers along the equator of Mars."</p>
<p>Scientists believe the MFF was most likely formed by wind-blown dust or volcanic ash. The formations could have formed after volcanic activity estimated to have taken place up to 3.8 billion years ago.</p>
<p>Images of the area show raised areas that scientists thought in the past might contain dust blown around the planet by wind over many years. But the new research used newer data collected by the orbiter's MARSIS instrument. It is "a subsurface radar sounder" with a 40-meter-long <strong>antenna</strong>. The tool looks for water on the surface, as well as up to five kilometers below the surface.</p>
<p>The MARSIS instrument is designed to send radio waves to an area scientists choose. It then attempts to listen to and examine "<strong>echoes</strong>" produced by the radio waves. The echoes help researchers recognize where water or ice might be, NASA <a class="wsw__a" href="https://mars.nasa.gov/express/mission/sc_science_marsis01.html">explains</a>.</p>
<p>Scientists say any water identified near the surface results in stronger signals while the presence of ice or other materials would produce weaker signals. The team said MARSIS readings suggest the MFF area of Mars contains a large amount of water ice rather than wind-blown dust.</p>
<p>Thomas Watters of the U.S. Smithsonian Institution led the new research. His team's findings were recently <a class="wsw__a" href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1029/2023GL105490">published in a study</a> in <em>Geophysical Research Letters</em>. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Buried_water_ice_at_Mars_s_equator">said in a statement</a> the radar data showed the deposits in the MFF area were even thicker than earlier measurement estimates had shown.</p>
<p>The researchers said the data showed the examined deposits extended beneath the Mars surface to depths up to 3.7 kilometers. They seemed to contain "<strong>layers</strong> of dust and ice, all topped by a protective layer of dry dust or ash."</p>
<p>Earlier data examinations of the MFF area found similarities in the electrical properties of deposits there to ice-rich deposits found in the planet's north and south poles. The latest MARSIS data strengthens this evidence by suggesting similarities between deposit layering in the MFF and the planet's poles.</p>
<p>"The radar signals <strong>match</strong> what we'd expect to see from layered ice," Watters said. He added that the radar waves were found to be "similar to signals we see from Mars's polar caps, which we know to be very ice rich."</p>
<p>It is not the first time scientists have discovered strong evidence for the presence of water ice on Mars. But the researchers say the latest study suggests the largest amount of water ever identified in the MFF area. They estimated the total amount of water contained there would be enough "to cover the surface of Mars to a depth of about 1.5 to 3 meters."</p>
<p>Colin Wilson is a project scientist with the Mars Express mission. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Buried_water_ice_at_Mars_s_equator">said</a> while the new finding is exciting, it also "raises as many questions as answers." He continued, "How long ago did these ice deposits form, and what was Mars like at that time?" Wilson said if confirmed to be water ice, the large deposits "would change our understanding of Mars climate history."</p>
<p>Watters added that since the discovery was made in an area near the Martian equator, it could be considered a good place for future exploration missions. He explained that with a lower <strong>elevation</strong>, the MFF area would be considered "an ideal landing spot for spacecraft." Such an elevation provides more atmosphere to support an effective, controlled landing, Watters said.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from the European Space Agency, NASA, Geophysical Research Letters and the Smithsonian. </em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">________________________________</h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>equator </strong>–n. an imaginary line around the middle of a planet that is an equal distance from its north and south poles</p>
<p><strong>mission </strong><em>– n. </em>the flight of a spacecraft to perform a certain task or job</p>
<p><strong>deposit </strong><em>– n. </em>a layer of a substance that has developed from a natural or chemical process</p>
<p><strong>erode </strong><em>– v. </em>to gradually be damaged over time</p>
<p><strong>antenna </strong><em>– n. </em>a piece of metal used for receiving television or radio signals</p>
<p><strong>echo </strong><em>– n. </em>the repeating of a sound caused by the reflection of sound waves</p>
<p><strong>layer </strong><em>– n. </em>an amount of substance covering a surface</p>
<p><strong>match </strong><em>– v. to fit together or make suitable for fitting together</em></p>
<p><strong>elevation </strong><em>– n. </em>the height of a place above the level of the sea</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple Releases New Stolen Device Protection  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/apple-releases-new-stolen-device-protection.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Imagine that you are in a crowded place. You do not notice, but someone is watching you and learns your iPhone passcode. Then, they steal your phone. Suddenly, your photos, documents, financial information, and the rest of your digital life have been taken from you.</p>
<p>A new security feature may prevent such a situation from happening. Apple, the iPhone maker, recently released an update to its iOS operating system. It has a new feature called Stolen Device Protection. The feature makes it a lot harder for phone <strong>thieves</strong> to open the device and <strong>access</strong> important functions and settings.</p>
<p>The company is urging users to turn this feature on immediately. Here is how to turn on the new security feature and why it is so important to do so.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An Apple iPhone 15 advertisement is seen as it officially goes on sale across China at an Apple Store in Shanghai, China September 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-410f-08dbbb5c0d64_cx6_cy13_cw93_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An Apple iPhone 15 advertisement is seen as it officially goes on sale across China at an Apple Store in Shanghai, China September 22, 2023. (REUTERS/Aly Song)</span></div>
<p><strong>Should I turn on Stolen Device Protection?</strong></p>
<p>Stolen Device Protection is a new setting that is included with the latest iOS release, version 17.3. The update for iPhones and iPads includes a new feature designed to prevent thieves from <strong>wiping</strong> phones for resale or getting to your Apple ID or other important accounts.</p>
<p>Apple says the feature adds extra security for users. It addresses a <strong>vulnerability</strong> that thieves have used to lock device owners out of their Apple accounts, <strong>delete</strong> their photos and other files from their iCloud, and take money from their bank accounts.</p>
<p><strong>How does it work?</strong></p>
<p>Stolen Device Protection <strong>keeps track</strong> of a user's "familiar locations," such as their home or workplace. The feature adds extra biometric security if someone tries to use the device to do certain things away from those places.</p>
<p>It also reduces the importance of passcodes. Instead, it favors "biometric" features such as faces or fingerprints, which are a lot harder to copy.</p>
<p>If a thief tries to <strong>erase</strong> or reset an iPhone, the device will require a Face ID or Touch ID scan to confirm that the person is the rightful owner. The new feature does not let someone use the passcode or any other backup method.</p>
<p>Another part of the new feature is designed to slow down thieves trying to change security settings. For example, if someone tries to sign out of an Apple ID account, change the passcode or reset the phone in an unfamiliar <strong>location</strong>, they will have to <strong>authenticate</strong> using Face ID or Touch ID, wait an hour, and then do a second facial or fingerprint scan.</p>
<p>Changing an Apple ID password, updating Apple ID security settings, adding or removing Face or Touch ID, and turning off the Find My device feature or Stolen Device Protection also will <strong>trigger</strong> this feature.</p>
<p>Apple said the delay is meant to prevent a thief from performing these operations so you can mark your device as lost and secure your Apple account.</p>
<p>The company added that, "When your iPhone is in a familiar location, these additional steps will not be required and you can use your device passcode like normal."</p>
<p><strong>How do I turn it on?</strong></p>
<p>First, download and update your iPhone or iPad with the latest iOS update. The update works for iPhone XS and newer models, including second- and third-generation SE models.</p>
<p>Then go to your settings, scroll down to "Face ID &amp; Passcode" or "Touch ID &amp; Passcode" and enter your passcode. Scroll down and you'll see Stolen Device Protection.</p>
<p>Make sure you have turned on two-factor authentication and Find My device for your Apple ID account. Otherwise, it will not show up.</p>
<p>I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Kelvin Chan reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>thief</strong> - n. a person who steals something</p>
<p><strong>access</strong> - v. to be able to enter or get into something</p>
<p><strong>wipe</strong> - v. to completely remove something</p>
<p><strong>vulnerability</strong> - n. the condition of easily open to attack, hurt or damage</p>
<p><strong>delete</strong> - v. to remove</p>
<p><strong>keep track</strong> - v. to be aware of what someone is doing</p>
<p><strong>erase</strong> - v. to remove something from a digital device</p>
<p><strong>location</strong> - n. place or position</p>
<p><strong>authenticate</strong> - v. to prove that something is real</p>
<p><strong>trigger</strong> - v. to cause something else to happen</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Find New Penguins Colonies in Antarctica  (2024/1/29)</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/scientists-find-new-penguins-colonies-in-antarctica.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Faith Pirlo</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">28 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have found four groups of emperor penguins in Antarctica that they did not know about before. These groups, called "<strong>colonies</strong>," were found with new satellite images.</p>
<p>Emperor penguins are the world's largest penguins, sea birds that cannot fly but that swim. They are consider "near threatened." This means the animals might have reduced numbers or live in fewer areas than before.</p>
<p>The penguins raise their babies, called chicks, during the Antarctic winter on areas of frozen sea ice. If the ice breaks up before the chicks grow up, many of the chicks might die.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This undated photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey in January 2024 shows adult emperor penguins with a chick near Halley Research Station in Antarctica. (British Antarctic Survey via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/22389179-9dd7-4bd6-a0b6-4c8200ec1b62_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This undated photo provided by the British Antarctic Survey in January 2024 shows adult emperor penguins with a chick near Halley Research Station in Antarctica. (British Antarctic Survey via AP)</span></div>
<p>Recently released research says that some of the penguins are moving away from their old colonies.</p>
<p>Peter Fretwell is a researcher at the British Antarctic Survey, a government organization. He said that conditions at one colony had become more dangerous since 2016. As a result, the colony near Halley Bay seems to have moved about 30 kilometers east.</p>
<p>He said, "Emperor penguins have taken it upon themselves to try to find more <strong>stable</strong> sea ice."</p>
<p>Fretwell said that the four new colonies have likely existed for years, but scientists have just recently seen them. They are small colonies with less than 1000 <strong>pairs</strong> of penguins, Fretwell said.</p>
<p>Scientists have identified 66 emperor penguin colonies and fewer than 300,000 <strong>breeding</strong> pairs. The four newly found colonies do not change population estimates for the birds very much. However, Fretwell said the fact that one of the colonies moved helps scientists to understand where the birds are going.</p>
<p>Daniel Zitterbart is a penguin researcher at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution in the U.S. eastern state of Massachusetts. He was not involved in the study of the newly found penguins. But he said that it is unclear if the new groups broke away from the larger colonies.</p>
<p>Zitterbart said that the places where the penguins <strong>reproduce </strong>are changing and that, as the world warms, more "penguins will be on the move."</p>
<p>I'm Faith Pirlo.</p>
<p><em>Christina Larson reported this story for the Associated Press. Faith Pirlo adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>colonies</strong> – <em>n</em>. groups of plants or animals living or growing in one place</p>
<p><strong>stable</strong> – <em>adj</em>. remain the same</p>
<p><strong>pair </strong><em>– n.</em> two of something</p>
<p><strong>breed </strong><em>– v.</em> to produce and raise young</p>
<p><strong>reproduce</strong> – <em>v</em>. to produce offspring by sexual reproduction</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Saudi Arabia Aims to Develop EV Industry  (2024/1/29) | 沙特意图发展电动汽车行业</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/saudi-arabia-aims-to-develop-ev-industry.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Saudi Arabia has spent billions of dollars to become competitive in the electric vehicle (EV) industry.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯花费了数十亿美元，让自己在电动汽车行业具有竞争力。</p>
<p>Such efforts are part of Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's broader plan to create jobs and diversify the country's economy. The kingdom has invested at least $10 billion in Lucid Motors, a United States-based company. It also set up a Saudi EV company, Ceer, and built an EV metals factory.<br/>
这些努力是沙特王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼创造就业机会和实现国家经济多样化的宏大计划的一部分。沙特已向总部位于美国的Lucid Motors公司投资至少100亿美元。它还成立了一家沙特电动汽车公司Ceer，并建造了一家电动汽车金属工厂。</p>
<p>The Public Investment Fund (PIF), Saudi Arabia's $700 billion sovereign wealth fund, has a goal to produce 500,000 EVs yearly by 2030, up from a target of 150,000 in 2026.<br/>
作为管理7000亿美元的主权财富基金，沙特公共投资基金的目标是到2030年每年生产50万辆电动汽车，而2026年的目标是每年生产15万辆。</p>
<p>Yet by December, Ceer, which opened in September 2023, had put together around 800 vehicles. Those vehicles were based on kits supplied from the U.S. state of Arizona.<br/>
然而截至去年12月，于2023年9月开业的Ceer公司已经组装了约800辆汽车。这些车辆是基于美国亚利桑那州提供的套件。</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia has failed in the past to appeal to foreign car makers.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯过去未能吸引外国汽车制造商。</p>
<p>Japan's Toyota rejected a proposed deal with Saudi Arabia in 2019. The company said labor costs were too high, local suppliers were too few, and the market was too small.<br/>
2019年，日本丰田公司拒绝了与沙特阿拉伯的一项拟议交易。该公司表示，沙特劳动力成本太高，当地供应商太少，市场太小。</p>
<p>As the world moves away from cars fueled by oil, experts say Saudi Arabia faces competition in the EV industry.<br/>
专家表示，随着世界逐渐放弃以石油为燃料的汽车，沙特阿拉伯在电动汽车行业面临竞争。</p>
<p>"There is tremendous competition that the country will face from established manufacturing power houses and from established supply chains," said Gaurav Batra of EY, a business advisory company.<br/>
安永商业咨询公司的高罗夫·巴特拉表示：“沙特将面临来自老牌制造业巨头和老牌供应链的巨大竞争。”</p>
<p>Batra added, "A lot of things need to come into place before this industry takes shape and really ignites."<br/>
巴特拉补充道：“在这个行业成型并真正爆发之前，需要做很多事情。”</p>
<p>Saudi officials did not respond to Reuters news agency requests for comment.<br/>
沙特官员没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">EV production<br/>
电动汽车生产</span></p>
<p>China currently leads the new supply chain as well as EV production. Chinese company BYD became the world's biggest maker of EVs last year, pushing Tesla motors into 2nd place.<br/>
中国目前在这条全新供应链和电动汽车生产方面处于领先地位。中国比亚迪公司去年成为全球最大的电动汽车制造商，将特斯拉汽车挤至第二位。</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia faces a lack of auto parts supply - anything from car doors to engines. There is no major local industry to produce these goods.<br/>
沙特阿拉伯面临着汽车零部件供应短缺的问题，从车门到发动机，无所不包。当地没有大型产业可以生产这些产品。</p>
<p>The EV manufacturer Ceer, a joint project between the PIF and Taiwanese company Foxconn, plans to launch a car by 2025. But the company has not yet built its factory.<br/>
电动汽车制造商Ceer是沙特公共投资基金和中国台湾省富士康公司的联合项目，该公司计划在2025年前推出一款汽车。但该公司尚未建厂。</p>
<p>A source connected to Ceer said it was unlikely the company would have a vehicle on the road before 2026. The source spoke on condition that they not be identified.<br/>
一位与Ceer有关的消息人士表示，该公司在2026年之前不太可能有车辆上路。该消息人士要求匿名。</p>
<p>In October, South Korean car manufacturer Hyundai and the PIF announced a project to build a factory for traditional engine vehicles and electric vehicles. The project, along with those of Lucid and Ceer, would create a group of factories in Jeddah's King Abdullah Economic City.<br/>
10月，韩国汽车制造商现代汽车和沙特公共投资基金宣布了一个项目，将为传统发动机汽车和电动汽车建造一个工厂。该项目连同Lucid和Ceer的项目一起，将在吉达市的阿卜杜拉国王经济城创建一批工厂。</p>
<p>Ceer will get parts from Germany's BMW automobile company, including batteries, the highest cost single part of an EV.<br/>
Ceer将从德国宝马汽车公司获得零部件，包括电池，这是电动汽车中成本最高的单个零部件。</p>
<p>Lucid vice president Faisal Sultan told Reuters in December that Saudi Arabia needed the presence of critical suppliers. He said the Saudi factory only rebuilt vehicles and the Arizona site carried out quality control testing.<br/>
Lucid副总裁费萨尔·苏丹12月告诉路透社，沙特阿拉伯需要关键供应商的存在。他说，沙特工厂只是重新组装了车辆，亚利桑那州工厂进行了质量控制测试。</p>
<p>The company's idea - keeping the supply chain and vehicle manufacturing in the United States - could lead other companies to set up rebuild sites as well. As a result, these companies might be able to get Saudi incentives, a Saudi auto industry leader said.<br/>
该公司将供应链和汽车制造留在美国的想法可能会导致其他公司也建立组装基地。一位沙特汽车行业领袖表示，因此，这些公司可能能够获得沙特的激励。</p>
<p>But such moves could slow the growth of local Saudi manufacturing as the country would continue to import foreign-made cars.<br/>
但这些举措可能会减缓沙特当地制造业的增长，因为该国将继续进口外国制造的汽车。</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.<br/>
我是约翰·拉塞尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Apple’s Computer Launch Leads to Study of User Experience  (2024/1/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/apple-s-computer-launch-leads-to-study-of-user-experience.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Many people first heard about Apple's Macintosh computer through a television <strong>commercial</strong> during the American football Super Bowl game in 1984.</p>
<p>However, the commercial did not show a computer at all. It showed a woman throwing a hammer at a large screen. On the screen was a man giving a speech. The screen exploded and an announcer said, "Apple Computer will introduce Macintosh. ... And you'll see why 1984 won't be like ‘1984.'"</p>
<p><em>1984</em> is George Orwell's book about an <strong>authoritarian</strong> government. And Apple aimed to tell people that the new computer would be different. It would be easy to use.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Part of an early model central processing unit is seen on display at the Computer History Museum on January 19, 2024 in Mountain View, California, as the museum celebrates Mac's 40th birthday. (Photo by Loren Elliott / AFP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6df27416-531f-4df9-bc58-f6ab6a6cc720_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Part of an early model central processing unit is seen on display at the Computer History Museum on January 19, 2024 in Mountain View, California, as the museum celebrates Mac's 40th birthday. (Photo by Loren Elliott / AFP)</span></div>
<p><strong>Made with humans in mind</strong></p>
<p>Many computers at the time only did one or two things. And they required the user to type complex commands to start the programs.</p>
<p>Jacob O. Wobbrock is a professor of information at the University of Washington. He wrote about Apple's commercial in <em>The Conversation</em>.</p>
<p>Apple "was selling a product for human beings to use," Wobbrock writes. After the commercial, he suggests, Apple became known for design and the world started paying attention to the idea of user experience, or human-computer interaction.</p>
<p>"The Macintosh was one of the first products to really <strong>prioritize</strong> user experience and <strong>focus</strong> on making something useable and understandable, learnable even guessable. So that people didn't have to always read a <strong>manual</strong> to learn how to use it."</p>
<p>Mackenzie Bristow is a former language teacher and researcher who now works in user experience in Atlanta, Georgia. She said Macintosh was one of the first products to think about "the user."</p>
<p>"What is the role of the person? What is the role of the user?" she asked. She explained that in design, the rule is "first, understand the person" before thinking about what the product looks like and what it can do.</p>
<p>Forty years after the launch of the Macintosh computer, we now see computer screens everywhere – at restaurants, at airports and even in cars. All of those devices have been designed by experts in user experience.</p>
<p><strong>STEM plus ‘soft skills'</strong></p>
<p>Many colleges and universities now offer study programs in user experience.</p>
<p>While it is part of STEM – science, technology, engineering and math – Wobbrock said students from different areas of study, including psychology or communication, could be successful.</p>
<p>"The kind of student that <strong>thrives</strong> in user experience is a student who has above all else, a real curiosity about how people <strong>interact</strong> with technology. ... And students whose first language is not English can absolutely do well in user experience."</p>
<p>One of those students is Kartik Sundaram of India. He studied computer science at the University of Michigan and chose user experience for his <strong>graduate</strong> study. He finished last year and is now teaching the subject.</p>
<p>"I never felt like I had a personal desire to pursue [computer science]," he said. He called the work "very <strong>isolating</strong>." For fun, he took a photography class. While in the class, he met someone who was studying in the User Experience Research and Design program.</p>
<p>"He told me about how, you know, it's like this <strong>blend</strong> of design and people and technology, and that kind of lit a fire in my heart to say ok, this seems a lot more interesting, ... ‘let's jump right in, let's learn more about it and let's apply to that school."</p>
<p>Sundaram said user experience is good for people who are "personable and good at making connections." Some of those are called ‘soft skills,' he said. And "the soft skills really matter."</p>
<p>While he grew up speaking English, Sundaram said the world of user experience is more and more open to people who are learning English or who may speak with an accent.</p>
<p>"I don't think it's an expectation that your English is <strong>flawless</strong>," he said.</p>
<p>Bristow said the ability to speak more than one language "is kind of a super power in user experience," because those people are comfortable interacting with many different kinds of people. "That's really something to be celebrated," she said.</p>
<p><strong>Future of UX and job outlook</strong></p>
<p>Sundaram is teaching but also looking for work in the field. Wobbrock is a professor and Bristow works on training programs for a large company.</p>
<p>They each spoke about the need for user experience professionals to work in the expanding field of artificial intelligence, or AI.</p>
<p>Sundaram said "We're not going to be restricted to a text box in ChatGPT for much longer. There are going to be other ways to interact with it."</p>
<p>Bristow said the ability to understand language is important. AI programs will need experts who understand how language changes based on where people live, their level of education and their age.</p>
<p>Wobbrock said user experience professionals are starting to work on projects called human-AI interaction. "There will be a great need for user experience professionals to help understand how people and AI can interact and work together in profitable ways," he added.</p>
<p>But Sundaram warned that user experience study programs, also known as UX, are becoming very popular. He said some students see UX as a field to make a lot of money with few <strong>certification</strong> requirements.<strong> </strong>And several companies are letting go of people with experience in the field.</p>
<p>Sundaram said, "It's definitely a difficult market, but it's an incredible field and there are new <strong>interfaces</strong> coming out that need our work."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell. And I'm Jill Robbins.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell wrote this story for Learning English.</em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>commercial </strong>–n. another name for a television advertisement</p>
<p><strong>authoritarian </strong>– <em>adj. </em>describing a restrictive government where power is with one or very few people</p>
<p><strong>prioritize </strong>–v. to put something first in order of importance</p>
<p><strong>focus </strong>– <em>v. </em>to make something the center of attention</p>
<p><strong>manual </strong>–n. a book with instructions or directions on how to operate something</p>
<p><strong>thrive </strong>–v. to do well or produce excellent work</p>
<p><strong>interact </strong>– <em>v. </em>how one thing mixes with another</p>
<p><strong>graduate </strong>–adj. a study program for an advanced degree, after a bachelor's degree</p>
<p><strong>isolating </strong>– <em>adj. </em>lonely, away from other people</p>
<p><strong>blend </strong>–n. a mixture of two or more things</p>
<p><strong>flawless </strong>–adj. without mistakes or errors</p>
<p><strong>certification </strong>– <em>n. </em>a test that proves you know how to do or perform a task</p>
<p><strong>interface </strong>–n. a system that permits two different things to connect with each other</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Snow Day? Don't Be 'Left Out in the Cold'  (2024/1/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/don-t-be-left-out-in-the-cold.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>And now, <em>Words and Their Stories</em>, from VOA Learning English.</p>
<p>On this program, we explore words and expressions in the English language. We give definitions, examples, notes on usage, and sometimes we use them in short conversations.</p>
<p>In a recent science report<a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/while-us-freezes-much-of-the-world-experiences-record-heat/7445844.html"> we explained</a> about a weather system called the polar vortex. It caused a <u>snowball effect</u> on extreme weather around the world. The event led to record-high temperatures in many parts of the world. But much of North America had to deal with extreme cold. Some areas recorded temperatures as low as minus 20 degrees Celsius.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Mist from the Great Falls has created a frozen wonderland around the waterfalls in Paterson, New Jersey, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-f776-08dc1a7fc685_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Mist from the Great Falls has created a frozen wonderland around the waterfalls in Paterson, New Jersey, Jan. 18, 2024. (AP Photo/Ted Shaffrey)</span></div>
<p>In an earlier Words and Their Stories program, we explained how to use the expression <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.51voa.com/a/when-does-a-problem-snowball-/7398657.html">snowball effect</a> to describe a situation where one action or event causes many other similar actions or events.</p>
<p>Are you thinking that there must be many more English expressions related to snow, ice, and cold weather? You are right! The term "snowball effect" is just the <u>tip of the iceberg</u>!</p>
<p>Or, to put it another way, we have many more expressions in American English related to the cold weather. So, today we will explore some winter words and expressions.</p>
<p>In the <u>dead of winter</u>, many people like to skate on frozen lakes. But watch out! You don't want to <u>skate on thin ice</u>. That is dangerous. If it breaks you could fall into the cold, dark water below. You could even drown.</p>
<p>So, the expression <u>skating on thin ice</u> serves as a warning. For example, if a friend is always late to work, you might tell him he is <u>skating on thin ice</u> with his employer.</p>
<p>But, you might not want to say anything to your friend. Maybe it is none of your business when your friend arrives at work. So, you decide to <u>put your warning on ice.</u></p>
<p>To <u>put something on ice</u> means to suspend action on something – a temporary halt. In fact, today a co-worker asked me to <u>put my project on ice</u>, so I would have time to help her with today's lesson.</p>
<p>When we put food on ice we <strong>preserve</strong> its quality for a time. We can wait to eat it later and it will still be good.</p>
<p>What about when we <u>break the ice</u>, though? That sounds dangerous, right? However, it just means reaching out personally to a stranger. Like in this example:</p>
<p><em>A: Hi Matt. Have you met our new teacher, Jennifer?</em></p>
<p><em>B: No. Not yet.</em></p>
<p><em>A: Why don't you <u>break the ice</u> and <strong>introduce</strong> yourself this afternoon?</em></p>
<p><em>B: I certainly will.</em></p>
<p>Ice is not all we might face in winter. Sometimes the snow is so deep we cannot even get out of the house. At those times, you might say there is a <u>snowball's chance in hell</u> I'm leaving home today.</p>
<p>Hell is fiery and extremely hot. A snowball has no chance at survival there. So, the expression describes something that is impossible.</p>
<p>Now that we are stuck inside the house, we say we are <u>snowbound</u> or <u>snowed under</u>. And we often use <u>snowed under</u> to describe a situation in which we have too much work to do.</p>
<p>American children usually love a <u>snow day</u>! That phrase is used to mean schools are closed. Students might spend the day outdoors throwing <u>snowballs</u> or building a <u>snowman</u>. Or maybe they stay inside, covered up in a warm blanket next to a hot fire, <u>snug as a bug in a rug</u>.</p>
<p>We use the expression <u>snug as a bug in a rug</u> to describe a soft, warm and safe position or situation.</p>
<p>Sounds like a great place to be, especially during a snow storm. I mean, no one wants to be <u>left out in the cold</u>. That can really hurt, physically and emotionally!</p>
<p>Sometimes we use this phrase, <u>left out in the cold</u>, when someone has rejected or forgotten us.</p>
<p>We will never leave English learners <u>out in the cold</u>, to be sure! Especially not in <u>the dead of winter!</u></p>
<p>And that's <em>Words and Their Stories</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>__________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>preserve</strong> - v. to keep something in its original state or in good condition</p>
<p><strong>introduce</strong> - v. to make someone known to someone else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Kenya Moving Rhinos to New Home  (2024/1/28)</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/kenya-moving-rhinos-to-new-home.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">27 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Kenya began its biggest rhino <strong>relocation</strong> project earlier this month. Workers began the difficult work of moving 21 of the <strong>endangered</strong> animals to a new home. They each weigh around one metric ton.</p>
<p>A previous attempt at moving rhinos in the East African nation was a disaster in 2018. All 11 of the animals died.</p>
<p>The latest project experienced early troubles. A rhino targeted for moving was successfully hit with a <strong>tranquilizer</strong> shot from a helicopter but ended up in a creek. Veterinarians and park rangers held the rhino's head above water with a rope to save it while a tranquilizer <strong>reversal</strong> drug took effect. It was then released.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Kenya Wildlife Service rangers and capture team pull out a sedated black rhino from the water in Nairobi National Park, Kenya Tuesday, Jan. 16, 2024. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-36ae-08dc1dc5a57f_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Kenya Wildlife Service rangers and capture team pull out a sedated black rhino from the water in Nairobi National Park, Kenya Tuesday, Jan. 16, 2024. (AP Photo/Brian Inganga)</span></div>
<p>Wildlife officials have said that the difficult project will take time, likely weeks.</p>
<p>The black rhinos are a mix of males and females. They are being moved from three conservation parks to the private Loisaba Conservancy in central Kenya, the Kenya Wildlife Service said. They are being moved because there are too many in the three parks. They need more space to <strong>roam</strong> and, hopefully, to breed.</p>
<p>Rhinos generally spend time alone and are at their happiest in large territories.</p>
<p>Kenya has had some success in saving its black rhino population. In the mid-1980s the rhino population fell below 300 because of <strong>poaching</strong>, raising fears that the animals might go <strong>extinct</strong> in a country famous for its wildlife.</p>
<p>Kenya now has nearly 1,000 black rhinos, says the wildlife service. That is the third biggest black rhino population in the world behind South Africa and Namibia.</p>
<p>There are just 6,487 wild rhinos left in the world, says rhino conservation group Save The Rhino. All live in Africa.</p>
<p>Kenyan officials say they have relocated more than 150 rhinos in the last 10 years or so.</p>
<p>Six years ago, Kenya moved 11 rhinos from the capital, Nairobi, to another <strong>sanctuary</strong> in the south of the country. All died soon after arriving at the sanctuary. Ten of them died from <strong>stress</strong>, lack of water and starvation, which was worsened by salt poisoning as they struggled with saltier water in their new home, investigations found. The other rhino was attacked by a lion.</p>
<p>Some of the 21 rhinos in the latest relocation are from Nairobi National Park. They will make a 300-kilometer trip in the back of a truck to Loisaba. Others will come from parks closer to Loisaba.</p>
<p>Loisaba was once home to a healthy black rhino population before they were wiped out in that area 50 years ago, said Loisaba Conservancy CEO Tom Silvester.</p>
<p>Kenyan wildlife officials say the country is aiming to grow its black rhino population to about 2,000. They believe 2,000 would be the best number considering the space available for them in national and private parks.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>relocation </strong><em>— v. </em>to move to a new place</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>endanger </strong><em>— v. </em>to cause to be in a dangerous place or situation</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>tranquilizer </strong><em>— n. </em>a drug that causes a person or animal to become very relaxed and calm</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>reverse </strong><em>— v. </em>to change to an opposite state or condition</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>roam </strong><em>— v. </em>to go to different places without having a particular purpose or plan</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>poach </strong><em>— v. </em>to catch or kill an animal illegally</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>extinct </strong><em>— adj. </em>no longer existing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>sanctuary </strong><em>— n. </em>a place where someone or something is protected or given shelter</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stress </strong><em>— n. </em> something that causes strong feelings of worry or anxiety</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Thailand Aims for Lithium Production  (2024/1/28) | 泰国意图生产锂产品</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/thailand-aims-for-lithium-production.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content"><p>Thailand hopes to start producing lithium from a mine in its southwest in about two years, government and business officials say.<br/>
泰国政府和企业官员表示，泰国希望在大约两年内开始从西南部的一个矿场生产出锂。</p>
<p>The mine could help the country become a center for electric vehicle (EV) production.<br/>
该矿可以帮助该国成为电动汽车生产中心。</p>
<p>Lithium is a metal critical to EV battery production.<br/>
锂是生产电动汽车电池的关键金属。</p>
<p>Establishing lithium mines would put Thailand in a special position among major producers of the metal because the country is also developing an EV production industry. Chinese carmakers already promised to invest $1.44 billion in that industry in Thailand.<br/>
建立锂矿将使泰国在该金属的主要生产国中处于特殊地位，因为该国也在发展电动汽车生产行业。中国汽车制造商已经承诺在泰国向该行业投资14.4亿美元。</p>
<p>The Australian company Miner Pan Asia Metals is preparing to register for mining permits in March for the Reung Kiet project. The project is taking place in the country's Phang-Nga area. The property could also include the proposed Bang I Tum mine.<br/>
澳大利亚公司泛亚金属正准备在3月份为良杰项目注册采矿许可证。该项目正在泰国攀牙府进行。该项目还可能包括拟建的Bang I Tum矿场。</p>
<p>Pan Asia's leader Paul Lock told Reuters that the company is "optimistic" about starting lithium chemical production from Reung Kiet by early 2026.<br/>
泛亚金属董事长保罗 · 洛克对路透社表示，该公司对2026年初开始从良杰项目生产锂化工产品持“乐观”态度。</p>
<p>Thailand's Department of Primary Industries and Mines (DPIM) predicts that the Reung Kiet site could produce about 164,500 tonnes of the metal.<br/>
泰国初级工业和矿业部预测，良杰矿场可能生产约16.45万吨锂。</p>
<p>That would be enough to produce at least 1 million EV batteries of 50 kilowatt-hours, said DPIM Director General Aditad Vasinonta.<br/>
泰国基础工业和矿业部部长阿迪塔德·瓦西农塔表示，这将足以生产至少100万个容量为50千瓦时的电动汽车电池。</p>
<p>The official said mining could begin there in about two years.<br/>
这位官员说大约两年后那里就可以开始采矿了。</p>
<p>And, Pan Asia's Paul Lock says the mineral resources at Bang I Tum may be 10 to 70 percent larger than Reung Kiet.<br/>
泛亚金属的保罗 · 洛克表示，Bang I Tum矿场的矿产资源可能比良杰矿场高出10%到70%。</p>
<p>Experts do not know how much reachable lithium exists in Thailand. Major suppliers of the metal include Australia, Argentina, Chile, and China.<br/>
专家们不知道泰国有多少可开采的锂。该金属的主要供应商包括澳大利亚、阿根廷、智利和中国。</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Center of production<br/>
生产中心</span></p>
<p>Thailand is Southeast Asia's largest automobile producer and exporter. It wants EVs to account for 30 percent of its yearly automobile production by 2030.<br/>
泰国是东南亚最大的汽车生产国和出口国。它希望到2030年，电动汽车占其汽车年产量的30%。</p>
<p>Narit Therdsteerasukdi is Secretary General of the Thailand Board of Investment. He said the government has supported 38 battery production projects, including those for EV use, with total investment at $659.4 million.<br/>
纳立·特萨提拉沙是泰国投资委员会秘书长。他表示，政府已支持38个包括电动汽车用途的电池生产项目，总投资为6.594亿美元。</p>
<p>"Our goal is to push Thailand to become the regional hub for battery production, both for EV and for energy storage," he said.<br/>
他说：“我们的目标是推动泰国成为电动汽车和储能电池生产的区域中心。”</p>
<p>A regional hub is an important center of activity for a part of the world.<br/>
区域中心是全球部分地区的重要活动中心。</p>
<p>The Thai government is also pushing for lithium exploration in new areas. That includes changing laws to permit private companies to study agricultural lands, Aditad said.<br/>
泰国政府也在推动在新的地区进行锂勘探。阿迪塔德说，这包括修改法律，允许私营公司调查农业用地。</p>
<p>One of the interested companies is Matsa Resources, an Australian miner looking for lithium in Thailand.<br/>
澳大利亚矿业公司麦莎资源就是其中一家感兴趣的公司，该公司正在泰国寻找锂。</p>
<p>Matsa holds two special permits to look for lithium in Thailand. And it has over 100 requests waiting, it said in January.<br/>
麦莎资源持有两张在泰国寻找锂的特别许可证。该公司在1月份表示，目前有100多个申请在等待处理。</p>
<p>"They will be only one of a handful of countries that have got the whole supply chain from mining to production within the same country," said Paul Poli, Matsa's leader.<br/>
麦莎资源董事长保罗·波利表示：“泰国将是少数几个在国内拥有从采矿到生产的整个供应链的国家之一。”</p>
<p>The lithium under exploration in Thailand is found within a mineral known as lepidolite. It is more costly to process than the kind of lithium mined in Australia and Chile.<br/>
泰国正在勘探的锂是在一种被称为锂云母的矿物中发现的。它的加工成本比澳大利亚和智利开采的锂更高。</p>
<p>Matsa and Pan Asia said they are in discussions with Chinese companies to process the lepidolite mineral. Chinese companies have experience producing lithium from lepidolite in Jiangxi province.<br/>
麦莎资源和泛亚金属表示，他们正在与中国公司商讨加工锂云母矿。中国企业在江西省拥有利用锂云母生产锂的经验。</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.<br/>
我是格雷戈里·施塔赫尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Scientists Map Largest Deep-Sea Coral Reef off US Atlantic Coast  (2024/1/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/scientists-map-largest-deep-sea-coral-reef-off-us-atlantic-coast.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Scientists have mapped the largest <strong>coral reef</strong> off America's Atlantic coast.</p>
<p>Researchers say the reef stretches about 500 kilometers from Florida to South Carolina. At some points, it is 109 kilometers wide. The researchers measured the reef using <strong>3D</strong> mapping technology.</p>
<p>"It's eye-opening – it's breathtaking in <strong>scale</strong>," Stuart Sandin told The Associated Press. He is a marine biologist at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography. Sandin was not included in the research.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this image provided by NOAA Ocean Exploration, an alfonsino fish swims on a cold water coral mound in the center of the Blake Plateau off the southeastern coast of the U.S., in June 2019.(NOAA Ocean Exploration via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-2072-08dc1c22603c_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this image provided by NOAA Ocean Exploration, an alfonsino fish swims on a cold water coral mound in the center of the Blake Plateau off the southeastern coast of the U.S., in June 2019.(NOAA Ocean Exploration via AP)</span></div>
<p>Ocean scientists have known since the 1960s that some coral life was present off the Atlantic Coast. But the reef's exact size had remained a mystery. New underwater mapping technology made it possible to construct images of the ocean floor in three dimensions.</p>
<p>The largest yet known deep coral reef "has been right under our noses, waiting to be discovered," said Derek Sowers. He is an oceanographer at the nonprofit group <a class="wsw__a" href="https://nautiluslive.org/">Ocean Exploration Trust</a>.</p>
<p>Sowers and other scientists recently released maps of the reef in the publication <em>Geomatics</em>.</p>
<p>The reef was found at ocean depths from 200 to 1,000 meters. Deep-sea life cannot use sunlight to carry out <strong>photosynthesis</strong>. Instead, reef corals at extreme depths must <strong>filter</strong> food particles out of the water for energy.</p>
<p>Deep coral reefs are known to contain animals such as sharks, swordfish, sea stars, octopus, shrimp and many kinds of fish.</p>
<p>Unlike deep coral reefs, tropical reefs are better known to scientists and sea explorers alike because they are easier to reach. The world's largest tropical coral reef system, Australia's Great Barrier Reef, stretches for 2,300 kilometers.</p>
<p>Sowers said it is possible larger deep-sea reefs will be discovered in the future since only about 25 percent of the world's ocean floor has been mapped in 3D. Only 50 percent of U.S. offshore waters have been mapped. Maps of the ocean floor are created using high-technology sound equipment, called sonar, on ships.</p>
<p>Erik Cordes is a marine biologist at Temple University and a co-writer of a study on the mapping operation. He said deep reefs cover more of the ocean floor than tropical reefs. But both are currently facing similar risks, including climate change and damage from oil and gas exploration activities</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press reported this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the report for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>_____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>coral </strong><em>– n. </em>a hard, usually pink or white substance produced by a type of small sea animal</p>
<p><strong>reef </strong><em>– n. </em>a collection of rocks or sand that sits below the surface of the ocean</p>
<p><strong>3D (three dimensional) </strong>–adj. showing the height, width and length of something rather than just two dimensions</p>
<p><strong>scale </strong><em>– n. </em>the size or level of something</p>
<p><strong>photosynthesis </strong><em>– n. </em>the process by which a plant uses carbon dioxide from the air, water from the ground, and the energy from the light of the sun to produce its own food and oxygen</p>
<p><strong>filter </strong><em>– v. </em>to pass a substance through a piece of equipment in order to remove solid pieces or other substances</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>2024 Academy Award Nominees: Surprises, Snubs and Fun Facts  (2024/1/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/academy-award-nominees-surprises-snubs-and-fun-facts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Caty Weaver</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences on Tuesday announced the nominees for Hollywood's highest movie awards --- the Oscars. As usual, there were surprises. And there were snubs, meaning filmmakers or films that were rejected as candidates. Here are some of the facts about this year's nominees.</p>
<p><strong>Fostering the Oscars</strong></p>
<p>Actor Jodie Foster was nominated for her performance in a supporting role in the film <em>Nyad</em>. It is her fifth nomination. The first came 47 years ago when she was just 14 years old.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - An Oscar statue appears outside the Dolby Theatre for the 87th Academy Awards in Los Angeles on February 21, 2015. (Photo by Matt Sayles/Invision/AP, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/23dac5d6-fa99-4d71-b4b5-25bc323a2275_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - An Oscar statue appears outside the Dolby Theatre for the 87th Academy Awards in Los Angeles on February 21, 2015. (Photo by Matt Sayles/Invision/AP, File)</span></div>
<p>This year she returns as a nominee after an unusually long absence from the Oscars. Her last nomination was for <em>Nell</em> in 1995.</p>
<p>Foster has won two Academy Awards as a lead actor. Her first came in 1989 for the movie <em>The Accused</em>. She won again in 1992 for the film <em>The Silence of the Lambs</em>. Her costar in <em>Nyad</em>, Annette Bening, is also nominated for an Oscar in the best performance by a lead actress <strong>category</strong>. Like Foster, Bening has been nominated four other times. But she has yet to win any Academy Awards.</p>
<p>Foster has more nominations than the rest of the actors in her category combined. Emily Blunt, Danielle Brooks, America Ferrera and Da'Vine Joy Randolph are all first-time nominees.</p>
<p>Foster's <strong>gap</strong> between nominations is not a record, though. Last year, actor Judd Hirsch got his first nomination in 42 years for his performance in <em>The Fabelmans</em>.</p>
<p><strong>John Williams dials in on Disney with ‘destiny'</strong></p>
<p>Music writer, or composer, John Williams, is back in the running for an Oscar. The 91-year-old became on Tuesday the oldest nominee in history for his <strong>original score</strong> for <em>Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny</em>. Williams broke the age record of 90 set last year by nominee John Williams.</p>
<p>The composer has been nominated for 54 Academy Awards. He is the most Oscar-nominated living person. He needs six more to overtake Walt Disney's record of 59 nominations.</p>
<p>Williams has won five Oscars. His last was in 1994 for the score of <em>Schindler's List</em>, which also won the award for best picture.</p>
<p><strong>Women's films honored, women snubbed</strong></p>
<p>A record three films directed by women were nominated for best picture: <em>Barbie</em> from Greta Gerwig, <em>Anatomy of a Fall</em> from Justine Triet, and <em>Past Lives</em> from Celine Song.</p>
<p>But only one of them – Triet – received a best director nomination.</p>
<p>Gerwig's snub, along with <em>Barbie</em> star Margot Robbie's in the best actress category, were widely protested after the nominations were announced Tuesday. But each is still in the larger group of nominees. Robbie is a producer who will get an Oscar if <em>Barbie</em> wins best picture. And Gerwig is nominated for best adapted screenplay.</p>
<p><strong>The spirit of Spielberg and scores for Scorsese</strong></p>
<p>Director Steven Spielberg was a 2024 Oscar presence even on a year off. Spielberg did not direct a movie last year that met time limits for Academy Award consideration. However, he is nominated as a producer of the movie <em>Maestro</em>.</p>
<p>If it wins best picture, Spielberg will take home his fourth Oscar.</p>
<p>Martin Scorsese, meanwhile, broke Spielberg's record on director nominations. Scorsese is nominated this year for the movie <em>The Killers of the Flower Moon</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p>Caty Weaver<em> adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><strong>__________________________________________</strong></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>category </strong>– <em>n. </em>one of the divisions or groupings used in a system of classification</p>
<p><strong>gap</strong> – <em>n. </em>a space or separation <strong>: </strong>a break in continuity</p>
<p><strong>original score </strong>– <em>n. </em> music that is written and tailored for use throughout a film</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>245,000 Holocaust Survivors Are Still Alive  (2024/1/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/holocaust-survivors-are-still-alive.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Almost 80 years after the Holocaust, about 245,000 Jewish survivors are still living across more than 90 countries.</p>
<p>A new report found that 49 percent of them are living in Israel. Eighteen percent live in Western Europe, 16 percent in the United States, and 12 percent in countries of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>The Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against Germany, also called the Claims Conference, which is based in New York City, carried out the study.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="95-year-old Ruth Winkelmann, who is one of the survivors of the Holocaust, looks out of a window in Berlin, Germany, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-0093-08dc1dbf9d9a_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">95-year-old Ruth Winkelmann, who is one of the survivors of the Holocaust, looks out of a window in Berlin, Germany, Wednesday, Jan. 17, 2024. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi)</span></div>
<p>Before the publication of the report, there were only general estimates about how many Holocaust survivors are still alive.</p>
<p>Their numbers are quickly falling. Most are very old and often in poor health, with a median age of 86. Twenty percent of survivors are older than 90, with more women (61 percent) than men (39 percent) still alive.</p>
<p>The report is called "Holocaust Survivors Worldwide. A Demographic Overview." It says 96 percent of survivors are "child survivors." That means they were born after 1928. Information in the report is based on numbers collected up until August 2023.</p>
<p>"The numbers in this report are interesting, but it is also important to look past the numbers to see the individuals they represent," said Greg Schneider. He is the Claims Conference's executive vice president.</p>
<p>Six million European Jews and people from other minorities were killed by the Nazis and their supporters during the Holocaust.</p>
<p>It is not clear exactly how many Jews survived the Holocaust. But their numbers were far smaller than the Jewish population in Europe before World War II. 3.3 million Jews lived in Poland in 1939. Only about 300,000 survived.</p>
<p>About 560,000 Jews lived in Germany in 1933, the year Adolf Hitler came to power. At the end of World War II in 1945, their numbers had fallen to about 15,000 — through <strong>emigration</strong> and murder.</p>
<p>Germany's Jewish community grew after 1990. More than 215,000 Jewish migrants and their families moved to Germany from countries of the former Soviet Union. Some of them were also survivors. The report said that 14,200 survivors still live in Germany.</p>
<p>One of them is Ruth Winkelmann. She survived by hiding with her mother and sister in a garden <strong>shed</strong> in northern Berlin. Her father was killed in the Auschwitz death camp. Her younger sister Esther died of illness, hunger, and <strong>exhaustion</strong> in March 1945, just weeks before the Soviet Red Army entered Berlin.</p>
<p>Winkelmann is 95 and still lives in Berlin. She said there has not been a day in her life when she did not remember her father.</p>
<p>For its new report, the Claims Conference said it defined Holocaust survivors "based on agreements with the German government in assessing <strong>eligibility</strong> for <strong>compensation</strong> programs."</p>
<p>For Germany, that definition includes all Jews who lived in the country from January 30, 1933, when Hitler came to power, to May 1945. That is when Germany surrendered in World War II.</p>
<p>The group deals with claims for Jews who suffered under the Nazis and negotiates compensation with Germany's finance ministry every year. Since 1952, the German government has paid more than $90 billion to individuals for suffering and losses resulting from the Nazis.</p>
<p>The Claims Conference has also launched several educational projects to pass on survivors' stories to younger generations.</p>
<p>Gideon Taylor is president of the Claims Conference. He said the data the group gathered "not only tells us how many and where survivors are, it clearly indicates that most survivors are at a period of life where their need for care and services is growing."</p>
<p>"Now is the time to <strong>double down</strong> on our attention on this <strong>waning</strong> population. Now is when they need us the most."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Kirsten Grieshaber reported this story for the Associated Press. Dan Novak adapted it for VOA Learning English with additional materials including the report.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emigration </strong>–to leave a country to live somewhere else</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>shed </strong><em>— n. </em>a small building mainly used for storage</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>exhaustion </strong><em>— n. </em>a condition of being very tired</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>eligible </strong><em>— adj. </em>to be able the receive or do something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>compensate </strong><em>— v. </em>to provide something of value especially for someone's hardship or difficulty</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>double down </strong><em>— v.</em>to continue to do something in a more determined way<em> </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>wane </strong><em>— v. </em>to become less, smaller, or less strong over time</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Meanings of 'As'  (2024/1/27)</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/meanings-of-as.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gena Bennett</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">26 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Hello! This week on <em>Ask a Teacher</em>, we answer a question from Bill in China about the word "as."</p>
<p><strong>Question</strong></p>
<p>Dear VOA,</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Ask a Teacher: Meanings of 'as'" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-6c54-08dc1db20f13_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Ask a Teacher: Meanings of 'as'</span></div>
<p>Thank you for your high quality American English teaching!</p>
<p>The following sentence is from one of your recent news, and I can't understand <strong>a bit</strong> of it. Would you like to help me?</p>
<p><em>And the comedy "Poor Things" <strong>upset</strong> summer hit "Barbie," as Hollywood threw its biggest party since labor disputes shut down much of show business last year.</em></p>
<p>To be <strong>precise</strong>, I can't understand the part after "as Hollywood..."</p>
<p>I think "as Hollywood..." might be a reason to describe the part before.</p>
<p>Thanks a lot.</p>
<p>Yours sincerely,</p>
<p>Bill YANG from Beijing, China</p>
<p><strong>Answer</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for writing, Bill. This is a very good question. The word "as" has many meanings and uses in English. In your example, "as" is a subordinator. Subordinators are used to join two <strong>clauses</strong> and add information.</p>
<p>In this sentence, "as" shows that the events were happening at the same time. The movie "Poor Things" upset the movie "Barbie" at the same time that Hollywood threw its biggest party. Both things happened at the Golden Globes earlier this month.</p>
<p>In addition to meaning "at the same time," "as" can be used to establish a reason.</p>
<p><em>I don't need to write it down, <u>as I trust myself</u>.</em></p>
<p>"I trust myself" is the reason I don't need to write it down.</p>
<p>"As" can also be used to point to the future. For example:</p>
<p><em><u>As you're coming to the station</u>, you'll see a pub in front of you.</em></p>
<p>In this sentence, "as" points to a future time.</p>
<p>"As" is often used as a subordinator in many longer phrases. These phrases include "as long as", "as soon as", "as far as".</p>
<p>There are many other ways to use "as" in a sentence. It can be a preposition, part of a prepositional verb, and used with adjectives or adverbs for comparison. But we can talk about those meanings another time.</p>
<p>We hope this explanation helps you understand the meaning of "as" in your example, Bill.</p>
<p>Do you have a question about American English? Send us an email at learningenglish@voanews.com.</p>
<p>And that's <em>Ask a Teacher</em>.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Gena Bennett wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>a bit</strong>—<em>adv</em>. a little, a small amount</p>
<p><strong>precise</strong>–<em>adj</em>. exact</p>
<p><strong>upset</strong> –<em>v</em>. to push out of place</p>
<p><strong>clause</strong>–<em>n</em>. a group of words with a verb</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Japan’s Moon Lander Hits Its Target  (2024/1/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/japan-s-moon-lander-hits-its-target.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency, or JAXA, said Thursday that its first lunar <strong>mission</strong> landed within 100 meters of its target over the weekend.</p>
<p>Japan became the fifth country to reach the moon when the Smart Lander for Investigating Moon, or SLIM, touched down on the moon early on Saturday. But trouble with the spacecraft's power system made it difficult to know whether it landed in the target area at first.</p>
<p>Earlier moon landers targeted landing areas as large as 10 kilometers. However, with its improved <strong>accuracy</strong>, Japan's SLIM aimed at a target area of just 100 meters.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="This image provided by the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) shows an image of a robotic moon rover called Smart Lander for Investigating Moon, or SLIM, on the moon. (JAXA/Takara Tomy/Sony Group Corporation/Doshisha University via AP)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-17dc-08dc1dc790ed_cx0_cy5_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">This image provided by the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) shows an image of a robotic moon rover called Smart Lander for Investigating Moon, or SLIM, on the moon. (JAXA/Takara Tomy/Sony Group Corporation/Doshisha University via AP)</span></div>
<p>Shinichiro Sakai is JAXA's project leader for the lander. He said, "We proved that we can land wherever we want." Sakai hoped that it would bring more missions "to try to land on unexplored places on the moon."</p>
<p>One of the lander's two main engines stopped working during the landing, causing SLIM to move 55 meters away from the target area to another position, Sakai said. Without engine trouble, he said SLIM could have landed as close as three to four meters from the target. However, the spacecraft could not produce power after landing. JAXA scientists said its <strong>solar panels</strong> might be facing the wrong direction.</p>
<p>JAXA said it received all data about the touchdown within the two hours and 37 minutes before the lander lost power. Officials said there is still hope the craft will be able to <strong>recharge</strong> when that side of the moon enters daytime in the coming days.</p>
<p>The power outage meant the lander's camera could only capture low-<strong>resolution</strong> images, JAXA said.</p>
<p><strong>Moon sniper</strong></p>
<p>The goal of landing within a target area of less than 100 meters led scientists to call SLIM the "moon sniper."</p>
<p>It used "vision-based" guidance that JAXA says could be a powerful tool for future exploration of the moon's mountainous areas. These areas might hold resources of fuel, water and oxygen.</p>
<p>Japan follows the United States, the former Soviet Union, China and India as nations reaching the moon's surface. The mission was the result of 20 years of work on <strong>precision</strong> technology by JAXA.</p>
<p>JAXA has experience with difficult space landings. Its Hayabusa2 spacecraft, launched in 2014, touched down twice on the 900-meter-long <strong>asteroid</strong> Ryugu. Hayabusa2 collected material that was returned to Earth for scientific research in 2020.</p>
<p>In the past year, three lunar missions have failed. One by Russia's space agency; one by a private Japanese company and another by a private U.S. company. However, more lunar landers will head to the moon this year.</p>
<p>U.S. company Intuitive Machines aims to launch its IM-1 lander in mid-February. China plans to send its Chang'e-6 spacecraft to the far side of the moon in the first half of the year. And the American space agency NASA is planning its lunar polar exploration rover VIPER for November.</p>
<p>I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Hai Do adapted this report for VOA Learning English from Associated Press and Reuters sources. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>mission</strong> <em>–n. </em>a flight of a spacecraft aimed at a specific goal or task</p>
<p><strong>accuracy</strong> <em>–n.</em> the level to which something is free from error</p>
<p><strong>solar panel <em>–</em></strong><em>n.</em> Flat devices that turn sunlight into direct electric current</p>
<p><strong>recharge </strong>–v. to process of adding electrical charge to a battery or device that stores electricity</p>
<p><strong>resolution </strong>–n. the level of detail that is visible in an image; the level of accuracy of a measuring device</p>
<p><strong>precision </strong>–n. to level to which something is exact and the way it is supposed to be designed</p>
<p><strong>asteroid </strong>–n. a body orbiting the sun that is smaller than a planet or what some scientists call a dwarf planet</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>US Scientist’s Advice Shocks British Tea Drinkers  (2024/1/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/us-scientist-s-advice-shocks-british-tea-drinkers.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Hai Do</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>An American scientist has started a <u>tempest in a teapot</u> by offering Britain advice on its favorite drink: tea.</p>
<p><u>Tempest in a teapot</u> is an expression to describe a strong, noisy, and angry reaction over something small or unimportant.</p>
<p>Michelle Francl is a chemistry professor at Bryn Mawr College, outside of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She said tea drinkers should add a little salt to make a perfect cup of tea.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - A cup of black tea with a spoon and tea leaves in London, on Aug. 29, 2022. An American scientist has started a tempest in a teapot by offering Britain advice on its favorite drink: tea. (AP Photo/Alastair Grant, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-e722-08dc1dba5fa9_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - A cup of black tea with a spoon and tea leaves in London, on Aug. 29, 2022. An American scientist has started a tempest in a teapot by offering Britain advice on its favorite drink: tea. (AP Photo/Alastair Grant, File)</span></div>
<p>That advice is included in her book <em>Steeped: The Chemistry of Tea</em>. The book was published Wednesday by the Royal Society of Chemistry.</p>
<p>Mixing tea with salt water has never gone well for British-American relations. In 1773, American colonists in Boston, Massachusetts, were angry at Britain for adding more taxes to raise money. So they dumped British tea into the sea. The event became known as the Boston Tea Party. It led to the start of the American Revolution.</p>
<p>Francl's suggestion caused <strong>outrage</strong> among tea lovers in Britain. They see Americans as coffee drinkers who know nothing about tea. And they think if Americans drink tea at all, they just heat water in a <strong>microwave</strong>.</p>
<p>"Don't even say the word ′salt′ to us..." said the <strong>etiquette</strong> guide Debrett's on the social media service X, formerly known as Twitter.</p>
<p>Even the U.S. Embassy in London joined the <u>tempest in a teapot</u>. In a social media post, it promised "the good people of the U.K. [United Kingdom] that the unthinkable notion of adding salt to Britain's national drink is not official United States policy."</p>
<p>"Let us unite in our steeped solidarity and show the world that when it comes to tea, we stand as one," the embassy said in the post. "The U.S. Embassy will continue to make tea in the proper way - by microwaving it," it added.</p>
<p>The embassy later said that the post was "a <strong>lighthearted</strong> play on our shared cultural connections" rather than an official press release.</p>
<p>Francl's book <em>Steeped</em>, however, is no joke. The advice, its publisher said, comes from three years of research and experimentation with more than 100 chemical compounds. The book, the publisher added, "puts the chemistry to use with advice on how to brew a better cup."</p>
<p>Francl said adding a small amount of salt — not enough to taste — makes tea seem less <strong>bitter</strong>. This is because "the sodium ions in salt block the bitter receptors in our mouths," she explained.</p>
<p>She also suggests making tea in a warmed pot, shaking the tea bag around, and serving tea in a short and wide cup to keep the heat. And she says milk should be added to the cup after the tea and not before – another issue that often divides tea lovers.</p>
<p>Francl has been surprised by the reaction to her book in Britain.</p>
<p>"I kind of understood that there would hopefully be a lot of interest," she told <em>The Associated Press</em>. "I didn't know we'd <strong>wade</strong> into a diplomatic conversation with the U.S. Embassy."</p>
<p>I'm Ashley Thompson.</p>
<p><em>Jill Lawless reported this story for The Associated Press. Hai Do adapted the story for Learning English. </em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>outrage</strong> - n. extreme anger, a strong feeling of unhappiness</p>
<p><strong>microwave</strong> - n. kitchen device to cook and heat food using electromagnetic energy</p>
<p><strong>etiquette</strong> - n. rules showing the proper and polite way to behave</p>
<p><strong>lighthearted</strong> - adj. not serious</p>
<p><strong>bitter</strong> - adj. having stong and unpleasant flavor, the opposite of sweet</p>
<p><strong>wade</strong> - v. to become involved in a discussion, situation...</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Croatian Artist Makes Life-size Sculptures with Matchsticks  (2024/1/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/croatian-artist-makes-life-size-sculptures-with-matchsticks.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Gregory Stachel</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Croatian artist Tomislav Horvat is not the first person to make models out of matchsticks, but he might be creating the largest projects.</p>
<p>A matchstick is the short, thin piece of wood that is used to make matches for lighting fire.</p>
<p>Horvat thinks nothing of using 210,000 matchsticks to create a life-size statue, or sculpture, of a musician<strong> </strong>playing on a large piano. The instrument even comes complete with matchstick <strong>strings</strong>.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Tomislav Horvat, 34, inspects a new sculpture of Michelangelo made of matches in Domasinec, Croatia, January 17, 2024. For the last six years, Horvat has been working on the sculpture of Michelangelo and David which will be made of around 430,000 matches. (REUTERS/Antonio Bronic)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/edcab7cb-5146-4403-a099-9732088a818b_cx0_cy7_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Tomislav Horvat, 34, inspects a new sculpture of Michelangelo made of matches in Domasinec, Croatia, January 17, 2024. For the last six years, Horvat has been working on the sculpture of Michelangelo and David which will be made of around 430,000 matches. (REUTERS/Antonio Bronic)</span></div>
<p>But that was not enough for the 34-year-old from the northern village of Domasinec. He is just a year and a half away from completing his version of Michelangelo's sculpture of David.</p>
<p>Michelangelo was a famous Italian artist who lived about 500 years ago. He created a famous marble sculpture of <em>The Bible's</em> King David that is in the city of Florence.</p>
<p>"I need another 30,000 matchsticks to finish it. That is, it'll need about 430,000 in total," he said. "I've been working on it for six years."</p>
<p>Horvat began making small models, but in 2013 he took on a larger project. He decided to create a life-size version of American actor Al Pacino as his celebrated <strong>character</strong> Don Corleone from Francis Ford Coppola's 1972 film <em>The Godfather</em>.</p>
<p>Sculptures that size would collapse without a supporting structure. He creates this additional structure from a material called papier-m<i></i>226;ché or wood.</p>
<p>The Pianist<em> </em>is his second work that is of a large size. His third is Desperate Man, which is made of 54,000 matches and took a year and a half to make.</p>
<p>Horvat has shown his works in <strong>galleries</strong> in Croatia, including the capital Zagreb. But they are not, for now, available to buy.</p>
<p>I'm Gregory Stachel.</p>
<p><em>Antonio Bronic reported this story for Reuters. Gregory Stachel adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>piano </strong>– <em>n</em>. a large musical instrument with a keyboard that you play by pressing black and white keys and that produces sound when small hammers inside the piano hit steel wires</p>
<p><strong>string </strong>– <em>n</em>. a long, thin piece of twisted thread that you use to attach things, tie things together, or hang things</p>
<p><strong>character </strong>– <em>n</em>. a person who appears in a story, book, play, movie, or television show</p>
<p><strong>gallery </strong>– <em>n</em>. a room or building in which people look at paintings or sculptures</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>UN: Taliban Enforcing Restrictions on Single, Unaccompanied Women  (2024/1/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/un-taliban-enforcing-restrictions-on-single-unaccompanied-women.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Friedell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A report from the United Nations says the Taliban are putting more and more restrictions on women in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>The Taliban re-took power in Afghanistan after the United States withdrew from the country in 2021. Taliban leaders said at the time they would permit women to be more involved in work, school and public life than during their previous rule, between 1996 and 2001.</p>
<p>However, the U.N. says the Taliban's Vice and Virtue Ministry is <strong>cracking down</strong> on single and unaccompanied women.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Afghan girls of all ages are permitted to study in religious schools, which are traditionally boys-only, a Taliban official said Thursday Dec. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/6067b961-83d7-4e99-8954-03c6d3d04739_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Afghan girls of all ages are permitted to study in religious schools, which are traditionally boys-only, a Taliban official said Thursday Dec. 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Ebrahim Noroozi, File)</span></div>
<p>In one case, the U.N. notes, the ministry told a woman to get married if she wanted to continue working at a health clinic. The ministry said it was not right for an unmarried woman to have a job.</p>
<p>The restrictions follow a <strong>pattern</strong> of the Taliban breaking their 2021 promise that life in Afghanistan would be more open to women. Girls are not permitted to continue going to school after sixth grade, for example. Places that cut and <strong>style</strong> women's hair have been shut down. And women who are not wearing a hijab, the Islamic head covering, have been arrested.</p>
<p>In May of 2022, the Taliban said women should go back to wearing the religious clothing called a burqa. A burqa is a covering that only shows a woman's eyes.</p>
<p>The U.N.'s Assistance Mission in Afghanistan is reporting on the restrictions. The group's latest report centers on restrictions on women who leave home without a male guardian.</p>
<p>There are no official rules about women needing to be accompanied by a male relative. But the Taliban now say women are not permitted to travel a certain distance away from their home without a man who is either their husband or a relative.</p>
<p>The U.N.'s report said three female healthcare workers were held by police in October when they left home without a guardian. They were only released when their families signed a document saying it would not happen again.</p>
<p>In the Paktia province, the Vice and Virtue Ministry stopped women without guardians from entering health centers starting in December. The men from the ministry are now entering women's health centers to be sure that all women inside are with a male guardian.</p>
<p>The <strong>Vice</strong> and <strong>Virtue</strong> Ministry is also known as the Taliban's "<strong>morality</strong> police." Ministry workers have been going to bus stations, education centers and other public places to make sure women are following their rules. They are looking for women who are not wearing head coverings and stopping buses to make sure women are not traveling without a male family member.</p>
<p>Women are also being arrested for purchasing birth control, which the Taliban have not officially banned.</p>
<p>Zabihullah Mujahid is the spokesman for the Taliban. In a statement, he said the U.N. report is filled with misunderstandings. He said the U.N. is ignoring or criticizing Islamic law, known as Shariah.</p>
<p>Mujahid added that the Islamic government in power in Afghanistan must fully observe "all <strong>aspects</strong> of Sharia for both men and women."</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.</p>
<p><em>Dan Friedell adapted this story for Learning English based on a report by the Associated Press.</em></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>crack down </strong>–v. to tighten restrictions and punish people for breaking rules</p>
<p><strong>vice </strong>–n. something seen as bad or immoral behavior</p>
<p><strong>virtue </strong>– <em>n. </em>good behavior or character</p>
<p><strong>pattern </strong>– <em>n. </em>a path or instruction that is repeated over time</p>
<p><strong>style </strong>– <em>v. </em>to create something in a way that is new or current or fashionable</p>
<p><strong>morality </strong>– <em>adj. </em>a belief about what is right and wrong</p>
<p><strong>aspects </strong>– <em>n. </em>parts of something, such as life</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Population, Overpopulation, Underpopulation  (2024/1/26)</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/population-overpopulation-underpopulation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">25 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Imagine you want to talk about the people in your country or in the world. In other words, you want to talk about a population.</p>
<p>How might you do so?</p>
<p>In today's <em>Everyday Grammar</em>, we will explore the noun "population." You will learn important ideas about the term and how to use it in everyday situations.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-396d-08dc1db9d60a_w268_r1.png"/><br/><span class="imagecaption"></span></div>
<p>Let's start with a visit to the <strong>dictionary</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Population vs. populate </strong></p>
<p>If you look in a dictionary, you might wonder about two words that seem closely related. We have the noun "population" and the verb "populate."</p>
<p>Is it important to know about the verb "populate," you might ask?</p>
<p>Google Ngram Viewer permits us to examine words and <strong>phrases </strong>in thousands of books. We can get a good idea of how often individual words and structures are used.</p>
<p>When we examine the frequency of "population" and compare it to that of "populate," we reach a clear finding: the noun "population" is much more commonly used.</p>
<p>Another way to understand the idea is this: you are much more likely to hear "population" in everyday situations.</p>
<p><strong>Countable noun </strong></p>
<p>Population is a noun meaning the number of people, animals, or other living things of a kind in an area.</p>
<p>We commonly use "population" as a countable noun. In other words, you can add an –s to the end of "population" to get the plural form "populations."</p>
<p>So, you might hear or read the singular form "population," as in:</p>
<p><em>Experts expect the world's population to increase by a very small amount over the next year. </em></p>
<p>We use the singular form because we are talking about all the people who live in the world – one very large group!</p>
<p>How might we use the plural form? In this case, we might use other terms to clarify that we are talking about different groups. For example, you might read or hear something like this:</p>
<p><em>Elderly and overweight populations face greater risk from the illness. </em></p>
<p>In this case, we use the plural form "populations" because we are talking about all of the members of two separate groups – elderly people and overweight people.</p>
<p>Now that we have explored the noun "population," we should consider the word in terms of broader language situations.</p>
<p><strong>Words before and after </strong></p>
<p>How do we commonly use the word "population" in everyday speech?</p>
<p>Let's start by examining the most commonly used words that come before and after "population."</p>
<p>Since "population" is a noun, we might expect that determiners – words that tell us if a noun is general or <strong>specific</strong> – should be commonly used before it.</p>
<p>Google's Ngram Viewer tell us that the word "the" is the most commonly used word before "population."</p>
<p>So, you are very likely to hear or read something like this:</p>
<p><em>Experts said the population declined by 1 percent. </em></p>
<p>And what about the most commonly used word after the noun "population?"</p>
<p>We find that the short word "of" is the most common by far.</p>
<p>So, you are very likely to hear or read something like this:</p>
<p><em>The population of Japan is aging quickly. </em></p>
<p><strong>Words connected to population </strong></p>
<p>Over and under are two words that can be attached to population to form a new single word.</p>
<p>Overpopulation describes a situation in which there are too many people.</p>
<p>Underpopulation describes a situation in which there are too few people.</p>
<p>Importantly, we generally use "overpopulation" and "underpopulation" as noncount nouns. In other words, there is no plural form. We do not add an –s to the end of either word.</p>
<p>How might you expect these terms to appear in everyday situations? Here are two examples:</p>
<p><em>Experts predict overpopulation will result in food shortages. </em></p>
<p><em>Experts predict underpopulation will result in labor shortages. </em></p>
<p><strong>Questions </strong></p>
<p>In today's lesson, we explored a useful noun and how to use it in everyday situations.</p>
<p>We will close our lesson with a call to action. Please answer the following questions in an email to <a class="wsw__a" href="mailto:learningenglish@voanews.com" target="_blank">learningenglish@voanews.com</a></p>
<p>What is the population like in your country or city? Is the population increasing or decreasing?</p>
<p>In a future lesson, we can provide feedback on some of the writing that we receive.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>John Russell wrote this lesson for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>dictionary</strong> <em>– n.</em> a reference book that contains words listed in alphabetical order</p>
<p><strong>phrase<em> </em></strong><em>– n.</em> a word or group of words forming a syntactic constituent with a single grammatical function</p>
<p><strong>specific</strong> –<em> n.</em> restricted to a particular individual, situation, relation, or effect</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Deepfake’ of Biden’s Voice Called Early Example of US Election Disinformation  (2024/1/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/deepfake-of-biden-s-voice-called-early-example-of-us-election-disinformation.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A <strong>fake</strong> voice message claiming to be U.S. President Joe Biden was recently sent to voters in an example of possible election disinformation.</p>
<p>The voice message is an example of what is known as a "deepfake." A "deepfake" is a piece of audio or video created to make it appear that people in it are saying or doing things that they never did. Newly developed artificial intelligence (AI) tools make it easier for people to make and publish such content.</p>
<p>The fake voice of Biden was included in a political message sent by telephone directly to voters in the northeastern state of New Hampshire. This marketing method, known as "robocalling," involves a machine that calls large numbers of people to play them a prerecorded message.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="In this file photo, U.S. President Joe Biden speaks in the East Room of the White House, on January 19, 2024,. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci, File)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-c0a8-0242-24ce-08dc1cfcbf42_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">In this file photo, U.S. President Joe Biden speaks in the East Room of the White House, on January 19, 2024,. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci, File)</span></div>
<p>The calls are being investigated by New Hampshire election officials. The state recently held America's first presidential primary contest. Primary elections in the United States usually choose the candidates for the presidential election in November.</p>
<p>It is not known who created the fake audio, which was heard by reporters from several news organizations. In it, Biden seems to try to persuade voters not to take part in the primary.</p>
<p>The voice says, "Voting this Tuesday only enables the Republicans in their <strong>quest</strong> to elect Donald Trump again." The message continues, "Your vote makes a difference in November, not this Tuesday."</p>
<p>Voting in state primaries does not affect a person's vote later in the U.S. presidential election, which is set for November 5, 2024.</p>
<p>The Biden robocalls even included language the U.S. president has often used in the past, specifically the phrase, "What a bunch of malarkey." The phrase is used to describe something foolish, unreasonable or meaningless. The phone message advises listeners to "save your vote for the November election."</p>
<p>It is not known how many people received the call with Biden's voice. Biden did not campaign in New Hampshire and his name was not on the state's primary ballot. This is because his campaign decided to begin the primary process in the state of South Carolina instead. However, a New Hampshire state law requires it to hold the nation's first primary.</p>
<p>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre confirmed the call was "fake and not recorded by the president." The campaign for former President Donald Trump said it was not involved with the call.</p>
<p>The head of Biden's re-election campaign, Julie Chavez Rodriguez, said in a statement the organization was investigating the incident and "actively discussing additional actions to take." Rodriguez said the robocall was a clear attempt "to suppress voting and <strong>deliberately undermine</strong> free and fair elections."</p>
<p>Robert Weissman is head of the nonprofit citizen activist group Public Citizen. He <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.citizen.org/news/new-hampshire-deepfake-of-biden-shows-danger-of-ai-in-elections/">said</a> in a statement the Biden robocall provided fresh evidence that "the political deepfake moment is here." He urged governments to consider passing legislation to limit the use of deepfakes to prevent election "<strong>chaos</strong>."</p>
<p>Deepfakes created with AI technology have already appeared in campaign advertisements in the 2024 presidential race, the Associated Press (AP) reports. The technology has also been used to spread false information during election campaigns across the world, from Slovakia to Indonesia to Taiwan.</p>
<p>Hany Farid is a digital investigations expert at the University of California, Berkeley. He told the AP the Biden robocall demonstrates how AI methods can be "weaponized" in elections. Farid added that recent cases of audio and video used to mislead voters "is surely a sign of things to come."</p>
<p>As AI technologies improve, governments around the world are seeking ways to restrict them from causing public harm. The U.S. Congress has yet to pass legislation to limit the use of such technologies in the political process. The Federal Election Commission is currently considering public comments on a <strong>petition</strong> for it to restrict AI-created deepfakes in campaign advertisements.</p>
<p>David Becker heads the nonprofit Center for Election Innovation and Research. He told the AP the use of deepfakes is just the latest tool in a long history of "dirty tricks" aimed at influencing the political process.</p>
<p>Becker added that the goal of such efforts can be to <strong>confuse</strong> voters to a point where they no longer recognize false information from the truth. "They don't need to <strong>convince</strong> us that what they're saying, the lies they're telling us, are true," he said. "They just need to convince us that there is no truth, that you can't believe anything you're told."</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from The Associated Press, Reuters and online sources. </em></p>
<p><em>_______________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>fake </strong><em>– adj. </em>false, not true</p>
<p><strong>quest </strong><em>– n. </em>an attempt to get or do something difficult</p>
<p><strong>deliberate </strong><em>– adj. </em>done purposefully, or planned</p>
<p><strong>undermine </strong><em>– v. </em>to lessen the effectiveness or ability of something to move forward</p>
<p><strong>chaos </strong><em>– n. </em>a situation in which there is no order at all</p>
<p><strong>petition </strong><em>– n. </em>to officially ask permission to do something</p>
<p><strong>confuse </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone unable to think clearly or understand something</p>
<p><strong>convince </strong><em>– v. </em>to make someone believe that something is true</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>WHO: Gaza’s Health Care System Collapsing  (2024/1/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/who-gaza-s-health-care-system-collapsing.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A World Health Organization (WHO) official who recently returned from the Gaza Strip said recently that the health care system is collapsing. He said more workers and supplies are needed.</p>
<p>WHO Health Emergency Officer Sean Casey told reporters at the United Nations: "I've seen the health care system collapsing before my eyes."</p>
<p>Casey spent five weeks in Gaza, starting in early December. While there, he met with medical professionals and patients across the territory.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - People inspect the damage in a room following Israeli bombardment at Nasser Hospital in Khan Yunis in the southern Gaza Strip on Dec. 17, 2023. (AFP Photo)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-55bb-08dc00cfb7e0_cx0_cy3_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - People inspect the damage in a room following Israeli bombardment at Nasser Hospital in Khan Yunis in the southern Gaza Strip on Dec. 17, 2023. (AFP Photo)</span></div>
<p>"I saw patients in hospitals every day with severe burns, with open <strong>fractures</strong>, waiting hours or days for care, and they would often ask me for food and water," he said.</p>
<p>Casey said a cease-fire is needed. But he also said the ability to move people and aid supplies safely and quickly within Gaza would help ease suffering.</p>
<p>Reports say Gaza had a strong health care system with 36 hospitals and 25,000 doctors, nurses and specialists before Hamas militants attacked Israel on October 7. Now, the WHO says, about 15 hospitals are partially operating. That makes getting care difficult for the more than 50,000 injured people.</p>
<p>Casey said there is a shortage of supplies but also of workers. Many of them are displaced and struggling to survive and care for their own families.</p>
<p>"There are unbelievably brave health workers across Gaza who are staying and taking care of people because there is no one else to do it," he said.</p>
<p>Casey was in Gaza to see how to bring in more international medical teams.</p>
<p>He said getting supplies to northern Gaza is especially difficult. During the five weeks that he was there, his team was unable to provide supplies to the largest hospital in the north, al-Shifa, for 12 straight days.</p>
<p>At Al-Ahli hospital, also in the north, Casey said the situation was very bad.</p>
<p>"I saw patients who were lying on church <strong>pews</strong>, basically waiting to die in a hospital that had no fuel, no power, no water, very little in the way of medical supplies," he said.</p>
<p>Israel has accused Hamas of stealing aid supplies. Casey said he had not seen evidence of that during his hospital visits.</p>
<p>"I have no evidence of supplies that have been delivered to hospitals going anywhere except to those hospitals," he said.</p>
<p>Dr. Seema Jilani is an emergency health expert with the International Rescue Committee. She returned recently from a two-week visit to Gaza with five British doctors.</p>
<p>Jilani is a children's doctor who has worked in conflict areas including Afghanistan, Iraq and Lebanon. She said, "In my experience of working in conflict <strong>zones</strong> around the world, this is the most extreme situation I have seen in terms of <strong>scale</strong>, severity of injuries, number of children that have suffered that have nothing to do with any of this."</p>
<p>Jilani worked in the emergency room at Al-Aksa Hospital in Deir al-Balah, the only hospital in the middle area of Gaza. Jilani said she treated children who had lost arms and legs and who had extreme burns.</p>
<p>After she left, Jilani said, the hospital ran out of fuel and the lights went out. She does not know what has happened to the babies she treated or whether they have been moved to a safer place.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Margaret Besheer wrote this story for Voice of America. Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English using additional reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>_______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fracture </strong><em>— n. </em>a broken bone</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>pew </strong><em>— n. </em>a long bench used for sitting in a church</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>zone </strong>–n. an area that is different from other usually because something is happening there, or it is being used for a certain purpose</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>scale </strong><em>— n. </em>the level to which something is large or small</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Americans Begin to Feel Better about Economy as Inflation Slows  (2024/1/25) | 美国通胀放缓 美国人对经济感受改善</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/americans-begin-to-feel-better-about-economy-as-inflation-slows.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Life is still more costly in the United States than it was about two years ago. But new research shows Americans are starting to feel better about the economy.<br/>
美国的生活成本仍然比两年前更高。但新的研究表明，美国人对经济的感觉开始好转。</p>
<p>An opinion study by the Federal Reserve Bank of New York found that Americans are increasingly hopeful that the inflation rate will continue to go down. The survey also found that the number of Americans who expect their financial situation to improve within the next year is at its highest since June 2021.<br/>
纽约联邦储备银行的一项民意研究发现，美国人越来越希望通货膨胀率会继续下降。调查还发现，预计明年财务状况会改善的美国人人数达到2021年6月以来的最高水平。</p>
<p>In addition, the University of Michigan's Surveys of Consumers recently reported the largest two-month jump in consumer sentiment since 1991. Consumer sentiment is a measure of how optimistic consumers feel about the economy.<br/>
此外，密歇根大学的消费者调查最近报告了自1991年以来消费者信心两个月来的最大增幅。消费者信心是衡量消费者对经济乐观程度的指标。</p>
<p>That optimism is balanced, however, by the fact that most Americans remember paying much less for daily purchases such as fuel and food only two or three years ago.<br/>
然而，这种乐观情绪是保持平衡的，因为大多数美国人记得，仅仅两三年前，他们为燃料和食品等日常购买支付的费用要少得多。</p>
<p>Many food items such as bread, milk and chicken are more costly than they were in February 2021. But economists say price increases have slowed significantly in the last year. At the same time, Americans are seeing pay increases higher than the rate of inflation.<br/>
面包、牛奶和鸡肉等许多食品的价格比2021年2月更高。但经济学家表示，去年物价上涨明显放缓。与此同时，美国人的工资增长率高于通货膨胀率。</p>
<p>The inflation rate was about 9 percent in June 2022. Today, the rate is 3.4 percent. The U.S. Federal Reserve would like to see the rate at only 2 percent.<br/>
2022年6月的通货膨胀率约为9%。如今，这一比例为3.4%。美国联邦储备委员会希望其仅为2%。</p>
<p>Grace Zwemmer is an analyst at Oxford Economics. She said it took some time for Americans to feel the effects of falling inflation. But, she said, "it appears the good news is finally getting through."<br/>
格蕾丝·泽韦梅尔是牛津经济研究院的分析师。她说，美国人需要一段时间才能感受到通胀下降的影响。但是，她说，“看来好消息终于传来了。”</p>
<p>Political observers wonder if the change in feelings about the economy will help U.S. President Joe Biden's re-election campaign. Will people feel the drop in inflation or will they still remember that prices are much higher than they were two or three years ago?<br/>
政治观察家们想知道，对经济感受的改变是否有助于美国总统乔·拜登的连任竞选。人们会感觉到通货膨胀的下降吗？还是他们还记得物价比两三年前高得多？</p>
<p>Ryan Cummings is an economist who studies how politics affect consumer confidence. He said many Americans today base their feelings about the economy on what they hear from the politicians they support.<br/>
瑞安·卡明斯是一位研究政治如何影响消费者信心的经济学家。他说，今天许多美国人对经济的感受是基于他们所支持的政客讲述的。</p>
<p>Cummings said Republicans are likely to speak negatively about the economic performance during Biden's presidency, even as Democrats speak of the economic gains.<br/>
卡明斯表示，共和党人可能会对拜登总统任期内的经济表现持负面看法，即使民主党人提到经济收益。</p>
<p>The University of Michigan research shows consumer sentiment among Democrats jumped almost 12 percent in January. That is the second-highest increase ever.<br/>
密歇根大学的研究显示，1月份民主党人的消费者信心上升了近12%。这是有史以来第二高的增幅。</p>
<p>Many Americans say they want to see the government take steps to bring the prices of food, oil and meat back to where they were in 2020 or 2021. But economic experts say that is not a good idea. The moves that would be required to make that happen would hurt the economy overall. Taxes could increase and jobs would be lost.<br/>
许多美国人表示，他们希望看到政府采取措施，将食品、石油和肉类价格恢复到2020年或2021年的水平。但经济专家表示，这不是一个好主意。实现这一目标所需的举措将损害整体经济。税收可能会增加，工作岗位可能会流失。</p>
<p>David Andolfatto is an economist at the University of Miami. He used to work for the Federal Reserve. He said the better idea for Americans is to "just move ahead." He explained that while the cost of living is higher than it was two or three years ago, many Americans are making more money than they were then.<br/>
大卫·安迪亚法度是迈阿密大学的经济学家。他曾经在美联储工作。他说，对美国人来说，更好的想法是“向前看”。他解释说，虽然生活成本比两三年前更高，但许多美国人赚的钱也比当时更多。</p>
<p>"There's no need for (the government) to bring the price level back down. It would be too painful," Andolfatto said.<br/>
安迪亚法度说：“（政府）没有必要让物价水平回落。这会太痛苦了。”</p>
<p>Claudia Sahm is another former Federal Reserve economist. She added that "people are angry" because they cannot afford the cost increases.<br/>
克劳迪娅·萨姆是另一位前美联储经济学家。她补充说，“人们很生气”，因为他们负担不起成本增加。</p>
<p>"Can you afford it?" she asked. "Not everybody can say yes to that question. But over time, more and more people will be able to say yes."<br/>
她问道：“你负担得起吗？不是每个人都能对这个问题说是。但随着时间的推移，越来越多的人会有底气说是。”</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Group: ‘Doomsday Clock’ Unchanged at 90 Seconds to Midnight  (2024/1/25)</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/group-doomsday-clock-unchanged-at-90-seconds-to-midnight.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">24 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A nonprofit group called Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists is again bringing attention to crises around the world with its "<strong>Doomsday</strong> Clock."</p>
<p>The group describes the Doomsday Clock as a measure of the risk of worldwide disaster. On Tuesday, the group kept its "clock" set at 90 seconds to midnight, the same position as last year. The group noted Russia's nuclear weapons activities during the Ukraine war, nuclear-armed Israel's war in Gaza and climate change.</p>
<p>The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists considers midnight to be the point of total world destruction. The group says its clock is based on "<strong>existential</strong>" risks to Earth and its people. Those includes nuclear threats, climate change and technologies like artificial intelligence and new biotechnology.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="Rescuers work at a site of a residential building heavily damaged during a Russian missile attack, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine, in Kharkiv, Ukraine January 23, 2024. (REUTERS/Vyacheslav Madiyevskyy)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/66159186-4934-48c6-bb46-d343359b78bc_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">Rescuers work at a site of a residential building heavily damaged during a Russian missile attack, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine, in Kharkiv, Ukraine January 23, 2024. (REUTERS/Vyacheslav Madiyevskyy)</span></div>
<p>Rachel Bronson is the Bulletin's president and CEO. She told Reuters news service that keeping the clock unchanged from the year earlier does not mean that the world is <strong>stable</strong>.</p>
<p>The group said on Tuesday that dangerous <strong>trends</strong> continue to point toward disaster. China, Russia, and the United States are all modernizing their nuclear weapons. The group said that increases the risk of a nuclear war through a mistake or misunderstanding.</p>
<p>Russia's invasion of Ukraine began nearly two years ago and has increased tensions with the West to their highest levels since the Cold War. An "end to Russia's war in Ukraine seems distant, and the use of nuclear weapons by Russia in that conflict remains a serious possibility. In the past year Russia has sent numerous worrying nuclear signals," Bronson said.</p>
<p>Bronson noted Russian President Vladimir Putin's February 2023 decision to suspend Russian involvement in the New START treaty with the United States. That treaty limited the nuclear supplies of the two countries. The United States and Russia together hold almost 90 percent of the world's nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>Bronson also noted Putin's March decision to send nuclear weapons to Belarus and the Russian withdrawal of approval for a treaty banning nuclear tests. Russian expert Sergei Karaganov last year supported threatening to carry out nuclear strikes in Europe to frighten Russia's enemies.</p>
<p>Alexander Glaser of Princeton University is a member of the group's board of experts on nuclear technology and climate science.</p>
<p>"The picture is quite <strong>bleak</strong> on the nuclear side this year," he said.</p>
<p>Nuclear-armed Israel has been at war with Hamas since the Palestinian Islamist group, based in Gaza, launched attacks in southern Israel in October 2023. Bronson said the conflict risks becoming a big war in the Middle East.</p>
<p>Climate change was added as an issue affecting the clock in 2007. Bronson noted that 2023 was the hottest year on record since satellite measurement of temperatures started in 1979. She also said <strong>fossil fuel</strong> <strong>emissions</strong> continue to rise.</p>
<p>Bronson said that 2023 was a record-breaking year for clean energy with $1.7 trillion in new investments. But fossil fuel investments also totaled nearly $1 trillion. Bronson called current efforts to reduce <strong>greenhouse gas</strong> emissions not enough. She said the results of climate change "<strong>disproportionately</strong> affect the poorest people in the world."</p>
<p>The Chicago-based nonprofit created the clock in 1947 at the beginning of the Cold War. The Bulletin was founded in 1945 by a group including scientists Albert Einstein and Robert Oppenheimer.</p>
<p>I'm Caty Weaver.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters.</em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>___________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2"> </h2>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>doomsday </strong><em>— n. </em>the day that the world ends or is destroyed</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>existential </strong><em>— adj. </em>having to do with existence itself</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>stable <em>–</em></strong><em>adj.</em> not likely to change; steady in nature</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>trend <em>–</em></strong><em>n.</em> the direction of change</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>bleak </strong><em>— adj. </em>not hopeful</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>fossil fuel </strong><em>— n. </em>carbon fuels such as oil, natural gas, and coal</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>emission </strong><em>— n. </em>something that is released into the air</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>greenhouse gas </strong><em>–n.</em> a gas that is believed to cause the atmosphere to get warmer</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>disproportionate </strong><em>— adj. </em>affecting one side more than the other</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Defining Plagiarism, How to Avoid It  (2024/1/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/defining-plagiarism-how-to-avoid-it.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Andrew Smith, Jill Robbins, and Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>It has become easy for students to find and copy published material. But copying another person's writing without giving them credit can get students and other scholars into big trouble. Copying another person's writing without crediting them is called plagiarism.</p>
<p>Recently, the leader of Harvard University stepped down over problems related to the use of other peoples' work in her writing.</p>
<p>American <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.copyright.gov/what-is-copyright/">copyright law</a> protects <strong>original</strong> works of <strong>authorship</strong> including books, movies, music, images and artworks. The protection extends to computer software and the design of buildings and structures.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - In this Aug. 13, 2019 file photo, students walk near the Widener Library in Harvard Yard at Harvard University in Cambridge, Mass. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/C6A8EF7E-A9FF-48D9-A135-EE53B3FCCFC8_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - In this Aug. 13, 2019 file photo, students walk near the Widener Library in Harvard Yard at Harvard University in Cambridge, Mass. (AP Photo/Charles Krupa)
</span></div>
<p>The owner can sell a copyright or permit others to use it because it is property and property ownership is protected by law in the U.S.</p>
<p>The idea is that copyright helps society. If people can gain from their own creations, called their intellectual property, then more people will want to create original works.</p>
<p>The law, however, permits the unlicensed use of copyrighted works under what is called <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.copyright.gov/fair-use/">fair use</a>. Fair use can include criticism, comment, news reporting, education and research. However, there are some limitations.</p>
<p>In education, students can include small parts of copyrighted work in their writing and research. But they must provide credit to the original creators through a citation which gives details about the <strong>source</strong>.</p>
<p>Many universities, including Harvard University, even urge students to give credit to sources of ideas when they come from discussions with professors or other students. Harvard even warns students about copying themselves. That is, they cannot hand in the same work for more than one class without the permission of their instructors.</p>
<p>A failure to do so is considered plagiarizing.</p>
<p><strong>How can professors know if a student is plagiarizing?</strong></p>
<p>Just as it is easy to copy, it is also easy for professors to know if a student has plagiarized.</p>
<p>First, there are computer programs and artificial intelligence, or AI, tools that compare students' papers to large databases of published writing. The programs can identify whether students have copied published writing. Second, if English is not a student's first language, a professor might recognize a change in wording and writing <strong>style</strong>. This could bring more attention to the student's paper.</p>
<p>Plagiarism is punished in different ways. Professors could simply warn a student not to do it again, lower their <strong>grade</strong>, or they might fail the student in that class. In more extreme cases, a student may be temporarily banned or expelled from school.</p>
<p><strong>Tools to avoid plagiarism</strong></p>
<p>There are free tools to make citations easier for students and to avoid plagiarism. <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.zotero.org/">Zotero</a> is a free, open-source program that helps organize all the research a student may use. For example, it can automatically create citations and combine them into a list. The <a class="wsw__a" href="https://owl.purdue.edu/owl/purdue_owl.html">Purdue Online Writing Lab</a>, or Purdue OWL for short, is another free resource.</p>
<p>Many universities also have writing centers where students can learn the citation rules. And another way for students to learn how to avoid plagiarism is to read published papers and pay careful attention to how information is presented. Students should observe when and how citations are used. This can help them learn the rules of citations.</p>
<p>In educational, or academic, writing, it is better to cite too much than too little.<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>A possible double standard</strong></p>
<p>Harvard's Claudine Gay resigned this month after several accusations of plagiarism in her <strong>academic</strong> work.</p>
<p>Gay's academic writing got attention after she was strongly criticized for her answers to a Congressional committee related to freedom of speech. Critics found several cases of possible plagiarism in her 1997 doctoral paper. Harvard's governing board first supported Gay, saying a review of her scholarly work turned up "a few instances of <strong>inadequate</strong> citation" but no evidence of research wrongdoing.</p>
<p>There has been debate among academics over whether her conduct amounted to academic dishonesty. D. Stephen Voss is an associate professor of political science at the University of Kentucky. He knew Gay when they were graduate students at Harvard. A paper he co-wrote in the 1990s was one Gay is accused of plagiarizing from.</p>
<p>He said in an <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/why-some-academics-are-reluctant-to-call-claudine-gay-a-plagiarist">interview</a> with the <em>New Yorker</em> magazine that Gay did plagiarize from him. But what she copied from his paper was "<strong>trivial</strong>" and "<strong>inconsequential</strong>."</p>
<p>What Gay used from his paper "did not take an idea of any <strong>significance</strong> from my work." He added: "the bit she used from us was not in any way a major component of what made her research important or valuable."</p>
<p>Roger Kreuz is a psychology professor at the University of Memphis who is writing a book on the history and psychology of plagiarism. He told VOA in an email that if plagiarism is defined as taking words from another person's work, "the opinion of (Voss) doesn't really matter."</p>
<p>Kreuz wrote in the online publication, <a class="wsw__a" href="https://theconversation.com/plagiarism-is-not-always-easy-to-define-or-detect-220592">The Conversation</a>, that university students and professors might face different requirements when it comes to plagiarism. Kreuz wrote that professors suspected of plagiarism may be given the <strong>benefit of the doubt</strong> by their schools. They may also be given the chance to make corrections to their published work.</p>
<p>Kreuz added that university leaders think that <strong>faculty</strong> members know what plagiarism is and how to avoid it. If a problem arises, administrators might think they were just being careless with their citations or use of quotation marks.</p>
<p>Students, on the other hand, must follow university policies on academic behavior. Harvard, for example, warns that students may be forced to leave the college if they plagiarize. Work written by students is more likely to be closely examined and put through tools that identify plagiarism than faculty work.</p>
<p>Many students consider this a <strong>double standard</strong>.</p>
<p>Kreuz wrote in <a class="wsw__a" href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2024/01/15/opinion/plagiarism-university-policies-faculty-harvard-claudine-gay/">an opinion piece</a> in <em>The Boston Globe</em> that university plagiarism policies for faculty are unclear.</p>
<p>How "can academics set or enforce policies for faculty when the concept is so ill-defined?" he asked.</p>
<p>I'm Dan Novak. And I'm Gena Bennett.</p>
<p><em>Andrew Smith, Jill Robbins, and Dan Novak wrote this story for VOA Learning English. Additional information came from Robert Kreuz's article in The Conversation and reporting from The Associated Press.</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>original </strong><em>— adj. </em>created first</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>author </strong><em>— n. </em>a person who writes a work or starts something</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>citation </strong><em>— n. </em>quotes from written works</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>style </strong><em>— n. </em>a way of doing something, such as writing, that is identifiable</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>grade </strong><em>— n. </em>a number or letter that is given to a piece of schoolwork that shows the student's level of success</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>academic </strong><em>— adj. </em>related to school especially colleges or universities</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>trivial </strong><em>— adj. </em>not important or useful</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>inconsequential </strong><em>— adj. </em>not important; resulting in nothing</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>significant </strong><em>— adj. </em>important</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>benefit of the doubt </strong><em>— idiom </em>to treat someone as honest or good although there is some doubt whether they are</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>faculty </strong><em>— n. </em>the teachers at a school or college</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>double standard </strong><em>— idiom </em>treating two groups very differently in a way that is considered unfair</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>‘Oppenheimer’ and ‘Poor Things’ Lead Oscar Nominations  (2024/1/24) | 《奥本海默》和《可怜的东西》领跑奥斯卡提名</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/oppenheimer-and-poor-things-lead-oscar-nominations.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<p>Oppenheimer, the film about the lead scientist in the American project to create a nuclear weapon, led the Academy Awards, or Oscars, with 13 nominations on Tuesday.<br/>
《奥本海默》是一部关于美国制造核武器项目首席科学家的电影，周二该电影以13项提名领跑奥斯卡奖。</p>
<p>The three-hour film was expected to be a top candidate for best picture. Oppenheimer also received nominations for best director for Christopher Nolan, lead actor for Cillian Murphy and supporting actors for Emily Blunt and Robert Downey, Jr. The film also received nominations for several production categories such as film editing and sound.<br/>
这部三小时的影片有望成为最佳影片的头号候选。《奥本海默》的克里斯托弗·诺兰获得最佳导演提名，西里安·墨菲获得男主角提名，艾米丽·布朗特和小罗伯特·唐尼获得男配角提名。该片还获得了电影剪辑和配乐等多个制作类别的提名。</p>
<p>Nolan is known as one of the top directors working in Hollywood today, but he has never won the award for director. None of his movies have won best picture. Experts say this may be his year to win both awards.<br/>
诺兰被称为当今好莱坞最顶尖的导演之一，但他从未获得过最佳导演奖。他的电影也从未获得最佳影片奖。专家表示，今年可能是他包揽两项大奖的一年。</p>
<p>Nolan told the Associated Press, "... getting this kind of recognition from the academy, I don't know what to say, really. It certainly confirms our faith in what studio filmmaking can be."<br/>
诺兰告诉美联社，“……得到学院的这种认可，我真的不知道该说什么。这肯定证实了我们对片厂电影制作的信念。”</p>
<p>Nine other films were nominated for best picture this year. They are Barbie, Poor Things, Killers of the Flower Moon, The Holdovers, Maestro, American Fiction, Past Lives, Anatomy of a Fall and The Zone of Interest.<br/>
今年还有9部电影获得最佳影片提名。它们是《芭比》、《可怜的东西》、《花月杀手》、《留校联盟》、《音乐大师》、《美国小说》、《过往人生》、《坠落的审判》和《利益区域》。</p>
<p>After Oppenheimer, the films with the most nominations were Poor Things with 11 and Killers of the Flower Moon with 10.<br/>
在《奥本海默》之后，获得提名最多的电影是《可怜的东西》（11项）和《花月杀手》（10项）。</p>
<p>Poor Things is a film about a Victorian-era woman brought back to life by a scientist and stars Emma Stone. She was nominated for best actress, along with Annette Bening in Nyad, Lily Gladstone in Killers of the Flower Moon, Sandra Huller in Anatomy of a Fall and Carey Mulligan in Maestro.<br/>
《可怜的东西》是一部关于一位维多利亚时代的女性的电影，这位女性由一位科学家复活，并由艾玛·斯通主演。斯通与《奈德》中的安妮特·贝宁、《花月杀手》中的莉莉·格莱斯顿、《坠落的审判》中的桑德拉·惠勒和《音乐大师》中的凯莉·穆里根一起获得了最佳女主角提名。</p>
<p>Barbie was the most successful movie in 2023. Greta Gerwig's film based on the famous toy brought in over $1.4 billion around the world. It received eight nominations. Gerwig, however, was not nominated for best director.<br/>
《芭比》是2023年最成功的电影。格蕾塔·葛维格根据这个著名玩偶拍摄的电影在全球带来了超过14亿美元的收入。它获得了八项提名。然而，葛维格并没有获得最佳导演提名。</p>
<p>Barbie received nominations for best picture, best supporting actor (Ryan Gosling as Ken) and two nominations for best song.<br/>
芭比娃娃获得了最佳影片、最佳男配角提名（瑞安·高斯林饰演肯）和两项最佳歌曲的提名。</p>
<p>The best director nominees were Nolan, Justine Triet of Anatomy of a Fall, Martin Scorsese of Killers of the Flower Moon, Yorgos Lanthimos of Poor Things and Jonathan Glazer of Zone of Interest. Scorsese was nominated in the category for the 10th time.<br/>
最佳导演提名者是诺兰、《坠落的审判》的茹斯汀·特里耶、《花月杀手》的马丁·斯科塞斯、《穷东西》的欧格斯·兰斯莫斯和《利益区域》的乔纳森·格雷泽。斯科塞斯是第10次获得该奖项提名。</p>
<p>The nominees for best international film were Society of the Snow, (from Spain); The Zone of Interest, (from Great Britain); The Teachers' Lounge (from Germany); Io Capitano (of Italy); and Perfect Days (from Japan).<br/>
最佳国际影片的提名者是来自西班牙的《绝境盟约》、来自英国的《利益区域》、来自德国《教师休息室》、来自意大利的《我是船长》和来自日本的《完美的日子》。</p>
<p>Experts say this year's group of nominees reflects a return to the traditional idea that films should be shown first in movie theaters before going to streaming services such as Netflix, Apple TV+ or Amazon Prime Video.<br/>
专家表示，今年的提名电影群体反映了对传统观念的回归，即电影应该先在电影院上映，然后再到Netflix、Apple TV+或亚马逊Prime Video等流媒体服务。</p>
<p>All of the top films spent at least one month in movie theaters first. Netflix was the top streaming video service with 18 nominations led by its film Maestro. That film tells the story of American composer Leonard Bernstein, and it stars actor Bradley Cooper, who also wrote and directed the movie.<br/>
所有顶级电影都会先在影院上映至少一个月。Netflix凭借其电影《音乐大师》等电影获得18项提名，位居流媒体视频服务榜首。这部电影讲述了美国作曲家伦纳德·伯恩斯坦的故事，主角布拉德利·库珀也是这部电影的编剧和导演。</p>
<p>The host of the awards broadcast on March 10 will be American late-night television presenter Jimmy Kimmel.<br/>
3月10日举行的颁奖典礼将由美国午夜电视节目主持人吉米·金梅尔主持。</p>
<p>I'm Dan Friedell.<br/>
我是丹·弗里德尔。(51VOA.COM原创翻译，请勿转载，违者必究！)</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Unwanted Plants Threaten Crops in North-Central US  (2024/1/24)</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/unwanted-plants-threaten-crops-in-north-central-us.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By John Russell</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">23 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Across the north-central United States, <strong>weeds </strong>that resist control efforts are worrying farmers. This development is the latest sign that weeds are becoming resistant to chemicals faster than major companies can make new weed-fighting products.</p>
<p>Scientists say that some sorts of weeds are developing resistance to chemicals used to destroy them.</p>
<p>Reuters news agency recently spoke with more than 20 farmers, scientists, weed specialists and company leaders. The news agency also studied eight research papers published since 2021. The studies described how weeds, including kochia, waterhemp, and giant ragweed, are affecting crops in North Dakota, Iowa, Wisconsin and Minnesota.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Kochia is seen in a sugar beet field near Nampa, Idaho, U.S., May 24, 2018 . (Clarke Alder/ Amalgamated Sugar Company/Handout via REUTERS)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/1b8c0191-0034-46d8-b3b7-39e8df73ecd6_cx0_cy2_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Kochia is seen in a sugar beet field near Nampa, Idaho, U.S., May 24, 2018 . (Clarke Alder/ Amalgamated Sugar Company/Handout via REUTERS)</span></div>
<p>Over the last 20 years, chemical companies have reduced the percentage of revenue meant for research and development spending. These companies are also introducing fewer products, says AgbioInvestor, a company based in Britain that studies the agricultural chemical industry.</p>
<p>Farmers say their battle with weeds threatens grain and oilseed harvests at a time when growers face inflation and extreme weather.</p>
<p>"We're in for big problems over the next 10 years for sure," said Ian Heap of the International Survey of Herbicide Resistant Weeds. It is a group of international scientists who work with governments and industry. He added, "We are in for a real <strong>shake-up</strong>."</p>
<p>The research group has a database of information on the reduced effectiveness of glyphosate, one of the most common weed-killing chemicals, against 361 weed species, including 180 in the U.S.</p>
<p>These weeds affect corn, soy, sugar beets and other crops.</p>
<p>Around the world, 21 weeds globally showed resistance to dicamba, the most recent major U.S. chemical, which launched in 2017.</p>
<p>Environmental groups argue that farmers should embrace natural weed-control methods instead of chemicals.</p>
<p>One Kochia plant can spread as many as 30,000 seeds. It can result in <strong>yields</strong> reduced by up to 70 percent if nothing is done to stop it. That information comes from Take Action, a farmer resource program of the United Soybean Board.</p>
<p>Other issues, including the development of stronger seeds, have pushed overall crop yields higher around the world. But scientists expect weed problems to worsen. Some weeds are even showing resistance the first time they are treated with chemicals.</p>
<p>In Douglas, North Dakota, farmer Bob Finken used dicamba and glyphosate to kill weeds late in the growing season. Neither product completely killed kochia.</p>
<p>"That was really scary," said Finken, age 64. "Each year seems to get a little worse."</p>
<p>Finken had to clear the weeds with harvesting equipment, which risks damaging the machinery.</p>
<p>Other farmers are hiring workers to pull weeds by hand, said Sarah Lovas of GK Technology, an agriculture company.</p>
<p>North Dakota was the largest spring wheat producing state in 2023 and ninth-biggest soybean grower.</p>
<p>Five of North Dakota's 53 counties have confirmed populations of dicamba-resistant kochia. That is only one year after it was first reported in the state, said Joe Ikley of North Dakota State University.</p>
<p>"It's just a matter of time before it hits your farm," said 65-year-old Monte Peterson who grows soybeans near Valley City, North Dakota.</p>
<p>Chemical producers Bayer, Corteva and FMC say longer development and government approval processes have limited new products to combat weed resistance. Industry leaders also say officials have become stricter about possible environmental and health effects.</p>
<p>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) said <strong>standards</strong> for approving new herbicides have not changed greatly since 1996. However, the EPA said recent efforts to study the effects of new active ingredients on threatened plants and wildlife have delayed some decisions.</p>
<p>The EPA did not estimate the increased processing time. The agency said it speeds up studies of lower-risk products.</p>
<p>I'm John Russell.</p>
<p><em>Rod Nickel and Tom Polansek reported on this story for Reuters. John Russell adapted it for VOA Learning English. </em></p>
<p>_______________________________________</p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>weed </strong><em>– n.</em> a plant that grows very quickly and covers or kills more desirable plants</p>
<p><strong>shake-up</strong> <em>– n.</em> is an important change or series of changes.</p>
<p><strong>yield</strong><em> – n.</em> the amount of something that is produced by a farm</p>
<p><strong>standard </strong><em>– n.</em> an acceptable level of quality or achievement; something that is used to judge the quality of something else</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Cameroon Launches First Malaria Vaccine Program for Children  (2024/1/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/cameroon-launches-first-malaria-vaccine-program-for-children.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Bryan Lynn</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>Cameroon has begun the world's first major malaria vaccine program for children.</p>
<p>The campaign launched Monday in the Central African nation. Health officials called the effort a major step in the fight against the disease across Africa. The continent accounts for about 95 percent of the world's malaria deaths.</p>
<p>The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates the disease, which is spread through mosquitos, kills more than 600,000 people a year. Most of the deaths involve young children.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="A nurse administers a malaria vaccine to an infant at the health center in Datcheka, Cameroon January 22, 2024. (REUTERS/Desire Danga Essigue)" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/01000000-0aff-0242-c50a-08dc1b8064f7_cx0_cy6_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">A nurse administers a malaria vaccine to an infant at the health center in Datcheka, Cameroon January 22, 2024. (REUTERS/Desire Danga Essigue)</span></div>
<p>The vaccine, called RTS.S, was developed by British drug company GlaxoSmithKline (GSK). It is meant to work with other preventive measures, such as the use of <strong>bed nets</strong>, to fight the disease.</p>
<p>Cameroon is the first country to offer vaccine injections through a <strong>routine</strong> program after successful tests, or trials, were carried out in Ghana and Kenya. Cameroon hopes to vaccinate about 250,000 children this year and next.</p>
<p>The international vaccine alliance called Gavi has said 19 other countries aim to launch their own campaigns this year. About 6.6 million children in those countries are to receive malaria vaccinations in 2024 and 2025.</p>
<p>"For a long time, we have been waiting for a day like this," said Mohammed Abdulaziz. He is with the African Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Abdulaziz spoke during a joint news briefing with the WHO, Gavi and other organizations.</p>
<p>Cameroon is using one of two recently approved malaria vaccines, called Mosquirix. When the WHO approved the vaccine two years ago, officials admitted it was not perfect. But they noted its use could sharply reduce severe infections and hospitalizations.</p>
<p>The GSK-produced shot is only about 30 percent effective. It requires four shots, or doses. Tests have shown the vaccine's protection begins to weaken after several months. GSK has said it can only produce about 15 million doses of Mosquirix a year.</p>
<p>Some experts believe a second malaria vaccine developed by Oxford University and approved by the WHO in October may be a better solution. That vaccine, called R21, is less costly and only requires three doses.</p>
<p>Launching the second vaccine is expected to result in enough vaccine supply "to meet the high demand and reach millions more children," said Kate O'Brien. She is the WHO's director of vaccinations.</p>
<p>"Having two vaccines for malaria will help to close the huge <strong>gap</strong> between demand and supply and could save tens of thousands of young lives, especially in Africa," said WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus.</p>
<p>India's Serum Institute – which helped develop the R21 vaccine –has said it could produce up to 200 million doses of it a year. Gavi has said that vaccine could be launched in May or June.</p>
<p>Some experts have raised questions about the long-term effectiveness of the vaccines. They have questioned whether attention and financing should be drawn away from the wider fight against the disease using established prevention methods.</p>
<p>But health experts at the news conference said the new vaccine launch included community efforts aimed at supporting the campaign. Officials advised individuals on vaccine safety and have urged them to continue to use existing protective methods alongside the vaccines.</p>
<p>I'm Bryan Lynn.</p>
<p><em>The Associated Press, Reuters and Agence France-Presse reported on this story. Bryan Lynn adapted the reports for VOA Learning English.</em></p>
<p><em>______________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p><strong>bed net </strong><em>– n. </em>a large piece of material made with crossed threads and holes that is placed over a bed and is designed to keep out insects</p>
<p><strong>routine </strong><em>– adj. </em>done regularly<em> </em></p>
<p><strong>gap </strong><em>– n. </em>an empty space or hole in the middle of or between two things</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
          <item>
            <title>Study: Diabetes, Obesity Drugs Not Linked to Suicidal Thoughts  (2024/1/23)</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://files.51voa.cn/202401/study-diabetes-obesity-drugs-not-linked-to-suicidal-thoughts.mp3"/>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="content">
<span class="byline">By Dan Novak</span><br/>
<span class="datetime">22 January 2024</span><br/>
<p>A large U.S. study found no evidence that taking Ozempic or Wegovy is tied to an increase in suicidal thoughts, researchers reported recently.</p>
<p>Both Ozempic for type 2 diabetes and the <strong>obesity</strong> treatment Wegovy have the same active ingredient, semaglutide.</p>
<p>The analysis included electronic medical record data from more than 1.8 million patients. Researchers actually found a lower risk of new and <strong>recurring</strong> suicidal thoughts in those taking semaglutide compared to those using other medications for weight loss or diabetes.</p><div class="contentImage"><img alt="FILE - Ozempic is displayed in a pharmacy in Provo, Utah on March 29, 2023. (REUTERS/George Frey/File Photo)
" src="https://img.51voa.cn/1/da277b7d-147e-499c-827f-8fb3abd5064e_cx0_cy4_cw0_w268_r1.jpg"/><br/><span class="imagecaption">FILE - Ozempic is displayed in a pharmacy in Provo, Utah on March 29, 2023. (REUTERS/George Frey/File Photo)
</span></div>
<p>Semaglutide belongs to a class of drugs known as GLP-1 agonists<strong>, </strong>which were designed to treat type 2 diabetes. In addition to helping control blood sugar levels, the drugs produce a feeling of fullness.</p>
<p>Concerns over reports of suicidal <strong>ideation</strong> connected with semaglutide led to an investigation by the European Medicines Agency. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has listed suicidal ideation as a possible safety concern for GLP-1 drugs.</p>
<p>A <em>Reuters</em> examination last year found that the FDA had received 265 reports of suicidal thoughts or behavior in patients taking semaglutide or similar medicines since 2010. Thirty-six of those reports describe a death by suicide or suspected suicide.</p>
<p>Such events do not prove a connection between a drug and a side effect. But they can signal to officials a need to study a specific risk.</p>
<p>The study appeared online in the journal <em>Nature</em>. It was funded by the U.S. National Institutes of Health. The researchers examined data on 240,258 U.S. patients <strong>prescribed</strong> Wegovy or other medications for weight loss and nearly 1.6 million with type 2 diabetes prescribed Ozempic or other treatments.</p>
<p>Researchers compared nearly 53,000 Wegovy patients to the same number of closely matched users of other weight-loss drugs.</p>
<p>They found that during the first six months of use, first-time suicidal thoughts were reported by 0.11 percent of Wegovy users. That is compared to 0.43 percent of users of other drugs that do not belong to the same class as semaglutide.</p>
<p>After taking other risk factors into consideration, the risk of first-time suicidal thoughts was 73 percent lower with Wegovy, the researchers said.</p>
<p>No patient in the Wegovy group reported a suicide attempt, compared to 14 users of the other drugs, the report said.</p>
<p>Among patients with a history of suicidal thoughts, the risk of recurring suicidal thoughts was 56 percent lower with Wegovy than other weight-loss medicines.</p>
<p>Similar patterns were seen for use of Ozempic compared with other diabetes drugs.</p>
<p>The findings were <strong>consistent</strong> no matter the patients' sex, age, or ethnicity for both semaglutide types, the researchers found.</p>
<p>Such a study cannot prove that GLP-1 agonists do not increase the risk of suicidal ideation. But the findings may reduce concerns.</p>
<p>The researchers were unable to <strong>assess</strong> the statistical significance of differences in actual suicide attempts. The researchers noted that suicide attempts are "critically different from suicidal ideations."</p>
<p>Pamela Davis is a professor at Case Western Reserve School of Medicine in Ohio. She was one of the writers of the study. She said the growth in popularity of Ozempic makes it very important "to understand all its <strong>potential</strong> complications."</p>
<p>Suggestions that the drug may cause suicidal thoughts are not supported by "this very large and <strong>diverse</strong> population in the U.S.," Davis added.<br/>
<br/>
I'm Dan Novak.</p>
<p><em>Dan Novak adapted this story for VOA Learning English based on reporting by Reuters. </em></p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><em>________________________________________________</em></p>
<h2 class="wsw__h2">Words in This Story</h2>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>obesity </strong><em>— n. </em>fat in a way that is unhealthy</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>recur </strong><em>— v. </em>to happen or appear again</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>ideation </strong><em>— n. </em>the formation of ideas or concepts</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>prescribe </strong><em>— v. </em>to officially tell someone to use as a remedy or treatment</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>consistent </strong><em>— adj. </em>always acting or behaving in the same way</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"><strong>diverse </strong><em>— adj. </em>different from each other</p>
<p class="CxSpMiddle"> </p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
            <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
          </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
